<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P015352_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing Resilience to Agricultural Drought in Africa through Improved Communication of Seasonal Forecasts (ERADACS)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ERADACS is a novel, multi-disciplinary project that brings together:  - a light-weight but powerful forecast system, state-of-the-art land surface data assimilation using NASA soil moisture data  - new methods for visualizing and communicating forecasts, co-developed with farmers in Africa - socioeconomic studies on building resilience through early warning and incentivizing action on forecasts The project will be led by the University of Reading and carried out in partnership the Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology (KNUST), a leading Ghanaian university; and Evidence for Development, a well-established NGO. The impact of agricultural drought on the world&apos;s poorest communities can be devastating. Changes in weather patterns due to changing climate can mean that decisions about when to plant and how to manage crops based on experience of weather in recent years are not reliable. Timely forecasts of the developing likelihood of agricultural drought have the potential to have a significant positive impact on the lives of small-scale farmers and their surrounding communities during such events.  The ERADACS project will develop a forecast system for agricultural drought using multiple streams of satellite data, the Met Office land surface model (JULES) and state-of-the-art mathematical techniques (Data Assimilation) to combine these. The resulting forecast will use climatological information from the 30 year TAMSAT data record to predict likely trajectories of rainfall. These seasonal forecasts will be produced across Ghana and made available openly via the TAMSAT website.  Beyond the lifetime of the ERADACS project we will sustain the forecast system via the operational TAMSAT platform.  A key aspect of the ERADACS project will be a pilot of how this information might be useful to specific communities in Ghana that are reliant on subsistence farming practices. We will visit and collect socioeconomic information from a number of communities to establish their vulnerability to agricultural drought as well as using serious game play to elicit likely responses. Our forecasts, and their likely uncertainties, will be discussed with the farmers and we will trial different methods of presenting this data. We will use feedback from these groups to refine the means of communication and to tailor the information produced from the forecast system. The work in Ghana will be carried out by KNUST and Evidence for Development, both of whom have many years experience of capacity building in Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ERADACS project seeks to enhance resilience to agricultural drought by providing seasonal forecasts of soil moisture with quantified uncertainty, to communicate this information in meaningful manner, and to understand how such information might improve decision making at a community level. Our objectives are to: (1) Demonstrate how (a) forecast information can be optimally combined with satellite observed soil moisture using the JULES land surface model using data assimilation techniques, and (b) the predictions from this system can be communicated in an effective and timely manner in such a way as to build resilience in farming communities. (2) Generate the foundation for a future international consortium building on and establishing new relationships between the University of Reading, two NERC Centres (NCEO and NCAS), NOAA Rainwatch, KNUST, the Ghana Meteorological Agency (GMA), and the Regional Climate Outlook Forum for West Africa, Chad and Cameroon (PRESASS) The research questions we will address in this foundational project are as follows, but an important end goal will also be to produce a clear well defined set of research questions for a future project: RQ1:  How can we best utilise satellite data, seasonal forecasts and new visualization techniques to communicate information about the current state of the land surface and its likely future trajectory?  RQ2:  To what extent is this information of value to end-users, and what additional information is required to build resilience to climate change/variability in farming communities in Africa?  Objective 1 will be met via our activity on the ground in Africa. We will hold a project workshop in Ghana in January 2017 and will attend the Regional Climate Outlook Forum for West Africa, Chad and Cameroon in May 2017 to disseminate results and to build the onward consortium.  Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology (KNUST) will be investigators on the ERADACS project and key partners in future research. Forecasts of agricultural drought (objective 2) will be based on a novel, lightweight system already developed in the University of Reading&apos;s TAMSAT group. These forecasts incorporate the outputs of the Data Assimilation system. We will devise new ways of communicating this information and refine this using feedback from the communities in Ghana we will engage with during the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-13">47451.69</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-13">110458.68</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-13">157910.374</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC GCRF Directed - International Award to University of Reading</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P015352_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FP015352%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-01-09"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
