<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_R001898_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A UK-Africa Data Science Network: Capturing the SKA-Driven Data Transformation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme will build a multi-institute big data research and training platform, between the South African and UK partner universities, that will establish sustainable links via a Data Science Network, led by academics and developed and refined in consultation with the user community. eResearch capacity is an absolute necessity in a world where the appropriate handling of big data, in the natural sciences, medicine, the humanities and the social sciences is of paramount importance. This program will support the development of research capacity in Big Data and Data Science in South Africa through the creation of a joint UK-SA training network which will form the basis of a long term sustainable research collaboration that has the potential to address issues of global concern.  The program is designed to create a UK-SA Data Science Network to advance research and training in big data science.  As a core tool to support the network and its programs we will develop and deploy an online portal gateway. Such cyber-infrastructure can be used both as a direct teaching resource, hosting MOOCs and other online material, as well as a research platform for data science and big data, hosting a data portal and collaborative work space. The program does not intend to build physical infrastructure, but will utilise capacity at existing facilities developed for data intensive research in conjunction with the SKA project in Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-10-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="ZA" type="SOUTH AFRICA"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTHERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1029</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-11-01">50903.16</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-11-01">404523.39</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-11-01">608169.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-11-01">411853.2</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The Newton program proposed here will use the big data challenge of next generation scientific facilities, such as the SKA, to build capacity for &quot;dealing with large data sets&quot; as a vehicle for transfer of knowledge and innovation to other research domains. The science-driven data-intensive research and training program will develop solutions for data-intensive infrastructure, including portal technologies, data distribution and movement technologies, e-science tools, application interfaces, visualization and visual analytics, discovery techniques such as data mining, machine learning, etc. by fostering the development of an international cohort of researchers with the skills, links and contacts to operate in the global research environment through international training and development activities.  The objectives of this project are linked to the UN Global Goals:   - Ensure inclusive and equitable quality education and promote lifelong learning opportunities for all (UN Global Goal 4)   - Promote sustained, inclusive and sustainable economic growth, full and productive employment and decent work for all (UN Global Goal 8)  Objective 1: Skills Development   This program will provide training for 4 students to a PhD level and 8 students to an MSc level. Projects will be organised under three research themes with one half of students working on SKA-focused projects and one half of students working on non-SKA projects across a wide range of other domains such as healthcare, climate change, sustainable agriculture, disaster management, social data, smart cities etc. By running projects with multi-disciplinary impacts in parallel under common data science and big data themes we intend to maximise the translation of expertise across different fields. Students on PhD fellowships will be allocated joint UK-SA supervision and invited to spend extended periods on secondment with their second supervisor. These visits are intended to expose students to different working practices and environments and to increase their transferable skill set.   Objective 2: Proof of Concept   The PhD and MSc projects conducted as part of this program not only have the potential to provide direct data science solutions, but will also act as proof of concept studies for developing a wider data science economy in SA and SSA. A key element of on-ramping industrial users of data science and big data solutions is demonstrating the value of these actions. Whilst the big data nature of the SKA project is clear, the translation of the expertise developed as part of the project to wider areas is less tangible. The parallel projects developed under this Newton program will illustrate the utility of these skills across a diverse range of applications and accelerate market engagement in HPC and big data.   Objective 3: A Coherent Approach to Big Data Tools and Systems  There is a need for a forum that brings together the big data requirements of nations and organisations across SSA. This Newton program will provide an initial cyber-infrastructure necessary for such a forum via its web portal. This portal will be an entry point to an on-line ecosystem of data, compute, e-science tools, visualization and visual analytics tools, and a collaboration environment that will combine these components together into a seamless platform for a multi-institutional and multi-disciplinary research collaboration around big data. The development of this cyber-infrastructure will itself be one of the core research and training project of the Data Science Network, and be one of the core research and training project of the Data Science Network, and build on physical infrastructure developed for SKA-driven data intensive research challenges.  It will be influenced by an awareness of what other countries and companies are doing with HPC, big data \&amp; data science, by leveraging the international nature of the Newton program partnership."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
