<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_R022747_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Understanding evolution of fungicide resistance in wheat blast field populations in Brazil; can we learn lessons for future disease management?</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Some diseases are becoming very difficult to control due to lack of host resistance and limited availability of crop protection products. Resistance, tighter regulations and a slowing pipeline of new products are reducing the range of available chemical classes. This has lead to a greater dependence of compounds with fewer modes of action and, subsequently, increases the selective pressure for further cases of resistance. In order to increase the shelf life of new and currently available actives, evolution-smart integrated pest management strategies are needed. This project will focus on the plant pathogen Pyricularia graminis-tritici (Pygt), the causal agent of wheat blast, an important fungal disease in Brazil that is very difficult to control, with several groups of fungicides (e.g. sterol demethylase, quinone outside and succinate dehydrogenase inhibitors) having become ineffective. Wheat blast has been a major disease across central and southern Brazil and was first described in Paran&#xE1; State in 1985. Following the emergence of wheat blast in Bangladesh in 2016, it has further spread into India in 2017.  These Asian strains are the same as that of Brazil due to contaminated seed import, and the disease is expected to move into Pakistan, South East Asia and Africa and is expected to impact food security, welfare and economic growth of millions of undernourished people. To improve disease control, a better understanding of the epidemiology, the fungicide sensitivity status and disease management strategies are needed. In this project we will focus on all three aspects using the lastest spore trapping technology, fungicide pheno- and genotyping assays as well as a fungicide target protein expression system, enabling to investigate the impact of target mutations on enzyme function and fungicide binding. These tools are generic and can be applied for other plant pathogens.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-20">48282.45</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Chemical control of wheat blast is currently dependent on three different modes of action, the azoles, Quinone outside Inhibitors (QoI&apos;s) and succinate dehydrogenase inhibitor (SDHI) fungicides. In vitro fungicide sensitivity assays have revealed different levels of resistance to all three groups. In order to rationalise fungicides inputs (e.g. choice, timing, dose-rate, spray number and mixing/alternation) and to test anti-resistance strategies aimed to delay evolution and spread of resistance to these three groups of fungicides and to future new actives entering the market, high throughput monitoring tools, enabling quantitative measurement of pathogen levels and detection of fungicide resistant alleles, in combination with disease forecasting are needed.   The main objectives of this pump-prime project are:  1, to improve our understanding of wheat blast epidemics.  2, to investigate current fungicide sensitivity status to azoles, QoIs and SDHIs of Pygt populations in different geographic areas in Brazil and identify fungicide resistance mechanisms. 3, to develop of a yeast-based heterologous expression system for high throughput screening of different CYP51 variants to allow us to investigate functional constraints on introduced cyp51 mutations through complementation assays."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
