<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006280_2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Poverty Research Network</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. To establish a transnational research community, promoted through a series of workshops in five carefully selected ODA recipient nations (Bangladesh, Brazil, the Indian Ocean World with an event in South Africa, Mexico, and Eastern Europe with an event in Slovenia), a major international concluding conference at the University of Warwick, and a dedicated project website.   2. Through this network, to investigate and document how different definitions and narratives of poverty and poverty reduction have been produced in specific localities across the developing world. This will provide people who have been the object of poverty discourses a voice and chance to share their experiences and ideas of solutions. 3. To harness the insights and methodologies of the arts and humanities, to diversify the subjects and productions of history through engagement with the often silent majority of global communities, and thereby initiate a change in narratives of poverty that have been created by economists and social scientists. 4. To bring these narratives and local knowledge into dialogue with contemporary international development policy and practice, through engagement with UK-based international development NGOs (Oxfam and Save the Children), and the governmental Department for International Development (DFID). 5. To cross research boundaries, promoting collaboration and dialogue between disciplines, universities, research cultures, academic and non-academic stakeholders, policymakers, practitioners, and national contexts. 6. To disseminate research findings through academic publications, workshops, and the project website. This includes the production of a special edition of the peer-reviewed journal Social History. A provisional commitment to publish this special edition has been confirmed, which will be edited by the Principal Investigator and publish the findings and experiences of the Network from a range of perspectives.   7. To generate public awareness of the project&apos;s work through a range of channels, including a dedicated social media platform and online website and forum, a regularly updated online blog, a series of exhibitions to be held in tandem with the project partner workshops, and an exhibition to be held at the University of Warwick in conjunction with the concluding international conference.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Poverty Research Network will contribute to our understanding of ways in which the world can innovate its approach to international development by increasing and intensifying grassroots dialogues between communities, academics across different disciplines, activists and policy makers. This project aims to excavate the narratives behind the numbers of poverty research, challenging the monopoly that economists and social scientists have had on approaches to poverty research. It uses the perspectives and tools of the arts and humanities not only to give a voice to poor communities around the world, the often silent majority, but also to diversify the production of representations of these communities and their histories. This project is not only trans-spatial but trans-temporal; it aims to take a long view, looking to history to understand the causes of inequality, and creating histories of communities which can be a source of empowerment and dignity, and using this as a platform to engineer alternative visions of the future and pathways of improvement of qualities of life.  Building on existing partnerships, the poverty research network will use the AHRC grant to forge a carefully coordinated international dialogue, hosting events at 5 partner institutions around a theme that has been determined by those ODA recipient regions as most pertinent. The project has been planned to represent different regions of the world that have been the subject of development policies, and to discuss different themes relating to development agenda in each location. The selected regions and themes are: Bangladesh, &apos;Women, Migration and Poverty&apos;; Brazil, &apos;Poverty, Tourism and Forced Labour&apos;; Indian Ocean World, &apos;Poverty, inequality and the politics of natural resources&apos;; Mexico &apos;Poverty and Indigeniety&apos;; South-East Europe, &apos;Intersecting patterns of poverty and the position of marginalized Romani minorities and post-conflict migration in Eastern Europe&apos;. The project will finish with an event at the University of Warwick, where representatives of the different regional events will attend and present summaries of their findings and have the opportunity to hear about experiences and ideas of solutions from different parts of the world, thinking about shared experiences, and regional variations. The Warwick event will happen in conjunction with an exhibition, which further aims to diversify representations of poor communities around the world.  The key output of the poverty research network will be the locally produced &apos;Archive for Alternate Futures&apos;; a website which captures stories of local communities, their histories, and their visions for achieving more equal futures. The project also aims to contribute to the transformation of modes of research project and policy formation, forging methodologies, experiences, and tools, for dialogic approaches to poverty research and poverty reduction strategies, and integrating the insights of histories.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-06" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-22">7838.18</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-22">15676.32</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-22">39190.864</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Research Networking Award to University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006280_2" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FP006280%2F2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-08-07"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
