<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_N006798_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional crop monitoring and assessment with quantitative remote sensing and data assimilation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aims: 1. To provide enhanced information to researchers, regional authorities and Agritech companies and extension workers advising farmers in China for monitoring and prediction of crop health, vigour and yield, from field to regional scales. 2. To assess the impacts of farming practices (importantly, crop type choices and rotation as well as water and other inputs) under current climate and future climate scenarios. Objectives: 1. To refine the underpinning theory, data and software tools for a prototype DA system in China for agricultural monitoring and prediction. 2. To test and apply this system for winter wheat and summer maize in the North China Plain. 3. To apply key Chinese satellite sensors (GF 1,2; BJ2) and data assets (GLASS) to the monitoring system. 4. To exploit recent operational availability of critical data inputs from the USA (Landsat) and EU/ESA Sentinel series (Sentinels 1,2,3), and explore the use of other data sources (RapidEye, Radarsat). 5. To provide and use a system for the assessment of farming practices under current climate and future climate scenarios based on information and tools provided by the DA system.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China has only 10% of the world arable land and water resources, but has to feed 20% of the world population. Moreover, the population continues to increase, while the amount of arable land is shrinking due to pollution, urban sprawl, groundwater depletion, and other stresses.  With future climate change expected to only worsen these pressures, the accurate monitoring of agricultural productivity is essential to China&apos;s future food security, in addition to the economic development of low-income rural regions.  In no part of the country is this more essential than China&apos;s north plain.  This has historically been the breadbasket of China.  Today, however, it faces an exceptionally challenging combination of very high population densities and ecological stresses, and low levels of household income.   Traditionally, researchers have used two general methods for monitoring agricultural productivity.  The first, which has long been used by Chinese government agencies, is to combine field surveys of crop growth, with mathematical models of crop growth processes, to construct estimates of changing harvest yields over time.  The second, which has risen to prominence more recently, is to use satellite imagery to continuously assess agricultural productivity.  Each of these techniques has its own notable strengths and weaknesses.  Survey-calibrated models of crop growth are able to produce highly accurate estimates of yields in the limited areas where survey data has been collected; however, their accuracy drops off significantly outside of these areas.  On the other hand, satellite remote sensing data offers universal geographic coverage; however, the resolution of this data is extremely coarse over either time or space.  MODIS data, for example, provides near-daily data that can be used to assess the productivity of every single farm in China.  However, the spatial resolution of pixels is only 500-1000 meters, an area which will invariably be contaminated, in densely populated China, by a mixture of roads, villages, and other non-agricultural land uses in addition to the farmland actually being studied.  Other satellites (e.g. LandSat TM and forthcoming Sentinel) provide finer scale pixel resolution than MODIS; however, they do not cover the same sites as often, making it harder to smoothly track agricultural production over time. Reflecting the wider explosion of the field of &quot;big data&quot; analysis, rapid strides have been made recent years in the development of so-called &quot;data assimilation&quot; techniques.  These can be broadly described as statistical methodologies that allow for otherwise incompatible datasets to be combined together, in order to produce hybrid datasets that are superior to any of their predecessors.  The basic objective of the proposed project is to apply advanced data assimilation techniques to multiple types of crop data-from both survey-calibrated crop growth models and satellite imagery-to produce superior estimates of Chinese agricultural productivity than would be possible using any of these data sources by itself.  In addition to making use of more advanced statistical methods than previous studies, this analysis will be among the first to make use of data from the forthcoming Sentinel and the Chinese GF satellites.  Taken together, we expect that the result will be the most accurate portrait created to date of changing agricultural production in the North China Plain.  Moreover, having created this data, we will be able to apply it predictively in conjunction with modelled scenarios of future climate change, in order to map and assess the likely geographies of agricultural stress that this will create.  Ultimately, the findings of this project will directly inform work by academic researchers, national and regional Chinese governmental authorities, agritech companies in both China and the UK, and extension workers directly advising farmers in China.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-10">240056.61</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-10">298964.38</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-10">377353.97</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-10">29125715.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC Newton Newton Fund Award to University College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_N006798_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ST%2FN006798%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
