<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S003975_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transitional justice as education: A feminist network for empowering truth commissions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia&apos;s Commission for the Clarification of Truth, Coexistence and Non-Repetition is tasked with investigating the truth behind one of the world&apos;s longest running armed conflicts. In its preparatory phase, the Commission has been attentive to lessons learned from truth commissions around the world, of which there have now been more than forty. It introduces a number innovative practices, positioning it as an important part of Colombia&apos;s wider transitional justice process and of its chances to build a lasting peace.   Too often, truth commissions (TCs) have left engagement with formal and informal education until the end of their work, missing out on opportunities to engage the wider population in their work and to effect change in mind-sets and educational processes. Likewise, many TCs have included women&apos;s experiences of violence only narrowly or have approached gender as a discrete theme, unconnected to the rest of the TC&apos;s work. The Colombian TC is determined not to repeat these mistakes. However, like the Colombian peace process more generally, the TC faces significant challenges - polarised public opinion around peace, as demonstrated by the no victory in the 2016 referendum on the peace deal between the government and the FARC; rising rates of violence and active conflict regions of the country; and an upcoming Presidential election that may jeopardise the peace process. As they begin their work, Truth Commissioners and TC staff working on gender and pedagogy are bound to confront daily challenges of a high stakes, emotional, and exhausting stakes endeavour to collect the testimonies of up 50,000 Colombians affected by conflict.  This network seeks to support the gender and pedagogy work of the Colombian TC, ensuring that the TC is able to make a significant contribution to embedding a gender just and inclusive peace in Colombia. Using tools from the arts and humanities in feminist methodologies, affective agency, and transformative pedagogy, the network will connect Colombian truth commissioners and their teams with inspirational feminist leaders, who have led and learned from TC experiences elsewhere. These former Truth Commissioners are peace activists, human rights advocates, indigenous leaders, educators, and dignitaries - they will share their experiences being part of truth commissions from South Africa to Canada and Timor Leste to Peru, and they will support and offer strategic advice on the gender and pedagogy work of the Colombian TC, through a series of workshops and travel visits.  The project will collect the experiences and reflections of these inspirational leaders through a series of peer interviews, that will also feed into the supportive relational work of the project. These will be used to produce an interactive website aimed at future feminist peace activists and leaders around the world, which shares the life histories, advice and inspiration of these incredible individuals.   The network will have impact at a number of levels, including for: 1) the individuals who make up the network and draw energy and inspiration from it for their important transitional justice work; 2) the success of the Colombian truth commission and its contribution to peace in Colombia; 3) international TC and transitional justice best practice; and 4) sharing and developing theoretical tools around affective agency and transformative pedagogy in transitional justice.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">There have been over forty truth commissions since the early 1980s; only two have been led by women. Truth commissions (TCs) in El Salvador, Uganda and Uruguay did not include any women as commissioners. In every truth commission apart from the Greensboro Commission in the USA, women commissioners have been outnumbered by men, sometimes dramatically so as in Peru (10:2) and Morocco (15:1).   Women truth commissioners, human rights advocates and feminists have worked hard to include and embed gender, attention to women&apos;s rights, and women&apos;s experiences during conflict into the work that truth commissions do, drawing on wider initiatives around women rights and feminism in peace movements and peacebuilding. Likewise, educators and scholars have argued for a richer attention to education and pedagogical practice within the work of TCs, pointing to the potential such engagements have both enhancing participation during the TC mandate and for the long term impact of TCs. Research and activism in both areas point to the importance of emotional and affective responses and relationships in the success of transitional justice work around gender and pedagogy.  TC processes, which involve repeatedly hearing difficult testimonies and uncovering truths about violence and human rights abuses, can be highly stressful, exhausting and even traumatic for those who lead and participate in them, and who are inevitably deeply personally and emotionally involved.Our network therefore adopts a feminist theoretical and methodological focus, enabling a space for theorising affect and affective agency in the pedagogical and gender work of the TC and a space for supporting, acknowledging and inspiring the affective agency that the individuals driving this work bring to it.  This network seeks celebrate, share, reinforce and theorise the efforts of the Colombian TC to embed gender and pedagogy as priorities.  The network brings together women truth commissioners (current and former) from around the world, feminist activists, transitional justice experts, and scholars towards the following objectives:    1) To support the Colombian TC to embed gender justice and innovative pedagogical engagement within the work of the commission and in its wider social impact.   2) To enable a space for those leading and working on gender and pedagogy within the Colombian TC to strategize and reflect on their work in dialogue with and learning from inspirational, feminist former truth commissioners, leaders, and experts from around the world (concentrated in the global South).   3) To create an interactive website that shares stories and insights, gathered through peer interviewing, from the inspirational individuals who make up the network for an audience of present and future feminists and peace activists.   4) To work together to theorise and publish academic papers on a feminist, affective transitional justice and its pedagogical potential.   These objectives will be realised through a network organised around a series of workshops and travel visits with leading current and former truth commissioners (the vast majority women from the global south), experts on transitional justice, pedagogy and gender, and members of the Colombian&apos;s TCs gender and pedagogy working groups. Network members will share experiences, strategize with the Colombian TC team, and conduct a series of peer interviews, generating content for the interactive website. The project will produce co-authored papers sharing the Colombian TC experience and theorising affective agency and transitional justice.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">37555.99</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">16373.98</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">53929.97</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Research Networking Award to University of Bristol</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH/S003975/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-01">37555.99</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S003975_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-01">16373.98</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S003975_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FS003975%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
