<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T005564_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The hidden peace-builders: from ambivalence to engagement, strengthening the role of local faith actors in peace-building and reconciliation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) Our key aim during the Development Award is to press on with growing a strong, interdisciplinary and equitable network of Global South and North research and peace-building organisations as either the basis for launching the Network Plus in April 2020 or as the cornerstone of identifying new funding possibilities with a firm proposal that is ready to go.  There is, however, inherent value in identifying and bringing actors with this interest together for networking, regardless of success in future funding schemes.  2) To organise our activities during the Development Award, and to support equitable and sustainable partnerships by addressing the specific feedback on our outline proposal. There will be three stages to how we tackle the feedback and begin to develop the Network Plus. First, there are areas to be addressed as we prepare the full proposal; second, there are areas to work on further in the period between proposal submission and learning the outcome of the call; and, third, there are areas that will be the focus of work either coinciding with the start of the Network Plus or forming a period where we work towards seeking additional funding to support this work beyond the end of June 2020. 3) To build an international, cross-sectoral and interdisciplinary network through the establishment of regional hubs in South Sudan, Sri Lanka and the Philippines. This will consist of academics, humanitarian/development organisations, grassroots civil society organisations (CSOs), local government, and faith actors working together to better understand and improve the role of local faith actors (LFAs) in peace building and reconciliation, with the aim of improving the lives of the most marginalised, including religious minorities, children and women. While the hubs are in three countries, they are to be regional hubs to facilitate engagement from stakeholders across East Africa, South Asia and South East Asia, regions with complex and diverse histories of conflict.  4) To speak into gaps within the UN&apos;s &apos;New Way of Working&apos; (NWoW), promoted since the 2016 World Humanitarian Summit. This means that humanitarian, development and peace actors are recommended to work together (the &apos;triple nexus&apos;) and to better understand and remove any barriers preventing engagement with local actors. While there is a mandate for international peace building, humanitarian and development actors to work closely together and with all local actors, LFAs have been generally been excluded from the NWoW.  5) To begin to develop networks and research that enables the greater visibility of LFAs at the local, national and global levels. They are often hidden to all but their very immediate communities due to the grassroots and small-scale nature of their activities. This is in line with the so-called, &apos;Grand Bargain&apos; and outcome of the 2016 World Humanitarian Summit. This commits donors to provide 25% of humanitarian funding to local/national responders by 2020 and encourages humanitarian actors to better understand and to remove any barriers preventing engagement with local actors. There is a mandate for international peace-building, humanitarian and development actors to work closely together and with all local actors, including LFAs. 6) To lay the ground work for developing curricula with project partners World Vision International and Islamic Relief Worldwide, including e-learning versions, for use by development and humanitarian organisations, grassroots CSOs and local government to equip them to engage LFAs in peace building processes, along with guidance and tools for monitoring and evaluation (M&amp;E) for these actors. The need for this has been recognised by the project partners. Attention has tended to focus on the work of higher-level faith actors, including national religious councils and internationally focused religious leaders, rather than LFAs. Where there has been work with LFAs this has not been researched or evaluated.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our key aim during the Development Award is to press on with growing a strong, interdisciplinary and equitable network of Global South and North research and peace-building organisations as either the basis for launching the Network Plus in April 2020, if our application is successful, or as the cornerstone of identifying new funding possibilities with a firm proposal that is ready to go. We have decided that the best way to organise our activities during the Development Award, to support equitable and sustainable partnerships, is to address the specific feedback on our outline proposal. Our  Network Plus aims to deliver the first large-scale comparative study on the role of local faith actors in inter- and intra-faith initiatives to support peace building, working from regional hubs in South Sudan, the Philippines and Sri Lanka. It will address the following research questions emerging as important for achieving SDG 16, RQ1: How can and do local faith actors (LFAs) best support peace in communities affected by violent conflict, and at what points in the journey from conflict to peace to reconciliation? RQ2: How can humanitarian organisations, grassroots civil society organisations and local government most effectively engage with LFAs in this process? RQ3: To what extent can this complement other aspects of community-based programming following the so-called &apos;triple nexus&apos; approach, for instance to promote sustained child well-being and gender equality?  RQ4: How do inter- and intra-faith initiatives can contribute to peace building efforts beyond the (apparent) religious dimensions of conflict? RQ5: In what ways do religious teachings and theologies drive the narrative of many local faith communities and their responses to conflict and peace building? In addition to facilitating research, the Network Plus will develop curricula, including e-learning versions, for use by development/humanitarian organisations, grassroots civil society organisations and local government. The aim of this curricula is to equip these stakeholders to engage LFAs in peace building processes. There will be three stages to how we tackle the feedback and begin to develop the Network Plus: STAGE  ONE - preparing the full proposal (July 1st - Sept. 19th, 2019). Work will be undertaken by a research assistant  who will: identifying existing curricula and projects on faith-based peace-building; carry out a stakeholder analysis in each country; and contacting, following up, phoning/skyping and introducing these people in the regions to begin to develop the network. This intensive process of locating and sharing information, and snowballing contacts, is essential to achieve a wide buy-in for the Network Plus. The work of the RA will be completed by the end of August so that it can feed into the full proposal.  STAGE TWO - run up to start of Network Plus (Sept. 20th, 2019 - 30th, March 2020) - We will hold three country meetings in South Sudan, Sri Lanka and Columbia. These will last three days each and will be organised with input from the hub leaders and the local offices of the project partners. -Day one: core team meeting - a chance for the core team members to meet and network; to review the three strands of the Network Plus full proposal and its fit with the region, including potential challenges and risks.  -Day two: an open meeting for broad range of stakeholders to introduce the Network Plus, and to generate local interest and feedback.   -Day three: a smaller more targeted workshop with key stakeholders, to work through the logistics of the three strands of the Network Plus, including beginning to plan the specific activities and their timing for Strand One.  STAGE THREE -(April 1st - June 30th,  2020) - to feed findings from the other stages into the inception of the Network Plus or use them to apply for other funding sources.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-02">56270.33</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-02">56270.322</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Large Grants Award to University of Leeds</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T005564_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FT005564%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
