<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008644_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Challenges and Risks Faced by Indigenous Peoples in Today&apos;s Brazil: Unpacking Vulnerability and Multiple Reactions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The long trend of environmental degradation and the socio-cultural impacts of mainstream development in Brazil have undergone a giant rise after the election of President Jair Bolsonaro, leading some organisations to denounce the unacceptable intensification of violence and conflicts (e.g. New York Times, 21 Sep 2019). In that context, the fate of indigenous groups constitutes one of the most serious political and economic questions in the country. These developments directly contradict the tendency to recognise indigenous rights initiated in the re-democratisation period in the late 1970s, which led to the inclusion of explicit articles in the 1988 Constitution. Whereas the indigenous population is trying to resist and react using all possible channels and opportunities, there is still limited understanding of barriers, prospects and feelings about the new adverse context. The research will address the impacts, perceptions and reactions of indigenous groups to the aggressive advance of conservative policies and social reforms by the new Brazilian administration. It will assess and theorise the combination of past legacies and new trends behind the intensification of violence affecting indigenous peoples. The project has three main phases: 1) analysis of pro- and anti-indigenous discourses, launch of a website to capture violence occurrences and elite interviews; 2) case studies in three hotspot areas in the states of Amazonas, Mato Grosso and Mato Grosso do Sul, targeting selected indigenous communities, involving indigenous researchers and making use of participant observation, interviews and focus groups, and in particular various artistic expressions (music, dance, drawings, drama, videos and pictures, etc.) that communicate suffering, the impacts and the perceptions of community members; 3) workshops, a national meeting and talks to communicate and problematize the empirical results and raise recommendations. Those combined research activities will all foster a dialogue between indigenous communities, allied organisations and researchers to shared experiences to better comprehend past legacies, mounting pressures and the diversity of responses. Its methodological approach means conducting academic work with and for the indigenous communities, allowing the expression of their own voices and direct involvement in the interpretation of findings, rather than the conventional research on those communities for the benefit of non-indigenous scholars and government agencies. The approach is inherently coproduced and will continuously engage relevant stakeholders in both the research design and its operation. It will encourage a &apos;relational reflexivity&apos; between the interdependent actors through an incremental methodology and research design with interrelated phases. The research team will deal with the national state of affairs and also focus on selected indigenous communities in three areas particularly affected by the action of public agencies and private entities. In addition to external pressures, there are also internal community factors that influence indigenous reactions and that need to be examined, such as internal disputes and hierarchies among indigenous communities and extended families, gender inequalities and domestic violence, intergenerational mechanisms of support or competition, forced adoption of indigenous children, and specific public service demands. In addition, the project will have wider theoretical and empirical repercussions considering that the specific situation of indigenous groups is certainly an integral part of the wider erosion of labour rights, the rule of law and democratic freedoms in many parts of the world, as well as an element of the international maelstrom associated with persecution of migrants, economic and political instabilities, global environmental risks and climate injustices.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed research deals with the rapidly deteriorating politico-economic situation of indigenous peoples in Brazil, which reflects the wider South American and international context of conservative, far-right politics. The work is particularly urgent due to the (so far badly understood) intensification of genocidal tendencies that has followed the aggressive attitudes, exacerbated rhetoric and perverse policies of the new Brazilian government elected in 2018 and its national and international allies.  The fate of indigenous groups constitutes one of the country&apos;s most serious humanitarian emergencies and rapid political change. It is a real time bomb waiting to explode. Indigenous populations are trying to react and are vigorously protesting, using all possible channels and opportunities, but there is much confusion and a prevailing sense of perplexity among academics, activists and civil society at large.  Taking those cross-scale and multifaceted challenges into account, this research will connect up disconnected discourses and disparate analytical approaches to the intensification of genocide, epistemicide and ecocide trends affecting indigenous peoples in Brazil. Its underlying assumption is the urgent need to systematise the more recent trends and interrogate the deteriorating human rights situation together with the affected populations, their strategic allies and broader civil society Over 12 months of collective work, coordinated by a bi-national team of academics and experts, the initiative will expand the existing theorisation of genocide (associated and also manifested in the form of epistemicide and ecocide) and examine indigenous resistance and reactions (in partnership with the affected communities and considering the national context) in order to raise policy recommendations and indicate pathways for the recognition of the creativity and political agency of indigenous groups in crisis situations aggravated by the disruptive interventions of the national state.   The main aim is to increase empirical, conceptual and analytical-based knowledge about the socio-economic and socio-cultural impacts of the intensification of genocidal pressures in present-day Brazil and understand the multiple forms of perception, sensibility, resistance and reaction. That will be achieved through a multiscale study at the national, regional and local levels of interaction and with an intense engagement with indigenous communities in the Brazilian states of Mato Grosso, Amazonas and Mato Grosso do Sul.  The project will meet the following interconnected objectives: Objective 1: Examine violence trends, discursive exchanges and the rationalisation of aggression associated with genocidal, epistemicidal and ecocidal practices.  Objective 2: Explore perceptions, experiences and attitudes of indigenous communities towards resisting violence and reacting to mounting pressures and risks. Objective 3: Develop new theorisations of the interconnected processes of genocide, epistemicide and ecocide that can inform the pursuit of inclusive development and democratic policy reforms. The research will integrate a range of participative and engaged research tools designed to address the above objectives. All partners will be considered co-authors and actively involved innovative, transdisciplinary research methods and the assessment of artistic expressions in selected indigenous communities. It will draw upon the research team&apos;s extensive experience working with indigenous groups and government agencies.  The work will mobilise a reflexive, inclusive research methodology that is also directly associated with the collective identification of socio-cultural and political transformations. Critical indigenous studies are a growing area of interest not merely because of the specific dilemmas affecting subaltern groups, but as it also helps to understand the contradictions and the injustices of development more broadly.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-11" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-20">25491.46</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-20">76474.39</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-20">101965.856</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Development Grants Award to Cardiff University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008644_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FT008644%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
