<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003529_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The GCRF Plastics Pollution Governance Framework Network</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Establish cooperation and knowledge exchange among diverse actors in the governance of plastics pollution,   2. Structure dialogue among members, and foster open information and knowledge sharing, 3. Forum to showcase and discuss plastics governance systems and their outcomes,  4. Targeted dissemination of appropriate plastics pollution governance information to diverse groups from global to local, 5. Identify, assess and disseminate information on new innovative circular tools and knowledge for plastics pollution governance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This network will focus on regulatory frameworks for plastics pollution globally and how they can inform its governance in six DAC countries, i.e. Ethiopia, Kenya, Malawi, Rwanda, Tanzania and Uganda. Plastics pollution involves the accumulation of plastic debris (micro, meso or macro) in the environment that adversely affects humans. While plastics pollution has risen rapidly up the scale of global environmental concerns, its gravity to ill health related to air, water and soil pollution has not been captured in relevant policies in the six and many other DAC listed countries. A comprehensive attempt to address this will require an interdisciplinary approach using basic and applied research as well as entrepreneurial innovation. In order to keep pace with environmental pollution as well as changes in policy, technology, and culture, there is a need to build partnerships with people and organizations that are deeply embedded in all facets of the issue. Learning from innovative circular approaches and new governance forms elsewhere, our network will create a fabric of contacts who will provide support, feedback, insight, resources, and information on how to best govern plastics pollution in DAC list countries and contextualize for the six eastern African countries. Harnessing the knowledge and ideas of multiple experts will highlight important research questions and help focus attention on areas considered to be issues of immediate importance for effective governance. Hence, the network will be set across various spatial and temporal scales that involve a series of individuals, institutions, disciplines, industry and the informal sector to: (a)  Share knowledge, research, education and training input on types, process, consequences and interventions in plastic pollution; (b)  Provide a forum for coordination and dialogue among academics, researchers, policy makers and practitioners from the plastic pollution governance community with a view to advance activities related to the management of plastic pollution in the DAC countries, while identifying and responding to challenges and opportunities; (c) Advise and support teaching and capacity building programs in the DAC countries on best practices in plastic pollution governance; (d)  Bring to the attention of DAC countries state-of-the-art research and academic trends on global plastic pollution management, or write white papers on any of related topics, and also offer training/ education in this field; (e)  Create a platform for members to share key problems and areas of research that are of high interest to local, national and regional organizations within DAC countries; (f)  Address governance, data management, institutional, technology adoption and sustainability issues related to the management of plastic pollution; (g)  Undertake measures in plastic pollution management that are able to contribute to the Sustainable Development Goals of the UN and other global (e.g. Aichi Targets) and regional (e.g. African Union Agenda 2063) goals as appropriate; (h)  Undertake activities that foster collaboration between universities and research groups at an international level, including to identify and address common research topics and overarching trends; and (i)  Promote and encourage close collaboration between knowledge communities and their national counterparts concerned with plastic pollution governance. As a means to capture and include the role and contributions of scholars and practitioners in global plastics pollution management, we have identified a list of &apos;champions&apos; who will provide strategic knowledge, research, training and case study experiences to assist in generating governance ideas. These champions will snowball the Network around globally and, in the DAC, listed countries through the networking activities. This will be achieved through a variety of strategies including workshops, Round Tables, mainstream and social media, and &apos;virtual&apos; networking events.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-04">18897.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-04">75741.42</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-04">57150.45</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">18897.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003529_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nairobi</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">18897.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003529_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nairobi</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">18897.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003529_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nairobi</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">18897.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003529_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nairobi</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
