<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S01313X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF Action against Stunting Hub</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The global community aims to decrease the number of stunted children under five by 40% by 2025. While targeted and specific, we know that this is presently unachievable. Part of the problem is that over the last three decades, the search for the &apos;silver bullet&apos; or the specific driver, which if addressed could solve this intractable problem, has narrowed praxis. This is not to say that gains have not been made, but rather our efforts have not been entirely impactful. While substantial disciplinary advances have occurred, often they have not been joined-up. And while systematic reviews abound, pan-disciplinary understandings, do not. Hence, child stunting is an intractable problem, waiting for a unified solution.   If we perceive child under-nutrition as a mosaic, we have knowledge of many of the individual elements. For example, biological advances demonstrate there is an identifiable &apos;epigenetic signature&apos; of stunting. Children who are stunted also have immature gut micro-biomes and we also know a large proportion of the global malnutrition burden is caused (either directly or indirectly), by infectious agents ranging from viruses and bacteria to protozoa and helminths. Food-borne toxins also impact stunting. Equally, we know a range of elements can help to prevent stunting from animal source Foods (ASF) to behavioural elements from dietary choices to feeding practices to water, sanitation and hygiene (WASH). Yet overall, it may be argued that we are missing the shape and structure of the mosaic and the synergies between the component parts. In many quarters, the literature on child under-nutrition is viewed as &apos;siloed&apos; and non-relational (Perkins et al., 2017). But equally importantly, &apos;integrated&apos; nutritional programmes have often not had the expected impacts.  Herein lies the problem and the related solution: we urgently need to understand the &apos;cascade&apos; of factors driving child stunting and the synergies and inter-relationship between drivers. And equally importantly, we need to better understand the &apos;tipping points&apos; or the critical points along this cascade where healthy linear growth diverges to slow or no growth. To do this, we propose to transform our exploration of child under-nutrition from the component parts to the &apos;whole child&apos;. Where the biological, social, environmental and behavioural context in which stunting occurs is understood in its entirety and where the strength and directionality of these drivers, inform related interventions. Based on this joined-up approach, we will explore the ability of a range of child-centred interventions to disrupt the cascade of factors that inhibit the ability of a child to grow. These actions and outcomes will then form the basis of a decision-making platform to enable users to identify the ex-ante and ex-post impacts of potential interventions. Embedded in this process, however, is a values-based approach that ensures that from the outset, our research directly connects to and betters the lives of the children, families and communities involved.   We will work across three countries: India, Indonesia and Senegal in over 50 communities. We aim to decrease child stunting by up to 10% our communities. Finally, to enhance our impact and legacy our Hub, we will engage a range of end-users in both our outputs and in the wider &apos;whole child&apos; approach. We will support new regional platforms on maternal and child nutrition proposed by UNICEF linking the work of FAO/The World Bank/WHO at the country-level. We will also engage our network of over 100 civil society organizations in our findings. Over the course of the project, we expect to positively impact the lives of up to 1 million children.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-12-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-04">449542.11</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-04">3603619.42</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-04">2719100.37</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-04">3185246.11</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-04">8313676.71</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The goal of our Hub is to &apos;disrupt&apos; present thinking and praxis related to child undernutrition. To do this, we will develop and deliver a new paradigm to address child stunting that begins with a new theoretical framework: the bio-development niche and will be operationalised utilising the Whole Child Approach (WCA). This move to a child-centered perspective changes &apos;the rules of the game&apos; by placing the child as the agent/focus of change driving a series of joined-up integrated actions, which prioritise partnerships, collaboration and co-operation. We will operationalise the WCA by developing and delivering an integrated platform for action to disrupt the current inter-generational cycle of stunting in Indonesia, Senegal and India. The aims of our Hub are as follows:  1. To create a new epistemology of stunting based upon a new theoretical framework. 2. To apply the WCA to prevent stunting among vulnerable populations and to support affected children in ameliorating the physical, cognitive, social and educational impacts. 3. To further praxis around child stunting via improved decision-support for projects and programmes and equally, enhance capacity around interdisciplinary approaches.  4. To support the World Health Assembly targets in reducing child stunting by 40% by 2025 and to accelerate actions taken by the global community to meet the SDGs around maternal and child nutrition and health in 2030.   Related to these aims, we have five core objectives:  1. To explicate the synergies, interactions and relative strengths and directionality between the drivers of stunting: biological, behavioural, environmental and social across a range of global geographies. 2. To use the above to create a new typology of stunting which identifies the scope for potential for change among populations of affected children.  3. To develop and test a range of bespoke interventions designed to interrupt the stunting cascade across three critical time periods during the first 1000 days.  4. To deliver a decision-support tool which collates existing and new knowledge in order to better identify the ex-ante and ex-post impact of interventions. 5. To embed Hub outputs within a network of end-users from multi-lateral and bi-lateral organisations to NGOs and civil society organisation.   We will work across three countries: India, Indonesia and Senegal. These countries provide a diverse study set with regard to both the interplay of drivers of stunting and both the variety and overall impact of programmatic interventions to address stunting. We anticipate that if funded, the outreach from our Hub could impact the lives of up to 1 million children across the three countries involved. By creating a platform for action, however, we anticipate that wider benefits will also accrue for both our partners and wider network of international organizations interested in engaging with our Hub."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">404587.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S01313X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">809175.79</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S01313X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">809175.788181818</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S01313X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">809175.79</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S01313X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">815730.11</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S01313X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">815730.11</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S01313X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">815730.11</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S01313X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">815730.11</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S01313X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
