<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S005927_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Navigating Futures: arts education as a route to youth empowerment and pedagogical innovation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) To run, in partnership with Pacific Resources in Education and Learning (an NGO affiliated to the Marshall Islands Ministry of Education), a series of workshops with teachers in a range of primary and secondary schools located within the Republic of the Marshall Islands (RMI). The workshops, which the Ministry of Education (MoE) has given us permission to undertake, will involve delivering training for teachers on current pedagogy and practice relating to visual literacy and arts education, to ensure they maximise the utility of a set of creative works and teacher toolkits produced from our previous GCRF project, in order to: support current government educational policy regarding raising literacy levels; introducing more culturally relevant teaching materials; and using new technologies and innovative teaching methods to increase student engagement and attainment.  2) To work with the Curriculum Division of the Ministry of Education, and Pacific Resources for Education and Learning (PREL), to implement feedback from teachers involved in the workshops outlined above in order to maximise the relevance of our teaching resource packs for local educators, and align them more closely with the RMI national curriculum. A longer-term goal is for teachers to adopt our resources (which include a graphic novel; a comic; and a volume of Marshallese children&apos;s art and poetry) and teacher toolkits, targeted to specific age groups.  3) To run, in partnership with NGO Jambo Arts, a series of animation, film-making and traditional navigational knowledge workshops with Marshallese young people. During the previous GCRF project our team ran poetry, drawing and mural-making workshops with Marshallese schoolchildren, and were told by participating schools and arts NGOs (in particular, Jambo Arts) that they would welcome further participatory arts activities focused on digital storytelling, not just to empower youth to express themselves through new media, but also to introduce technological skills that could be used to develop a range of information resources in the future. These workshops are specifically designed to involve/benefit marginalised young people who have dropped out of formal education and/or are unemployed, with an emphasis not just on employing the arts for specific ends (skills building, innovation), but on the &apos;doing&apos; of art to explore, problem-solve, create, and enhance wellbeing (Biesta 2018: 17).   4) To make the skills and activities introduced during the youth workshops sustainable by establishing a mentoring scheme in which project artists support the artistic development of two workshop participants, and leaving 10 iPads to allow young people/NGOs to continue creating and building on our models.   5) To produce new creative outputs/resources including (a) an animation of Kathy Jetnil-Kijiner&apos;s antinuclear poem &apos;History Project&apos;, which was adapted to comic format during the previous GCRF project, and will form the focus of the animation workshop (b) 500 hard copies of the first-ever published RMI graphic novel, which currently exists in digital form (60pp.) (from our previous project), but is intended for free distribution in hard copy to RMI schools (c) a selection of short films created by film-making workshop participants, and drawings/reflective prose pieces by participants of the traditional navigation knowledge workshops, for uploading to project/NGOs&apos;/other stakeholders&apos; websites.  (6) To use social media (particular facebook and twitter); websites hosted by the project, stakeholders and partners (such as PREL, Jambo Arts and Okeanos RMI); presentations at conferences attended by educators, arts practitioners and policymakers (including the Micronesian Youth Summit and the conference of the Social Development Programme at the Pacific Community [SPC]); international NGO networks (UNESCO, UNICEF, IoM) to promote the work of our project/stakeholders and forge new routes to impact for our project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project seeks to enhance engagement with, and impacts from, research and resources produced from a previous project funded under the Global Challenges Research Fund (entitled &apos;From displacement to development: arts education as a means to build cultural resilience and community-led arts production in the Marshall Islands). It responds to particular development challenges in the Republic of the Marshall Islands (RMI) concerning the education, self-expression and wellbeing of young people. The RMI has the second youngest population in the Pacific, with 40% of the population under 16 years of age, but in spite of having one of the highest levels of per capita spending on education in the region, school dropout rates, and youth unemployment and suicide rates, are high. Our project responds to current government policy on improving student participation and attainment in education through developing more culturally relevant teaching resources, improving literacy in both English and Marshallese, and making better use of Information Technology for innovative teaching (PSS annual report 2016-17). It also responds to national and regional Pacific policies on young people, by seeking to engage and empower marginalised young people, particularly those in urban settings (SPC Pacific Youth Development Framework 2014-23; RMI National Strategic Plan, 2015-17). Further, it addresses several of the UN&apos;s Sustainable Development Goals focused around education, equality, and fostering partnerships for development.    The project will involve:  (1) A series of workshops with schoolteachers in four RMI elementary, middle and high schools during April/May 2019, with a further four workshops undertaken in June/July 2019. These will involve upskilling teachers in innovative pedagogical approaches to improving children&apos;s literacy and skills in artistic expression and interpretation, using a set of culturally relevant creative works, and accompanying teaching resource packs, produced from the project team&apos;s previous GCRF project. The project team will use feedback from participating teachers, and advice from our project partner Pacific Resources for Education and Learning (PREL) and the Curriculum Division of the RMI Ministry of Education, to align the teaching resource packs more closely with the RMI National Curriculum (completing revisions by October 2019, and undertaking further trials from November 2019-January 2020).  (2) A series of workshops (also undertaken during April/May 2019) focused around creating animations, film-making, and implementing traditional navigational knowledge, to be attended by young Marshall Islanders, including those who have dropped out of the formal education system and/or are unemployed. These workshops have been requested by project partner Jambo Arts (a youth NGO) and various other RMI stakeholders, and will result in an animation of Kathy Jetnil-Kijiner&apos;s poem &apos;History Project&apos; and various short films and reflective pieces by youth participants that will be uploaded to NGO websites (by October 2019), entered for competitions (such as the RMI film competition and AHRC Research in Film Awards) and further promoted by the project team via our website (map.llc.ed.ac.uk, to be launched August 2018) and social media, during the final stages of the project (and post-award).  These activities bring potential benefits that resonate not just with RMI youth policy, but also with wider national sustainable development goals, outlined in the RMI National Strategic Plan (2017), focused around (a) creating an innovative population by improving education access and opportunities, and (b) mobilising local and traditional knowledge to address emerging challenges facing people communities and governments. Our project will empower teachers and young people to use arts education not only to develop literacy and technical skills, but also to enlist traditional cultural knowledge to address current development challenges.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marshall Islands</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1034" percentage="100" vocabulary="MICRONESIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-20">83032.42</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">83032.42</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S005927_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">-54.42</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S005927_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
