<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_P020917_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RCUK-SEA Identifying trade-offs of changing land use for aquatic environmental and socio-economic health and facilitating sustainable solutions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The economies of Southeast Asian countries (Malaysia, Indonesia, Vietnam, Thailand, the Philippines), and hence living standards of people living in this region, are intimately coupled to the ocean which is a valuable source of protein via fisheries and income via tourism. Many of these regions also contain valuable natural resources in the shape of forests and peatland which can be harvested for timber, converted to agricultural systems and which store carbon thus regulating the composition of our atmosphere and reducing the rate of global warming. Working out best how to extract resources from terrestrial systems with minimal impact on the coastal systems that they are linked to via rivers is an enormous challenge; logging and land clearance leads to soils entering rivers and coastal waters, changing their transparency, altering fisheries and ultimately losing carbon to the atmosphere. What is needed to understand the best way to manage these competing pressures on the natural environment is information about how it functions and about how the communities which use these systems will respond to likely changes. Putting together the natural scientists who think about soils, forests and rivers with those social scientists who understand what drives people to make the decisions about how they live their lives that they make is a massive challenge. However unless we do this we will only understand one half of the problem. In this project we will therefore both sample coastal waters and rivers in western Borneo to assess their functioning and health and assess the needs of the local communities via questionnaires and interviews. We will put these two halves of the project together via a series of workshops which we believe will better help Malaysia cope with environmental change and manage their natural resources in a sustainable manner. Key elements of the project involve sampling a range of disturbed and Undisturbed rivers and coastal waters, working out the key processes which lead to the loss of soil into the Marine environment, what happens to it and how it affects the ecosystem and looking at how these processes have changed over time and how people&apos;s exploitation of coastal espouses have evolved in parallel.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Throughout Southeast Asia forest is being degraded in favour of commercial crops and logging, which destabilizes soils, increasing their transfer to rivers. These inputs are detrimental to &apos;downstream&apos; fresh, brackish and marine ecosystems and cause the release of CO2. Currently the degree by which these land use changes alter the flux of both dissolved and particulate matter is unknown, furthermore no attempts have been made to establish the degree of degradation they cause to marine ecosystems, and estimates of their impact on carbon cycling are minimal. These are significant knowledge gaps as aquatic environments are central to the wellbeing and economy in SE Asian countries, such as Malaysia, where the vast majority of people live on the coast. In addition to the paucity of environmental knowledge, the socioeconomic implications of changing land use on downstream communities have yet to be assessed, yet these factors are vital for the development of effective mitigation and adaptation measures. We will address these challenges and priorities by harnessing a team of social and environmental scientists to conduct a comprehensive study of the variously degraded rivers systems, plumes and adjacent marine environments in the Sarawak region of Malaysian Borneo. The environmental data gathered will be used in concert with surveys of the local communities to conduct a Vulnerability Assessment. Local land owners, resource managers and other relevant stakeholders will be engaged to communicate our findings in a succinct and politically unbiased manner with a view to promoting a collaborative effort between stakeholders and scientists to identify sustainable solutions which safe guard the environment yet permit commercial activity to continue. This will be achieved by the following specific objectives:  1/ To evaluate the influence of land use changes on the flux, and associated key processes, of dissolved and particulate matter originating in peatlands and other terrestrial ecosystems from rivers to coastal environments;  2/ To assess the impact of increased dissolved and particulate matter loads on parameters relevant to the health of riverine, estuarine and coastal ecosystems and CO2 emissions;  3/ To assess the socioeconomic impacts and trade-offs on coastal community livelihoods of logging and the conversion of forest to commercial crops;  4/ To engage and inform local resource management, policymakers and other relevant stakeholders and in collaboration develop sustainable solutions.  In this way our project will highlight the interdependencies of environmental resources in the context of land use and the potential trade-offs for the health of aquatic environments and assist in the development of potential solutions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-11" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MY" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaysia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-17">10045.11</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-17">40261.81</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-17">20252.96</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
