<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_N003527_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agri-Tech in China Network+</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The great majority of China&apos;s farms are smallholder properties with insufficient productivity to support farmers in rural communities on their own. Agriculture on these properties is threatened by a number of forces including soil degradation, pollution of soils and chemical residues in crop plants, unsustainable water use and polluted water, and inefficient use of inputs. The UK, through programmes like Newton Network+, will invest tens of millions of pounds over the next few years helping China progress to smarter and more sustainable agricultural systems - ensuring its food security, while opening up huge opportunities for economic growth. Firstly, this Network+ will ensure the effective coordination of these initiatives, and that the different projects link together to strengthen each other. It will do this by undertaking a wide range of networking and engagement activities to link researchers and businesses in China and the UK to ensure maximum possible knowledge sharing and new project development. Secondly, the Network+ will support a pipeline of innovation through the funding of feasibility studies and around 35 proof of concept and feasibility projects to develop pathways to new solutions to the challenges outlined above. Finally, up to 3 of the proof of concept projects will be selected for development into full-scale projects that will result in solutions on the ground to help support economic growth and development in rural communities in China. Finally, the Network+ will support a wide range of dissemination events to ensure that knowledge generated from STFC projects, as well as new results from across the agritech sector, is shared across the community.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2015-09-09"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-08" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="CHINA (PEOPLE&apos;S REPUBLIC OF)"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-01">234101.38</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-01">1010526.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-01">514977.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-01">262758.09</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="To enable STFC RAL Space to achieve its objectives of applying the UK&apos;s expertise in satellite imaging, remote sensing, smart sensors and modelling to the development of new solutions for the Chinese farming community, the Agri-Tech China Newton Network+ will deliver: (i) The commissioning of 25 de novo interdisciplinary and multi-agency feasability studies, 15 proof-of-concept studies plus up to 3 full scale solutions that target development and economic growth that integrate across the food chain in the agri-tech sector in China. (ii) Full integration of Network+ with the University of East Anglia UK-China Sustainable Agriculture Innovation Network (SAIN). (iii) Active coordination of existing and new initiatives within the Newton Fund and across other UK and international agri-tech activity including the creation of effective networks of science, technology, industry and end-users between the UK and China. (iv) The creation of new networks and partnerships to alleviate poverty by facilitating innovative and integrated approaches to development in the agri-tech sector in accordance with OECD Development Assistance Committee recommendations and to promote environmental protection and low carbon emission goals. (v) Support from the UK Agritech Centre for Agricultural Informatics and Metrics of Sustainability (AIMS) and SAIN, and their academic and business partners to ensure access and integration of data, support for modelling, engagement with stakeholders and services to promote economic growth."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
