<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T011947_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Life-Saving Lullabies: Reducing adolescent maternal and neonatal deaths in Zambia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Across the world, caregivers have sung sentimental and traditional folk lullabies to their babies for over four millennia with many transcending the generations as oral tradition. (McDowell, 1977). Ethnomusicological studies of lullabies texts have uncovered that lullabies are imbued with both covert and overt orientated objectives; from an expression of love and affection as well as a pacifier for mothers&apos; to reclaim precious time for work or sleep (Ebeogu, 2017; Klymasz, 1968). Until now, the potential for extending the functional purpose of lullaby lyrics as a methodological tool for delivering essential knowledge and survival skills to support behaviour change and the development of better parenting practices has been overlooked.   &apos;Life-Saving Lullabies&apos; is a highly novel, adaptable, transferable and sustainable arts-based innovation strategy that seeks to disrupt the traditional models of healthcare practice and service delivery, while informing a new approach to improve the health and wellbeing outcomes of adolescent mothers and their newborn in resource-stressed environments. Central to this, is our human-centred design approach that will: confront inequalities associated with the accessibility of antenatal care services (ANC); improve upon the current ANC practices used to up-skill service users with maternal health information; and empower local communities to conceive new lullabies to address immediate local and national challenges. Importantly, we will achieve this by foregrounding the needs of young mothers from their experience rather than those defined by clinicians or others removed from the intimate daily and nightly social being of women.  In recognising mothers&apos; experiences as women, our primary focus will be supporting the transition of adolescents into motherhood to reduce maternal and postnatal mortalities across the care-giving continuum: pregnancy, birth, postnatal and childhood. This project fills an urgent strategic need in Zambia- increasing the number of youth-friendly services that address the family planning needs of adolescents and educates them about pregnancy, danger signs and newborn care. The goal of the project is to apply art, design and humanities research methodologies to discover, define, develop, deliver and empower adolescent parents and caregivers with responsive skills for meeting their needs as both women and mothers. We will apply our collective knowledge to co-compose a repertoire of new &apos;life-saving lullabies&apos;. This repertoire will created by and for local communities and will directly respond to the President&apos;s declaration, the strategic needs of the Ministry of Health and the viewpoint of frontline MCH teams: the impact of pregnancy and motherhood on women; awareness of malaria in pregnancy; awareness of the critical danger signs following birth (APGAR: Appearance, Pulse, Grimace, Activity, and Respiration); importance of medication compliance and good nutrition for a healthier mother and baby; and attending ANC services for a safer pregnancy and delivery.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2020-01-06"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-21" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-05" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="ZM" type="ZAMBIA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1027</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-14">129795.42</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The main objectives of the research are to:  1. Define, develop and deliver a &apos;zero-cost&apos;, art-based, service innovation strategy, that is responsive to current and unanticipated maternal health needs in Zambia. See: https://vimeo.com/345342095  2. Enhance the capacity and voice of vulnerable adolescent mothers to participate in interventions and decisions that impact on their health and well-being but also on their consciousness as young women.  3. Contribute to Zambia&apos;s attainment of United Nation Sustainable Development Goals 3, 5 and 17 (SDGs) through the application of novel arts and humanities-led strategy.  In June 2019, President Lungu of Zambia declared a public health emergency in Maternal and Child Health (MCH), calling for &apos;heightened interventions&apos; to ensure no woman or child dies. This was a call for an urgent response to increasing rates of maternal and child mortality, particularly for vulnerable younger women. The immediate and significant areas of need are to:  - address the quality of care for adolescent mothers and neonates. - address prematurity and newborn deaths, especially in the 15-19 age group. - promote responsive parenting. - provide equitable interventions (urban-rural divide); and - provide scalable and sustainable high quality interventions.  The secondary objective of the research is to respond directly to these immediate areas of need. However, we will do so through an arts, humanities and social sciences lens. Consequently, our human-centred design approach foregrounds the experiences and needs of mothers, rather than the standpoint of clinicians, and enables mothers to define the response to the emergency. Since the emergency declaration, we have undertaken scoping work with St John Zambia to develop this project (June 2019); work funded by the University of Huddersfield. St John provides volunteer MCH services across Zambia on behalf of the Ministry of Health, who support this research initiative. Our highly innovative Life-Saving Lullabies research proposal speculates a &apos;zero-cost&apos;, scalable and transferable intervention that provide critical maternal health education to reduce maternal and neonatal mortality, while support adolescent mothers in their transition into motherhood. We will meet the primary and secondary objectives of this research study in answering the following research questions:  RQ a) What is the historical and cultural significance of lullaby, and what are familial, community and societal attitudes, meanings and practices in motherhood and childhood? How have these changes since Independence?  RQ b) How are the voices of adolescent mothers recognised, heard and acted upon in the development of maternal health interventions to meet their needs?  RQ c) What is the potential for educational lullabies to become a responsive, &apos;zero-cost&apos; and transferable service innovation strategy in Zambia and beyond?  RQ d) What impact can an arts and humanities approach have on reducing gender inequalities and the empowerment of women and girls through acquisition of knowledge through life-saving lullabies?"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">32448.85</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T011947_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sheffield Hallam University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">32448.85</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T011947_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sheffield Hallam University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">32448.85</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T011947_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sheffield Hallam University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
