<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S003789_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Learning lessons from wartime education projects in South Sudan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In South Sudan&apos;s civil wars since the 1960s, millions have died or suffered in internecine violence, famines, and flight. Renewed conflict since 2013, only two years after national independence, has displaced over four million people. Most people continue to struggle against mass unemployment, military recruitment, and few educational options. Today, the formal schools, buildings, and education programmes established during a short peace in 2005-2013 are again threatened or destroyed by war, economic collapse, and displacement. South Sudanese people fear the loss of another generation. South Sudan&apos;s endemic conflicts and structural instability pose a major challenge to education policy-makers, formal sector practitioners, scholars, and national activists. The network is driven by the belief that a new approach needs to be rooted in the realities of the community&apos;s own educational work amidst chronic insecurity since the 1960s. This leads us to two key questions: 1. How have South Sudanese people pursued their own informal and self-funded educational projects over the last sixty years of civil wars?  2. How can this history of community education during war and displacement inform education delivery, curricula, and pedagogy in chronic crisis? The network focuses a hidden resource to answer these questions. Over three generations of conflict, displacement, and collapsed formal government, South Sudanese communities have organised their own educational projects and home-made textbooks in refugee camps and rebel-held territories. These often self-taught teachers and their supporters have worked with highly traumatised, displaced communities, with combatants or ex-combatants, filling gaps in educational provision and working in remote, inaccessible, highly mobile and/or violent settings. These men and women, and their communities and personal archives, hold an unexploited wealth of knowledge about managing and promoting education and intellectual cultures in war.  The main goal of the network is to built a new academic and practitioner community centred on these local experts. The network will bring together around 30 local organisations and teachers from across South Sudan and neighbouring refugee camps in Uganda with the policy and academic community, to share knowledge and ideas as peers: the network includes the South Sudan Council of Churches, the South Sudan Women&apos;s Empowerment Network, members of major schools including Issa Girls, the British Council, and academics across South Sudan and the UK. Through three transnational consultations across multi-ethnic, multi-lingual communities divided by conflict - contingent on risks and emergent opportunities - the network will draw out hidden community educational histories, projects, and strategies for teaching during conflict and displacement. This is the first project of its kind to bridge the divide between scholars, policymakers, and community activists in South Sudan. The network consultations and database of partners and translated resources will provide new sources and collaborators for curriculum and education programme development; new approaches to methods of education in mobile and extreme circumstances; new ideas for innovative and community-led provisions for marginalised, disabled, combatant, and adult learners; and contextualised, locally-rooted definitions of quality and excellence.  These uncovered histories of community educational activism, and resulting possibilities for new education agendas, will be circulated through open academic, policy, and media platforms and an accessible, translated briefing to reach the widest possible audience in South Sudan and internationally. The network will address both immediate planning and reform agendas, and longer-term routes to community reconstruction and reconciliation rooted in shared community intellectual and educational histories.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The core aim of the network is to produce new paths and partners for educational development for South Sudan and its refugee communities. It challenges formal state-centric education development theory and practice by bringing academics, donors and humanitarian workers into direct consultation with (often-excluded) informal, self-taught, community-funded teachers and educational activists who have worked within rebel-held territories and refugee camps in South Sudan&apos;s past and present civil wars.  The network is driven by the rift in education provision in South Sudan&apos;s civil war. The new national curriculum, laws, and state budgets are disconnected from the realities of institutional collapse and the challenges of wartime education within fragmented communities: around 4m people are internally and externally displaced, and c. 2m children are not in formal education. There is a collective demand across South Sudan for significant innovation reflecting the complex needs of divided and displaced communities in this protracted conflict.  The project builds on ideas developed by the PI, Co-I, and network members over 2017-2018 in a series of workshops at the University of Juba and UNICEF South Sudan (see Case for Support). The network takes momentum from these academic and policy meetings in developing new routes to a community-based, mobile and responsive sector that reflects long-term South Sudanese teaching expertise; and addresses the complex demographics and the intellectual and practical needs of a fragmented, traumatised, and angry community.  It will achieve this through bringing together hidden community educational projects and informal teachers with the formal academic, policy, and education sectors in South Sudan, establishing establish conversations and shared expertise, and discussing pedagogy and local provision in insecure contexts.  The network&apos;s resulting methodological and practical aims are: 1. To bring community educational activists and practitioners into conversation with development practitioners and academics through series of 3-day transnational consultations, in South Sudan&apos;s capital Juba; in Wau town, a site of major internal displacement; and in Arua town in Uganda, in an area host to c. 1m refugees. 2. To engage the wider community in debates around past and present struggles to access education, and educational needs in war, through forum theatre involving community actors, led by the Likikiri Collective. 3. To collect, translate and database community-based projects and educational texts from these consultations, on the project website, providing an opportunity for scholars and education practitioners to explore an untapped resource of locally-produced educational material and methods. 4. To bring community activists, teachers, humanitarian education providers and donors, South Sudanese and international academic community together at a major workshop at the University of Juba to develop an agenda for collaborative research and policy development. 5. To produce a summary statement of the network&apos;s findings and reflections, including recommendations of new approaches and methods for regional and global scholarship and policy. 6. To result in at least one grant application to take these ideas forward in a programme of collaborative research, ideally co-funded by humanitarian, donor and research communities as a model of research practice.  The core South Sudanese and international academic team will work with civil society and policy partners (including the British Council, Rift Valley Institute and AnaTaban) and with the DFID-funded Conflict Sensitivity Resource Facility in South Sudan, who will support focused briefings to donor bodies and national and international agencies engaged in education provision and planning in South Sudan (see Impact Summary). The consultations and workshop will produce a section of African Education Review, aimed at a multidisciplinary global audience.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">37427.27</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">16102.68</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">53171.89</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Research Networking Award to University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S003789_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FS003789%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
