<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T008067_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Towards Trajectories of Inclusion: Making infrastructure work for the most marginalised</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The bulk of global population growth until 2050 is projected to occur in cities in Africa and Asia. International agreements, such as UN Habitat&apos;s New Urban Agenda and the Sustainable Development Goals seek to ensure that this growth in as inclusive as possible, yet cities are notoriously unequal places. Our previous GCRF-funded research (&apos;The Unknown City&apos;) highlighted the overwhelming significance of securing housing tenure for the most marginal urban residents. The possibility of eviction hangs heavily over everyday life and wellbeing for the urban poor.  This project builds on that work. Security of tenure both shapes and is shaped by state decisions to extend infrastructure to &apos;off grid&apos; settlements. Extending infrastructure can be part of legalising trajectories towards housing security, but can also reverse such trajectories for some by producing new exclusions. This project seeks to bring greater clarity to this complexity and identify ways in which infrastructure for the most marginalised can initiate &apos;trajectories of inclusion&apos;. The project is designed as action research in which the ultimate goal is a supported intervention in marginalised urban neighbourhood with the aim of implementing findings around these trajectories of inclusion for poor urban residents. The effects of this intervention will be carefully evaluated during the project and the results will be widely communicated.  Research builds on the Unknown City project, working in the same cities with the same partners with whom successful collaborations are now well established. The project will focus on two sites from that project in each city in order to develop longer term data sets but it introduces four new neighbourhoods in each country and develops very different approaches, including the central objective of the intervention. Research will be conducted in three countries: Bangladesh, Sri Lanka and Zimbabwe and the independent but unrecognised northern region of Somalia, Somaliland. These four countries have extremely dynamic by highly contrasting urban environments. Most research will be conducted in the capital cities, respectively, Dhaka, Colombo, Harare and Hargeisa. All four cities are expanding rapidly and are the subject of major urban redevelopment programmes. The project involves core partner academic organisations in each city engaged in research and evaluation of these redevelopment programmes. In addition to two neighbourhoods involved in previous research, research will expand to two additional contrasting neighbourhoods in the capital and two further neighbourhoods in a secondary city in order to highlight if the capitals are unusual in their planning approaches.  This selection of six neighbourhoods in each of these four countries are the location for the first stage of research. A variety of techniques including focus group discussions, a large survey and in-depth interviews will be employed to map access to five key infrastructure grids - water, sanitation, energy, transport and communications. This will form a detailed picture of patterns of differential access to these services and the wide variation between &apos;off-grid&apos; and &apos;on-grid&apos;. The second stage of research will move beyond these neighbourhoods to follow the grids. In each country, two of these infrastructures will be identified and an approach known as &apos;Systems of Provision&apos; will map the grid, identifying key individuals responsible for delivery of each service. This will explain the differential patterns of access identified in the first stage of research. These two research stages will lead to and inform the final stage of the supported intervention to enhance accesswhich will be carried out in conjunction with grassroots organisations in each city. The project will engage with local government, NGOs and infrastructure companies throughout with the aim of demonstrating thepotential of these interventions and communicate the need to focus on trajectories of inclusion.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project has three closely interlinked objectives. The most significant will come towards the end of the project, to develop positive interventions to address inequality of provision of basic infrastructure (water, sanitation, energy, transport and communications). This will result in a supported intervention in at least two neighbourhoods in each of the four main cities in the project. In conjunction with community associations, we will use the research to identify and develop a programme of supported intervention to work with residents, private sector organisations and government officials to help ensure that the infrastructural improvements associated with the transition to on-grid provision does not create a burden or exacerbate exclusions. There are obviously clear limits to what can be achieved in practical terms even as a result of a relatively large research project such as this one so the main objective is to demonstrate what may be possible. Stakeholder meetings and broader communication and engagement will help ensure that this demonstration is clearly communicated and widely known about. The two other objectives precede and are intended to inform this primary objective. The project is designed as an action research to lead up to the supported intervention. The second objective is to Establish differential patterns of access to basic services. This requires research in particular neighbourhoods of low income or off-grid housing. Six neighbourhoods will be selected in each city to represent the variety of situations of urban marginalisation. Four of these will be in the capital city and two in a secondary city to establish further comparison. Research will involve representative surveys to Identify patterns of inclusion and exclusion in the provision of basic services (water, sanitation, energy, transport, communication) from the perspective of residents and qualitative interviews will examine the impact of infrastructure development on housing security. This will lead to the selection of two infrastructure grids in each city.  The third objective will move beyond the selected neighbourhoods to follow the services to identify trajectories of inclusion. Following the detailed research in the selected neighbourhoods, research teams in each country will select the two most relevant infrastructure grids in each specific context. These two grids will be examined in detail to explain the basis for the patterns of inclusion and exclusion analysed previously. This research will draw on the Systems of Provision approach to identify key agents in the relevant infrastructure grid. These agents will be interviewed and those who are willing will be involved in the PhotoVoice project to exchange perspectives with residents of the selected neighbourhoods. The comic book method will be applied to visualise possible interventions and form a means of discussing these interventions with all relevant stakeholders. All research data will be combined to identify &apos;trajectories of inclusion&apos; which support the expansion of services while maintaining situations of equality. This leads back to the primary objective of establishing the practical intervention. These three objectives arise from a collectively produced theory of change with the overall goal of ensuring the urban change benefits the poorest urban residents in Asia and Africa. The supported intervention will be used as a demonstration to highlight what can be achieved in terms of enhancing equality of access in infrastructure provision. This informs the impact strategy which will involve evaluation of the intervention and engage all stakeholders in the process from the very beginning of the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sussex</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">301163.24</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">151801.35</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">306061.57</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">36433105.72</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to University of Sussex</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T008067_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sussex</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FT008067%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
