<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_N01622X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral BBSRC-Embrapa: Uncovering the genetic and functional basis of the unique leaf rust resistance in the Brazilian wheat variety Toropi</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The global demand for wheat is increasing, but so is the distribution and aggressiveness of the pathogens that seriously impact on wheat productivity. The Food Agricultural Organisation (FAO) estimates that wheat production must increase by 60% by 2050 to meet the demand from the growing human population. The fungal pathogens responsible for rust of wheat are a major constraint to achieving this increase in production and in recent years we have seen numerous epidemics due to the breakdown of rust race-specific resistance (R-) genes.    There are three rust pathogens of wheat, stripe (yellow-Puccinia striiformis), leaf (brown-P. triticina) and stem (black-P. graminis) rust. In the UK stripe rust is the most prevalent, occurring every year. Leaf rust has been confined to warmer regions, being prominent in the south-west of England. However, in recent years the UK Cereal Pathogen Virulence Survey has detected leaf rust on wheat as far north as the border with Scotland. This is considered to be as a result of milder winters increasing the ability of the pathogen to overwinter, and warmer springs allowing leaf rust to take hold in regions of the UK where previously it has not been considered a problem.  In Brazil leaf rust is the major problem. Many sources of leaf rust resistance used in wheat varieties have proven to be race-specific, with virulence rapidly arising in the P. triticina population, overcoming the resistance after only a few years of deployment in new wheat varieties. However, a small number of slow-rusting, adult plant resistance (APR) genes effective against leaf rust have been reported. These include Lr34, Lr46, Lr67  and Lr68. These leaf rust APR genes have proven effective over long periods of time, large acreages and under high disease pressure. Some of these durable, leaf rust APR genes have now been cloned, confirming, as suspected, that they do not function in the same way at race-specific, leaf rust R-genes.   The old Brazilian cv. Toropi contains a unique, durable source of leaf rust APR. Preliminary studies have identified two genes in Toropi which account for 71% of the resistance. However these two genes are poorly defined and we know very little about their mode of action, e.g. at what plant growth stages the leaf rust APR becomes effective and whether environmental factors such as temperature can effect the action of these resistance genes  In this study we will improve the genetic resolution of each gene by generating a high-density genetic map of Toropi using state-of-the-art DNA marker systems, and wheat genomic resources. We will develop wheat genetic materials that will enable us to unravel the mode of action of each gene, and marker tools that will enable each leaf rust APR gene to be identified and followed during the process of breeding new improved wheat varieties. We also aim to incorporate these Toropi resistance genes into elite Brazilian wheat varieties, using the marker tools we develop, thereby providing the Brazilian wheat breeder with materials they can enter directly into their wheat breeding programs.  To help understand the mode of action and biology underlying these leaf rust APR genes we will study the development of the leaf rust fungal pathogen in wheat at the microscopic level, infecting wheat plants at different stages of it growth and when grown at different temperatures.  This project also focusses on the training of young Brazilian researchers, and on broadening the international collaborative research network of the Brazilian team.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-25">137892.81</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-25">184974.01</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-25">171618.68</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The old Brazilian cv. Toropi expresses a unique, durable source of adult plant leaf rust (Puccinia triticina-Pt) resistance that has remained effective for more than 50 years. The resistant phenotype exhibits all the characteristics of slow-rusting resistance, as seen with the known, durable resistance genes Lr34, Lr46, Lr67 and Lr68. We have used the Pump-priming award (BB/N004477/1) to screen Toropi, IAC 13 and a Toropi x IAC 13 F7 RIL population with markers for these slow-rusting leaf rust genes. We can confirm that Lr34 is not present in either Toropi or IAC 13, and that the markers defining Lr46, Lr67 and Lr68 do not provide the expected allelic haplotype.    Two recessive QTL, trp-1 (1AS) and trp-2 (4DS) were identified by single marker regression analysis in the Toropi x IAC 13 population that together accounted for 71.5% of the leaf rust resistance in Toropi. However, trp-1 and trp-2 are genetically poorly defined, lying within regions spanning more than 50cM, and were mapped using AFLP, a difficult to reproduce marker system.  A high-density genetic map of the Toropi x IAC 13 RIL population using DArTseq SNP and SSR markers is currently being generated by the Brazilian PhD student Gerarda Pinto da Silva at NIAB (BB/N004477/1). The phenotypic contribution of each QTL to the leaf rust APR in Toropi, their genetic interaction and interaction with other leaf rust resistance genes, as well as their mode of action (biology) remains unknown.   The objectives of this proposal are therefore: Objective 1: To identify and develop diagnostic markers linked to trp-1 and trp-2 for use in Marker-Assisted Selection as part of a wheat breeding program. This will provide wheat breeders with the tools to stack the Toropi genes alongside other rust resistance genes, including the slow rusting Lr34, for which reliable markers are already available. The approaches used will set the foundations to clone the genetic loci underlying trp-1 and trp-2, if not lead directly to the identification of these genes.  Objective 2: To determine the mode of action of the Toropi Lr APR genes trp-1 and trp-2.  Defined genetic lines, carrying trp-1 and trp-2 individually, and in combination are currently being developed by the Brazilian team in the wheat varieties Morocco and IAC 13 (leaf rust susceptible). Five Brazilian elite bread wheat varieties will be selected into which the Toropi leaf rust APR genes will be backcrossed. In so doing wheat genetic resources will be developed that will enable detailed biological and molecular examination of the potential role of these slow-rusting resistance genes against leaf rust, and other rust diseases, as well as materials that Brazilian wheat breeders will be able to incorporate directly into their breeding programs. These materials will enable the assessment of trp-1 and trp-2 in different wheat genetic backgrounds to determine the components of Pt infection compromised by each gene; infection efficiency, latent period, colony development, percentage sporulation and levels of urediniospore production. The wheat plant growth stage at which trp-1 and trp-2 become effective will be examined in Pt inoculations at defined wheat growth stages. The temperature dependence of trp-1 and trp-2 resistance will be examined in temperature-controlled growth cabinet expts. Microscopic studies of Pt development on flag leaves will examine the chemical changes occurring in the leaf, including lignin and callose formation, and whether a micro hypersensitive cell death is associated with either gene.   Objective (3) To enhance human capacity, expertise and skill base. To date two PhD students, Alice Casassola and Gerarda da Pinto Silva have spent extended periods at NIAB working in the research group of Boyd. Within the existing Brazilian CNPq Partnership award there are funds for a 3rd PhD student and a post-doc to spend 6 months at NIAB."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
