<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R024324_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Historical and epidemiological transitions in urban Caribbean foodscapes: understanding the past to enhance future healthy eating</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aim: To develop a conceptual framework and methodology for a historically informed epidemiology and an epidemiologically informed history of the relationship between urban transformation and foodscapes in LMICs that can inform the work of urban planners and public health officials to restrict unhealthy food environments and increase healthy options.  Objectives  Work package 1: Partnership development workshops: To create a model of interdisciplinary collaboration between public health researchers and historians with a view to building a historically grounded public health programme.  a. To bring together co-investigators from within the UK and the Caribbean and other interested academics as well as government, private sector and civil society partners (e.g. policymakers and practitioners of urban planning, public health, transport; local business people; community groups as appropriate) in a Project Co-Development Workshop to develop a joint research agenda that aims to address and integrate methodological and epistemological aims across humanities and public health research, and arrive at meaningful outputs for stakeholders. b. After conducting feasibility research in three further work packages, to reconvene co-investigators and stakeholders in a Project Co-Analysis Workshop with a view to establish a joint research programme which builds on the strengths and lessons learnt from this project.  Work package 2: Historical transitions: To examine the historical socio-political development of Kingston and Port-au-Prince and its impact on healthy eating since the Second World War through to the present:  a. Research conducted principally in online newspaper archives to investigate the extent to which urbanisation, population growth, and movement inside and outside the city spaces impacted on social inequalities. b. Interviews to explore changing food cultures and foodscapes. c. And to draw on this research and data to identify the complexities of food culture and dietary practices manifest in contrasting social attitudes to food production, consumption, availability of food outlets, and dining habits.  Work package 3: Health transitions: To identify current and historic epidemiological and health trends of Kingston and Port-au-Prince for nutrition and non-communicable diseases (NCDs), and health inequalities since the Second World War: a. Existing local surveys to identify social determinants of major health burdens, in particular related to NCDs and malnutrition. b. Existing focus group data to gain insight into the processes by which women&apos;s experiences of heath inequalities and heath beliefs - in particular in relation to food and eating - have been determined.  Work package 4: Joining the threads by mapping urban foodscapes: To fuse the historical and epidemiological research findings by mapping the data onto archival and recent city maps using geographic information systems (GIS) in Kingston (and scoping for Port-au-Prince). a. To produce a digital map hosted on the project website and available as hard copy that goes beyond identification of urban areas to include changing spaces of popular outlets for food consumption and distribution. b. With the map to elucidate the interrelation between public health history and food culture and by so doing provide invaluable data for policymakers desirous of improving the healthy lifestyles of the citizenry, and co-design public engagement tools.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Current public health strategies fail to effectively promote adequate nutrition in populations, because they focus on individuals&apos; behaviours and choices without addressing larger influences such as food cultures and food systems. Instead, healthy environments need to be created that enable easy access to healthy and nutritious food. Cities in an increasingly urbanising world are ideal places for such transformation.   The Caribbean region has identified chronic non-communicable diseases such as diabetes and heart disease as a major threat to population health, social and economic development, and has made a concerted commitment to address this problem through a comprehensive, multi-sectoral response that includes urban planning. To inform their efforts and accelerate action, we propose a cross-disciplinary project to understand historical and epidemiological transformations in two neighbouring but contrasting cities, Kingston (Jamaica) and Port-au-Prince (Haiti), to be able to identify the ways cities in low and middle income countries impact on their populations&apos; food practices, opportunities and in turn health. We aim to develop an in-depth understanding of underlying mechanisms that have led to both &apos;unhealthy&apos; spaces (e.g. fast food dense neighbourhoods) or &apos;healthy&apos; spaces (e.g. urban gardens). By investigating how these social, political and economic determinants of nutrition have developed and shaped into contemporary foodscapes, the goal of our project is to inform the prevention of chronic diseases by enhancing healthy eating strategies. The project will map health data onto the historical data to produce an interactive map of the evolution of foodscapes, which will be used to engage with both policymakers and the public as a tool to aid the creation of healthy environments that enable easy access to healthy and nutritious food.  Under the guidance of leading historians and global health researchers, early career researchers at the University of the West Indies will conduct feasibility research merging methods from historical and health research. A historical work package will use online newspaper archives, and innovatively combine with interviews with local experts to examine changes in urban population growth and urban inequality and its impact on food production and consumption, the availability of food outlets, and dining habits from the Second World War to present. A health work package will examine major epidemiological trends in nutrition for the same time frame and assess its impact on NCDs through an analysis of existing public health survey and routine data, and combine this analysis with focus group data on contemporary food practices and choices. This feasibility fieldwork will be carried out in Kingston, Jamaica, and Port-au-Prince, Haiti, in preparation for the development of a larger follow-up grant proposal expanding to the wider region and similar settings. This feasibility work will be prepared during a Project Co-Development Workshop in Jamaica to which we will invite regional stakeholders from academia, government and civil society (e.g. health NGOs) to agree on common research goals that tie into current practice and policy projects (e.g. regeneration plans for parts of Kingston); and it will be consolidated in a final Project Co-Analysis Workshop to analyse the data and develop a sustainable collaborative research strategy and future projects.  Melding humanities and epidemiological methods and expertise, we propose a highly innovative project with a research question novel for both fields, and based around a unique collaboration. It will build the methodological capacity needed to understand the mechanisms that have produced &apos;unhealthy&apos; and reduced &apos;healthy&apos; foodscapes in urban areas in low and middle income countries, which is essential for urban planners working to create healthy urban food environments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-31">185735.14</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF RCUK Award to University of Exeter</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/R024324/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Exeter</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-04-01">185735.14</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R024324_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Exeter</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FR024324%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
