<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T005459_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF Development award: Contextualising Peace Education</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project addresses the programme call by uncovering community-centred approaches to peace to explore their potential for informing contextualised gender-sensitive peace education materials. In doing so, the project will showcase and advance the benefits of Arts and Humanities methodologies in peace and conflict-management studies. It will support peace educators to develop context sensitive pedagogic content for higher education through innovations in curriculum design and delivery. It thus aims to enhance the role of education in building future peace by improving access to quality peace education for young people. By connecting and comparing findings across the different partners and countries we will develop educational resources that can be used in other countries by a diverse range of organisations from international agencies, governments, civil society, communities and academia to support and complement peace education curricula. In order to achieve our overarching aim we have a series of linked objectives:  Networking 1. To collaboratively develop a network grant by testing contextual and networking methodologies in the community, among user groups in partner countries, and evaluating these through exit interviews;   2. To build interdisciplinary research capacity across two ODA recipient countries by producing high-quality research outputs, engagement events and teaching materials. Two proof of concept projects will scope the methodologies in societies facing conflict. Networking will help broaden the international reach of the materials and will enhance collective learning from the project;  3. To build on existing knowledge in partner countries in order to maximise the impact and effectiveness of GCRF funding; 4. To foster knowledge exchange and develop partnership, both in ODA recipient countries and the UK, between local NGOs and INGOs, academics, local communities and higher education institutions.  Research design and data collection 5. Establish a small network of researchers in Nigeria, UK and Zimbabwe to refine a conceptual and methodological framework that explores the meanings and mechanisms of peace in a number of localised contexts; 6. Undertake scoping projects in each of the partner countries using storytelling as method to learn from community peace practices. Develop educational materials that can be used in peace education;  7. Capacity and partnership building through co-design and co-development of learning materials for use in global south and north;  8. Connect and compare these projects, methodologies and outcomes, and different types of conflict across partner countries to develop best practice and draw lessons to improve understanding intersectionality of conflict across different contexts; 9. Employ this framework for developing the larger bid.  Theoretical development Through journal articles advance debates at the intersection of four concerns: gender, peace and conflict, education and storytelling in order to contribute to: 10. Decolonising peace education, gender and peacebuilding through empirical examples of locally appropriate concepts and methodologies; 11. Conceptually advance educational pedagogies in face-to-face and technologically enabled systems in conflict-affected communities; 12. Co-produce 3 articles in order to identify an accessible comparative analysis of the nature, activities and impacts of different groups in Africa.  Impact  Through processes of co-design and co-production we will: 13. Develop the capacity of African and UK policy-makers and students in peace education through dissemination of the teaching material produced; 14. Enhance the capacities of researchers in Zimbabwe and Nigeria through targeted research career development and also in the UK through support in pedagogic methods; 15. Enlarge the global stock of knowledge by submitting data in the 2 African countries and to ReShare in the UK for use by other researchers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project uses storytelling as method to further a contextually sensitive understandings of everyday gendered peace in  two countries facing conflict: Nigeria and Zimbabwe. The project has two foci: networking and contextualising peace.   Networking: First, we focus on fostering partnerships and knowledge exchange between civil society organisation (NGOs, INGOs, research centres, arts organisations), local communities, government bodies and schools, including higher education; between local, national and international peace workers and educators and across countries to identify best practice in peace education. We will begin with networking meetings and early engagement workshops to  deepen our engagement with stakeholders in each country and  critically review the current local peace and intervention practices in Nigeria and Zimbabwe. Secondly, we will carry out three storytelling workshops in each country to explore how community based practices of peace are understood, created and inherited. The stories will be used to produce educational resources for peace education that we will trial in Global South and North. These 2 &apos;proof of concept&apos; projects will, later on, be connected across the network and compared through an international networking meeting in Nigeria and a local meeting in Zimbabwe  to broaden knowledge about local peace building and to strengthen teaching materials. We will evaluate the networking methodology through interviews with stakeholders and with the community.  Contextualising peace: The project particularly highlights the importance of understanding locally embedded peace practices. This contextualisation is essential  to creating resources for learning materials that can disrupt hegemonic narratives of peace and to reverse the knowledge transfer from north to south.  Peace can sometimes be seen as a Eurocentric project with the underlying knowledge and methods for peace arising from the West. There are, nevertheless, local meanings and mechanisms for peace but they are overlooked in peace education although demands to address this lacuna are growing. This is part of a wider trend to use African concepts and knowledge in teaching there, and thus to decolonise education. However, there has been no attempt to systematically collate, compare, evaluate and draw out lessons from these existing peace practices or to see how these can be incorporated into peace education. Likewise, there have also been limited initiatives to investigate gendered constructions of peace from a decolonial perspective. This project addresses these two gaps. The overall aim of the proposed research is to understand: a. what are the different meanings and mechanisms attached to peace, with particular attention to gender differences in creating everyday peace in our 2 case study countries - Nigeria and Zimbabwe; b.  how can these practices be connected and compared across countries to create peace education content and mode of delivery in Higher Education in order to decolonise peace education? In responding to these questions, we will use the arts-based methods of storytelling to unearth the locally embedded stories and meaning of peace. Building on our previous funded projects, this network will offer an intersectional analysis of gender, religion and ethnicity to explore meanings of peace and how to embed this into peace in Higher Education through co- designing and co-producing two lesson plans and trialing it across the three countries: Nigeria, UK and Zimbabwe. We will later on collate the feedback from the students to assess the effectiveness of learning materials and make necessary improvements based on the experiences of student.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-000391" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Open University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-02">145334.68</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-02">151646.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Large Grants Award to Open University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH/T005459/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-CHC-000391">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Open University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">53830.71</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T005459_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-CHC-000391">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Open University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">91503.97</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T005459_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-CHC-000391">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Open University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FT005459%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-08-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
