<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P005950_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDERSTANDING AND SUPPORTING CREATIVE ECONOMIES IN AFRICA: EDUCATION, NETWORKS AND POLICY (HN)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In recent years there has been a growing interest in the role that cultural and creative industries play in developing economies - both in terms of their economic contribution but also in connection with social change and cultural engagement (UNESCO, 2013). To contribute to this field and to support related policy agendas, the research network will connect and mobilise different communities, including academics, practitioners in the creative/cultural sector and cultural and creative policy bodies. The aim will be to develop a better understanding of the creative economies in emerging African countries and to explore strategies to encourage and enable sustainable context-specific cultural, social and economic development. The network will provide a platform for a range of international and interdisciplinary academics working in this area of research, practitioners across a range of creative fields, as well as policy and networks bodies to reflect on their work and practice in relation to creative economies in Africa. The research network will establish three creative hubs (Kenya, Nigeria and South Africa). In year one a series of local workshops will be organised and in year two each hub will host an academic seminar focusing on 3 interrelated topics:  -&apos;Creative Education and Careers&apos; (hosted by the Nigeria Creative Hub in Lagos) -&apos;Mapping Creative Economies: frameworks, data sources and policies&apos; (hosted by the South African Creative Hub in Port Elizabeth) -&apos;Sustainable Cultural Production Networks&apos;(hosted by the Kenya Creative Hub in Nairobi) These events will generate benefits for African and international academics, African universities, creative practitioners in a range of local African contexts and African and non-African policy makers.   Overall, the research network has four main objectives: 1. Compile a literature review of existing research which aims to understand the specific context of emerging creative economies in Africa, with a focus on the role of creative education, cultural production networks and policy; 2. Develop an open access knowledge platform which acts as a point of reference for the work of academics and practitioners in this area, with case studies, links, interviews, working papers and policy briefings; 3. Through systematic analysis, develop a clearer articulation of the relationship between localised knowledge and practice in the creative economies of three African countries (Kenya, Nigeria and South Africa) and opportunities for the development of sustainable ecologies of cultural production and consumption; 4. Explore the potential role that universities might play in the African context for bringing together researchers, creative practitioners, policy makers and civil society to work towards sustainable and local cultural development.   Data, knowledge and findings from the seminars and other activities from the research network will be disseminated through a dedicated website. This will provide an open knowledge platform, publishing reports on the various seminars taking place, collecting case studies / interviews / discussions. Alongside this open platform, further means of dissemination are also planned, such as an edited book which collects case studies, reflections and experiences, a journal article which reflects theoretically with the outcomes of the network, and the organization of sessions and delivery of presentations at international conferences in the fields of geography and creative studies.    The activities of the research network will give participating academics, creative practitioners, and policy makers a shared platform to engage and reflect on the emerging role that creative economies can play in shaping the future of Africa and establish new international connections. It will offer the opportunity to critically consider challenges but also sustainable pathways to support future cultural provision across the continent.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-11-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-20">42377.58</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="In line with the Highlight Notice and the UN 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development, which aims to build collaborations across a range of countries which receive Official Development Assistance (ODA), the research network will connect and mobilise different communities, including academics, practitioners in the creative/cultural sector and cultural and creative policy bodies. It aims to develop a better understanding of the creative economies in emerging African countries and to explore strategies to encourage and enable sustainable context-specific cultural, social and economic development. The network will provide a platform for academics, creative practitioners, and policy and network bodies to reflect on their work and practice in relation to creative economies in Africa. It will facilitate knowledge exchanges between the Global North and the Global South, highlighting the importance of context specific knowledge and encouraging connections between local cultural production networks.  The research network has four main objectives: 1. Compile a literature review of existing research which aims to understand the specific context of emerging creative economies in Africa, with a focus on the role of creative education, cultural production networks and policy; 2. Develop an open access knowledge platform which acts as a point of reference for the work of academics and practitioners in this area, with case studies, links, interviews, working papers and policy briefings; 3. Through systematic analysis, develop a clearer articulation of the relationship between localised knowledge and practice in the creative economies of three African countries (Kenya, Nigeria and South Africa) and opportunities for the development of sustainable ecologies of cultural production and consumption; 4. Explore the potential role that universities might play in the African context for bringing together researchers, creative practitioners, policy makers and civil society to work towards sustainable and local cultural development.  Two sets of networks will be created to address these objectives. The first set will encourage flows between the North and South and will benefit UK-based academics and policy makers interested in knowing more about the specificities of African creative economies as well as African-based academics interested in discussing current UK expertise in relation to mapping and investigating creative and cultural production ecologies. The second set will encourage South to South exchanges, knowledge flows and collaborations. It will be academically informed but more practice-based to allow academics and practitioners in Kenya, Nigeria and South Africa to situate and understand their own practice and when possible to learn from each other&apos;s experiences. These networks will be centered on three &apos;Creative Hubs&apos; anchored around three local universities. In the first year, small scale workshop activities will be organised to gain a better understanding of the key questions highlighted for each hub. In year two, three academic seminars, one in each hub, will be scheduled to consider the knowledge and questions developed to that point in relation to theories and practice. The Nigeria Creative Hub will focus on &apos;Creative Education and Careers&apos; to explore the role that education plays in shaping the practices and careers of emerging and established cultural producers. The Kenya Creative Hub will explore &apos;Sustainable Cultural Production Networks&apos; to consider the role that local networks play in helping cultural producers to find, connect and ultimately build sustainable relationships with local and international audiences. The South African Creative Hub will explore &apos;Mapping Creative Economies:  frameworks, data sources and policies&apos; to examine the role cultural mapping plays in developing countries."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">42377.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P005950_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000297">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
