<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P02274X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Metal contamination of rice supplies in Asia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">There has recently been much public debate about contamination of rice supplies across Asia with heavy metals. Two elements in particular are discussed: arsenic (As) (which is strictly a metalloid not a metal) and cadmium (Cd). Rice is thought to be one of the main sources of As in the human diet, and chronic As exposure is linked to cancers of the skin, lung, bladder and prostate as well as heart disease. Contamination of rice fields with As has been found in many parts of Asia, especially in the heavily-populated deltas of the Ganges and other rivers draining from the Himalayas whose rocks contain it. The solubility of As in soils - and hence the ease with which it is absorbed by plant roots - increases when a soil is flooded for paddy rice production because of changes in soil chemistry linked to redox conditions. Hence the particular link between rice and As.   Cadmium is also a primary carcinogen and a chronic nephrotoxin. Sources of Cd in rice soils include parent rock materials and base-metal mining and industrial discharges up-stream of rice field water supplies. In contrast to As, the solubility of Cd tends to decrease when a soil is flooded for rice production, again linked to changes in redox chemistry. But conversely, if the soil is drained during the growing season, as for example in water-saving irrigation systems that are becoming widespread in various parts of Asia, Cd solubility and hence plant uptake tend to increase. So there is concern that water-saving irrigation technologies may exacerbate Cd contamination risks. There is also concern that new varieties of rice with enhanced uptake of micro-nutrients such as zinc, for the sake of human nutrition, may also take up more Cd.   However, the extent of these metal contamination risks across Asia is not well understood. Because of the complex mix of processes and variables controlling metal uptake, making predictions across diverse rice environments is difficult. In the absence of reliable assessments of the extents the problem, it is difficult to prioritise research to develop technologies to lessen contamination risks, though there are promising possibilities for doing this through rice breeding and agronomic management. There is therefore a pressing need for better estimates of contamination risks in the different rice environments across Asia.  In this project we propose to develop methods with which to do this based on spatial data analysis and modelling. We will develop models for predicting contamination levels in rice grain based on spatially-resolved data on environmental, management and genetic variables. We will use the latest spatial data analysis and modelling techniques for this. To develop our models, we will make pilot studies in Bangladesh and the Philippines, in which we will conduct surveys of contamination and its drivers over relevant geographic areas. Our reasons for choosing Bangladesh and the Philippines are related to the availabilities of relevant spatial data resources in these countries, and favourable political conditions for studies on rice contamination in these countries. We will seek to widely disseminate the project findings and the generic methods we will develop through the project team&apos;s wide network of partnerships within target countries and across scientific disciplines.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-05-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="PHILIPPINES"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-16">280290.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-16">211920.42</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Our overall aim is to develop generic methods for assessing the extent that Asian rice supplies are contaminated with toxic metals. We will do this using spatial data collection, analysis and modelling to obtain relationships between contamination levels in rice grain and environmental and management drivers. We will make pilot studies in Bangladesh and the Philippines in which we will conduct surveys of contamination over wide geographic areas and analyse them using spatial analysis methods. We have chosen Bangladesh and the Philippines as case studies for reasons of political convenience and data availability as discussed in the Case. Our specific objectives towards these ends are:  1. To gather data on biophysical conditions (soils, geology, water), rice growing conditions (ecosystems, crops per year) and pollution risks (geogenic and anthropogenic) across the main rice growing areas in Bangladesh and the Philippines, and as necessary to digitise detailed spatial data.   2. To conduct surveys of rice farms in potentially contaminated parts of Bangladesh and the Philippines to obtain (a) rice grain, which we will analyse for metal contents and DNA fingerprints for genotype information; (b) soil samples, which we will analyse for general properties and metal contents; and (c) information on rice production conditions and practices, and socio-economic factors.  3. To use digital soil mapping and spatial modelling techniques to interpolate conditions at the geo-referenced survey sites, and to combine the analytical results with the mapped information to derive associations and empirical relationships between contamination levels in rice grain and environmental and management drivers.  4. To develop generic methods for use across rice-producing countries, leading to methods for assessing the extent that Asian rice supplies are contaminated with toxic metals.   Each of these objectives is integral to the project."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">70072.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P02274X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cranfield University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">70072.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P02274X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cranfield University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">70072.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P02274X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cranfield University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">70072.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P02274X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cranfield University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">70640.14</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P02274X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cranfield University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">70640.14</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P02274X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cranfield University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">70640.14</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P02274X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cranfield University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">70639.77</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P02274X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cranfield University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
