<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_M026345_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton001 Pregnancy in Lupus: gestational, immunological and vascular risk factors and outcomes</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our goal is to combine clinical and research expertise to inform new approaches to improving patient and pregnancy outcomes in systemic lupus erythematous and associated autoimmune syndromes. Our collaboration will:  &gt;Compare results of pregnancy outcomes in SLE between UK and Brazilian Centres;   &gt;Evaluate adverse pregnancy outcomes from a maternal and neonatal perspective both between centres and compared to healthy control pregnancies in both countries; &gt; Study best practice in care;   &gt;Study how the following factors influence pregnancy outcomes in SLE; -Maternal blood vessel function: -Immunophenotypes that influence fetal/placental rejection (Treg and Th17 cells); -Factors that promote and inhibit blood vessel development (angiogenic and anti-angiogenic mediators);  &gt;Analyse placental pathology/immunohistochemistry to define mechanistic pathways of compromise. Ultimately, these collaborative studies will provide excellent opportunities to study a wide range of disease expression and severity and will help us to agree best practice in care which will be of international relevance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Two of the most serious health problems facing Brazil today are childhood and motherhood mortality, which outstrip the UK by 6- and 10 -fold, respectively. The reasons for this divide are multifactorial, but shared knowledge between the UK and Brazil could feasibly impact upon these figures.  Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (SLE), often termed Lupus, is an autoimmune disorder that frequently affects women in their child-bearing years. When superimposed on pregnancy, Lupus and Lupus-like disorders (LLD) significantly increase the incidence of all major obstetric complications, including miscarriage, stillbirth, high blood pressure, premature birth and fetal growth restriction. These women are therefore a major obstetric concern, regardless of their country of origin or clinical setting.  Clinically, the optimal care, treatment and monitoring of this group are still evolving. This application seeks to harmonise and expand the research/expertise in the study and management of these pregnancies, through the active exchange of ideas, research and best practice between the UK and Brazil.  This project brings together two renowned facilities for the study of these complex pregnancies, one in Rio de Janeiro the other Manchester, both with a wealth of obstetric and rheumatology experience. In coordinating our research efforts, our joint aims are to better define the key vascular, endocrine and immunological factors which drive poor pregnancy outcome in these affected women. By standardising clinical and research protocols across centres, sharing data and study samples, current research projects will be enhanced and joint initiatives developed. Moreover, by maximising clinical practice across centres, the stratification of SLE/LLD patients according to their pregnancy risk will be improved, with potential immediate benefits in patient care and clinical guidelines.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-05">9046.03</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-05">18092.06</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-05">36184.12</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Strategic Awards Award to The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/M026345/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FM026345%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-01-16"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
