<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T004185_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOIL-SAFE: Employing archaeological insights in the co-design of agricultural soil erosion mitigation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since the proposed partnership has the overarching objective of directly contributing to the design of future soil and water conservation practices in LMICs, the partnership&apos;s objectives correspond to Phases 1-4 of the pathway to impact.  These are listed here chronologically rather than in order of priority since each objective is a prerequisite of the objective that follows. 1) Re-establish contact with NGOs in the UK, Europe and eastern Africa to highlight the benefits and costs of sediment traps as an underutilised and understudied form or soil erosion mitigation, emphasising the crucial role of soil health in food security and within the ambitious aims of the UN&apos;s SDGs, particularly SDG 2 and SDG 15.  Recruit suitable third sector partners to contribute to subsequent partnership activities. 2) Through dialogue, data sharing, knowledge exchange and joint participation in data collection during fieldwork, co-design a method of assessing the costs and benefits of sediment traps (and by extension other forms of soil and water conservation) that can be applied by NGOs and researchers (either jointly or separately), and which is sufficiently flexible to be applicable in a range of social and ecological environments within LMICs and worldwide. 3) Disseminate the co-designed methodology through all appropriate means in order to reach a range of target audiences, including discipline-specific, sector specific, and policy-oriented peer-reviewed journals, as well as via practice briefs and online databases (e.g. www.wocat.net), with priority placed on the production of a clear and widely applicable work-flow.  4) Work with academic and third sector collaborators developed during the partnership to produce a bid for follow-on funding to establish a pilot project, thereby testing and further refining the published method of sediment trap cost-benefit analysis.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Soil health is fundamental to agricultural production and by extension to ensuring food security and achieving the UN Sustainable Development Goals, particularly SDG 2 (Zero Hunger) and SDG 15 (Life on Land).  Where soil is at risk of erosion, measures are often put in place to prevent it, most commonly by the construction of agricultural terracing designed to stop erosion before it occurs and thus preserve soils in situ. However, archaeological research from Tanzania and Ethiopia demonstrates that food security was achieved in the past by initially allowing soil erosion to occur - and perhaps even encouraging it - since this permitted the capture of eroded soils in river-side sediment traps.  This has several important benefits, because sediments transported and deposited by water are fine in texture making them easy to till and for roots to penetrate, whilst repeated depositions lead to the accumulation of deep deposits of fertile sediments in irrigable locations and enable prolonged irrigation without salinization - a common problem in irrigated soils. Indeed, in the ancient examples examined in Tanzania and Ethiopia salinization was avoided for centuries.  The sediment traps may thus represent historic examples of the recent concept of &apos;land degradation neutrality&apos; that is integral to SDG 15: degradation in one part of the landscape is mitigated by increases in capacity elsewhere.  Sediment traps could therefore act as models for sustainable agricultural development, but to fully assess this it is essential to quantifying the trade-offs between erosion losses and the benefits of sediment capture. Building on relationships with agricultural NGOs in the UK, Europe and eastern Africa, this partnership will combine archaeological, ethnobotanical and development studies research to co-design an interdisciplinary method of assessing the costs and benefits of sediment traps that can be applied by NGOs and researchers (either jointly or separately), and which is sufficiently flexible to be applicable in a range of social and ecological environments worldwide.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-15">77778.98</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-15">77779</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-15">1683.37</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-15">3144827</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Development Grants Award to University of York</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T004185_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FT004185%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-12-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
