<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T038292_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Extending an inter-generational cohort to develop a multimorbidity research platform in rural and urbanising India</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In India, people that have more than one long-term health condition (&quot;multimorbidity&quot;) are more likely to have high healthcare costs, which they usually pay out-of-pocket, and to be disabled which can affect their ability to work. As a result, multimorbidity can impact the economic well-being of people&apos;s families, potentially pushing them below the poverty line. Rural and urbanising communities are particularly vulnerable to rapid rises in multimorbidity because social changes are affecting behaviours (e.g. people are eating more processed foods) and environmental exposures (e.g. rising air pollution from traffic), while old, poverty-related health issues (e.g. malnutrition) remain common. Healthcare is also lacking in these areas, so people can struggle to manage their conditions. As a result of these factors, rising multimorbidity could inhibit future development in rural and urbanising areas. As such, it is important to understand what causes multimorbidity, so that we can develop ways to prevent it. This study will build on work done over the past 30 years in 29 villages on the outskirts of Hyderabad city, Telangana. The study team has previously collected detailed health data on families within these villages (the Andhra Pradesh Children and Parents Study) (~5% of the village population, N=6,972, aged ~22-50 in 2010-12) who were involved in a trial of nutritional supplements for pregnant women and young children in the 1980s. Our ultimate aim is to follow this cohort up over the long-term to see how conditions develop and cluster together at different life-stages, to examine what causes these clusters, and to develop ways to target these causes to prevent multimorbidity developing. We will particularly investigate how factors at early-life (e.g. malnutrition) and related to the rapidly changing environment (e.g. air pollution) are linked to multimorbidity, as their impact on multimorbidity has not been assessed. Nevertheless, we need to do considerable groundwork to be able to do this accurately. This current study will analyse previously collected data to understand which clusters of conditions and potential causes are important in the local community. We will also collect data on the presence of chronic conditions in the older sub-group of the cohort (N=~2,000, aged ~60 in 2020), who are more likely to experience multiple conditions. This will be analysed in combination with previously collected data (2010) and used to calculate how many community members we need to study to accurately quantify the impact of potential causes on the risk of multimorbidity. We will also interview people with varying severities of multimorbidity (and their family members) and conduct focus-group discussions with wider community members, to understand how multimorbidity affects people&apos;s lives and what they wish APCAPs to prioritise and research in the future. A final goal is to investigate how feasible it would be to develop a system that automatically collects data on community members&apos; healthcare records, as this would allow us to collect data over the long-term and at low cost. We will do this by randomly selecting 200 of the surveyed cohort who have used healthcare in the past year, tracking down their records in local facilities, and comparing the diagnosis with results from our own clinical examinations. Working closely with community members and key parties (e.g. local health workers, village leaders), we will use the above findings to develop a research proposal for a multimorbidity research platform, to establish the causes of multimorbidity, assess its impact, and develop and test ways of preventing multimorbidity. We expect our findings will also be applicable to other communities experiencing similar social changes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our goal is to capitalise on 30 years of investment and extend the inter-generational APCAPs cohort into a platform for understanding the epidemiology of multimorbidity and its corresponding burden and healthcare use, which could ultimately be used to develop and test interventions.  Our vision for the future platform is: 1. Long-term follow-up of the APCAPs cohort to establish the lifecourse and environmental risk factors of incident multimorbidity in rural and urbanising India 2. Development and testing of low-cost and scalable interventions targeting multimorbidity prevention and burden alleviation.  To achieve this vision, we need to conduct considerable preliminary research, which constitute the specific objectives for the current seed-proposal: 1. To conduct preliminary analyses on lifecourse and environmental risk factors of prevalent multimorbidity using existing APCAPs data (N=6,972) 2. To collect pilot data on the parental generation of the APCAPs cohort to identify common clusters of multimorbidity and their incidence (N=~2,000) 3. To conduct qualitative research with community members (with and without multimorbidity) and other stakeholders to establish priorities and design of the proposed research platform 4. To explore the feasibility of establishing a low-cost disease surveillance system 5. To use the above findings to develop proposal for a multimorbidity research platform</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">198228.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/T038292/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">100318.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T038292_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FT038292%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
