<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R004331_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanities For Resilience</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development and sustainability, if they are to mean anything, must include an understanding of how communities endure, abide, and even flourish in times of adversity. Resilience is at the heart of these activities. The World Humanitarian Summit (2016) echoes these calls, insisting upon collective endeavour to &quot;leverage the strengths and abilities of affected people and communities affected by crises&quot;. Resilience is more than developing capacities to absorb shocks to communities, or systems, but is also about embedding resilience practices and dynamics in everyday activities. Currently the first approach remains the priority of international development aid and policies on resilience and so focus on preserving the status quo and biological life. However NGOs and researchers view this limited framework as a lost opportunity to &quot;restore humanity by protecting and enabling people as the primary agents of their own responses to crisis&quot; (World Humanitarian Summit). This network responds to their concerns and aims to address how resilience can be fostered by better understanding what makes &apos;ways of living&apos; resilient. Focusing on a &apos;ways of living&apos; approach to resilience, the network is an exploration of the shared human experience of resilience. A &apos;ways of living&apos; perspective additionally prioritises &apos;bottom-up&apos; formations of resilience, operating as a network of practice. The purpose of the network is to understand which resilient experiences, interactions, moves, and actions &apos;create value&apos; in diverse and complex social worlds.   The network is global in its reach and activities, operating in the UK, Zambia, Pakistan and Lebanon, with participants from Europe, North and South America, Africa, the Indian Subcontinent, and the Middle East. Shared leadership, the co-production of knowledge, and joint creation of outputs between participants are built into the structure and practices of the network. The 1st workshop (Birmingham) examines the conceptual basis for resilience by examining where and how resilience has been utilised in policy and practices from a variety of disciplinary and practitioner perspectives, including from engineering, environmental sciences and the social sciences. We will explore how international development concerns have moved from sustainability towards resilience. It will highlight the positive and negative consequences this has had across cities, policies and sectors. The 2nd workshop (Zambia), examines the targets of resilience: minority and marginalised communities. In this workshop we explore who is being made resilient and why. We will report firsthand on the work of our partner - VMM. The 3rd (Lebanon) examines &apos;practical humanities&apos; by focusing on resilient places - and where resilience is absent. It looks at resilience in transitory places as well as permanent, historical, and &apos;pop-up&apos; communal sites. The 4th (Pakistan) examines the type of interventions in the name of resilience. This addresses the artefacts and outputs associated with resilience, such as dialogue, heritage, art, literature and dance. This workshop explores whether the properties of certain objects hold &apos;resilience&apos; and how they generate resilience in others. The workshop activities will be linked and ongoing through cross-circulation of the workshops&apos; findings, and papers and debates developed through online discussion and across our partners&apos; existing communication channels. A closing plenary (Birmingham) will bring together all members of the network to develop and showcase how, as a field of disciplines, the humanities contribute towards understanding and building resilience in international development aid settings. Finally, the network, through incorporating a self-evaluation mechanism, will explore how networks themselves contribute towards resilience. Together the network&apos;s activities explore the human experience of resilience, and how &apos;ways of living&apos; are made or become resilient, and what can be done to facilitate them.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aims of the network &quot;Humanities for Resilience&quot; are to explore (a) the human experience of resilience, and how &apos;ways of living&apos;, are made or become resilient, and what can be done to facilitate them, and (b) how the arts and humanities can contribute to these understandings and practices of resilience in Lower and Middle Income Countries. It will bring together stakeholders and scholars from across the globe to achieve the following key objectives: 1. Use the network activities as a platform from which to develop a new international research and development agenda for Resilience 2. Facilitate and amplify the resilience practices and experiences of network partners 3. Identify and map activities across the arts and humanities that contribute to resilience across diverse settings 4. Provide constructive critique of existing resilience practices and policies based on the experiences of resilience of the Arts and Humanities network partners and learn from insights from non-AHRC disciplinary experts. 5. Evaluate the Humanities for Resilience network via a &apos;value creation framework&apos; as a mechanism for enhancing resilience  6. Ensure the network&apos;s sustainability through active participation of postgraduates and early career researchers especially from LMICs 7. Develop future research capability and externally funded projects with academic and NGO partners from Zambia, Lebanon and Pakistan with the aim of extending this to further LMICs in the long-term.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-EDU-133784" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-29" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-07">33589.98</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-07">14395.7</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-07">47985.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Research Networking Award to University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH/R004331/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-01">33589.98</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R004331_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-04-01">14395.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R004331_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FR004331%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-01-29"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
