<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N013816_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing Research Capacity for Inclusive Urban Governance: a Sheffield-Witwatersrand PhD training partnership</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives of the project are: 1) To deliver, through collaboration between the Universities of Sheffield and Witwatersrand and their non-academic partners, high-quality research training to a cohort of PhD students from each institution in the field of governance and social inclusion in rapidly-changing urban environments. This training will enable the researchers involved to: i) Make significant theoretical and policy-relevant contributions to their field through critical analysis of urban governance processes, and of the impacts of urban policy on marginalised individuals ii) Operate effectively in a global research environment through the experience of participating within a community of researchers working across institutions internationally. 2) To use the training delivered to effect sustainable development of research training in both institutions by: i) Driving forwards the establishment of a formal PhD training programme in Witwatersrand&apos;s School of Architecture and Planning ii) Enhancing PhD training in University of Sheffield through specific new content on co-producing research in an international context, and broader development to support distance-learning, international partnerships and cohort-based learning.  iii) Establishing lasting research training linkages between the two institutions that are reflected in future exchanges, studentship applications and joint publication on doctoral training 3) To use the collective strength of the theoretical and empirical work of an integrated cohort of PhD researchers to pursue a sustainable research agenda by: i) Developing high-quality academic outputs which collectively showcase the best of the research conducted through the exchange programme. ii) Engaging non-academic partners in the project, from training delivery through to exploration of the policy-relevance of research findings, to maximise the potential for international impact   iii) Enhancing research linkages between members of the project team that will result in future collaborative studentship and research funding bids.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed partnership will develop an international cohort of researchers in South Africa and the UK with the skills and capacities to conduct high-quality research on governance and social inclusion in rapidly-changing urban environments.  Since Apartheid, the South African state has made major investments in housing and urban infrastructure, and yet faces ongoing protest over housing and urban service delivery, and the persistence of &apos;informal&apos; housing and employment. These conditions, which are echoed in other international contexts, indicate the pressing need for critical research that examines the gaps between urban policy goals, everyday state practices, and the life-worlds of intended policy recipients.  This exchange programme draws together a team of researchers (from School of Architecture and Planning, University of the Witwatersrand, and Department of Town and Regional Planning, University of Sheffield) who are undertaking internationally-leading work on &apos;actually existing&apos; governance practices in the local state, and the impacts of urban policy on the lives of poor urban citizens, to build research capacity in this challenge area. It does so through collaboration which draws on the complementary strengths of their respective institutions: Sheffield&apos;s leadership of the ESRC&apos;s White Rose Doctoral Training Centre and interdisciplinary research within Sheffield Institute for International Development and its new Urban Institute, and the Witwatersrand&apos;s expertise in co-produced research in urban planning.  It uses this partnership to deliver high-quality doctoral training structured around key stages of PhD progression, from research design to write-up and dissemination. Delivery of bespoke &apos;training packages&apos; will be concentrated in short, intensive exchange visits, supported by on-line communication and follow-up activities, a structure that facilitates participation of part-time, and mid-career PhD students. Sequencing these exchanges throughout the PhD process will develop researchers&apos; skills base, and also develop a strong cohort identity and intellectual coherence among the Sheffield and Wits students working together over the course of the programme. Beyond directly enhancing the research capacities of the participants themselves, the exchange programme will have two major benefits. The first is cross-institutional learning about doctoral training. Staff exchange visits within the core team will be used to collaboratively develop high-quality training materials, and embed best practice within doctoral programme development in each institution. The timing of this exchange is ideal, coinciding with a push to formalise doctoral training within Wits, and a significant review of Sheffield&apos;s provision in preparation for a DTP bid (March 2016). Members of the core team lead Sheffield&apos;s Faculty of Social Sciences Doctoral Programme, and PhD training in the Planning school in Wits, and so are uniquely placed to ensure that pedagogical learning over the course of the exchange programme is reflected in lasting institution-level change. The second is the development of a sustained academic research agenda, emerging from the cohort identity of the researchers themselves, and collective publication and knowledge-exchange activities they will undertake over the course of the programme. The core project teams in both institutions are committed to taking this forward beyond the period of Newton funding through collective bids for further PhD studentships and joint research projects.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-18">17266.42</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-18">34672.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-18">34953.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-18">17547.18</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-18">522199</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC Newton Newton Fund Award to University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N013816_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FN013816%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-11-02"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
