<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009999_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transitional Justice in Cambodia: Victim Participation at the Extraordinary Chambers in the Courts of Cambodia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed fellowship aims to contribute to the scholarly debate, policy discussion and policymaking on victim participation, its role, scope and implications in transitional justice. It will build upon my doctoral research at the University of Oxford, which centred on the participation of victims of gross violations of human rights as civil parties in international criminal proceedings, and will further explore the development and dynamics of civil party participation at the Extraordinary Chambers in the Courts of Cambodia (ECCC).  Victim participation is still a novelty in the realm of international criminal justice, and as such, the trials at the ECCC in Cambodia have appeared more as &apos;experimenting laboratories&apos; than as processes guided by sound and well-crafted rules and procedures. My doctoral thesis has argued that whilst the apparent benefits of participation seem self-evident, and may lead, at least in theory, to the realisation of the aspiration of restorative justice for victims of the Khmer Rouge, the manner in which civil party participation has been crafted and interpreted in the trials before the ECCC has raised some important issues and questions regarding its role and impact with respect to the functionality of court proceedings, the rights of the accused, and the rights of victims themselves.  In this context, the proposed research will offer an invaluable platform for me to communicate my research findings to both academic and non-academic audiences. More specifically, the fieldwork that I intend to undertake for one and a half months in Cambodia will serve two main goals. Firstly, it will enable me to engage with those who participated in my previous research through interviews, group discussions and conversations, by sharing with them empirical evidence and practical understanding of, and insights into, the assumed benefits and harms resulting from victim participation. I plan to organise two separate one-day interactive workshops in Phnom Penh, Cambodia. The first workshop will be with the civil parties and victim complainants I interviewed for my doctoral research. The aim is to present my research findings as well as to create a forum where victims as primary stakeholders in my research can participate by sharing their thoughts and ideas. The second workshop will be with representatives of the ECCC, Victims Support Section (VSS), Cambodian Human Rights and Development Association (ADHOC), Documentation Center of Cambodia (DC Cam) and other victims advocate and human rights organisation operating in Cambodia. The aim of this workshop is to present my research findings, discuss current developments of victim participation, and most importantly provide clear recommendations for effective policies and appropriate measures to support a meaningful and active civil party participation at the ECCC. Secondly, the fieldwork research in Cambodia will provide me with a base to further investigate the up-to-date development and dynamics of civil party participation at the ECCC. In addition, the proposed research will offer an excellent opportunity for me to contribute to academic and policy debates on victim participation in Cambodia by presenting my research findings at various conferences and seminars as well as engaging with academic and non-academic audiences with the view to exchanging and producing high-quality scholarship. To this effect, I intend to organise a one-day expert workshop with academics, practitioners and policymakers from Cambodia and the United Kingdom to be held at the Centre for Criminology in Oxford. Finally, following the successful defence of my doctoral thesis at Oxford, both examiners commended my research as an original and significant contribution to scholarship in the area of victims&apos; rights in international criminal justice, and have encouraged me to pursue publication of my work in the form of a monograph.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed research will have six key objectives:  1. To further engage with practitioners, policymakers and victims, who participated in my doctoral research in Cambodia, by communicating to them the research findings, empirical evidence and further insights into the dynamics of civil party participation at the Extraordinary Chambers in the Courts of Cambodia (ECCC). The goal is to provide practitioners and policymakers with research findings that can help them enhance and support the meaningful and active participation of victims in proceedings at the ECCC, as well as safeguard the welfare of victims and survivors of the Khmer Rouge regime.  2. To contribute to the developing theory and policy concerning victim participation as a transitional justice mechanism in post-conflict societies through methodical theoretical and empirical analysis of the complex and multi-faceted civil party participation regime at the ECCC. It is in this context that this research aims to enrich our understanding of victim participation as both an approach and a principle with the view to building effective transitional justice institutions in Cambodia and other conflict-affected societies.  3. To enhance our understanding of the role, scope and implications of victim participation in Cambodia, and the extent to which it might lead to the fulfilment of the aspiration of a more inclusive justice system for victims of mass atrocities in terms of helping to unearth the truth, fostering national reconciliation, as well as potentially providing substantive remedies.  4. To liaise and engage with academic and non-academic audiences by sharing knowledge and research findings with the view to exchanging and producing high-quality scholarship. To this effect, I intend to organise a one-day expert workshop with academics, practitioners and policymakers from Cambodia and the United Kingdom to be held at the Centre for Criminology in Oxford. The discussion and knowledge exchange in this expert workshop would be particularly beneficial to practitioners and policymakers who are in the best position and vested with the authority and discretion to give full scope to victims&apos; participatory rights.  5. To build upon my DPhil experience and further develop my research skills by participating in methodology training as well as acquiring a greater understanding of the socio-cultural and politico-legal dynamics and challenges in Cambodia&apos;s post-conflict society.  6. To publish my DPhil thesis as a monograph and produce publications in the form of articles and reports on the development of victim participation as a restorative justice mechanism aiming to contribute depth and dimension to the general understanding of victim participation as a legal principle and norm. Both my DPhil viva examiners have encouraged that I publish my thesis as a monograph, and I am working towards the preparation of my book proposal to be submitted to Oxford University Press.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF Post Doctoral Fellowship Award to University of Oxford</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES/P009999/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-01">0.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009999_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-01">0.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009999_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-01">-0.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009999_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FP009999%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-12-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
