<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_P004237_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building debt capital markets in China</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since 1978, the start of the transformation of the People&apos;s Bank of China into a central bank and four major state-owned commercial banks, China has pursued a major development of new financial institutions. In this China has pursued its own particular vision of when and where to integrate market elements into its economy. Elsewhere, during the 1970&apos;s and 1980&apos;s many countries around the world pursued a policy of financial development whose cornerstone was the liberalization and modernisation of the sovereign debt market accompanied to varying degrees of disintermediation through the development of corporate and sub-sovereign (i.e., &quot;muni&quot;) bond markets. To date China has not gone very far down this path. However, increased opening of the economy, the internationalization of its currency and its accession to the SDR are all creating pressures to transform the bond market to conform to the global norm established by the US, Europe and Japan. Furthermore its commitment to major infrastructure investments internationally through the Belt and Road Initiative will create even greater pressure to transform China&apos;s fixed income market for the next 4 to 5 years. Our project will examine the relevance and suitability these elements of market based finance to China&apos;s economic development strategy over the next ten years.  Our aim is to produce original theoretical and empirical, policy-oriented research on the growth of debt markets in China since 2008 and on its future development over the next 5 years. We intend for this project to become a major reference for other researchers and therefore building block for further research. Furthermore, our research will help to provide answers to pressing questions being asked by Chinese policy makers, business practitioners and the public generally.  - Our studies of dynamics of the sovereign debt market will shed light on whether interest rates across the term structure reflect an efficient flow of credit to high return investments which support robust long-term economic growth. Furthermore, as the bond market is opened to international capital flows are the authorities adapting tools of monetary control to help keep the economy on a stable growth path?  - Our work with corporate bonds will reveal the extent to which the market is integrated across a wide spectrum of issuers so that borrowers in different segments but with the same risk and return prospects face the same cost of capital, i.e., is finance flowing to the most promising projects. Our studies of corporate bond liquidity will show how effective the market is a reconciling the needs of borrowers for stable long-term funding with needs of savers for flexibility withdraw from the market when they need or want. - Our studies of the sub-sovereign debt market will show whether financial discipline is being brought to the major investment projects supported by regional and local governments. This is crucial to understanding whether recurrent issues of non-performing loans are being brought under control. And in China this is directly relevant to questions of provision of better housing and public services in the areas where they benefit society most.  To achieve these objectives we have set small number of operational objectives for the project:  - We will assemble a core team of academics in the UK and China to carry out a series of related research projects on Chinese debt capital markets. - We will promote the adaptation of advanced methodologies used in analysing mature debt markets to the Chinese context by facilitating international awareness of important institutional features of the Chinese financial system. - We will assemble the best available data resources on China&apos;s debt markets to be shared among the research team. - We will encourage the dissemination of our research on debt capital markets in an accessible form relevant to policy makers, finance practitioners and a broad international community of academics.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main directions of our project are organized under three headings.  Sovereign bonds: This concerns the trading of securities issued by the central government to domestic and foreign savers including short-term instruments (Treasury bills) and longer term instruments (Treasury notes and bonds). The modernisation and liberalization this market has typically proceeded by organizing security issues to permit trading over the full range of the term structure from less than one-month to twenty years or more.  By issuing standardized contracts (e.g., non-callable, non-amortizing bonds) at regular intervals it can allow users and the fiscal authority the means of managing risks flexibly over a very long time horizon.  Through a process of arbitrage it can facilitate the development of liquid trading of a wide range of other instruments used in money markets and debt capital markets.  Liberalizing this market involves increasing the range of institutions participating in the market and eliminating or greatly relaxing quantitative controls.  Institutional development to support this process involves simplification and effective regulation of pre-trade and post-trade services including market-making (both primary and secondary), clearing and settlement, managing central securities depositories and custodians.  The development of this market is often accompanied by a change of the methods of monetary control with the progressive elimination of quantitative tools (credit quantities, reserve ratios...) and increased reliance on controls through broad monetary aggregates and price-based (interest rate) policy tools.  Implementing monetary policy using a liquid sovereign debt market requires policy makers to rethink how they hope to achieve objectives for price stability, exchange rates and credit (and investment) growth.    Corporate bonds: The development of a broad and liquid corporate bond market can provide an effective means of providing funds to private sector enterprises as an alternative to bank finance which may result in lower costs of debt capital and thus promote growth.  For savers investing in a broadly diversified portfolio of corporate bonds can provide better risk adjusted returns than investing in stock markets or bank savings accounts alone.  They can play a large and important role in retirement finance as one of the main investment vehicles for life insurers and pension funds. Developing an efficient corporate bond market involves overcoming a range of important institutional challenges.  It requires provision of investor protections against abusive trading practices.  These rely on sound accounting and reporting standards for issuers, insurance, pensions and fund managers.  It requires collection and dissemination of information about credit histories and ratings.  It requires well-designed bankruptcy regimes with sound legal foundations and efficient administration.  Corporate bond markets can become fragmented across maturities and legal status of issuers. Providing liquid trading of corporate bonds is challenging, and developing repurchase agreements, securities lending and other forms of securities funding transactions can be key to reducing transactions costs.   Sub-sovereign/muni bonds: This segment of the bond market is directed at the funding of public sector investments that are not supported by the budget of the central government.  It involves bond issues by regional and local governments and special purpose public and quasi-public entities (highway authorities, water authorities, etc.) The development of this market segment is intimately related to the organization of local public finance.  Thus our research will necessarily take into the account the particular Chinese structure of organizing both government entities and also state owned enterprises.   In the current context reforms in the area will need to deal with the issue of an overhang of non-performing loans.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-22">25937.74</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-22">103961.05</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-22">104803.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-22">52719.26</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-22">313780.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC Newton Research Grants Award to London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES/P004237/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FP004237%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
