<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T018941_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Discerning the genetic contributors to autonomous aldosterone production through whole genome sequencing</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaysia, like the rest of the world, has a high prevalence of high blood pressure (hypertension), 32.7% for aged &gt;18 years. Difficult to control hypertension can lead to co-morbidities and mortality as it is a major risk factor for stroke and heart diseases. Primary aldosteronism (PA), showing excess production of the hormone aldosterone from the adrenal glands, is probably the commonest curable cause of hypertension. While a recent report suggested that 60% of patients with hypertension have PA, a more conservative estimate, with concentration on curable patients, might suggest 5-10% of all patients, but in much higher proportions among those with treatment resistant hypertension, and ethnic groups with low-renin hypertension. In many patients, the discovery of a unilateral aldosterone-producing adenoma (APA) of the adrenal gland offers the opportunity for complete cure of hypertension. However developing country like Malaysia lacks the resources to identify these patients. Even making a reliable diagnosis of PA is currently fraught, requiring withdrawal of most first-line antihypertensive drugs from high-risk patients for the hormone (renin and aldosterone) measurements, often on more than one occasion if a confirmatory test (e.g saline or captopril suppression) is required. Hence, &lt;1% of patients with PA are currently diagnosed. However, preventing excessive aldosterone is not only essential to attenuate high blood pressure which can lead to cardiovascular diseases, but also to prevent direct cardiac damage. We therefore aim in this proposal to identify the genetic contributors for autonomous aldosterone production, using the powerful whole genome sequencing technology, with the hope of developing a low-cost high-throughput peripheral blood assay that will allow mass diagnosis and targeted treatment of autonomous aldosterone production. Whole genome sequencing, a powerful technology to detect all the genetic sequences in an individual, will be able to identify heritable mutations associated with PA. Heredity is estimated to contribute 25-64% of inter-individual variation in blood pressure, yet currently genome-wide association studies have only identified ~3.5% of the genetic contribution with most hits occurring in the non-coding regions. This work will provide deeper genetic understanding of the disease development especially on the non gene-coding regulatory sequences and interplay between heritable germline mutations and somatic mutations that occur in the adrenal. Interestingly, one of the top hit GWAS polymorphism associated with PA in the recently released UK Biobank data is SMUG1, a DNA repair gene where the signature for its failure is C/T or G/A mutations. To note, almost half of aldosterone-producing cell clusters and micro-aldosterone-producing adenomas in PA patients have this signature. We hypothesize that WGS will discover informative, causal variants, e.g. in enhancer regions, which are rare (&lt;1%) in control population databases, but &gt;10-fold more frequent in documented PA with somatic mutation in aldosterone-driver genes. Such discovery may be rewarded by the potential for a clinically useful diagnostic test, a potential which is never realised by the common SNPs used in GWAS. We postulate that much of low-renin hypertension is due to undiagnosed autonomous aldosterone production and the low tech high throughput assay that can be developed from this study will cut cost of diagnosis and justify cheap preventive treatment despite spironolactone&apos;s known plethora of side effects. With the new information generated from this project, a simple genotyping test may be developed to identify hypertensive patients due to autonomous aldosterone production, which can then be treated by the cheap aldosterone receptor antagonist spironolactone, decreasing blood pressure and risk of cardiovascular diseases.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall Objective To identify and elucidate the causative germline mutations associated with primary aldosteronism (PA) underlain by CACNA1D somatic mutations. Specific Aims 1. To identify genome-wide germline mutations from DNA extracted from blood samples of PA patients especially those that carried CACNA1D somatic mutations. Whole genome sequencing (WGS) will be used as this is the most powerful approach that can identify non-coding and/or rare variants besides coding and/or common variants that are usually identified through GWAS or whole exome sequencing approaches.  2. To functionally verify the germline mutations in relevant cell types so the causality of the mutations can be established. Mutations identified from WGS will be technically validated using Sanger method first. Then the validated mutations will be generated in relevant cell lines using CRISPR technologies. Gene expression and cellular phenotypes of the edited cells will be studied. 3. To investigate the interplay between germline and somatic mutations in PA patients. We will compare WGS outcomes with somatic mutations and other clinical manifestations to identify the relationship between germline and somatic mutations such as those located in CACNA1D. We will have about 100 patients with confirmed PA and 100 patients with high aldosterone to renin ratio to test the hypothesis.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">32870.45</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">98877.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">33136.67</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">5280571.36</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T018941_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FT018941%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
