<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_R022879_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RCUK-CIAT Newton Fund Advancing sustainable forage-based livestock production systems using multi-source remote sensing and social science approaches</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture and livestock production have historically been one of the major components of Colombian economic development and it is one of the top countries in the world in terms of greatest agricultural land expansion potential. Approximately 34% of the land area (~40m Ha) is used for livestock activities, with most pastures dedicated to extensive grazing systems. Agriculture is a critical source of employment in rural Colombia and is one of the sectors most affected by climate and climate change and where solutions to key challenges affecting the productivity and sustainability of pastures and the livestock sector are required. This collaborative project between University of Glasgow (UofG) University of Bristol (UofB) and CIAT will bring together cross-disciplinary perspectives and methodologies to develop RS-based approaches for forage monitoring and management at local and regional levels. The specific objectives are to: 1) develop co-designed work-flows for acquiring, processing and analysis of multi-dimensional multispectral and radar data for trial sites at CIAT headquarters; 2) investigate operational functions for extraction of grass growth and quality metrics from combined airborne/spaceborne/in situ datasets and develop a framework for a forage management decision support system; and 3) investigate methodologies for engagement with smallholders and determine attitudes to and potential barriers of incorporation of such technologies and their outputs into practice. The project will deliver new data to establish a baseline understanding of the capabilities of multi-source remote sensing and predictive analysis tools to provide reliable and consistent information on forage quantity and quality and smallholder capability and willingness to adopt such technologies. Outputs from the project will directly inform forage production management activities and will be communicated to stakeholders via a project website, an end-of-project workshop, and through promotion at further dissemination events run by CIAT.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This collaborative project between University of Glasgow (UofG) University of Bristol (UofB) and CIAT uses state-of-the-art airborne and satellite multispectral and radar remote sensing to quantify rates of forage productivity in Colombia, applying new methods to estimate forage quality, and builds a new interdisciplinary relationship between the UK institutions and CIAT. The project capitalises on field trials, existing technological infrastructure at CIAT and existing contacts with smallholder farmers, and represents the first phase of collaboration on using high resolution &apos;Big&apos; geospatial data and machine learning approaches to ultimately improve forage-based livestock production systems. The techniques developed during this project will be transferable to other tropical locations within Colombia. The project aims to: develop combined multi-source remote sensing based approaches to monitor and manage tropical forage-based production systems. To deliver this aim, the specific objectives are: 1. Develop co-designed work-flows for acquiring, processing and analysis of multi-dimensional multispectral and radar data for trial sites at CIAT headquarters. 2. Investigate operational functions for extraction of grass growth and quality metrics from combined airborne/spaceborne/in situ datasets and develop a framework for a forage management decision support system. 3. Investigate methodologies for engagement with smallholders and determine attitudes to and potential barriers of incorporation of such technologies and their outputs into practice. The project will deliver new data to establish a baseline understanding of the capabilities of multi-source remote sensing and predictive analysis tools to provide reliable and consistent information on forage quantity and quality and smallholder capability and willingness to adopt such technologies. The project will build relationships between UofG UofB and CIAT researchers and strengthen relationships with smallholder farmers thus developing a network of partners for future project applications. The project remit spans across NERC (Barrett - environmental remote sensing), BBSRC (Selvaraj, Arango - crop physiology) and ESRC (Escobar - using non-cognitive social science methodologies to understand farmer practices).</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-30">79371.05</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
