<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R005435_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deepening democracy in extremely politically fragile countries: networking for historical, cultural and arts research on Parliaments and people</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The challenges for democracy across the globe are chronic, intensifying and urgent. The prospects for greater stability, and meeting the SDGs on inclusive institutions and global partnership, are remote unless ways are found of working towards what Appadurai calls &apos;deep democracy&apos;: local activism by NGOs and movements combined with global networks working in partnership with states. Our networking will link researchers interested in Parliaments and public engagement. The priority will be to support the development of national capacity to study democracy in extremely politically fragile states with a focus on Ethiopia and Myanmar. We will partner with Forum for Social Studies (Addis) and Enlightened Myanmar Research Foundation (Yangon) to enable research capacity development by: networking and training; allocation of small, medium and large grants to researchers; mentoring in research methods and dissemination; facilitation of learning between grantees and support in advocacy; stimulating debate; and fostering multi-disciplinary co-operation. National researchers will be given support and opportunities to undertake high quality research on the links between Parliament and the People and collaborate with arts organisations.  This three year project will enable scholarly innovation through: (a) The study of politics in fragile countries has been dominated by development studies and political science. This research will create opportunities for scholarship in arts and humanities disciplines, including anthropology, political and social history, and cultural studies (especially gender and sexuality); (b) While development and politics scholars, and organisations working on governance in the Global South, tend to focus on either civil society/citizens or elite institutions, this research network will address the relationship between them; (c) Although researchers from the UK and India will manage the project, national researchers permanently based in &apos;extremely politically fragile&apos; countries will do research and influence policy-makers. We have drafted research themes with partners:  1. Culture of representation: How do cultural ideas about effective representation, gender equality and public engagement emerge for elected politicians and citizens within specific cultures and histories? What are citizens&apos; (or non-citizens) and CSOs&apos; attitudes to Parliaments (national and regional) and politicians, what difference does gender and sexuality make, and how are attitudes changing? What conversations take place between them and how are they gendered through language, performance and ritual? How and why does trust increase or decrease between politicians and people? What is the potential for combining representative and participatory democracy, what incentives can be created and what change is realistic?  2. History of exclusion and instability: In what circumstances has representation historically contributed to gender equality, the promotion of the rights of excluded groups, as well as stronger trust, peace and stability? Do women and men imagine the future differently and how is this shaped by their histories? What role does gender (including masculinity) have in political performance, violence and interaction? How do inequalities, rituals, language, self-confidence and claims of authority include or exclude people? 3. Imagining deeper democracy through media and the arts: How can national and regional Parliaments respond to people, improve outreach and enhance the relationships between politicians and the public? How can decentralization and the power dynamics between national and regional legislatures work more effectively? How can arts disciplines or creative industries  (art, photography, media, social media, theatre) evoke emotions to transform relationships and influence politics in democracies? How can we measure these changes? What is unique to particular locations and what generalisation can be found across them?</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of this project is to create opportunities for scholars in extremely politically fragile states to undertake research on democracy, public engagement and women&apos;s political participation. It is designed to support national researchers to be the main protagonists in all aspects of this project: Objective 1: Develop a network of scholars in politically fragile states interested in research on Parliament, public engagement and women&apos;s political participation  A new Global Research Network of Parliaments and People will be launched by SOAS/Hansard Society/Leeds University, inviting research institutes, universities, NGOs and parliamentary monitoring organisations and individual researchers from around the world to become members. The priority of this network during 2017-2020 will be to support project partners and researchers in Myanmar and Ethiopia, and neighbouring states, to develop national capacity to undertake historical, ethnographic and cultural research on democracy. In preparation for awarding grants, we will offer training, guidance and mentoring with our project partners - Enlightened Myanmar Research Foundation (Yangon) and Forum for Social Studies (Addis Ababa) - and create links between researchers, arts/media/theatre organisations and policy-makers. To encourage humanities research on democracy and dissemination through the arts, and challenge the dominance of political science, we will also hold workshops in the focus countries and in neighbouring extremely politically fragile states. Objective 2: Develop national capacity by awarding grants to undertake historical, ethnographic and cultural research on Parliament, public engagement and women&apos;s political participation We will develop a grant-making mechanism with our project partners awarding grants for research on extremely politically fragile states: (a) of &#xA3;1,000-5,000 to carry out small projects, hold events, write think pieces or develop larger research proposals, (b) of &#xA3;5,000-30,000 to do medium sized projects, (c) of &#xA3;30-100k to undertake or disseminate larger-scale research. Preference will be given to Ethiopia and Myanmar for all grants and then secondarily to neighbouring extremely politically fragile states for small and medium grants. The grants will be for undertaking research, disseminating findings but also working with media outlets, artists, theatres or museums to investigate through arts methodologies and/or to amplify their impact. Objective 3: Establish links between network members (especially grantees) and enable them to compare and synthesise findings, create imaginative outputs and influence donor agencies and other policy-makers/stakeholders  To support partners and grantees we will: hold annual meetings to review and plan activities; run research workshops to support researchers and facilitate learning between them (both grantees but also other researchers including those working as staff within both Parliaments); support them to synthesise and disseminate findings (including submitting evidence to the UK&apos;s International Development Select Committee and other influential bodies); ensure on-going monitoring and evaluation into work-plans to ensure high quality research but also to provide evidence of this so members can secure future financial support; provide mentoring, training and advice on research methods, analysis and writing up; create links with selected experts in art, theatre, museum exhibitions, radio- and film-making when requested; and facilitate meetings between researchers and policy-makers to debate and adopt researchers&apos; recommendations. We will also support network members by developing a website and on-line digital presence; establish an online forum on Facebook for sharing good practices and reflections; offer an on-line based research technical enquiry service, distance support, and webinars on humanities research and dissemination through the arts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOAS University of London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-29">304692.62</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-29">611853.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-29">616809.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-29">309648.73</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-29">1843003.952</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Large Grants Award to SOAS University of London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R005435_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOAS University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FR005435%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
