<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T030283_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elucidating molecular determinants of Trypanosoma cruzi persisters.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chagas disease is endemic in 21 countries with around 70 million people at risk of infection, and an estimated mortality rate of over 10,000 people per year. This neglected tropical disease is caused by the intracellular protozoan parasite Trypanosoma cruzi. Current drugs (benznidazole and nifurtimox) have serious adverse side-effects and long-treatment duration resulting in many patients not completing appropriate treatment. There is thus an urgent need for new, shorter-course, efficacious and safe drugs, but unfortunately the current drug discovery pipeline is very sparse, reflecting the many challenges faced by the Chagas disease drug discovery community. Chronic Chagas disease is associated with a very low parasite burden as the immune system effectively clears most parasites during the acute phase of the disease. It is therefore thought that the most effective new treatments will be the ones that kill every single parasite in the patient. This is made even more challenging by the presence of a small sub-population of parasites that is less susceptible to drugs. We, and others, have recently identified these &quot;persister&quot; parasites and have demonstrated in vitro that they can withstand long drug exposures that otherwise quickly kill the majority of intracellular parasites. The current understanding is that these persister parasites are quiescent (i.e. do not divide), are able to exit from the persister state, and can spread the disease. A key issue for Chagas disease drug discovery is the complete lack of understanding of the biology of these persister parasites. We do not know how they are triggered, what genes they express, what cellular pathways are active and what proteins are suitable drug targets for this population.  To start addressing these questions, the proposed research will study the persister parasites at the molecular level. Specifically, this work will use state-of-the-art single-cell methodologies to determine which genes are expressed in the persisters and compare this with the total parasite population. Understanding this will shed light on the fundamental biology of the persister parasites and will help develop better assays and choose suitable drug targets for new drug discovery efforts. Knowing which genes are expressed and which are not will also allow us to define a set of marker genes to specifically detect the persister population, something that is currently not possible.  Once we have identified markers for the persister population we will carry out experiments to show that the persisters we see in the laboratory are relevant to the ones seen in Chagas disease, through in vivo studies using animal models of the disease.  The final main objective of this proposal is to identify compounds that can either induce the persister state or force persisters into a replicative state. Understanding how compounds that induce persisters act may reveal the mechanisms underlying persister formation. Compounds that release parasites from the persister state can be used to validate a new treatment concept where a compound that induces replication of persisters is combined with existing drugs that kill replicative parasites. By characterising the T. cruzi persisters at the molecular level this proposal will enable better, more targeted, drug discovery approaches for Chagas disease. It will allow development of fit-for-purpose assays for drug discovery, assist with the identification of suitable drug discovery targets and allow tracking of the effect of drugs against persisters in vivo. This work will also enable future detailed studies of persister biology, such as persister dynamics and the study of proteins that regulate the persister state.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chagas disease, a neglected tropical disease caused by the protozoan intracellular parasite Trypanosoma cruzi, has a large impact in Latin America and beyond. New treatments are urgently needed. However, despite the concerted effort of multiple drug discovery groups, the drug development pipeline remains very sparse due to the many challenges associated with Chagas disease drug discovery. Along with others, we recently discovered a small subpopulation of parasites that are less susceptible to drugs and are thought to play a key role in treatment failure and disease progression. At the molecular level nothing is known about these persister parasites, hampering drug discovery efforts for Chagas disease. Single-cell RNA-seq transcriptome profiling is an extremely powerful technology for gaining an understanding of cell population heterogeneity and of rare populations such as the T. cruzi persisters. The overall objective of this proposal is to characterise the persister parasites at the gene-expression level to develop an understanding of their underlying biology and to improve drug discovery efforts for Chagas disease.  The specific objectives of this proposal are:  1) Determine intracellular parasite population heterogeneity and the molecular determinants of intracellular T.cruzi persister parasites at the transcriptome level.  2) Validate that persister parasites observed in vitro are physiologically relevant.  3) Identify compounds that either induce the persister state or release parasites from the persister state.  Persister parasites pose a huge challenge for Chagas disease drug discovery. I will address this by generating, for the first time, a molecular understanding of persister parasites. The proposed work will identify markers for persisters that can be used in in vitro assays and in vivo studies, allow the rational identification of drug targets for persister parasites, and provide chemical tools to explore new treatment paradigms for Chagas disease. As such, this work will significantly increase the ability of the worldwide Chagas disease drug discovery community to develop much needed new treatments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-SC-015096" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIVERSITY OF DUNDEE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-08-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-31">60120.85</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FQ2 2021-2022 spend on Elucidating molecular determinants of Trypanosoma cruzi persisters.</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T030283_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-13">727294.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Dundee</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/T030283/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-SC-015096">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Dundee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FT030283%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
