<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N013247_2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Healthy, Secure and Gender Just Cities: Transnational Perspectives on Violence against Women and Girls (VAWG) in Rio de Janeiro and London</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Brazil an estimated 15 women are killed by men every day. Within the past three decades, at least 92,000 women have been killed, many at the hands of their partners representing a rise of 230% between 1980 and 2010. The situation in Rio de Janeiro is no less alarming where 17 women a day are victims of gender-based murder and sexual violence.   This project provides an opportunity to make an important contribution to understanding Violence Against Women and Girls (VAWG), which is one of the world&apos;s major public health and development concerns, with a view towards reducing it in order to make the cities of Rio and London ultimately healthier as well as to develop a mutual learning partnership between the Global North and Global South.  The research explores the nature of VAWG in Rio de Janeiro with a simultaneous examination of such violence among London&apos;s Brazilian diaspora. It develops an innovative inter-disciplinary framework that builds on the strengths of the research team to bridge geographical and disciplinary borders. It combines the analytical approach of the social sciences with the traditions of knowledge production in the humanities, and the ability of theatre to explore new relationships between authors and audiences. It recognises growing linkages between cities of the Global South and North, connected through globalisation and international migration, as well as the need to learn from cities of the South.  The research is rooted empirically in two urban locations 1) in the largest favela in Rio de Janeiro, Complexo da Mar&#xE9;, where residents are predominantly poor and where everyday VAWG is endemic; and 2) among the diasporic community of Brazilians in London, which is one of the fastest growing migrant groups in the city and the largest component of the wider Latin American population. With no existing systematic analysis of the nature of VAWG in either the territorial or diasporic community, the project explores the nature, causes and consequences of VAWG and the health outcomes locally and across borders. Specifically, it uses a range of mainly qualitative methodologies such as participatory appraisals, testimonial interviews, mapping of service provision, theatre production and film as tools to explore what happens to women in one of Latin America&apos;s most violent cities and examine how this violence affect linkages and movement across borders between Rio de Janeiro and London. This is facilitated through the close links the research teams have with the communities, especially through their collaborating partners - in Rio, Redes da Mar&#xE9; (a community organisation); in London, the Latin American Women&apos;s Rights Service (LAWRS), and the People&apos;s Palace Project (an arts-based research centre working on London and Brazil, based at QMUL).  Theoretically, the project aims to develop new understandings of VAWG that move beyond the traditional epidemiological approach to explore how participatory appraisal and theatre in particular can uncover processes that have previously been hidden. As part of this approach, the project aims to develop a nexus (&apos;multi-scalar-VAWG-health-nexus&apos;) that will assist in explaining why VAWG occurs and especially how this occurs across borders, the sources of support available, and how VAWG motivates women&apos;s movement to the UK from Brazil as well as how this affects health inequalities.   It actively considers the potential for learning from existing community interventions and especially those revolving around theatre and performance, and in creating new interventions to reduce VAWG and reduce the urban public health risks associated with it. It also proposes to devise effective tools to increase women and girls&apos; knowledge about their rights in relation to the experience of violence. Thus, it will raise awareness of VAWG transnationally as a means to strengthen and build capacity, compare experiences, promote alternative narratives and impact on policy debates in both countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This multi-disciplinary project attempts to understand the localised realities of extremely high levels of Violence Against Women and Girls (VAWG) in relation to health, citizenship and justice and especially its transnational links. In exploring possible resolutions that might encourage learning across cultural divisions of the Global North and South, the research proposes a multi-scalar approach to examine the nature of VAWG in Rio de Janeiro in transnational perspective with a simultaneous examination of VAWG among London&apos;s Brazilian diaspora. The project develops an innovative inter-disciplinary analytical and methodological framework that builds on the strengths of the research team to bridge geographical and disciplinary borders. It combines the analytical approach of the social sciences with the different traditions of knowledge production in the humanities, and the ability of theatre to explore ethical dilemmas, performative contexts and new relationships between authors and audiences. Innovative coproduction and simultaneous generation of impact and knowledge exchange between Brazil and the United Kingdom is consequently central to the research aims and design. Rooted empirically in spatially bounded community research in the largest favela in Rio de Janeiro, Complexo da Mar&#xE9;, together with a non-territorially defined diasporic community of Brazilians in London, these aims will be explored by: Conceptually:  -Developing a &apos;multi-scalar-VAWG-health nexus&apos; in relation to transnational and translocal interpretations to explore how structure, agency and identities change across borders and the role of theatre within this.  -Developing theorisations of urban VAWG and health inequalities through transnational recalibration/learning between Brazil and the UK. Empirically: -Transnational exploration of VAWG- how do women experience VAWG in Rio and London?  With women moving from one very violent culture to less violent one, what are the continuities and differences?  How does VAWG transform and mutate? What role does migration and immigration status play in the violence experiences of women in London?  -Examining causal factors underpinning VAWG and the risk factors of living in Rio and London. To what extent are gender inequalities the root cause of VAWG and how do these play out transnationally? What role do structural factors that cause very high levels of VAWG and femicide in Rio transfer to the diaspora in London?  -Considering the main outcomes of VAWG in relation to health and well-being in Rio and London. To what extent does VAWG generate health inequalities and how does this influence their well-being transnationally?  -Mapping service provision for women who experience VAWG in Rio and London. To what extent are women survivors of violence needs met by service providers? What are the differences between Brazil and the UK and how can Brazil learn from and apply models of governance developed in London and vice-versa? Methodologically:  -Developing a predominantly qualitative methodological framework to examine VAWG that combines participatory appraisal, testimonies, service mapping, verbatim theatre and film as an effective way of understanding the lived realities of VAWG in Rio and London, treating participants as active agents.  -Sharing methodological tools across disciplinary and geographical borders with Brazil and the UK. How do innovative methodologies travel across these borders?  -Training in participatory appraisal and theatre methodologies, building capacity among civil society organisations and academic partners.  Policy Interventions:  -Devising effective policy tools to increase women and girls&apos; knowledge about their rights in relation to violence inside and outside the home  -Raising awareness of VAWG transnationally as a means to strengthen capacity, compare transnational experiences, promote alternative narratives and impact on public policy in both countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-17">152961.98</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
