<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_V034502_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF_NF178 Mobile Arts for Peace (MAP) at home: online psychosocial support through the arts in Rwanda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Research: To research the use of online arts-based methods to enhance psychosocial well-being and to provide mental health support.  2. Partnership working: To create a network between health organisations, cultural organisations and research and education organisations in order to best address some of the challenges faced by the coronavirus using an interdisciplinary approach.   3. Capacity-building: To create a child and youth friendly psychosocial module to promote resilience in school and out of school settings.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">During COVID-19 lockdown the Rwandan government initiated strict measures to prevent movement outside the home. Restrictions due to the pandemic increased risks of gender-based violence, teenage pregnancy and school drop-out. Previous studies reported that 26.1% of the population were estimated to have symptoms related to posttraumatic stress disorder (Munyandamutsa et al. 2009); whereas recent studies have reported similar prevalence (RMHS, 2018) and genocide survivor organizations have reported an increase in mental distress during the lockdown. Deteriorating economic conditions pose a significant risk to young people&apos;s mental health, which could be further entrenched should further waves of the pandemic occur. Specifically, within Rwanda, there are no current initiatives to provide psychosocial support at home (including referral systems for those in need of more specialist intervention) or building two-way communication and synergies between formal and informal education structures (i.e. schools and community-based groups) to enable learning and social networking during social distancing.   MAP at home examines the potential for providing mental health support and community engagement in Rwanda through interactive online platforms, participatory arts workshops, and communications between young people, educators, cultural artists and psychosocial workers across the five provinces of Rwanda: Rwamagana District (Eastern Province); Rubavu District (Western Province); Gicumbi District (Northern Province); Huye District (Southern Province); and Kicukiru District (Kigali Province). MAP at home will research the prevention of, response to and awareness of mental health and promotion of psychosocial well-being among youth, families, and community members through an innovative arts-based, culturally-informed approach, responsive to the needs of participants.   MAP at home will generate knowledge on how to reach, engage and equip young people and caregivers with tools for psychosocial wellbeing through the development of a psychosocial module, online and participatory workshops (subject to COVID-19 guidance and social distancing measures), and integration of psychosocial workers. MAP will partner with community-based mental health provider Uyisenga Ni Imanzi, research organisation Institute of Research and Dialogue for Peace (IRDP), national cultural organisation Rwanda Arts Council, and government mental health providers Rwanda Biomedical Centre/Mental Health Division and National Rehabilitation Services to coproduce the design, implementation and dissemination of research from a local to national level. UNESCO serves as a project partner to align national to international policy implementation concerning youth policy and mental health. The project will respond to the following research questions in relation to COVID-19:  *How can arts-based approaches be translated to online platforms to enhance psychosocial well-being? *What lessons can be learnt from the provision of online arts programmes for psychosocial well-being, especially regarding building resilience (individual and systemic) against future outbreaks or crises? *How might MAP at home advance digital innovation in the design and delivery of mental health provision and response services in Rwanda?</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-15">156188.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-15">313641.69</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">78094.14</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_V034502_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Lincoln</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
