<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_M026442_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton001 Temporal profiling of cardiac autonomic changes following organophosphorus poisoning</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organophosphorus (OP) compounds are the most widely used insecticides in many countries including Brazil, Egypt, India and USA. According to the latest reports, OP are responsible for the majority of poisonings, deaths and suicides attempts in Brazil. The latest Brazilian National System reporting on Toxico-Pharmacological Poisoning (SINITOX, 2009) indicated that the number of people poisoned by pesticides between 2001 and 2007 increased in 347% in a single State alone (Espirito Santo) compared to an equivalent period in previous years. This Brazilian State now has the second highest number of OP poisoning cases (5,512) within the south-east region of Brazil. OP compounds act by interfering with nerve cell communication by blocking an enzyme (acetyl cholinesterase). This leads to disruption of both the central and peripheral nervous systems. The effects on the heart, circulation and breathing by OP are likely to contribute in a major way to their lethality. Although clinical signs of OP poisoning are well described, our understanding of the precise mechanisms and their time course is highly limited and it this we wish to study. This is important because it would reveal the most effective therapeutic treatment relative to the time after OP poisoning. Following OP exposure, clinical symptoms are classified into 3 stages: (i) acute crisis syndrome within the first few hours; (ii) an intermediate stage between 12-96 hours and (iii) a delayed nervous system dysfunction stage. We wish to understand how the heart, circulation and respiratory symptoms occur within the first two stages of OP poisoning, and whether these are worsened in conditions of pre-existing heart failure. We propose that the deleterious effects of OP poisoning immediately affect the peripheral nervous system controlling the heart, circulation and respiration, worsen with time and are exaggerated if the subject has pre-existing heart failure.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organophosphorus poisoning (OP) is a major problem in the developing countries. We will provide a detailed understanding of the autonomic dysfunction that occurs after OP. Improved phenotyping and mechanistic insight of the clinical symptoms will optimize appropriate treatment strategies, which are urgently required.  Consolidate a collaboration between English and Brazilian research laboratories in order to exchange knowledge in different research fields and to facilitate training of young scientists through an exchange program.  Acquire equipment to set up a novel in situ experimental approach in Brazil that has been developed by the English partner. This will provide essential research infrastructure for understanding autonomic mechanisms of OP poisoning.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-05">10207.01</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-05">30621.03</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-05">816560.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Strategic Awards Award to University of Bristol</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_M026442_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FM026442%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-01-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
