<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T017988_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LOng-Term anatomical fluid dynamics for new Univentricular heartS palliation (LOTUS)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children with functionally univentricular hearts (UVH) have poor life prognosis, despite surgical treatment. This project aims to build an open-source combined Artificial Intelligence and Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) tool to determine &apos;optimal&apos; designs for the Fontan procedure to be used by surgeons, to enhance patient life expectancy (currently 20-30 years). Detailed imaging from UVH patients will be provided by USM to produce 3D geometries on which UK numerical models can be applied. USM currently treats 40-50 new UVH patients/year and 150 in follow-up, therefore they have a large databank covering a wide range of anatomical morphologies changing with patient growth and various palliative stages. This databank enables the construction of a novel mathematical model of how morphology/flow in later life depends on surgical procedure, with the prediction of the &apos;optimal&apos; surgical design minimizing the negative impact of the Fontan circulation. Combining high-fidelity curvilinear discretization, multiscale modelling, and machine learning, the CFD tool will reliably inform on long-term impact of surgical procedures, including a novel physiological Fontan procedure by the UK team. Expected outcomes.  1. Study of the long-term prognosis of subjects with complex congenital heart defects, specifically following all patients with UVH.  2. Consolidate partnership between Malaysia and UK teams, provide training to USM personnel introducing CFD tools for surgery optimisation.  3. Develop a patient-specific open-source computational tool to optimize surgical procedures in children with functionally UVH, for better long-term quality of life.  4. Combine artificial intelligence techniques with efficient and reliable multiscale CFD modelling based on recent polyhedral discretisations to predict long-term outcome of surgery.  5. We envisage that the project&apos;s tool will provide a new insight on the reason for the failure of UVH palliation.  6. The tool will also permit the validation of new Fontan procedures based on more physiological types of surgical connections, such as the one recently proposed and evaluated with CFD studies by the UK team.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 1. Classify, regress, and phenotype UHV morphologies in Malaysia database. Identify classes, age patterns, variances and commonalities across the population. Describe subject-specific aging of the UHV morphology through the subject&apos;s lifetime. Objective 2. Produce an open-source tool able to input patient-specific CT scan and MRI at age 1 (pre-Glenn) and investigate the performance of different surgical options (age, prosthesis, location of anastomoses, etc.) on the subject&apos;s vascular circulation. Objective 3: Develop new CFD tool based on new curvilinear numerical approach recently proposed at SMS to considerably reduce computational turnaround times and minimise user intervention. Objective 4: Obtain through-life performance estimates of UVH re-vascularization and perform multi-objective optimization; produce guidelines for the surgical decision-making process for through-life optimized outcomes. Objective 5: In depth analysis of a new &apos;physiological Fontan procedure&apos; aimed at long-term reduction of blood pressure of the single ventricle circulation. Objective 6: Dissemination of tools and training of Malaysia team.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">40135.41</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">120731.33</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">40460.54</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">8381976.512</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T017988_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FT017988%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
