<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R024502_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maternal Mortality in East Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives  This partnership will bring together researchers from the Arts and Humanities - history, historical and medical anthropology, linguistics, and theatre studies - with medical and public health specialists, in a collaborative attempt to better understand the interplay of sociocultural as well as clinical causes of high Maternal Mortality Ratios (MMRs). It will build on its existing supportive relationships with local hospitals, Kenya&apos;s Ministry of Health, Kenya&apos;s National Council for Population and Development, the Kenyan Medical Research Institute, a range of key NGOs including the INDEPTH network and the WHO, and local community groups.  Its key objectives are as follows: 1. To investigate why MMRs in East Africa have tended to stagnate since 2000, in contrast to the significant improvements seen in other key mortality markers. This partnership will focus on one local case study, the western Kenyan city of Kisumu and its hinterland, but seek to influence national and regional policy and practice. 2. To explain why institutional MMRs in East Africa improved so rapidly during the third quarter of the twentieth century, and then deteriorated. Research will investigate how these apparent declines in maternal health reflected shifts in policy, resourcing, and patient:provider relationships. 3. To examine why recent interventions, such as free maternity services and building referral hospitals, have had less impact in Kenya than anticipated. The partnership will consider why some interventions, which have proved effective in other contexts, have proven problematic within the Kenyan context. 4. To analyse and address the tensions which often characterise clinicians&apos; relationships with pregnant women. Research will focus specifically on issues of (mis)communication, and unintended consequences of policy changes. 5. To investigate gender and generational factors which shape risk perception and health-related decision-making around pregnancy within the household, peer-groups, and extended family. Researchers will utilize a range of methodologies, including participatory theatre, interviews and linguistic analysis.  6. To develop new interdisciplinary methodologies for research and the transmission of maternal health information. This partnership will bring together researchers from the Arts and Humanities - history, historical and medical anthropology, linguistics, and theatre studies  - with medical and public health specialists, and partners in the arts, in a collaborative attempt to better understand the sociocultural as well as clinical causes of high MMRs. 7. Through collaboration, to increase medical and public policy practitioners&apos; awareness of the distinctive value of arts and humanities approaches to recalcitrant healthcare problems; and increase arts and humanities&apos; scholars understanding of the complex challenges experienced by healthworkers in East Africa. 8. To further develop medical humanities within the East African region. The partnership is envisaged as a pilot study, designed to demonstrate the value of medical and arts and humanities collaboration within one particular geographical context. Through the involvement of leading clinicians, Ministry of Health policymakers, and NGOs, we hope to establish a regional consensus that maternal mortality can be effectively addressed through socio-cultural research. We also hope that the success of the Kisumu partnership would form solid foundations for future, larger funding applications.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This partnership brings together researchers from the Arts and Humanities - history, historical and medical anthropology, linguistics and theatre studies   - with medical and public health specialists, to address a key global health development challenge: extremely high Maternal Mortality Ratios (MMRs). It will focus on western Kenya, but seek to influence policy and practice across East Africa. While Kenya&apos;s crude death rate is now on a par with Europe, its MMR was 510/100,000 livebirths in 2015, 43 times higher than high-income regions. On current trajectories, Kenya, like most African countries, will not come close to the Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) MMR target of 70/100,000 by 2030. Our partnership seeks to develop new approaches to maternal health through interdisciplinary research and networking. Drawing on and further developing established relationships between East African and European arts and humanities and medical researchers, this medical humanities partnership will be based on the principles of international collaboration and co-production, motivated by the goal of reducing excessive maternal mortality. Our broader aim is to establish a regional consensus that socio-cultural research can effectively address major health problems.  That high MMRs are a particularly important, intractable health problem has been acknowledged both within the UK government, which has made working &apos;to end preventable child and maternal deaths&apos; one its seven aid priorities, and in Kenya&apos;s national plan (Kenya Vision 2030), which identified MMRs as one of two key areas &apos;where Kenya is lagging&apos;. Kenyan partners in government, medical institutions and key NGOs recognise high MMRs as a national priority, acknowledge that risk factors remain poorly understood, have informed the definition of problems which this partnership seeks to addressed, and are prepared to engage in research, policy development, and implementation. This partnership&apos;s approach has developed from medical researchers&apos; recognition that high MMRs result not only from physiological problems and infrastructural deficit, but also relate to patients&apos; experience of biomedical maternity services, domestic decision-making, social norms and collective understandings of motherhood, health and illness. Arts and Humanities researchers will work with medical practitioners, policymakers and teaching staff to consider in particular how, in both domestic and clinical settings, risk is evaluated, information is communicated, and resources are allocated.  Research will focus on the western Kenyan region around Kisumu, investigating why recent interventions, such as free maternity services and building referral hospitals, have had less impact in Kenya than anticipated. The partnership will consider why some interventions, effective in other countries, have proven problematic within the Kenyan context, and also compare Kenya&apos;s past successes in maternal healthcare with the relative stagnation of recent decades. Researchers will utilize a range of methodologies, including archival research, interviews, linguistic analysis and participatory theatre. They aim to better understand the tensions and miscommunication which often characterise clinicians&apos; relationships with pregnant women, and the unintended consequences of policy changes. They will also investigate the gender and generational factors which shape health-related decisionmaking within the household, peer-groups, and extended family.   Throughout, our partnership will be shaped by co-production with African academics, practitioners and institutions, building capacity in north the Global North and South. This will assist communication of findings to government, hospital administrations, citizens and NGOs such as INDEPTH, WHO, and Unicef. Outcomes will be shared with policymakers across the East African region, and a range of tools, music, radio and theatre will be used to communicate key messages across the Kisumu region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-01">154595.46</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF RCUK Award to University of Leeds</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/R024502/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">77297.73</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R024502_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">77297.73</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R024502_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FR024502%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
