<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_V003933_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Crafting Technology for Textiles</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of this project is to establish an interdisciplinary network that can tackle how to bridge between the heritage craft and 21st technology in textile making in Turkey. Thus, we began asking the question of how we can employ a &quot;thinking through making&quot; approach in textile practice fitted within the boundaries of technology. The project also aims to address:   (i) How can we reintroduce hand-craft and include this tremendous knowledge of artisans into the contemporary craft?  (ii) In the light of economic challenges confronting creative businesses, how twisting technology can help them to reach a wider community?  (iii) What hybrid skill sets and mindsets can they shape at the intersections of creativity and innovation?   To meet the objectives of the project, the following actions are planned:  (i):   - establish an interdisciplinary textile network in crafted technology  - map the recent understanding of tangible technologies and the technology perception in creative communities in Istanbul  In the scope of soft systems, this proposal aims to gather an interdisciplinary design network between UK-Turkey and explore a creative and sustainable future for craft-based textiles. The first stage of the project focuses on assembling a stakeholder group grounded in existing links that includes local textile artisans based in Istanbul, friends and consultants of Istanbul Modern, academics from Turkish institutions such as exhibition consultant Asli Kiyak Ingin from Bilgi University and researchers and visiting lecturers from the Royal College of Art, Crafts Council and their UK collaborators.  (ii):   - Identify the priority areas that can benefit from these technology interventions, and tailor the symposiums and workshops around the target audience.   - Assess the benefits and limitations of knowledge exchange in the context of a soft system and analyse the particular challenges around Istanbul.  As a continuation of this collaboration, the research team will explore the territory of craft-technology interactions through networking activities that will include demonstrations, collaborative workshops and studio visits. Two members from each partner country will form a steering committee and meet regularly for evaluation of research progress and to organise dissemination activities and networking meetings. This committee has a significant role in engaging with the public and targeted audience focused through workshops and seminars.  (iii):   - Understand the learning curve of apprenticeship and explore the strategies to integrate this knowledge in a new context.   - Test the idea of thinking through making at the technology-craft interface.   The process of traditional textile making understands the value of apprenticeships for generations. Today&apos;s textiles synchronise design and technology, embracing different practitioners&apos; perspectives and requires systematic exploration of conceptual inspirations and practical skills. We aim to facilitate a cross-pollinated environment for either college-educated or self-taught artists and designers and local artisans and enable collaborative creating spaces at the museum.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Throughout history, Istanbul has been a city where different communities have coexisted, and many languages, religions, and cultures have interacted with and influenced one another. Despite changes over time, the city is still home to a culture where, within craftsmanship, textiles are used in a variety of forms. The breadth of colour and thread types, designs, and motifs used in textile practice has transformed worldwide into a means of expression through which the stories of a particular culture are passed down from generation to generation. Quilting, carpet weaving, cloth stamping, embroidery, and point lace are just some of Turkey&apos;s many textile crafts. Passed down from master to apprentice, the various trades associated with these crafts are now slowly giving way to technology. In a project to be carried out by RCA and Istanbul Modern Museum, a network of scholars, artists, and craftspeople from Turkey and the United Kingdom will coalesce to move textiles, as used throughout crafts and art, closer to contemporary technology by creating avant-garde technology and design products. The project is aimed at academics, textile artists, designers and artisans based in Istanbul. Notably, we seek to reach the craftspeople working in the fields of traditional textile craft and art, and young communities of textile art and research, to focus on knowledge transfer and best practice. Hence, universities, arts institutions, craft guilds and associations will be linked through a series of workshops and panel discussions, with the project findings disseminated at a final symposium in Istanbul Modern. The proposed activities will support the economic development of the textile craft sector in Turkey, contributing to Istanbul&apos;s 2014-2020 Regional Plan targets by (i) introducing new textile-making skills (ii) gathering local and international qualified creative labour to Istanbul through the symposiums (iii) sharing textile research and development activities with young artists and designers and craftspeople to assist in increasing turnovers in their businesses. From the notion of bringing textile thinking in interdisciplinary practices, we will use this network as a platform to engage with a broader community and test our idea of joint research to launch long-term initiatives. Looking beyond the current state of the art, we will facilitate the sharing of experiences and expertise across different disciplines, which also includes material innovation, AI and technology start-ups. With a strong emphasis on the policy of future craft, we will explore strategies as to how these relationships might be framed to support new talents. By aspiring to make art easily accessible by the masses, and to initiate a conversation at the intersection of craft and technology, Istanbul Modern would be an excellent host to seed this hybrid design framework. Through this series of events, we aim to mutually transfer and share the experience of research and industrial relations to support the local artisans, artists and early career researchers working with textiles to reach a wider audience and discover new elements in crafted textiles. The outcomes of the proposed activities would promote the economic development and welfare of Turkey by (i) suggesting possible pathways and bringing new skills to increase the value of textile craft and goods by technology embodiment (ii) exampling successful models and knowledge transfer to reach the creative labour&apos;s full potential and meet international and national demands (iii) promoting interdisciplinary research in traditional craft to enter new sectors, which in turn will increase the export (iv) developing new infrastructure and free programmes in Istanbul Modern encouraging technology adaptation in art and design (v) initiating a dialogue for creation of local policy frameworks and discussing necessary policy measures based on successful models in the UK.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkey</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="EUROPE, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-29">36212.98</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
