<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T002956_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fostering Resilient Recovery in Displaced Communities via School-based Hubs</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project seeks to foster the resilient recovery of the poorest communities of Palu, Central Sulawesi, Indonesia, displaced by the 28th September 2018 earthquake and tsunami. During this disaster 184 000 pupils were affected by the damage or collapse of 12 000 schools in Palu and 164 000 people were displaced from their homes. These communities are highly vulnerable and marginalised from decisions made concerning their recovery and it is this marginalisation that this project seeks to address.  An interdisciplinary team of academics and NGO practitioners from the UK and Indonesia will co-develop an innovative intervention that targets psycho-social disaster support, hygiene and the safety of the physical environment, and which centres on schools as hubs for fostering community empowerment. Schools play a major part in shaping future generations and thus a community&apos;s future. Safer school can save the lives of children in future disasters; they can serve as a temporary shelters; and help to bring normalcy back to society in times of disaster, thus increasing community resilience.  This multi-pronged intervention will recreate not just the former status quo for these displaced communities but a more resilient future in which their needs and aspirations are put centre stage, and in which their wellbeing is fostered. The intervention will be created via three work packages: one targeting the psycho-social aspect, one for the water and sanitation hygiene aspect and one for structural infrastructure. The intervention involves four sets of stakeholders: pupils, their caregivers, their teachers and the contractors who build schools. It takes place over three sites in the poorest, most devastated parts of Palu. In order to devise a survivor-centred intervention an assessment phase will take place first. The goal will be to assess the aspirations and needs of these survivors - psycho-social, hygiene services-related and infrastructural - in order to devise and implement an intervention that will foster their recovery and simultaneously empower them to make decisions around their future disaster resilience.  Through this work we aim to establish a sound evidence-base for what works to improve the capacity of disaster-displaced people, and develop tools and education material to foster dialogue concerning disaster resilience and safer schools. The project builds the research capacity of two Indonesian Universities, and the collected evidence will enable them to further their mission of influencing the Indonesian Ministry of Education to implement an effective, compulsory disaster recovery and preparedness program in all Indonesian schools. No such program has been implemented yet, though our Indonesian team are at the forefront of devising this. The interdisciplinary evidence base that emerges from the proposed project will ensure that this disaster recovery and preparedness program, and others in different regions of the world that target similar contexts, are based on sound scientific evidence and knowledge of local contexts gleaned from survivors themselves. The research involves close collaboration with the Humanitarian sector, and so the proposed research will not only produce traditional academic output but also practice-based reports and guidelines, which will be developed with the aim of improving the efficiency of future disaster response and resilient recovery programs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This research is formed on the basis of a partnership between UCL&apos;s EPICentre (Earthquake and People Interaction Centre), UCL&apos;s EFID Centre (Engineering for International Development), Syiah Kuala University&apos;s Tsunami and Disaster Mitigation Research Centre (TDMRC), Tadulako University in Palu and Save the Children/Save Indonesia. The project combines research methodologies from psychology, social science, and environmental, structural and infrastructure engineering. This is highly innovative, and reflects the interdisciplinarity needed to aid post-disaster recovery. Resilient recovery requires community and family wellbeing, functioning services and safe structures and it is these that the proposed project addresses. It has the goal of fostering the resilient recovery of the displaced communities in the poorest parts of Palu, where an earthquake and tsunami in September 2018 displaced 164 000 people and damaged/destroyed 12 000 schools. The project aims to develop evidence-based, multi-pronged interventions for fostering resilient recovery in the marginalised, disaster-displaced communities of Palu via school-based hubs. The overall goal of the proposed project is to assess the psycho-social, environmental (water and sanitation hygiene (WASH)) and physical causes for most children in the marginalised regions of Palu remaining outside of full-time education and to then intervene, at the psycho-social, environmental and physical levels to create a more resilient future for them. The project will achieve this goal through the delivery of the following objectives: Assessment phase -To gauge pupil, caregiver and teacher priorities in three marginalised communities -To assess the environmental needs and aspirations of local communities concerning access to basic services, such as WASH, to aid resilient recovery processes  -To assess the physical and social impact of earthquakes, tsunami and ground failure on school buildings through purpose-developed fragility and vulnerability models; validating these against observations from the September 2018 Sulawesi event and other recent Indonesian earthquakes Intervention phase -To intervene to increase empowerment of the community and foster resilient recovery via disaster preparedness programs  -To develop a locally appropriate set of interventions for improved access to WASH through engagement with local communities, teachers, contractors and governmental stakeholders -To propose a set of locally appropriate approaches for intervening on both damaged and undamaged schools in Palu, for their improved future disaster resilience. -To disseminate a culture of safer and resilient communities through safer schools by training local engineers  -To develop datasets and practical tools (e.g., mobile app) for multi-hazard risk assessment and resilience enhancement and demonstrate their capabilities in the case-study of Palu Overall -To foster new partnerships between UK and Indonesian researchers and practitioners to investigate equitable resilience challenges and define research and innovation gaps for future joint work The research aims to contribute to the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) of &apos;ensuring inclusive and equitable quality educational opportunities for all&apos; (SDG4), &apos;making human settlements inclusive, safe, resilient and sustainable&apos; (SDG11) and providing access to basic WASH services to all (SDG6). The research findings will be disseminated widely, in academic journals and practice-oriented reports and guidelines. In this way the project aims to influence future recovery assistance delivery by NGOs, who are a further targeted beneficiary. The project looks to provide a legacy in Indonesia beyond the end of the project in the form of 1. An educational curriculum for disaster risk reduction through TDMRC&apos;s strategic role as advisor to the Ministry of Education in Indonesia, and 2. A stronger research capacity in the field of disaster risk reduction</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-09">66706.76</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-09">215635.65</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-09">72851</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-09">135722.39</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-09">847270.512</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to University College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T002956_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FT002956%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
