<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N028376_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Understanding pharmacokinetic - pharmacodynamic determinants of outcome to inform dose optimisation for non-MDR TB re-treatment patients in Vietnam</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TB remains a major global public health problem burden, with 9.6 million new cases and 1.2 million deaths in 2014. Vietnam is ranked 12th among the 22 highest TB burden countries (TB). 140 new cases were reported per 100,000 population in 2014. National TB Control Programme data indicates that 6 months of first-line month therapy for new TB patients is not successful in 10% of cases (some patients are still unwell at the end, and others relapse after apparent cure). Only 20-30% of unsuccessful treatments can be attributed to major problems with antibiotic resistance, which requires specialist management. The remainder go on to receive a standard &quot;Category 2&quot; treatment regimen, which is internationally approved but has not been carefully studied. Unfortunately, re-treatment patients on this regimen do not always do well; in Vietnam, the Category 2 regimen results in only 60-75% treatment success.  The reason why patients may fail two rounds of treatment is not well understood.  One reason could be that the levels of drug in the body (a study known as pharmacokinetics) of some patients is too low to kill the infection.  This problem could also be worsened by the fact that the drug levels required to kill the bacteria causing TB (known as Mycobacterium tuberculosis) are not the same in every patient i.e. some patients are infected with a strain of the M. tuberculosis bacteria which can survive higher concentrations of drugs than others.  In this project we will focus on the retreatment patient group to determine whether clinical outcome can be explained by measuring individual patient drug levels and carefully studying the ability of TB drugs to kill M tuberculosis. The project will use advanced analytical techniques to measure drug level in patient&apos;s blood samples and a number of new laboratory techniques to study how well the drugs kill each M. tuberculosis strain.  All of this information will then be combined and analysed using mathematical models to; (i) determine whether the laboratory/analytical measurements can explain the low treatment success rates and (ii) determine whether this information can be used in the future to improve treatment by predicting bad outcomes at an early stage and recommending a better drug course.  Data obtained from this study will be shared with other researchers working on TB around the world and will contribute to the wider discussion on tackling TB by designing better treatment.  Significantly, this project aims to also increase the local capacity for advanced studies of this type by providing training and mentoring to our Vietnamese colleagues in all of the methodological areas described.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-04-04"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-03" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="VN" type="VIET NAM"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-06-28">121018.14</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-06-28">162311.22</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-06-28">81635.02</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Despite recent advances in global tuberculosis (TB) control, mortality remains high with 1.2 million TB deaths in 2014. First-line treatment of new TB patients was established after rigorous clinical trials and is successful in 90% of Vietnamese patients. 20-30% of those who fail an initial course of therapy, or relapse after apparent cure, have multi-drug resistant (MDR) TB and are referred for specialist management. However, optimal management of the remaining 70-80% of re-treatment patients is unclear. In many countries, including Vietnam, TB-retreatment is provided using a World Health Organisation (WHO) approved Category 2 regimen. This approach has never been systematically trialled and outcomes are mixed. In Vietnam, Category 2 treatment success is only 60-75%. A focussed assessment of the Category 2 regimen is long overdue.       Amongst the factors which determine TB treatment outcomes are pharmacokinetic (PK) measures of systemic antibiotic exposure and pharmacodynamic (PD) parameters describing how effectively TB therapy kills infecting M tuberculosis organisms. Prior PK/PD studies in   new TB patients from a range of global settings have described 10-fold variability in maximum plasma concentration (Cmax) and area under the concentration-time curve (AUC) measurements for first-line anti-TB drugs. It has been proposed that low antibiotic exposure contributes to failure/relapse. However, no such studies have been performed in re-treatment patients who are often more physiologically unwell and may be prone to even greater PK variability. Re-treatment patients are also infected with &quot;antibiotic experienced&quot; bacillary populations - even in the absence of confirmed drug resistance, their PD responses are likely to be different.   In this study we will use PK/PD covariate modelling to investigate factors specifically related to poor treatment outcomes in non-MDR pulmonary TB patients on the Category 2 regimen. Some of the PD tools used will exploit a novel high-content imaging platform specifically developed at the Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine to assess killing of intracellular bacteria. These innovative PD assays may be important because antibiotic-tolerant intracellular bacteria could be a key driver of poor clinical response to therapy.  Our analyses will seek to develop dose optimisation strategies for future clinical trial evaluations. Specific objectives are as follows;  Primary objective: To determine whether PK/PD parameters describing inadequate drug exposure of first-line anti-TB drugs can explain or predict treatment failure/relapse amongst non-MDR pulmonary TB re-treatment patients in Vietnam.  Secondary objective: To establish whether there are cohort-level differences in PK/PD parameters between new and re-treatment patients from the same overall population, providing additional insight into whether these factors contribute to higher rates of failure/relapse outcomes in the re-treatment group.  Exploratory objective: To use the data from the primary and secondary objectives to build PK/PD models which will set target parameters for success in the re-treatment regimen.  Expected outcomes: On completion of the study we anticipate being able to use PK and PD variation to predict treatment failure/relapse and to recommend dose optimisation strategies for clinical trial evaluation in non-MDR pulmonary TB re-treatment patients. Progress towards more evidence-based management of this vulnerable group will be a significant advance."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
