<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024548_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evaluation of a novel microbiological diagnostic test for latent tuberculosis infection in Ethiopia (Micro-LTBI)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tuberculosis (TB) is a bacterial infectious disease. It causes 1.5 million deaths each year, 95% of which occur in low- and middle-income countries (LMICs). The disease particularly affects young adults, with adverse consequences for economic growth. In many LMICs, this problem is compounded by the problem of TB in cattle (bovine TB). This &apos;double-hit&apos; is a particular problem in Ethiopia, which has the tenth highest burden of human TB in the world: bovine TB is widespread (prevalence 5-30%) and the country&apos;s economy is highly dependent on cattle farming. Improved TB control in humans and cattle would significantly enhance economic growth and welfare in Ethiopia and other similarly-burdened LMICs.  Most TB cases in humans arise when a dormant TB infection re-activates to cause disease. Dormant TB infection is very common in LMICs and this pool of infection will need to be treated if TB is ever going to be eliminated. Antibiotic treatment for dormant TB infection is effective, but roll-out of this treatment is limited by the lack of an accurate &apos;gold standard&apos; diagnostic test for the condition. Existing tests for dormant TB infection rely on detecting an immune response to the bacteria, rather than detecting the bacteria itself. However, less than 10% of those with a positive immune test ever go on to develop active TB. This makes it difficult to target antibiotic treatment for dormant TB infection at the people who will benefit from it.  This situation could be about to change: very recently, a team of researchers in Germany (one of whom is a co-applicant on this grant) has reported that they have been able to detect TB bacteria in the blood of people with dormant TB infection. The number of bacteria is very small, and quite a large amount of blood (100 ml) is needed in order to detect them reliably. This remarkable finding has been made in just seven people living in Europe. The next step is to run the new test in a larger group of people who live in a country where TB is widespread. To take this idea forward, we have forged a new collaboration between Ethiopian and British scientists who together have the exact combination of clinical and technical skills needed to evaluate this new test.  We will carry out the following studies. First, we will recruit 200 healthy people who have recently been in contact with an infectious case of TB (&apos;TB contacts&apos;) - 100 urban residents of Addis Ababa who have been exposed to a person with infectious lung TB living in their home, and 100 rural cattle herders who have been exposed to a cow suffering from bovine TB. We will run the new blood test in these TB contacts, and, where we find dormant TB bacteria in the blood stream, we will do genetic fingerprinting to see if the dormant bacteria found in the bloodstream are identical to those isolated from the case of infectious TB (human or bovine) to which they were exposed. If the genetic fingerprints of the TB bacteria are the same, this will suggest that detection of TB bacteria in the blood of people with dormant TB infection is very unlikely to be a &apos;chance finding&apos;.  We will also recruit 40 people who are about to start antibiotic treatment for dormant TB infection, and run the new test before and after treatment. If we find that the antibiotic treatment clears dormant TB bacteria from the blood stream, this would suggest an additional potential application for the new test: monitoring response to antibiotic treatment of dormant TB infection. This is important, because existing tests cannot tell if antibiotic treatment for dormant TB infection has been effective or not.  Taken together, these studies will give us a clear idea as to whether the findings of the German team can be reproduced in a LMIC setting. If so, then we will apply for further funding to optimise the test to use smaller blood volumes, and conduct definitive studies to evaluate whether it could be integrated into existing TB control programmes in LMICs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="ET" type="ETHIOPIA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1027</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-09">191409.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-09">144720.27</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="We will conduct two cross-sectional studies (n=100 each) and a prospective study (n=40) to evaluate a novel microbiological test for latent tuberculosis (TB) infection in Ethiopia. This test utilises quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR) to detect DNA of Mycobacterium tuberculosis complex (MTBC) in CD34+ long-term repopulating pluripotent haematopoietic stem cells isolated from 100 ml peripheral blood. Our objectives are:  a) To determine whether MTBC DNA is consistently detectable in CD34+ peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC) of Interferon-Gamma Release Assay (IGRA)-positive healthy TB contacts living in Ethiopia, using qRT-PCR;  b) To determine whether MTBC DNA is undetectable by qRT-PCR in CD34+ PBMC of IGRA-negative TB contacts;  c) To identify the clinical and epidemiological correlates of a positive result with the new qRT-PCR test for latent TB infection in the same population of TB contacts;  d) To determine whether MTBC strains isolated from the site of disease in human and bovine index cases of active TB are genetically identical to those detected by qRT-PCR in CD34+ PBMC of associated contacts; and   e) To determine whether a 6-month course of isoniazid (chemoprophylaxis) renders MTBC DNA undetectable in CD34+ PBMC of adults who were qRT-PCR-positive at baseline.  These objectives will be achieved by conducting the following work:  - Writing the study protocol and securing approval from Research Ethics Committees in Ethiopia and the UK to conduct the study  - Identifying human and bovine index cases of active TB, and culturing and sequencing MTBC isolates from them  - Enrolling a total of 200 healthy adult contacts of these index cases (100 contacts of human index cases, 100 contacts of bovine index cases) into cross-sectional studies, and performing the novel qRT-PCR test on CD34+ PBMC as well as a commercial IGRA (QuantiFERON-TB Gold Plus).  - Enrolling a cohort of 40 IGRA-positive HIV-infected adults into a prospective study, and performing the novel qRT-PCR test before and after completion of a 6-month course of isoniazid chemoprophylaxis.  - Conducting statistical analyses to compare results of the new qRT-PCR test vs. IGRA (2x2 tables, cross-sectional studies); to identify clinical and epidemiological correlates of qRT-PCR-positivity (logistic regression, cross-sectional studies); and to determine the effect of chemoprophylaxis on results of the new qRT-PCR test (analysis of paired proportions, prospective study).  - Writing-up, publishing and disseminating study findings to the scientific community, participants and their communities.  If results show promise, we will apply for major funding from MRC Response Mode schemes to operationalise the assay for large-scale use in low- and middle-income countries, explore pathways of TB transmission between humans and cattle, and evaluate the predictive value of this test for progression from latent TB infection to active TB.  In summary, our study precisely fulfills GCRF Foundation Award criteria: it is a &apos;One Health&apos; study that will rapidly inform a go/no-go decision regarding the utility of a novel microbiological test for LTBI that could revolutionise global TB control."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">47852.4933333333</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024548_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">71778.7333333333</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024548_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">71778.7333333333</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024548_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">47852.4933333333</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024548_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">60300.1133333333</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024548_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">60300.1133333333</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024548_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">60300.1133333333</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024548_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">60300.1366666667</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024548_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
