<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S005900_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Creativity for Peace Festival: Creative Methodologies for Unearthing Hidden War Stories</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our Peace Festival project (PF) identified outstanding groups and initiatives that amplify the voices of marginalized peoples that challenge official histories in Peru and Colombia. It successfully facilitated the gathering of peace activists from these groups in Cartagena de Indias, Colombia, to discuss and produce art about the ways they use creative methodologies to tell stories about conflict and violence, their methodological challenges and possibilities, and the alternative narratives that subvert established accounts. Such creative spaces for dialogue and reflection contribute effectively to inclusive democracy and sustainable peace.  We produced a multi-authored article on the theoretical and methodological lessons of this novel approach to working with peace activists, currently under review for publication. A second paper, examining the achievements of creative methodologies, was presented at the Latin American Studies Association congress in Barcelona, May 2018.  In the follow-up Creativity for Peace Festival, we plan to expand the creative spaces further across academia and activist communities, building on three key insights of the original PF for other co-production initiatives across academic disciplines and with community based organisations: 1) That sharing and co-producing knowledge is enhanced by the embodiment created by active engagement with emotions. 2) There is a creative force inherent in embracing participants&apos; own goals and strategies. 3) Tensions between participants around process and goals, once acknowledged, can be productive; these tensions can serve as a common act producing a collective focus on creating an affective community.  The Creativity for Peace Festival responds to participants&apos; calls in the original PF to explicitly incorporate these lessons and bring in new participants with distinctive experiences of conflict and peacebuilding. Thus, participants working to effect change expressed the necessity of broader spaces for dialogue, exchange, and reflection to produce actionable knowledge and creative know-how that reinvigorates their practices given the complex realities in which they operate. They also stressed the need to find ways to connect with other actors in networks of solidarity and knowledge that create synergies to increase their impact. Thus, the follow-on Festival consolidates what was produced and opens new spaces for knowledge transfer and wider impact.   This project involves new participants from Cuba and Nicaragua to generate new pathways for collaborative engagement that greatly widen the impact of the original project. Including these two countries will further strengthen previous collaborative links with partner organisations, and build capacity for incorporating them into a research network for future projects.   The Creativity for Peace Festival builds on the findings of the first PF in order to achieve new and expanded impact with existing and new partners involved in peacebuilding efforts in Latin America. For this, we will: a) Organise and facilitate the Creativity for Peace Festival as a four-day event with activists from the four countries, apply the fine-tuned methodology and create a space for exchange in-situ with community-based experiences in Cuba. b)  Re-connect with existing groups and initiatives (Peru/Colombia) and accompany their process of reflection on lessons and changes to produce materials to be shared in the Festival. Connect with new initiatives invited to the Festival (Nicaragua/Cuba). c) Facilitate the building of a trans-national network of knowledge production, exchange and transfer between participants, non-academic and academic actors. d) Design publicly accessible material detailing how to use the lessons and findings from the original project. e) Co-produce artefacts and a short-film with participants during the Festival that will be made available in a public exhibition in UK and deposited in an open-access archive.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The AHRC GCRF Peace Festival project (2016-17), dedicated to capacity-building and network-formation amongst activist groups, had three broad outcomes:  a)  it transformed activist practices into actionable knowledge for community-building and memory-making in post-conflict Peru and Colombia, b)  it documented the dialogic space into a short film, where participants shared the work carried and its potential https://goo.gl/2uHKnz c)  it created a body of methodological interventions and practices that can be applied to other contexts, particularly ODA contexts.   The three outcomes work effectively towards the UN Sustainable Development Goals on promoting peaceful and inclusive societies, and meet the stated ambitions of the Global Challenges Research Fund. The purpose of the follow-on funding is to take this successful example of co-production to new contexts, particularly Central America and the Caribbean, to expand on the explanatory power and the applicability of the methodology for peace work, while generating and disseminating new pathways for academic research partnerships with activists groups that promote meaningful change.    The Creativity for Peace Festival involves existing participants in Peru and Colombia, and new ones in Cuba and Nicaragua. The partner organisation in Cuba, Centro Martin Luther King, internationally recognized for working with popular education methodology, has played a critical role in the negotiations between the Colombian government and FARC in Havana that resulted in the Peace Agreements. The organisations in Nicaragua have experience with community-based initiatives to respond to the ongoing political conflict and its escalating violence.   The aim of this project is to contribute to sustainable, inclusive peace and reconciliation processes in divided societies in Latin America. It supports and further creates space for the voices and memory projects of marginalised groups within national transitional justice initiatives, and within wider everyday processes of post-conflict transition and social change.  The specific objectives are:  1. Capacity-building of partner organisations and participant initiatives through their involvement in the project and during the Festival&apos;s main event. This will further strengthen their work by learning new methods, sharing their experiences, and engaging in the co-production of knowledge based on reflective practices.  2. Network-building: through the sense of community that is constructed in the Festival we plan to focus our work on re-energising participants&apos; practice, and strengthening connections and horizontal links between participants in order to cultivate the development of networks of solidarity and knowledge exchange for conflict transformation and peace-building.  3. Knowledge exchange and transfer: building from our previous project which was based on horizontal and reciprocal relationships, our purpose here is to go beyond the space for knowledge co-production by complementing it with new methods to make that knowledge available to the protagonists (participants in the previous project), new actors during the Festival (invited participants) and afterwards (public exhibit, participants&apos; networks, media outlets).</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-20">86590.95</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">86590.95</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S005900_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">-6658.44</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S005900_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
