<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_S001883_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia River Stories:improving socio-environmental understandings for building sustainable peace</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia has experienced one of the most protracted civil conflicts in the world. Despite the 2016 peace agreement between the Government and the FARC-EP, conflict in Choco&apos;, Colombia&apos;s poorest region, has worsened (UMAIC, 2017). To understand why conflict persists in Choco&apos;, and the possibilities for sustainable peace, it is necessary to consider the central role that Choco&apos;&apos;s rivers play. Rivers not only offer substantive benefits to Choco&apos;&apos;s communities (e.g. transport, food), they are also woven into their cultural identifies and livelihoods. It is generally acknowledged that the illegal exploitation of rivers by armed actors through alluvial gold mining, and the impact this has on communities&apos; cultural identify and sustainable livelihoods, is a primary factor that fuels the wider conflict ecosystem. However, it is a factor that has received little attention and that remains poorly understood. This project will address this knowledge gap. It will deliver fresh understandings of the interrelations between illicit mining activity, the natural environment and conflict and violence in Choco&apos; by answering two research questions: RQ1: Who / what are the actors and drivers of conflict in Choco&apos; and how have they developed with respect to alluvial gold mining? RQ2: To what extent can integrated &apos;river stories&apos;, including perspectives of communities and the river itself, inform more inclusive strategies for building sustainable peace? Our approach is founded upon peace and reconciliation processes around the world that foreground the telling and curation of testimony and stories as central to revealing how complex conflict ecosystems function and where interventions can maximise opportunities for peace. Stories enable different conflict actors to explain their actions to one-another and support a collective transition from narrow understandings of conflict, and the interrelationships that sustain it, to more expansive and inclusive ones through which roadmaps to sustainable peace can ultimately be plotted. They allow the voices of marginalised and silenced groups to be heard. This is crucial for building an inclusive peace. However, the agency of Choco&apos;&apos;s rivers in relation to the conflict means that the river&apos;s stories must also be voiced and articulated alongside those of human actors. This necessitates a novel, transdisciplinary coalition of researchers and methods from the social and natural sciences that combine Latin American traditions of community co-production and popular education with scientific methods for environmental reconstruction and monitoring. To this end, the project&apos;s work packages are constructed around three core objectives: Obj 1 (WP1): To deliver an integrated &apos;river story&apos; from multiple perspectives, across both time and space, that will be used to inform communities&apos; priorities and strategies for sustainable peace. Obj 2 (WP2): To capture and analyse the interrelationships and feedbacks between river system form and function, alluvial gold mining, and conflict in Choco&apos;. Obj 3 (WP3): To co-design and produce curated river stories that can be told to local, national and international audiences to inform more inclusive and sustainable strategies for peace.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia is in the process of transitioning from one of the most protracted civil conflicts in the world to peace. However, one of the major societal issues for post-conflict transitions in Colombia is how to ensure the inclusion and participation of vulnerable and marginalised groups in transition processes so that their knowledges, abilities and capacities are represented, and so that they can influence post-conflict development. This raises questions of how innovative community- engaged and participatory processes can achieve greater inclusivity in peace building processes. It also raises the question of how different conflict actors can be encouraged and facilitated to articulate their knowledge and experience of conflict in ways that enable their actions to be explained to one another, and that support a shift from narrow understandings of the causes of conflict based on personal experience to more expansive understandings that are based on collective experiences. In this research, we focus on riverine communities along the Atrato River - the main artery of Choco. These communities have been deeply impacted by armed actors who are engaged in widespread, illegal alluvial gold mining which is a key factor in their forced displacement and the loss of traditional, sustainable livelihoods. Despite a 2017 Colombian Constitutional Court ruling to empower riverine communities with &apos;bio-cultural rights&apos; that protect their land title and livelihoods, they remain marginalised. They struggle to make their voices heard and to influence and inform peace building processes. This marginalisation has also been experienced by the river itself, whose voice has been silenced through the abandonment of state-sponsored environmental monitoring programmes at the height of the conflict. As a result, the effects of conflict and alluvial mining on the form and function of the river, and the impacts of these on interactions between armed actors, the river, and the communities it sustains are poorly understood. This will only be addressed if marginalised voices of communities and the river are articulated and amplified so that their knowledges, abilities and capacities can be integrated into sustainable peace building processes. Achieving this is the primary aim of this project. Conceptually, our project builds on a key emphasis of peace processes worldwide: the capture and re-telling of testimony so that conflict actors can better appreciate the complexities of the conflict in which they are engaged, and the inter-relationships and feedbacks between their actions, and those of others, which fuel the conflict. Such knowledge is a fundamental precursor to the development of sustainable and feasible strategies for peace. The project is structured and designed to elicit, analyse and co-produce testimonies as an integrated &apos;river story&apos;, sourced from multiple participants and perspectives - including marginalised human actors and the river itself. The project therefore uses an innovative and multi- disciplinary methodology that brings social scientists and natural scientists together - integrating their research methods and techniques to capture human stories through community-level, participatory research and the river&apos;s story through field- based scientific monitoring and environmental reconstruction and mapping. The story books that are produced, and the policy briefs that they underpin, will be the vehicles through which policy-makers are bought into dialogue with the marginalised voices of both riverine communities and the river itself, and thorough which they improved understandings of the key actors and drivers of conflict in Choco&apos; and the priorities and strategies for sustainable peace building, will be gained.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-13" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-18">117711.73</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-18">170501.06</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-18">32630.93</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
