<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023005_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rational Design, Synthesis and Biological Evaluation of Benzimidazoles; Towards a Novel Therapy Selectively Targeting C. neoformans beta-tubulin</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cryptococcus neoformans (C. neoformans) is a fungus that is a common cause of lethal meningoencephalitis. In sub-Saharan Africa C. neoformans causes more deaths annually than TB, is the most common cause of systemic mycosis in patients with AIDS and an estimated 1 million cases of cryptococcal meningoencephalitis occur worldwide each year. First line treatment for C. neoformans is a 2 week course of amphotericin B (associated with anaemia, infusional toxicity and nephrotoxicity) and 5-flucytosine (associated with hepatic and renal toxicity) followed by a long term course of fluconazole (is fungistatic and resistance seen). The significant limitations of current agents highlights the need for the development of new orally bioavailable anti-cryptococcal agents with reduced toxicity and improved efficacy.  The objective of this proposal is to carry out the early stage drug discovery activities required to ultimately develop new agents for cryptococcal meningoencephalitis that can be used in sub-Saharan Africa. The longer term aim being to develop an agent that results in rapid fungicidal activity in the CNS. Providing a monotherapy that does not require subsequent long term treatment with fluconazole and that can be administered both orally and intravenously.    This will be achieved through the development of novel benzimidazole compounds which selectively target C. neoformans beta-tubulin. This is supported by:  - In vitro potency against C. neoformans - albendazole (MIC = 0.5 mg/L) and flubendazole (MIC = 0.125 mg/L). - Known mode of action - benzimidazoles disrupt mitosis by binding to the beta-tubulin subunit of microtubules.  - In vivo potency - Preliminary data indicates flubendazole is active against C. neoformans in a murine model of cryptococcal meningoencephalitis.  This objective will be achieved through completion of the following aims and activities:  Aim 1: Lead optimisation of the benzimidazole template for C. neoformans potency, selectivity for C. neoformans beta-tubulin and suitable DMPK properties.  - Each series of synthetic targets will be prioritised according to predicted DMPK properties. - Series F1 - F4 and A1 - A4 will be investigated to ascertain Structure Activity Relationships (SAR), improve solubility and reduce metabolic turnover (see case for support).  - Further compound synthesis will be guided by the data generated in Aim 2.  - In silico screening will be used to exploit the differences between the binding sites of the two beta-tubulin proteins identified through homology modelling.  Aim 2: Utilisation and development of in vitro assays to determine C. neoformans potency, selectivity for C. neoformans beta-tubulin and suitable DMPK properties.  - C. neoformans MIC measured for all compounds. - Development of beta-tubulin selectivity assays - A quantitative tubulin IC50 assay for both C. neoformans beta-tubulin and human beta-tubulin to establish selectivity. - In vitro DMPK assays - logD7.4, aqueous solubility, mouse and human microsomal clearance and plasma protein binding (outsourced). - In house BBB-PAMPA permeability assay and Caco-2 permeability.  Aim 3: Demonstrate that lead compounds have in-vivo activity and PK/PD relationship suitable for pre-clinical development.  - In vivo uninfected mouse PK - 5-10 compounds. - In vivo efficacy in C. neoformans mouse model - 2-5 compounds. - Full in vivo PK/PD profiling - 1-2 compounds - multi-dose PK/PD in infected mice, dose fractionation against 2 C. neoformans strains. - Safety - hERG and mini AMES - on the 1-2 compounds entering full profiling (outsourced). - Medicinal chemistry - Synthesis of compounds for in vivo studies.  Following successful completion of Aim 3 further funding will be sought to completed additional studies required for candidate selection and subsequent pre-clinical studies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Need:  Cryptococcus neoformans (C. neoformans) is a yeast like fungus which manifests as meningitis and less frequently pneumonia within the human body. In sub-Saharan Africa C. neoformans causes more deaths annually than tuberculosis. C. neoformans is the most common cause of fungal infection in patients with AIDS and there are an estimated 1 million cases of cryptococcal meningitis worldwide each year. The current drugs used to treat this disease are a 2 week course of amphotericin B and 5-flucytosine followed by a long term course of fluconazole. Amphotericin B  and 5-flucytosine are associated with toxicity and fluconazole suppresses the growth of the fungus but does not completely remove it from the body. There is a therefore a great need for new drugs to treat C. neoformans infections. These drugs must have less toxicity and work better against the disease. The aim of this proposal is to complete the early stage drug discovery activities required to ultimately develop new drugs for cryptococcal meningoencephalitis that can be used in sub-Saharan Africa.  The Concept:  It has previously been reported within scientific papers that a class of compound called the benzimidazoles (widely used to treat worm infections in humans and as fungicides in agriculture) have good activity against C. neoformans in a laboratory and this has subsequently been confirmed by work here at the University of Liverpool (UoL). Benzimidazoles have been shown to interfere with cell division in C. neoformans through binding to beta-tubulin. Beta-tubulin is a protein that is essential for cell division and growth, when benzimidazoles bind to beta-tubulin the fungal cell can no longer grow. More recently, unpublished studies carried out at UoL have shown flubendazole to be active against C. neoformans in the mouse model. Humans also have beta-tubulin so it is essential that any new drug developed against the beta-tubulin target is selective for C. neoformans beta-tubulin. Medicinal chemistry (modification of the chemical structure of a drug) can be used to improve both selectivity for beta-tubulin and activity against C. neoformans.  The Solution:  Identification of an active class of compound, against a known target, with established whole cell C. neoformans and animal model activity provides an excellent starting point for medicinal chemistry modification. To date benzimidazole compounds have never undergone medicinal chemistry optimisation to establish beta-tubulin selectivity or to improve C. neoformans activity. The two most commonly use benzimidazole drugs (Flubendazole and albendazole) are extensively metabolised within the body and have a limited ability to move from the stomach into the blood stream. New compounds will be designed using information from computer models to predict how they are likely to behave within the body.  In order to improve the safety profile of the newly designed compounds their selectivity for C. neoformans beta-tubulin over human beta-tubulin will be measured in the laboratory (alongside activity against C. neoformans) and computer models of the binding sites of the two tubulins used to look at how new compounds are likely to bind better with C. neoformans beta-tubulin. Once C. neoformans activity, selectivity for beta-tubulin and improved levels of circulating drug have been established the compounds will move into a mouse model of C. neoformans infection.   Impact:  The long term aim is to develop a single therapy that does not require subsequent long term treatment with fluconazole and that can be given both orally and by injection. Given the number of patients affected by C. neoformans this project has the potential to have a dramatic beneficial impact on individuals and societies.  Development:  Compounds demonstrating activity in the mouse model will form the basis of further funding applications to progress the new drugs through the drug development pipeline.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-04-21">102914.06</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-04-21">143800.8</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-04-21">143175.43</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-04-21">425518.97</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/N023005/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-07-01">33991.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023005_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-01">33991.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023005_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-01">34931.32</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023005_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-01">34931.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023005_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-01">36289.83</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023005_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-01">36289.83</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023005_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-01">36289.83</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023005_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-01">36289.81</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023005_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-01">35628.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023005_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">35628.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023005_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-01">35628.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023005_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">26851.59</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023005_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FN023005%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
