<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T029811_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">An inter-disciplinary approach to understanding the contribution of household flooring to disease burden in rural Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to adequate, safe and affordable housing plays a fundamental role in human health. This includes thorough limits our exposure to infectious diseases such as those that cause diarrhoea, which remains a leading cause of death in children under five. Conventional approaches to reducing environmental exposure to faecal pathogens include ensuring universal access to safe water and basic sanitation. Recent evidence has suggested that this alone may be insufficient to reduce the high levels of environmental contamination seen in poor rural communities, and that transformative cross-sectoral approaches will be required to see real impacts in child health. For example, these approaches fail to address the fact that most poor rural homes have rudimentary (earth, sand or dirt) floors that are difficult to sanitise, providing an ideal environment for the survival of faecal pathogens and other parasites. These floors can also host parasitic infections including intestinal nematodes and sand fleas, both of which are responsible for considerable morbidity and poor quality of life.   We propose to examine flooring and its impact on enteric and parasitic diseases in three culturally and environmentally diverse settings in Kenya, and aim to address two related questions:  1. What is the importance of household flooring as a driver of enteric and parasitic infection risk in rural communities, and does this vary across wider social and environmental contexts? 2. Can infection risk be mitigated by replacing existing rudimentary (earth, sand or dirt) floors with improved (sealed, washable and durable) materials, and what additional behaviour changes are required to ensure impact?  We expect that successful installation and ongoing maintenance of improved flooring will reduce the transmission of enteric and parasitic infections, by preventing direct exposure and through an intermediate effect of improved domestic hygiene. This will however be influenced by local context. A priority in each setting will therefore be to explore the interplay between domestic flooring, water and sanitation infrastructure, domestic hygiene behaviours, and the wider socio-cultural and environmental context.   Our planned approach involves comprehensive formative research, intervention development conducted in collaborative partnership with recipient communities and key stakeholders, and then implementation trials to test the effects, feasibility and acceptability of the resulting intervention. We will assess the impact of the intervention on a range of child health outcomes, including prevalence of enteric and intestinal worm infections, prevalence of tungiasis, and incidence of gastrointestinal illness. We will also monitor levels of environmental contamination, and explore the impact of the intervention on domestic routines and self-reported wellness. During implementation, we will work with recipients and stakeholders at community, regional and national level to assess the extent to which interventions are acceptable to target communities, feasible given existing resource constraints, and can be scaled-up across Kenya and elsewhere. This includes work undertaken to understand options for scale-up should the intervention prove successful.   This study is the first of its kind to comprehensively assess feasibility and effects of combining improved flooring technologies with tailored behaviour change programming on a wide range of parasitic and enteric outcomes. In doing so, we aim to provide important policy and technical guidance on the impact and effectiveness of new transformative approaches to community health. This is an important first step towards the establishment of transformative, community-driven and cross-sectoral approaches to building out water, sanitation and hygiene-related diseases.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed research will answer the question: do rudimentary (earth, sand or dirt) domestic floors play an important role in the transmission of infection in rural communities, and are there effective intervention strategies to mitigate this risk?  Our proposed trial would be the first study of its kind, providing an important step towards the establishment of transformative, community-driven, integrated approaches to environmental health.   Specific Objectives:  1. To determine the role played by rudimentary floors in the transmission of enteric pathogens, soil-transmitted helminths and tungiasis in rural Kenyan communities.  This includes describing how water and sanitation infrastructure, domestic hygiene behaviours, animal husbandry practices, and wider socio-cultural and environmental contexts, influence this relationship.  2. To develop and implement contextually relevant interventions to mitigate the effects of rudimentary flooring on infectious diseases in rural Kenya.  We envisage these will comprise replacing existing floors with an improved (sealed, washable and durable) floor, accompanied by a participant-informed behaviour change programme to promote floor cleaning and maintenance and improve associated domestic hygiene. Within this objective, we intend to: i) describe the roles of planned, motivated and reactive behaviours in relation to domestic hygiene and explore how these are influenced by wider socio-cultural and environmental contexts; ii) explore the structural, economic and household requirements and end-user preferences for low-cost improved flooring technology; iii) characterise the pathways through which socio-cultural and environmental contextual factors influence the final intervention design;  3. To evaluate the effect of the interventions on individual-level risk of enteric, STH and tungiasis infection, and explore how this varies with local context.  This will be conducted in three settings across Kenya, and includes to:  i) Assess changes in prevalence of enteric infections, STH and tungiasis, and the incidence of self-reported gastrointestinal illness in children; ii) Quantify changes in entero-pathogen and parasitic contamination levels in sleeping and communal resting areas; iii) Explore how intervention effects differ across community and household contexts (including WASH infrastructure, animal husbandry practices); iv) Assess additional health and quality of life changes, including subjective wellbeing, in both children and their caregivers; v) Characterise causal pathways linking intervention activities to health and behaviour outcomes, and explore the roles played by mediating contextual factors; vi) Assess the extent to which interventions are acceptable to target communities, feasible given existing resource constraints, and can be scaled-up across Kenya and elsewhere.  4. To translate research tools and findings at each stage, in dialogue with stakeholders, into high quality resources for key stakeholders and input for national guidance and policies. In line with our Pathway to Impact, we will actively engage with research beneficiaries and use a range of strategies to translate tools and findings into usable formats to maximise research uptake.  5. To promote inter-sectoral and cross-institutional collaboration and build capacity in behavioural science, molecular diagnostics, and the development and evaluation of complex interventions in Kenya.  As outlined in our Capacity Statement, we have established a number of mechanisms through which the proposed work will substantially contribute to scientific and programmatic capacity in Kenya, within collaborating and partner institutions and the wider stakeholder community.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-EDU-133903" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-02">335652.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-02">285664</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-02">670012.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-02">720000.26</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-02">2011328.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/T029811/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">167826.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T029811_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FT029811%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
