<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_N006801_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PAFiC: Precision Agriculture for Family-farms in China</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rapid advances in fertiliser use and other inputs to crops have dramatically improved Chinese crop production over recent decades, but this has not been done in a sustainable manner and it is estimated that &gt;10M t of synthetic nitrogen fertiliser is wasted annually in China. The number of small to medium-sized commercial family farms is increasing from a merging of smaller, non-commercial family plots. It is desirable to support these farms to maintain rural populations and economies. These family-farmers also need technological assistance to manage larger areas that they have no historical connection to.  Precision agriculture, allowing for fine-scale within-field management of crops based on detailed spatial data collection, has an essential role to play in increasing fertiliser and resource use efficiency on farms. This will increase production efficiency (profitability) as well as reduce the environmental footprint of agricultural practices linked to fertilizer use. However, in China there are fundamental barriers to uptake of precision agriculture methods and technology, including high costs relative to income and unquantified financial benefits, a lack of data and services and a lack of awareness and acceptance by growers, communities and administrative agencies.  This joint UK-China collaboration aims to improve the use efficiency of nutrients and agri-chemicals in crop production in China, by addressing key technological, agricultural and social or economic barriers to the use of precision agriculture methods in commercial family farms. The project will develop new technology and data sources for agricultural decision making, including the application of advanced hyperspectral cameras, able to measure many wavelengths of light and provide detailed information on crop health, and improved technology for precise spatial positioning within fields. Improved methods to utilise satellite imagery, especially from radar sensors systems, to provide accessible data on crop nutrient levels and growth will also be developed and the advantages of combining data from multiple sources (satellites, airborne sensors and ground monitoring) will be assessed. These improved data layers, providing frequent and detailed spatial information on crop growth, crop health and soils, will then be combined with models of crop growth to provide a system for agricultural decision making that is applicable to family farms in China. This will promote the optimal use of agricultural resources, such as fertiliser. Developed methods will be tested on exemplar farms in China, covering a range of geographic regions and crop systems that have been established in previous research projects. To facilitate both the maximum engagement from a diversity of community and industry members, and the maximum usage of the agri-technologies and precision agriculture methods by farmers, it is critical to incorporate both scientific and local (community and practitioner) expertise into the project. This is critical to understanding and addressing issues specific to these farming system. An integral aspect of the project is to therefore undertake focussed research on the societal and economic barriers to uptake and to use of these technologies. This research will identify and address these barriers via the mode of development and the delivery of the project outputs onto family-farms. This work will also form the basis for wide-reaching and effective public engagement, knowledge exchange and policy translation to ensure the latest methods are adopted in China. Activities will include the development of a data information portal for crop management, stakeholder workshops and technical training for local growers and agricultural specialists.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overarching goal for this project is to deliver precision agricultural services to Chinese  producers, particularly those that are managing commercial family farms. The focus will be on site-specific nutrient management services that tailor fertiliser inputs to crop requirements; however, the technologies, methodologies and delivery services proposed will be amenable to improved resource use efficiency for almost all agricultural inputs (e.g. agrichemicals, machinery and labour).  The proposal&apos;s specific objectives are as follows:  Objective 1: Refine existing and develop novel agri-technologies for deployment onto family farms in China. We will address the opportunities for low-cost high quality multi-GNSS positioning systems, hyperspectral imaging systems, multi-platform Synthetic Aperture Radar, and agri-diagnostic tools on Chinese farms.   Objective 2: Develop methodologies and decision systems for the deployment of agri-technologies on-farm and validate this using an existing network of exemplar production systems in China. This will focus on the delivery of effective digital soil information; the development of data integration protocols and the integration of geospatial information layers with agronomic decision systems.  Objective 3: Employ Responsible Research Innovation (RRI) and economic analysis to understand socio-economic barriers to agri-technologies and address these barriers via the mode of delivery of PA services in China. The results from this objective will direct the mode of development and translation of the technologies and methodologies from O1 and O2.   Objective 4: Engagement and Dissemination: A clear pathway for knowledge transfer and exchange and for engagement and delivery of research outcomes with all actors in Chinese agriculture from farmers to local and national policy-makers.  The three science-based objectives (O1-3) are interconnected and dependent on knowledge flow between objectives. Technology cannot be developed (O1) without knowing how it will be received and utilised (O3). Likewise, methodological advances (O2) depend on the available technological outputs (O1). O4 provides routes for engagement and dissemination internally among project partners as well as externally to stakeholders and potential end-users. O4 focuses on knowledge transfer and exchange (KTE) of research outcomes once completed. O3 differs from O4 in that it has a focus on understanding how technology is accepted in China and how it could be translated into commercial situations, i.e. how the research should be conducted so that the outputs can be successfully commercialised via KTE in O4.   Holistically, this program will investigate the socio-economic barriers to agri-technology adoption in China to inform the research directed at the development of new technologies and methodologies. This will then be extended through KTE approaches structured around industry, societal and governmental needs in China with the ultimate aim of delivering effective PA services, especially fertiliser services, to Chinese farmers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China (People&apos;s Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-10">454111.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-10">356930.22</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-10">379768.17</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
