<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_N009312_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt&apos;s Living Heritage: Community Engagement in Re-Creating the Past</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&apos;Egypt&apos;s Living Heritage: Community Engagement in Re-Creating the Past&apos; explores and promotes the engagement of local communities with their heritage through the deployment of the arts as particularly effective in the transmission of the values and meanings that intangibly inhere in tangible artifacts, architecture and environments. It selects as its case study the area of Historic Cairo, in tandem with the Urban Regeneration project for Historic Cairo (launched by UNESCO-WHC in 2010), in order to address the interface between past and present in multi-dimensional ways. The intellectual research is motivated by questions of what of the past continues in the present and of how the living transmission of the past is effected, as will be explored through workshops bringing together UK and Egyptian scholars and arts practitioners and through the screening of documentaries pertinent to this enquiry. Building on this basis, research by practice will involve communities in the curating of their own artisanal and creative products, together with the cultural memories and legacies attendant on these, through both oral history and specialist ateliers. Conventional approaches will be combined with more experimental methods as the working communities of Historic Cairo and contemporary visual artists, musicians and writers from Egypt and the UK will be brought together in order to create a forum for the sharing of skills and ideas towards, in the first instance, an exhibition, with the further aim of generating new forms of entrepreneurship leading to increased revenue opportunities. In addition, the psycho-geography of Cairo will be explored through the analysis of dreams in relation to Egyptian myths, folk tales and literature as will be disseminated through a short film. The project will serve to realize connections between the traditional and contemporary, between the popular culture of the past and the popular and youth cultures of the present, and between Egyptian cultural heritage and international recipients, with outputs including publications and an insiders&apos; heritage map. In the process of this range of activities, new cultural, social and intellectual networks will be formed towards the establishment of a new research centre and the ongoing preservation of heritage through community engagement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. To engage local communities with their heritage on a more profound and effective level with the deployment of art and literature as a means to highlight and convey heritage values and social meanings. This aim is to be realized in tandem with the following objectives.  2. To involve communities in the social construction and curating of their heritage for cultural preservation, social engagement and economic development, initially by means of oral history, skills workshops and research by practice towards an exhibition and insiders&apos; map. 3. To explore how modern and contemporary artists, intellectuals and writers deploy an understanding of &apos;the living past&apos; as widely definitive of Egyptian intangible heritage. 4. To forge a relationship between contemporary Egyptian artists, intellectuals and writers with local communities as a means of defining and promoting awareness of the specificity of Egyptian intangible heritage and as an under-utilized means of mutual knowledge and skills transfer.  5. To counter the alienation of communities from their past in exploring both the positive and negative impacts of marketing on the viability and integrity of Egyptian heritage.  The context for this is that when intangible heritage is relegated to a dead past by certain modernist discourses of &quot;heritage and development&quot;, associated marketing strategies use heritage assets not as elements of a living legacy and cultural capital for a better future, but as a source of revenues reliant on exoticism, nostalgia and antiquarian appeal that then determine the forms of souvenirs and curios. Given that the project will be implemented in one of the most heritage-renowned areas of Cairo, this constitutes a prime venue for the generation of vibrant new forms of entrepreneurship. 6. To raise the visibility of modern and contemporary Egyptian arts on the international scene, through exhibitions, concerts and the art market, to the economic benefit of the cultural sector, as well as to promote cultural and heritage tourism. 7. To provide a sustainable framework for collaboration between Egyptian and UK partners in a creative and inspiring context for educational purposes, allowing for equitable exchanges in order to enhance mutual intercultural understanding and mutual practical, professional support.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Kent</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-17" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="189" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-26">31273.27</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-26">31273.26</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC Newton Development Grants Award to University of Kent</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH/N009312/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Kent</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FN009312%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-02-12"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
