<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S015027_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving earlier diagnosis and precision medicine for reduced mortality of breast cancer in Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Data show breast cancer rates are rising in Kenya with scant molecular pathology studies performed. Mortality is high in Kenya compared to the UK and cancer registry data estimate that breast cancer is the second leading cause of cancer death-making it a significant public health problem and loss of economic productivity. Advances in genomic and molecular technologies have transformed our understanding of breast cancer and provide a way to more accurately classify cancers into similar distinct types based on their genetic characteristics. Breast cancer survival has improved significantly in the UK over the last 20 years, but in lower income countries such as Kenya, increasing survival remains a significant challenge likely through a combination of issues. A major barrier to reduce mortality in low and middle-income countries (LMICs), such as Kenya, are multifaceted. However, two major challenges are late stage at diagnosis and limited capacity for accurate molecular tumour subtyping of breast cancer to identify women who would most benefit from endocrine therapies (a form of precision  medicine). Hence, a multidisciplinary approach combining expertise in epidemiology, surgery, oncology, pathology, and molecular genetics, could provide new insights into the risk factors of the disease relevant to the Kenya population, as well as new avenues for combatting the high mortality in Kenya. The observation that tumours release DNA into circulating blood, provides a potential means for earlier and more accurate diagnosis of cancer in low and middle resource countries like Kenya. DNA from the tumour that gets in the blood stream could be used as a test to provide minimally invasive diagnosis of cancer. To design effective approaches to improve health-care, consistent with the MRC 2014-2019 strategic plan we aim to  1) Collect data to inform research priorities that are most likely to deliver improved health outcomes, through the use of molecular defined disease datasets including tumour tissues and blood samples; 2)Bring the benefits of excellent research to all sections of society, in collaboration with academic and other research partners; 3) Develop new innovations through the use of new health data-to improve and inform cancer control and treatment programs and enhance economic development in Kenya. This pump-priming award would allow for knowledge exchange and provide a foundation for improved molecular epidemiology studies that would inform development of improved surveillance, diagnostic and treatment paradigms for breast cancer in Kenya. Through this multinational consortium we envision this proposal to provide future opportunities to train and build capacity for molecularly defined health data collection in Kenya and more broadly other countries in sub-Saharan Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-11-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="KE" type="KENYA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1027</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-08">54375.58</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-08">81783.59</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Data from Globocan and the Nairobi Cancer Registry show breast cancer as the second most common cancer and a leading cause of cancer associated mortality--making it a significant contributor to loss of life and economic productivity for the Kenyan population. Breast cancer survival has improved significantly in high-resource settings such as the UK, but in lower income countries such as Kenya, about half of women diagnosed with breast cancer will die.  Like many diseases, breast cancer is a heterogeneous disease arising from different aetiological factors with varied clinical outcomes. For example, the finding of the oestrogen receptor (ER), a key molecular marker for responsiveness to anti-oestrogen therapy, provided a major breakthrough in breast cancer targeted treatment. There are many more molecular markers identified that can define different subgroups of tumours and their prevalence is poorly defined in the Kenya population. To design effective approaches to improve health-care, consistent with the MRC 2014-2019 strategic plan, this proposal aims to deliver improved health outcomes through the use of molecular defined disease datasets. Specifically we will build off a recently funded multidisciplinary research grant by the Kenya National Research Fund (NRF) by co-investigator Dr. F. Makokha and:  1) Develop a new partnership between the University of Edinburgh and Mount Kenya University. PI: Dr. J. Figueroa has over a decade of experience in molecular epidemiology and pathology studies of breast cancer, including conduct of a large multidisciplinary study in Ghana, west Africa (Brinton...Figueroa International Journal Cancer 2017) . 2) Design data collection pipelines for molecular pathology studies of breast cancer and mortality outcomes--which are desperately needed to inform what the key barriers and challenges are for breast cancer surveillance, diagnosis and treatment.  3) Exchange knowledge of contemporary molecular subtyping methods for breast cancer, and perform a pilot study to assess whether we can collect and quantify cell free DNA (cfDNA) tumour fraction at the time of breast cancer diagnosis and the relationships with clinics-pathological characteristics of breast cancer tumours for (N=100 cases)-for potential earlier diagnosis of breast cancer. 4) Using pilot data collected in this study, engage key stakeholders (e.g. physicians, ministry of health, policy makers) to prioritise the key areas needed for long term planning to enhance capacity to tackle the increasing burden of breast cancer in Kenya.  This proposal would begin to build the foundation and unique sample sets of breast cancer, which could be expanded on for future molecular epidemiology studies of breast cancer--allowing opportunities for building capacity and economic development in genomics, epidemiology and health data science for improved public health and treatment outcomes in Kenya."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">27187.79</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S015027_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">27187.79</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S015027_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">27187.79</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S015027_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">27187.79</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S015027_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">27408.01</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S015027_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
