<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S014551_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing a multiplex serology panel to detect and quantify Epstein-Barr virus infection</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) accounts for more than 200,000 cases of cancer each year and 1.8% of all cancer deaths are due to EBV-attributable malignancies including nasopharyngeal carcinoma (NPC) and gastric carcinoma which have higher incidence in low-middle-income-countries (LMICs), e.g. NPC in southern parts of china with &gt;25 times higher incidence than the rest of the world. However, the mechanisms of cancer causation by EBV remain an area of active investigation and controversy. Since the clinical symptoms of NPC are nonspecific and no known pre-cursors exist, diagnosis is often delayed until the advanced stages of disease when five-year survival is less than 50%, as opposed to 90% survival when NPC is identified at an early stage. To date, there are no specific effective treatments for EBV-associated diseases, thus identification of different biomarkers present in subsets of EBV-positive individuals to aid early detection of disease is particularly important. In addition to well-established biomarkers, ten more EBV antigens that best discriminated NPC status have recently been identified through protein microarray technology. However, the output from this technology does not directly translate to an exact amount of antibody circulating in the blood. The proposed study will develop and validate a panel capable of measuring and quantifying the amounts of EBV biomarkers, using a new technology that is high-throughput with low-cost and low volume of samples required. We also propose to use this panel in a pilot case-cohort study including 200 each of NPC, gastric cancer cases and population-based subcohort individuals in the well-established China Kadoorie Biobank (CKB) - a prospective study of 0.5 million individuals recruited at age 30-79 years from 10 diverse regions in rural and urban China, with stored blood samples. The aim of this pilot case-cohort study is to evaluate whether the EBV serology measured several years prior to disease diagnosis could be used to identify high-risk individuals and also to assess the association between EBV biomarkers, their joint relationships with other lifestyle and environmental risk factors and the risk of NPC and gastric cancer. Given the high throughput and low cost features of the technology together with preliminary data identifying high-risk populations provided by this research, this EBV panel may be suitable for large epidemiology studies which can comprehensively investigate EBV-related disease mechanisms; and could potentially be used for early detection/screening among high-risk individuals who experienced other lifestyle or environmental risk factors such as smoking or with a family history of cancer. It may then help to inform EBV-related disease prevention and control policy making by treating infection or vaccinating high-risk individuals, i.e. those infected with highly-disease-associated EBV biomarkers also with other lifestyle and environmental risk factors such as family history of cancer or smoking. The improved cancer prevention/control policy will benefit not only LMICs but also global populations. We will also compare the results with our ongoing project using a panel of 46- biomarkers which was initially designed for the UK population in which only 4 EBV biomarkers are included. It will provide us with more information about the seroprevalence for those disease related EBV biomarkers in a Chinese population. It will help us to design an improved infectious pathogens panel which is suitable for Chinese populations. The improved panel will be then used in our future studies of multiple infectious pathogens conducted in the entire CKB cohort, in order to understand how multiple infectious pathogens can cause different diseases, and will have benefits for disease prevention and control worldwide.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-11-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-08">49061.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-08">102109.35</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Background: Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) accounts for more than 200,000 cases of cancer each year including nasopharyngeal carcinoma (NPC) which has higher incidence in low-middle-income-countries (LMICs), such as North Africa and Southeast Asian, particularly in Southern China where there is &gt;25 times higher incidence than in West. However, the mechanisms of cancer causation by EBV remain controversial. Since symptoms are often nonspecific, and no existing pre-cursors and no selective treatments for EBV-associated diseases, diagnosis is often delayed until the advanced stages with low survival rates, e.g. &lt;50% survival rate for advanced NPC stage vs 90% for early stages. Identification of different biomarkers present in subsets of EBV-positive individuals to aid early detection of disease is particularly important. Twelve EBV antigens best predicting NPC risk have been identified by using protein microarray technology but the output cannot directly translate to an exact amount of circulating antibody.  Aims and methods: Based on the well-established China Kadoorie Biobank (CKB) prospective study that recruited &gt;0.5 million Chinese adults from ten diverse regions in China including two located in the NPC high-risk areas in south China, this proposed research aims to: 1) develop and validate a EBV-Monoplex panel including the 12 identified EBV biomarkers, based on high-throughput Luminex-based technology capable of measuring/quantifying the amounts of serum EBV biomarkers; 2) assess the role of EBV and the joint relationships of EBV antibodies and other lifestyle and environmental risk factors in NPC development and to predict the risk of NPC in a pilot case-cohort study including 200 verified NPC and 200 population-based subcohort individuals, by using the validated 12-EBV-Monoplex panel; 3) identify the most significant disease-related EBV biomarkers to be included in an improved CKB multiplex panel design, through comparing EBV antibody levels in the plasma of incident NPC, gastric cancer cases and subcohort participants that will be detected/quantified by both the 12-EBV-Monoplex panel and a 46-Multiplex panel (4 EBV antigens included) from an ongoing CKB project of infectious pathogens in gastrointestinal cancers.  Linear regression analysis will be used to assess the relationships of EBV antibodies with participants&apos; characteristics and the reproducibility and correlation for both the published EBV proteome array and the Luminex assay. Weighted Cox proportional hazards regression models will be used to calculate risk ratios, predict risk of NPC and to identify the most strongly disease-related EBV biomarkers, adjusting for potential confounders. The seroprevalence of EBV biomarkers measured in the 200 individual subcohort by both EBV-Monoplex and 46-Multiplex panels will be compared. Sensitivity, specificity and area under the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve will be used to evaluate the discriminatory ability of the model. How results will be used: Given the high-throughput, low cost and low sample volume required, the Luminex-based EBV-Monoplex panel developed in this research may be suitable for future large epidemiology studies to comprehensively investigate EBV-related disease mechanisms. The panel may also potentially be used for early detection/screening for EBV-associated diseases among high-risk individuals identified by jointly investigating EBV and other lifestyle risk factors as the preliminary results provided in this study. This may help to inform EBV-related disease prevention/control policy making, which will benefit not only LMICs but also globally. With preliminary detailed data on EBV biomarkers seroprevalence in the Chinese population, this pilot study will also help improve the design of CKB multiplex panel to be used in future whole cohort-wide studies to elucidate the aetiological role of infectious pathogens in diseases development, with benefit for disease prevention/control worldwide."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">24530.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S014551_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">24530.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S014551_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">33944.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S014551_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">33944.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S014551_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">34219.75</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S014551_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
