<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T008628_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child malnutrition&amp; Adult NCDs-Generating Evidence on mechanistic links in Jamaica, Malawi &amp; Ethiopia to inform future policy/practice (CHANGE study)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Severe malnutrition in early childhood is a major public health concern globally. This has serious consequences: - Short term: for children to survive: malnutrition in all its forms underlies some 45% of all under 5 child deaths worldwide. - Long term: for children to thrive: there is increasing realisation that early life malnutrition contributes to the fast-growing global epidemic of non-communicable diseases (NCDs).   As more children now survive episodes of malnutrition in childhood there is increasing need to understand what causes the long term problems. Evidence on this would lead to: improved early treatment of child malnutrition; improved longer term treatment aiming to reduce long term adverse effects.  In this project we have a unique opportunity to explore three groups of children/adults in: - Jamaica: children suffering from severe malnutrition in the 1980s have been followed up on several occasions already, with scope for further analysis from already collected data. - Malawi: We recently followed up a group of children admitted for severe malnutrition in 2005/6. We plan to both analyse existing data in more depth: also to possible collect new data in future.  - Ethiopia: Individuals who were young children at the time of the great Ethiopia famine of 1983-85 are about to be followed up in a pilot study. Learning from the above two projects will inform and improve plans for the Ethiopia work. We aim to understand what are the long term problems following early child malnutrition and why they occur (the &apos;mechanisms&apos; by which the two problems are linked)   The work proposed in this applicaiton is background towards the above future project. There are two main activities planned   A) Review of exisiting evidence: we will search the scientific literature to better understand what other have found to date re links between early life malnutrition and adult NCDs. Through this we will identify key knowledge gaps to target in future work.  B) Collaborator meeting - we will bring together the teams working on the above three groups of children to: learn from each other and share experiences. Through this better future work will be possible and there is great potential to enhance the overall learning compared to following each group as a stand-alone. This meeting will be organised in Ethiopia in Autumn 2019: we will invite a number of key experts to make detailed plans for future work. The Ethiopia/Malawi/UK teams will also visit Jamaica (the most advanced/experienced group) to learn from their experience and thus help plan better future projects in Malawi and Ethiopia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This development grant will generate background data on and will refine the following longer term aims and objectives:   Aim:  To inform future improvements of SAM management strategies by better understanding the mechanisms by which SAM / child malnutrition leads to adult NCD   Objectives:  1) To investigate the clinical and biochemical profile of older children and adults who have experienced severe malnutrition during childhood vs controls who were not affected   We will combine public health and epidemiological methods with state-of-the-art biochemical/molecular techniques (proteomics, metabolomics, lipidomics, epigenetics) to study the association of SAM on two main NCD-related biochemical processes:           i) Muscle and cardiac physiology; ii) Glucose and lipid metabolism  2) To investigate the effect of timing of the malnutrition exposure. Global child health currently focuses on the &quot;First 1000 days&quot; (i.e. conception to age 2). We will explore possible wider windows of sensitivity by studying the association of our biochemical outcomes vs timing of the SAM insult (at &lt;6mo, up to 1 year, 1-2 years, 2-5 years, &gt;5 years)  3) To investigate the effect of speed of catch-up growth  It is often believed that quicker catch-up growth post-SAM is better. In fact, this may increase rather than decrease risk of NCDs. To answer this question, we will again explore associations with our biochemical processes.    Towards these, in this development phase we will plan two separate work packages: 1) Systematic literature review(s) of the long-term effects of postnatal undernutrition on NCD risk, including mechanistic links and studies of famine survivors.  Details of the question and search strategy will be defined by the wider co-investigator group and the review itself will be conducted by the study research assistant. The review will be registered on PROSPERO  2) Collaborator grant-writing meeting (likely in Ethiopia) Review findings will be presented at a 3-4day all- collaborators meeting. This will be combined with field visits to the proposed Ethiopia field site. At this meeting we will also: - Share details of existing cohorts (with initial focus on our cohorts in Jamaica; Malawi; Ethiopia): what data is currently available; which blood and other samples are available in storage for future analysis. - Develop a draft conceptual framework of potential mechanistic pathways linking early-life undernutrition and  NCDs by comparing similarities in results between existing cohort studies (namely studies of the Jamaica survivors and studies of the Malawi SAM-survivors).  - Identify gaps in knowledge and research from these original cohort studies,  - Explore potential for biosamples still available from these studies,  - Explore the need for future fieldwork: e.g. Practicalities, logistics and cost will be discussed</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-04">24909.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">24909.52</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T008628_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">20280.69</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T008628_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
