<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_S009051_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Household air pollution and risk of esophageal cancer: a case-control study in Western Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Esophageal cancer is the third most common cancer and cause of cancer death in both men and women in Kenya, with 3000+ newly diagnosed patients in 2012. This pattern is common to other East African countries and West Kenya appears to have extremely high rates of the disease. This status contrasts to much of West Africa where the cancer is extremely rare, i.e. 40 times lower. Sadly, the majority of these patients pass away within 6 months of their diagnosis, few being able to afford the limited treatment options. Additionally, up to 15% of patients are very young, in their 20s and 30s. Despite researchers having known about this unusual disease pattern since the 1950s, the risk factors for the disease had hardly been studied prior to 2014. Consequently, there are no targeted strategies to prevent the disease, and no prediction models to identify who might be at high risk of the disease, people whom may benefit from early detection. In 2014, we - i.e. the Kenya PI Dr Diana Menya of Moi University, Eldoret - commenced the first comprehensive study of lifestyle, environmental and genetic factors for esophageal cancer in Kenya. The study was conducted at the Moi Teaching and Referral Hospital, Eldoret, which serves a catchment population stretching to the Ugandan border. In the study, patients newly diagnosed with esophageal cancer were compared to hospital patients and hospital visitors who did not have the disease. The study blood and tumour samples were also collected for genetic analyses.  Results from the study have shown that alcohol and tobacco contribute to the disease in older men, but not in women or in young patients, a knowledge gap which the present study hopes to fill through a UK-Kenya collaboration between Dr Menya and Dr Daniel Pope, a household air pollution expert from the University of Liverpool. This study hypothesizes that household air pollution, from using biomass for cooking in poorly ventilated kitchens, is a large contributor to esophageal cancer in the young and in women, through traditional domestic roles associated with cooking. Household air pollution from biomass and coal use is already an established lung carcinogen, but few studies have examined its influence on esophageal cancer. However, work in an Iranian area of high esophageal cancer rates has shown that chemical compounds formed after combustion of biomass fuels are implicated in esophageal cancer risk in that setting.    In this UK-Kenya collaboration, we propose to continue the core study as previously successfully implemented, and add to it an in-depth component on household air pollution as measured in kitchens and for personal exposures during household visits to a subset of female and younger (&lt; 40 years) participants who live within reach of the referral hospital. A detailed analysis of oesophageal cancer risk with household air pollution will be provided and finally, considering a range of lifestyle and environmental risk factors, a comprehensive report on the strategies needed for primary prevention esophageal cancer in Kenya will be developed.  Rates of this disease have declined in many areas of the world - Kenya should be able to follow this trend.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives Esophageal cancer, predominantly squamous cell histology, is the third most common cancer in both men and women in Kenya and has extremely poor prognosis. This cancer is extremely rare in West Africa - a contrast that points to possible primary prevention. Relevant aetiological research in Kenya needs to be informed by an overarching framework of hypotheses that build upon this cancer&apos;s unique spatial distribution worldwide. Notably, two high incidence areas exist: an Asian esophageal cancer belt and an East African esophageal cancer corridor which includes Kenya. This geospatial clustering spans different cultures and genetically diverse peoples and thus points to the presence of a dominant environmental factor, on top of which lifestyle factors operate. This framework is also consistent with the tumour genetics of this cancer, one with high rates of somatic mutations.  To commence pertinent research, an esophageal cancer case-control study was initiated by the Kenyan PI, Dr Diana Menya at Moi University, Eldoret, four years ago. This work has identified lifestyle factors (tobacco and alcohol) which contribute to approximately half of the disease burden, but only predominantly in older male patients. This &apos;core&apos; case-control study is valuable, but its self-reported data are not sufficient for a comprehensive evaluation of some of the suspected environmental risk factors. We now propose to continue this core study and extend it to evaluate the role of household air pollution (HAP) in this cancer, through an intensive approach of 24-48 hour HAP monitoring in the home. Expertise on HAP and other environmental factors is brought by the UK-PI (University of Liverpool). We hypothesize that HAP exposures contribute to esophageal cancer risk in women and in younger patients through intense daily exposures which can commence early in life, especially in the colder seasons of high-altitude West Kenya. Throughout the fieldwork, we will invest in biospecimens collection for longer-term maximum scientific insight and public health gains in Kenya and across East Africa.  The study&apos;s objectives are: (i) To evaluate relative risks of esophageal cancer associated with questionnaire-based HAP in West Kenya, overall, by intensity, duration and types of HAP exposure. Analyses will be based on questionnaire data from existing and new recruitment in what will be East Africa&apos;s largest case-control study on esophageal cancer, totalling 650 cases and 650 controls. (ii) To quantify average 24-hour HAP exposures to PM2.5 and PM2.5-bound polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAH), in the homes of all female and young (&lt;40 y) newly-recruited case-control study participants. HAP exposures will be compared to international standards, and their sociodemographic and physical determinants, and life-time HAP exposures will be predicted. Using these improved HAP metrics, evaluate its association with esophageal cancer risk, overall and in combination with other esophageal cancer risk factors.  (iii) To quantify population attributable factions to HAP, overall and in demographic and exposure subgroups, and compare these fractions to those for other risk factors evaluated to date (alcohol, tobacco, thermal injury) to produce a report on esophageal cancer control priorities for Kenya. (iv) To invest in a high-quality cancer research resource for Kenya, continue biobanking for future genomic and infectious agent studies, and during home visits for HAP measurements, commence an environmental specimen bank (water, soil, crops) to allow the possibility for studies of water quality, micronutrients, mycotoxins, nitrosamines.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-07" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-06" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-17">31682.85</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-17">126988.02</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-17">96077.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-17">32198.27</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-17">9582052.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_S009051_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FS009051%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
