<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T008121_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dietary Interactions and Risk of Non-Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease: Epigenetics, Immune Factors and Gut Microbiome from Cohort Studies Across India</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liver disease is one of the most important non-infectious diseases in the world today, causing 2 million deaths each year.  It is particularly common in low and middle-income countries where it imposes a considerable burden on health-care systems. Some of this burden is due to chronic hepatitis B and C infection, although we now have the means to prevent and effectively treat these infections and many developed countries have set realistic targets for eradicating hepatitis C and preventing new cases of hepatitis B. As a result, the global burden of hepatitis-related liver disease is beginning to fall, but at the same time there have been marked increases in liver disease associated with obesity and excess alcohol consumption.  Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) is now the most common liver disease worldwide, and is also common throughout India although the number of people affected in a given area can vary from&lt; 10% to &gt; 50%. NAFLD is associated with obesity, and the majority of people with NAFLD develop fatty deposits in their liver. A small number of these go on to develop inflammation in their liver and this stage is called non-alcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH) and from there to cirrhosis the most serious form of liver injury. The majority of people with NAFLD are overweight and/or have the &apos;metabolic syndrome&apos; which includes diabetes, raised blood cholesterol and high blood pressure.  However, NAFLD can develop in people who do not have these features. We don&apos;t currently understand why some people with risk factors develop NAFLD and others do not. Additionally, Indian patients in particular can develop &apos;lean NAFLD&apos;, which occurs in the absence of obesity. This suggests that factors other than obesity and the metabolic syndrome may be important for the development of NAFLD and NASH in this population. These factors could include a person&apos;s genetic makeup, or the way in which their genes work- so-called epigenetic factors. In addition, the bacteria in the gut (the microbiome) are known to affect the way in which the body&apos;s immune system works and gut bacteria are often altered in patents with liver disease.  None of these possible mechanistic factors have been studied in Indian populations.  We have access to over 1000 people with NAFLD, and over 4000 people without NAFLD (acting as controls) from three sites in India. Extensive information is already available on their diet, alcohol intake, health history and blood test results as well as samples of their DNA. We plan to undertake &apos;Fibroscans&apos; on the people recruited-a simple non-invasive test to determine how scarred the liver is, and also to look at their genes and alterations in epigenetics.  This information, together with the information already available will be used to identify risk factors for NAFLD and NASH in this population.  We will also undertake laboratory tests on urine, blood and stools from a smaller subset of people to explore alteration in the bacteria in the gut and the body&apos;s immune responses. This information may allow us to develop new treatments for this condition  The information gathered during this project will provide us with a better understanding of the risk factors for developing NAFLD and NASH in India.  It will allow identification of people at risk at an early stage so they can be advised to make appropriate life-style changes such as weight loss and diet modification.  It will also provide information on the actual &apos;cause&apos; of the condition which might allow development of drugs to treat those people in whom the condition is already established.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overarching aim of this proposal is to explore potential interactions between demographics, co-morbidities, diet, genetics, epigenetics, gut microbiota and host immune factors in the development of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD), and its progression in people in India.  This will provide a better understanding of disease pathophysiology and evolution which, in turn, should facilitate better detection and management of the condition both at a public health and individual level.   This proposed project will utilise four existing, well-phenotyped, nested case-control cohorts across India, as well as a broad range of expertise to facilitate downstream mechanistic studies.  The full proposal has four principal objectives: (i) To perform the first genome-wide association study (GWAS) for NAFLD in individuals of Indian descent. This will identify differences in the phenotypic-genotypic profile of expression between the Indian and existing European cohorts, and will also have the potential to identify novel gene associations some of which may be potential therapeutic targets.   (ii) To perform the first epigenome-wide association study (EWAS) for NAFLD in individuals of Indian descent. This work will identify associations between DNA methylation and phenotype in the Indian cohort. Importantly, we also have access to a UK cohort (Whitehall II) where DNA is available over a 15-year interval, hence candidate loci can be compared with this cohort for to assess causality. The identification of these loci will have novel diagnostic and therapeutic impact, such as the discovery of novel biomarkers or therapeutic targets.  (iii) To conduct faecal metagenomic and plasma/urine/stool metabonomic analyses from a subgroup of NAFLD cases and controls. This will allow in-depth, integrative profiling of gut bacterial species and bacterial metabolites, in well-characterised patients with advanced liver disease (steatosis with inflammation/fibrosis) and non-NAFLD controls. Similar work has been performed in Causasian populations with hepatic steatosis, but this work will provide important comparison data in Indian patients as well as provide the first data in NAFLD patients with advanced liver disease.  (iv) To determine immuno-metabolic phenotype in a subgroup of NAFLD cases and controls. This will build on prior work that has implicated altered innate and adaptive immunity in NAFLD, as well as the metabolic profiling outlined above. Specifically, in an overlapping subgroup of NAFLD and advanced liver disease, and non-NAFLD controls, we will characterize circulating immune cells, including monocytes and mucosal-associated invariant T-cells (MAIT), by flow cytometry. We have previously shown that faecal metabolites can modulate MAIT cell function. This work will integrate the microbiome and metabolite data above, with immune phenotype, thus providing an immuno-metabolic profile for advanced NAFLD. Functional ex vivo work will determine if immune phenotype can be restored from the disease state using metabolic intervention, thus providing a basis for nutritional or pharmacological therapies targeting immuno-metabolism in NAFLD.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-29" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-04">50405</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-04">50405</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T008121_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FT008121%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-09-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
