<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008008_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maghreb Action on Displacement and Rights (MADAR) Network Plus</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MADAR (Maghreb Action on Displacement and Rights) is a challenge-led Network Plus which deploys a broad interdisciplinary approach to the protection of displaced people in the Maghreb region. Drawing on equitable established partnerships, MADAR mobilises a range of international and contextually-informed research expertise to deliver a regional-level intervention in the Maghreb.  MADAR aims to generate an evidence base on humanitarian protection of people affected by South-South displacement in the Maghreb. MADAR will commission research which addresses the challenges of how to effectively affirm protective rights and mitigate harm to the most vulnerable (including conflict- and environment-induced internally displaced people, refugees and asylum seekers in the Maghreb).   MADAR responds to SDG 16: &quot;Promote peaceful and inclusive societies for sustainable development, provide access to justice for all and build effective, accountable and inclusive institutions at all levels&quot;. MADAR&apos;s objectives as a GCRF Network Plus are three-fold:   1) FACILITATE INTERDISCIPLINARY RESEARCH AND CROSS-SECTOR COLLABORATION BETWEEN RESEARCHERS AND PRACTITIONERS WORKING ON DISPLACEMENT IN THE MAGHREB.  a) To generate interdisciplinary research that addresses the multiple and layered protection challenges associated with large scale and diverse displacement and conflict in the Maghreb region. b) To mobilise a qualitative interdisciplinary approach to the protection of displaced people through the arts and humanities and social and political sciences.  MADAR seeks to promote &quot;non-discriminatory laws and policies for sustainable development&quot; (SDG 16.b) and ideas that &quot;the poor and the vulnerable, have equal rights to economic resources, as well as access to basic services&quot; (SDG 1.4).  2) ENHANCE CAPACITY FOR RESEARCH AND INNOVATION IN THE UK AND IN THE MAGHREB, WITH A PARTICULAR FOCUS ON ECRs, CIVIL SOCIETY ORGANISATIONS, AND RESEARCH ADMINISTRATION.  a) To foster and nurture research collaborations amongst established and emerging researchers across institutions in Algeria, Morocco and Tunisia and with research communities beyond the Maghreb.  b) To facilitate and sustain cross-sector synergies between research institutes and cultural and advocacy organisations in order to promote peaceful and inclusive societies through cultural and creative modes of engagement.   3) GENERATE EVIDENCE-BASED SOLUTIONS TO PROTECT VULNERABLE DISPLACED PEOPLE IN THE MAGHREB AND FACILITATE UPTAKE AND UTILISATION BY KNOWLEDGE USERS THROUGH APPLIED KEI STRATEGIES.  a) To generate context and evidence-based knowledge in order to inform scholarly and policy-making debates about displacement in neighbouring regions (Europe, Middle East, and sub-Saharan Africa). b) To deliver and disseminate contextually-informed research in order to guide and shape planned and well-managed practices and policies in Maghreb countries that will protect the rights and prevent harm to people in displacement.  MADAR aligns to SDG 10.7 for &quot;orderly, safe, regular and responsible migration and mobility of people, including through the implementation of planned and well-managed migration policies&quot;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Maghreb Action on Displacement and Rights (MADAR) Network Plus is a regional approach to protection in contexts of conflict and displacement in central Maghreb (Algeria, Morocco and Tunisia). MADAR deploys an interdisciplinary approach, a wide range of regional and national research expertise, and established and equitable partnerships with civil society organisations to respond to the complex protection needs of refugees and other displaced people in the region.   Maghreb is an important migration hub with links to Africa, the Middle East and Europe. While it is often assumed to be a region of emigration and transit (South-North), the Maghreb is increasingly a destination, including for thousands of displaced people fleeing conflict and endemic poverty in countries across Africa and the Middle East (e.g. Syria and Libya). Europe relies heavily on the cooperation of its neighbours south of the Mediterranean Sea to manage and curb migration in an attempt to reduce arrivals on European shores. In the case of Maghreb, states are not equipped to deal with the increasing number of displaced people; they have inadequate infrastructures to ensure the humanitarian protection of those who are vulnerable, the rights of displaced people are routinely infringed, and relationships with host populations are often fraught. As a consequence, Maghreb hosts a large number of vulnerable displaced people at risk and in need of protection.  MADAR (Arabic for &apos;path&apos;) responds to SDG16 to: &quot;Promote peaceful and inclusive societies for sustainable development, provide access to justice for all and build effective, accountable and inclusive institutions at all levels&quot;. MADAR addresses issues faced by Morocco, Algeria and Tunisia to make a transformational impact on the humanitarian protection of vulnerable, displaced people across the Maghreb region. Through interdisciplinary, challenged-led and solution-focused research MADAR aims to:   1) Facilitate interdisciplinary research collaborations drawing on the regional expertise of UK and Maghreb-based scholars from across the arts and humanities and the social and political sciences. 2) Foster partnerships amongst research institutes in the Maghreb and beyond (e.g. MENA) through MADAR&apos;s commissioned, high-impact research projects across the region. 3) Promote research-focused partnerships, developing and sharing best practice amongst academics, activists, artists, and practitioners working on displacement. 4) Identify measures to overcome barriers and enhance access for displaced people to healthcare, education, and employment opportunities. 5) Inform policies, legislation and practices on asylum and migration and promote effective institutional frameworks to support displaced people. 6) Collaborate with civil society organisations in tackling the region-specific causes of racism and xenophobia across the Maghreb to develop strategies for lobbying, advocacy and awareness-raising.  MADAR&apos;s research findings will contribute to reducing risk and improving protection for displaced people in the Maghreb. It will shape and influence national and regional policies and practices that stimulate and facilitate protection for displaced people in Morocco, Algeria, and Tunisia respectively. In addition, given its geographical focus, MADAR will generate knowledge which will affect and impact neighbouring regions and beyond.  MADAR&apos;s key benefit is enhanced protection for people at risk in the contexts of conflict and displacement in the Maghreb. It will also strengthen the research capacity of scholars in the Maghreb region and beyond. MADAR&apos;s sustainable partnership with CSOs in the Maghreb will build capacity and enrich relationships and networks across the region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-06">462271.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-06">200477.07</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-06">469791</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-06">739135.57</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">115567.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008008_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keele University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">115567.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008008_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keele University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">115567.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008008_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keele University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
