<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_N013611_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Super-Rice: a UK-China Collaboration to Improve Rice Nitrogen Use Efficiency (NUE)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The twin objective foci of the project are Research: collaborative interdisciplinary research that will underpin the long-term sustainable production of rice and Research Partnership Development: promotion of long-term collaborative partnerships between transnational UK-China research teams to generate added value in the above research.   The 3 year proposal specifically addresses the overall call Research Challenges of improved resource use efficiency (nitrogen) and novel research tool and technology development (gene and trait discovery) and the China-Specific Challenge of sustainably increasing the yield potential of rice in the CAAS Priority Areas for Rice Genetic Breeding (Super Rice), Cloning and Application of New Gene Responses for Yield and Sustainable Development of Rice (Rice Cropping). Our overall Research Objective is high-yielding, low nitrogen (N)-input, high N use (U) efficiency (E) (NUE) rice agriculture for China and the world. Our pioneering approach combines natural genetic variation with &apos;genome-editing&apos;, and will transform the biology of current rice Green Revolution Varieties (GRVs), moulding them into Super-Rice Varieties that are high-yielding in low N soils. Our vision is to achieve the following unique sequential goals: - First, to discover genetic variants potentially increasing rice GRV NUE - Next, to validate the effects of these individual variants on NUE - Finally, to create Super-Rice genotypes by combining (&apos;stacking&apos;) multiple selected variants, and to conduct initial Super-Rice field trials in low-N soils. These goals will be pursued in linked Workpackages (WPs) with individual objectives:  [WP1] Engineering Genetic Regulation of NUE: Building upon recent discoveries by QQ and XF, WP1 enables molecular identification of gene variants associated with improved NUE and grain yield. WP1 Objective: Discovery of genetic variants that individually enhance the NUE of GRV rice varieties.   [WP2] Engineering Developmental Regulation of N metabolism: Building upon recent collaborative discoveries by XF and NPH, WP2 advances and exploits developing knowledge of the role of developmental regulation of N uptake and metabolism. WP2 Objective: Discovery of genetic variants that individually enhance the NUE of GRV rice varieties.  [WP3] Engineering N-Transporters: Advances and exploits developing physiological knowledge of N uptake transporters for NUE enhancement. WP3 Objective: Discovery of genetic variants that individually enhance the NUE of GRV rice varieties. [WP4] Creation of Super-Rice: Super-Rice is bred via marker-assisted breeding and variant stacking via genome editing. Variants discovered in WPs1-3 are combined &apos;stacked&apos;, with expected additive or synergistic enhancement of NUE in resultant Super-Rice varieties. WP4 Objective: Super-Rice varieties with increased yield in low-N fields.  Our Research Partnership Development Objective will be achieved by making more sustainable and giving added value to the pre-existing bilateral UK-China partnership between XF and NPH and to the pre-existing within-China partnership between QQ and XF, and by the addition of a new bilateral partnership between QQ and NPH that will lead the project, making it a fully integrated three-way collaboration. Our project will involve a range of partnering activities, thus promoting strengthened bilateral NUE-research strategic relationships between the UK and China, by: being a joint research project; laboratory exchanges (academics, postdoctoral researchers, students); a visiting Professorship (NPH at CAS IGDB, Beijing); sharing of key expertise, resources and infrastructures between partners; use of robust interfaces for data management/sharing; regular joint symposia, workshops and meetings. In summary our project will deliver world-leading research and enhanced bilateral strategic research relationships between the UK and China in the science and development of rice with enhanced NUE.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World food demand is predicted to double by 2050. Meeting this demand is a major global challenge, and requires increased crop yields at minimal environmental cost. Present-day high-yielding &apos;green revolution crop varieties&apos; (GRVs) are inefficient in their use of nitrogen (N) fertiliser, an inefficiency that is costly to the farmer and damaging to the environment. The world needs new crops that are both higher yielding and have increased N use efficiency (NUE).  Our project fuses distinct UK/China expertise to improve rice NUE. It retains the outstanding features of current rice GRVs, and transforms them into Super-Rice varieties that are high yielding and have enhanced NUE. Using a pioneering approach combining the discovery of natural genetic variants with marker-assisted breeding and &apos;genome editing&apos;, we will create Super-Rice that will be high-yielding when grown with reduced N fertiliser inputs. First, WPs1-3 exploit a variety of genetic, genomic and bioinformatics techniques to discover individual genetic variants that increase the NUE of rice GRVs. WP1 discovers the molecular identities of variant genes increasing NUE in the field. WP2 focusses on variants of the developmental regulatory genes that play overarching roles in controlling the growth and metabolism of plants. There is important precedent for exploiting such regulatory variation, because the initial GRVs themselves were created by use of such variants. WP3 focusses on the discovery of variants increasing the activity of the transporters that enable rice to extract N from the soil. However, the variants discovered in WPs1-3 may come from wild or other strains of rice that are not themselves GRVs. WPs1-3 therefore importantly use the new technique of genome-editing to specifically determine if these new variants increase NUE in GRV genetic backgrounds. Genome-editing enables precise alteration of genome sequence, thus enabling us to edit specific GRV gene sequences (change them into the newly discovered variant form). The yield of these genome-edited GRVs will then be measured in low-N soils, thus telling us if the newly discovered variant can indeed increase the NUE of the GRV. Next, WP4 further exploits the ability of genome editing to simultaneously edit more than one genomic location. This enables the combined (&apos;stacked&apos;) introduction of multiple variants into one GRV. It is possible that variant combinations will generate NUE increases that are at least additive (a simple sum of individual variant effects) and that may be synergistic (increases that are greater than the simple sum effects of individual variants). Thus, in WP4, we will combine (&apos;stack&apos;) multiple selected variants into Super-Rice genotypes, and then determine the yields of these Super-Rice genotypes in low-N soils. Our genome-edited Super-Rice will not contain any &apos;foreign&apos; transgenes, and may therefore more readily receive regulatory approval for agricultural use than will transgenic &apos;GM&apos; varieties. However, because full adoption of Super-Rice requires general public acceptance, we will also pioneer the use of genome-edited Super-Rice to enhance the efficiency, focus and speed of conventional marker-assisted breeding of Super-Rice. Genome-edited Super-Rice will guide plant breeders in the development of (non-genome-edited) Super-Rice that will be bred using natural rice variants and that will be publicly acceptable because it is neither GM nor genome-edited. The promotion of bilateral UK-China rice research relationships is another major objective of our proposal. We build upon and sustain pre-existing partnerships (XF and NPH; XF and QQ), and derive added value from a new one (NPH and QQ). In summary, we propose a transnational UK-China partnership that will breed publicly acceptable enhanced-NUE Super-Rice that will enhance the sustainability of Chinese and world agriculture and helpfeed the world in the years leading up to 2050 and beyond.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-16">49443.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-16">198172.81</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-16">199778</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-16">150741.95</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-16">5383222.632</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC Newton Newton Fund Award to University of Oxford</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_N013611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=BB%2FN013611%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
