<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R006148_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">An exploration of mental health and resilience narratives of migrant workers in India using community theatre methodology</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This highly innovative, interdisciplinary and collaborative global public health partnership aims to explore the mental health challenges and opportunities for resilience for internal migrants in Pune, India using theatre storytelling practices. Our focus is on co-creation of mental health and resilience knowledge for raising mental health awareness and support through community theatre engagement with migrant slum dwellers. This project aims to develop partnerships between UK and India academic researchers, community theatre groups, migrant communities, government agencies and public health NGOs. Our vision is to work towards the UN sustainable development agenda: Transforming our world: the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development goals 3, 5, and 10 (Good health and wellbeing, Gender equality, and Reduced Inequalities). There are an estimated 450 million people worldwide with mental disorders and about 75% of them live in developing countries, where insecurity, illiteracy, poverty, and violence increase the prevalence of mental illness. There is the widespread ignorance within society about mental health, which often results in human rights abuses and stigma against people with mental illness. Physical health problems and addictions are also associated with mental health problems. Internal migration is a matter of great importance in Low and Middle Income Countries (LMIC). Shrinking agriculture in rural areas and industrialisation and increasing urbanisation leads to ever increasing numbers of internal migrants seeking livelihoods in the cities. Our collaborative research will be in Pune in the state of Maharashtra, India. The rationale for this location is due to our academic and NGO contacts and partnerships within this area.  In Pune the urban poor make up fifty per cent of the population with about 564 slums as per the Indian census data in 2011.  Mental health interventions are still typically dominated by deficit-based models of theory and practice. Traditionally, many of the human service agencies have focused on trying to better understand the biological/psychological or environmental risk factors that increase the likelihood of the development or maintenance of at risk behaviour and the potential implications for prevention. Interventions that are based on the deficit, problems, or pathologies of individuals tend to direct the attention of professionals to only one view of the person. Supporting resilience requires a shift away from deficit-based models of mental health theory and practice. Our aim is to examine the opportunities presented by theatre practice for exploring and developing resilience at both personal and community level for migrant communities who are marginalised and struggling to meet their basic needs with very little public health support for health and wellbeing. Mental health narratives of internal migrants in India have hitherto tended to focus on the prevalence of psychological distress, anxiety and depression; but we have scant evidence about the resilience of migrant slum dwellers. The psychological distress and experiences as a result of migration can indeed be a risk factor for higher prevalence of mental disorders, but the lack of knowledge on how migrants mediate risk in the midst of adversities and construct resilience for positive living is an untold story. A key strength of theatre is its capacity to develop narratives capturing, but also powerfully communicating, the whole spectrum of health experiences - exploring not only the crises in people&apos;s lives but also asking and answering &apos;what is the beautiful?&apos; in people&apos;s lives (beauty can be a key source of meaning and resilience).With the growing burden of mental ill health among migrant communities this international research partnership adds a new dimension to the co-creation of knowledge and understanding of resilience of internal migrant slum dwellers for developing appropriate public health support and intervention models.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposal details a novel and highly collaborative approach to our understanding of how migrant communities construct resilience and positive coping in the midst of socioeconomic adversities. There will be an emphasis on formulating knowledge in new, creative and accessible ways, through use of community theatre and communication technologies to enable knowledge to be used in genuinely empowering and emancipatory ways by migrant communities, researchers and health service agencies. Our focus will be on migration, mental health and resilience and will develop this through engagement with migrant slum dwellers, their lived experiences and key stakeholders.  Our overall research question is: how effective is community theatre as a means for understanding and communicating risk and resilience for mental health and well-being in internal migrant communities in India?   In addressing this, we will:  (1) Develop an international collaborative research partnership to explore risk and resilience models for mental health and wellbeing of internal migrant communities in India.  (2) Collaborate with theatre practitioners in the UK and India towards advancing participatory models of theatre practice that develop the &apos;voice&apos; and agency of migrant workers in exploring resilience and positive coping for mental health and well-being. (3) Contribute to new knowledge, and advancement of knowledge in public mental health. (4) Explore potential of community theatre to &quot;re-story&quot; migrant narratives i.e. co-creating, hearing and telling new stories as part of the &quot;glue&quot; holding social networks together through times of change. This international research partnership with a Middle Income Country (India) will innovate and develop new knowledge in the area by:  1. Developing a collaborative model of applied theatre practice for exploring resilience for mental health and wellbeing.  2. Co-producing a piece of community theatre reflecting the lived experiences of migrant community (children and young people, adults with families, and older people).  3. Developing an inclusive, participatory research model with volunteers and stakeholders from migrant community including using appropriate language and communication strategies. 4. Co-producing knowledge of risk and resilience for mental health and wellbeing of migrant communities. 5. Conducting a literature overview of current applied theatre practice within the specific context of Indian health and well-being education. 6. Conducting a rapid review of mental health of migrant communities within the South Asian countries.    The overall research question and our subsidiary questions will be examined through a two year scoping study.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">De Montfort University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-13">87782.27</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-13">44050.82</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-13">45511.15</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-13">177344.242</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF RCUK Award to De Montfort University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R006148_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">De Montfort University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FR006148%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
