<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M01438X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Learning from health systems strengthening in maternal and newborn health (MNH) in China to inform accelerated progress for saving lives in Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Globally, 289,000 women die each year due to complications of pregnancy and childbirth, and 2.9 million babies do not survive the first month of life. Sub-Saharan Africa - with only one tenth of the world&apos;s population - carries the greatest burden and there is little evidence of progress. Several strategies have been identified to accelerate progress in reducing maternal and newborn mortality, including increasing the number of health workers and upgrade specific skills for care at birth and exploring ways to attract health workers to rural areas, but how to implement these measures at large scale in sub-Saharan Africa remains uncertain.  Sub-Saharan Africa can learn important lessons from China&apos;s progress in maternal and newborn health (MNH), in particular in terms of the process and the &quot;how&quot;. Over the last twenty years, China&apos;s newborn and maternal mortality rate fell dramatically. The reasons for this success are multiple, but China&apos;s strategic investments in health systems strengthening have no doubt contributed, particularly in terms of building a strong midwifery workforce, encouraging women to give birth in hospital and making delivery care mostly free. Regional disparities in access to MNH care persist, but even the poorest regions, - which face geographical barriers not dissimilar to sub-Saharan Africa - have made substantial progress. The mortality difference between China and sub-Saharan Africa at national level is about 3-fold for newborn mortality and ten-fold for maternal mortality; and the current urban-rural maternal and newborn survival gap in China is about 3-fold. So evaluation of China&apos;s learning could serve to both accelerate progress for closing China&apos;s urban-rural gap and to the increasing momentum for change in Africa.    The aim of this project is to use China&apos;s experience in MNH to answer a number of questions that are critical to understanding how similar progress can be achieved in sub-Saharan Africa, including: 1. Do existing health systems indicators discriminate among areas with high and low maternal and newborn mortality? Can thresholds be set (e.g. density of providers per 1000 population) below which mortality cannot decline? 2. What is the appropriate midwifery workforce, and how is it best deployed, to equitably deliver essential MNH interventions at scale and quality, and what resources and systems (financial, training, governance, supervision, etc.) need to be in place to achieve universal access to these interventions? 3. How do existing structures and processes enable successful referral from the community to facilities offering obstetric care? 4. What changes in the health financing system, including introduction of new insurance schemes, pooling arrangements, and provider payment mechanisms, have reduced financial barriers, thereby supporting the expansion of coverage of essential MNH services? 5. What lessons from China can be transferred to Tanzania?  We will answer the above questions through a number of studies. First, we will use China&apos;s unique and extensive routine data systems to examine the relationship between health systems inputs and maternal and newborn mortality across all counties. Second, we will collect data in eight counties in China&apos;s poorest Western provinces to provide an in depth understanding of the relationship between MNH inputs that are more difficult to capture through routine data sources, including the mix and levels of the midwifery workforce, referrals and levels and allocation of health care financing, and selected service coverage and outcome indicators. Third, we will examine whether the successful MNH strategies deployed in China can be implemented in Tanzania and whether the effectiveness would remain the same given Tanzania&apos;s different health and socio-economic context.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of this project is to examine China&apos;s progress in reducing maternal and neonatal mortality in order to draw lessons applicable to the maternal and neonatal health context in sub-Saharan Africa.  The project will specifically assess implementation strength, an emerging approach to programme evaluation which aims to characterise the intensity of programme effort (both quantity and quality) required to achieving programme goals. Implementation strength will be determined by assessing the relationship between various levels and combinations of programme inputs and outputs and reduced maternal and neonatal mortality, while taking into account key contextual factors.    The focus of this work will be on system inputs and outputs that have enabled progress towards universal access to basic and comprehensive obstetric care in health facilities, particularly for the rural poor and those living in remote areas, and the financing mechanisms that facilitated removal of financial barriers at the point of care. Our analysis will focus on evidence from Western China where progress has been more recent and the socio-economic context has relevance for sub-Saharan Africa.   Specific objectives are:   1. To examine whether minimum thresholds of implementation strength exist below which maternal and neonatal mortality cannot decline. This will be done by analysing the relationship between routinely available indicators of health system inputs and outputs, contextual factors and maternal and neonatal mortality across all counties in China  2. To identify the health system inputs most strongly associated with declines in maternal and neonatal mortality, and how these are most effectively deployed. This will be done by  measuring and comparing key health system inputs for MNH (including health facility infrastructure, midwifery workforce, referral mechanisms, financing and governance structures) in selected rural and more remote counties in Western China with different speeds of decline in maternal and neonatal mortality, using an in-depth case study approach  3. To support the process of adapting lessons from China&apos;s experience in maternal and neonatal health to the current context of Tanzania</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-12-20">169314.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-12-20">170360.44</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-12-20">115038.12</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q1">42590.1</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M01438X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q2">42590.1</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M01438X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">42590.1</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M01438X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">42590.1</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M01438X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">38346.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M01438X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">38346.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M01438X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">38346.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M01438X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">10632.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M01438X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
