<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S019006_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Risk-based pedigree-analysis for regulation of prophylactic aquaculture health products and improved smallholder health management in Bangladesh</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rapidly growing demand for seafood products for domestic and export markets is driving intensification of aquaculture sectors still dominated by small-holders in Bangladesh. Ensuring effective health management has become the single most important challenge for sustainable intensification of the smallholder sector just increasing restrictions on use antibiotic and other therapeutants are being imposed. Farmers are increasingly dependent on a proliferating range of poorly regulated prophylactic health products including probiotics (beneficial bacteria), often of uncertain provenance &amp; efficacy.   Although probiotics are often viewed as a response to the problem of &apos;imprudent&apos; antibiotic use in aquaculture, screening of probiotics in a previous BBSRC and DFID funded project (IMAQulate Project, Ref: BB/N005082/1) revealed serious problems with a number of commercial products including; ineffective active ingredient concentrations, contamination with  bacteria pathogenic to humans, fraudulent inclusion of antibiotics, presence of antimicrobial resistance genes. In addition many products lack of credibility regarding their mode of action &amp; efficacy claims. Findings also point to a lack of effective sampling approaches as part of emergent regulatory efforts resulting in lack of detection of some problem-products in screening efforts whilst the economic burden of poor quality assurance and unjustified claims is likely to fall most heavily on small-holders.   In response the project has developed a PHP risk analysis tool  helping users to identify &apos;high-risk&apos; products  based on label-information and other secondary indicators. Focusing  on emergent market for PHPs in pangasius and shrimp sectors, this project (PEDIGREE) aims to increase awareness of these issues to support improved regulation for  safety and quality assurance in Bangladesh and more effective small-holder health management. To do this the project will feed into a national health management regulatory strategy being developed by the Department of Fisheries as well as providing probiotic quality and management advice to farmers through a farmer advisory hotline established and operated by project NGO partner Practical Action Bangladesh.  Lead by the University of Stirling (UK), other partners in Bangladesh include the Bangladesh Aquaculture Product Companies Association (BAPCA), the WorldFish Center Bangladesh (WFC) and Bangladesh Agricultural University (BAU).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will build on and communicate findings of the following ongoing BBSRC Newton Fund project to end-users in Bangladesh: Evaluating Costs and Benefits of Prophylactic Health Products and Novel Alternatives on Smallholder Aquaculture Farmers In Asia and Africa (IMAQulate). Project Ref: BB/N005082/1. Although PHPs are routinely framed as a response to the problem of imprudent antibiotic use in aquaculture, screening of commercial prophylactic health products (PHPs) marketed to shrimp producers in India has revealed a range of with poorly regulated products in the main probiotic PHP product class:  (i) lack of credibility around mode of action &amp; efficacy claims  (ii) sub-therapeutic active ingredient concentrations  (iii) contamination with/ fraudulent inclusion of antibiotics (iv) contamination with bacteria pathogenic to humans (v) presence of antimicrobial resistance genes (vi) sub-optimal sampling approaches as part of emergent regulatory efforts  A PHP predictive tool (PEDIGREE) based on label-information and other secondary data has been developed by IMAQulate to raise awareness of these issues and to support a risk-based sampling approach to safety and quality assurance. Exchanges will be based on training and implementation of the tool in Bangladesh i.e. UoS staff will work with partners to use the tool to sample &apos;high-risk&apos; PHPs for screening (ii)  Bangladesh users will then be trained on the laboratory analysis of these products at the University of Stirling (iii) finally partners will share findings at appropriate policy/ industry fora in Bangladesh including a national country aquatic health-strategy currently being developed by the DoF with coordinating support of the WorldFish Center.  In a parallel thrust the project will work an NGO partner to provide small-holder farmers with access to impartial, independent advice on product quality, risks and efficacy advice through an established telephone hotline advisory service.   Partner &apos;user-groups&apos; in Bangladesh will be the Bangladesh Aquaculture Product Companies Association (BAPCA), Practical Action Bangladesh (PAB) who will nominate members for interchange visits to the UoS. Co-researchers will include IMAQulate partners from the WorldFish Center Bangladesh (WFC) and Bangladesh Agricultural University (BAU). IMAQulate partner; the Central Institute of Fisheries Technology (CIFT) in India will also be a (no-cost) affiliate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-21">62651.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC GCRF Standard Grant Award to University of Stirling</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB/S019006/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Stirling</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-04-01">22782.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S019006_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Stirling</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">22782.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S019006_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Stirling</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">11187.69</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S019006_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Stirling</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=BB%2FS019006%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
