<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P010253_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tying Quipu&apos;s Key Knots</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project takes the successes of the AHRC-funded Quipu Project and shares them with the local participants and organizations that catalysed the project and provided its driving force. Technological limitations have meant that this has not been possible, as we hoped it might have been, under our present system.  The launch of the Quipu Project in December 2015 was primarily aimed at influencing political debate in Peru in the run-up to the 2016 presidential elections. It formed part of a movement which sought to make the issue of the sterilizations a political issue, and thereby to gain justice and reparations for the people who were sterilized without their concept. The impact thus far has been considerable but felt primarily on the international and national scales, whereas the project now seeks to draw that resonance back to the regional / local levels. We are conscious of practical, ethical and scholarly imperatives to take that impact back to where it all began, to the protagonists of the Quipu story.  This project will focus on producing materials from the Quipu archive which can be used by the local organizations who provided us with our first contacts. These are the Group of Sterilized People of Independencia in Ayacucho; AMAEF-C-GTL in Cuzco, and Convenio IAMAMC-AMHBA in Huancabamba, Piura. The project will take those materials to them, organize workshops to provide skills to local leaders and participants, and empower them to act fully as agents within the research and its dissemination rather than simple objects of study.  As part of these local workshops we will record, and then transcribe, translate and publish, the participants&apos; responses to Quipu&apos;s global reach, in order to add an extra layer of interactivity to the Quipu archive, and to problematize simplistic accounts of research impact on the global scale.  This project will therefore work to bring into dialogue the responses of local &apos;recipients&apos; of impact, with broader global narratives about what &apos;impact&apos; could and should be.  We will have completed the Quipu circle if we can bring our global successes back to our original participants - (1) Listening to the roots - and use our encounters in order to (2) Further Elevate Public Discourse in Peru and worldwide about the impact of this (and other) forced sterilization programmes. These outcomes will allow us to produce a video guide for projects like this, which will enable us to (3) Improve Social Innovation by carrying our learning out from the Andes and onto potential social innovation collaborators in the UK, in Peru and globally.    In 2015-2016 the Quipu team (Brown, Tucker, Court, Lerner, Sebastian Melo and Cass-Kavanagh) have given invited talks and demonstrations of Quipu at venues including many UK universities and in Switzerland, the Netherlands, Colombia, Peru and Chile. In the next twelve months we already have many invitations pending, and this stream of recognition has convinced us of the need to produce a video guide for researchers, creative practitioners and community practitioners interested in adopting similar methodologies for divergent projects. The events in Lima and Bristol would take a question and answer format, and would shape and inform the video guide. Lerner and Court will be present to film the events, and to produce the video guide which will be placed on the Quipu Project website with links from the AHRC website. This will use Quipu as a case study for how three-way collaborative learning processes can be designed and managed. It will be useful for community practitioners and NGOs looking to achieve social change through the fusion of storytelling, technology and research. This guide will prove a lasting legacy of Quipu so that the lessons we have learned in the Andes, in Lima and in Bristol can be applied elsewhere by collaborative partnerships with similar aims and objectives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="PE" type="PERU"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">489</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-04">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-04">56060.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The Quipu Project was a collaboration born from the AHRC REACT-Hub Future Documentary Sandbox. It has had a number of wide-ranging, global impacts, raising the level of public debate around the subject of the forced sterilizations in 1990s Peru, and amplifying the voices of women who have traditionally been marginalized from media and politics. The project used innovative participatory methodology to bring hi- and lo- technology together. The project was covered in China, India, the USA, and across South America and Europe. Within Peru it was acknowledged as an important part of the movement which put the issue at the centre of the campaign for Peru&apos;s presidential elections in 2016.  The nature of the technology adopted meant, however, that most of these impacts occurred outside of the communities most affected by the forced sterilization policy. This new project takes Quipu back to where it began - the isolated Andean communities whose stories gave Quipu its power. There are three main aims:  1. Listening to the roots. We want to enhance the empowering nature of the Quipu Project by sharing the emancipatory power of our pioneering digital-storytelling methodology. We want to show the communities and our participants what we achieved globally, by organizing half-day workshops in Ayacucho, Cuzco and Piura with our partner organizations. Through these workshops we can learn from our participants what it means for their stories to have been amplified and listened to. In this way we can listen to them, and then strengthen our partner organizations and their nascent national collaborations by providing them with the resources they need to further their campaigns for justice and reparations. These may include paper pamphlets, radio adverts or increased national visibility.  2. Elevating Public Discourse. We want to further elevate the level of public discourse in Peru around the subject of the forced sterilizations. Working with our partner the new national memory museum the Lugar de la Memoria (LUM) we will disseminate our findings through talks, exhibits and a permanent Quipu exhibit. This might include recording new responses and testimonies at the workshops, transcribing and translating them and incorporating them as a new thread within the online Quipu archive. We will invite opinion-formers, NGOs and politicians to consider the testimonies we have gathered together, in order to help our local partner organizations to achieve their objectives relating to justice and reparations.  3. Improving Social Innovation. We want to show the global community of independent documentary makers and practitioners of creative technology the importance of locally embedding their work and the impact that this can have. We will share how we worked collaboratively with local practitioners to meet their objectives and needs by developing an accessible video guide for future projects, using Quipu as a case study. This will highlight areas where social innovation projects need to invest time and resources, and where the impact of storytelling can be enhanced through technological solutions using both traditional technologies and new media.  Objective: Completing the Quipu Circle. These three aims are tied together into one principal, overriding objective. This is to complete the Quipu circle, by physically taking our successes and sharing them, tying them together, and exchanging knowledge with our original participants. This will enable us to reflect critically on this experience, learning from the participants how the project has benefitted them, how we might carry their testimonies further both nationally and internationally, and to achieve the impacts that they are seeking. This will enable us to shape debate in the UK about impact, putting the marginalized voices of those &apos;impacted&apos; at the centre rather than the periphery, and to paving the way for more effective social innovation projects for the future."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">100000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P010253_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">56060.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P010253_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">-60756.97</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P010253_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
