<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_P032591_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategic University Network to Revolutionise Indian Solar Energy (SUNRISE)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Below is a list of outcomes expected to be achieved by the SUNRISE consortium: 1. Development of new fabrication routes to deliver low-cost solution processed and vapour deposited perovskite PV modules.   2. New stable solar energy materials that match the requirements for climatic conditions appropriate to the Indian sub-continent.  3. New device architectures for tandem solar cells designed to achieve &gt;25% efficiency that include Perovskite/ CIGS, c-Si/ Perovskite structures. 4. With funded existing partners adapt and implement integration and storage systems for electrical power from company and research partners for real world demonstration. 5.      Development of efficient processes for the conversion of biomass in to fuel and power. 6. With funded existing researchers from Gates Foundation develop new strategies for sanitation and to obtain clean water for the villages in India. 6. Deployment of newly developed and directly building integrated flexible CIGS panels by our industrial partners (BIPV Co) in demonstration buildings in India 7. Development of demonstration communities in India (led by Tata Trust and Tata Cleantech Capital) to showcase new and existing technology and create local supply chains for low cost manufacturing of renewable energy products 8. Demonstrable knowledge transfer and development of the skills of the Indian researchers achieved via collaboration and joint study. Key will be to develop the close working relationships that exist in teh UK between academicv partners and industry in an Indian context; essentially this will involve creating an Industrial Doctorate (EngD) concept for challenge led research and an innovation hub where industrial and academic teams can be brought together to solve key challenges.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In November 2016 the UK Government mounted a technical trade mission to India. During this visit the delegation witnessed some of the worst aerial pollution in Delhi&apos;s history. At times the air quality was contaminated with 999 mg per cubic metre of particulates almost five times the emission consent of an iron making coke oven! India will be the World&apos;s largest economy potentially as early as 2030 requiring a total transformation in energy generation. At the Trade summit Prime Minister Modi detailed a vision for India to leapfrog other countries reliance on fossil fuels harnessing global science implemented locally. As such the timing of SUNRISE could not be better.  SUNRISE is an ambitious programme to rapidly accelerate and prove low cost printed PV and tandem solar cells for use in off grid Indian communities within the lifetime of the project. SUNRISE will combine world leading UK research teams from Imperial (Durrant/Nelson), Cambridge (Friend), Oxford (Snaith) a key Indo UK research leader (Uppadaya at Brunel) with an internationally leading photovoltaic scaling activity (SPECIFIC IKC at Swansea University (Worsley/Watson)) and key Indian institutions notably IIT Delhi (Dutta/Pathak), NPL Delhi (Chand, Gupta), CSIR Hydrabad (Giribabu, Narayan), IISER Pune (Ogale), IIT Kanpur (Garg, Gupta). The research impact of scaleable and stable low cost metal mounted PV products will be supported by technology demonstration at five off grid village communities (each of up to 20000 people). The EPSRC JUICE consortium will support the systems integration and electrical storage elements to create real technology demonstrators using local manufacturing supply chains (Tata Cleantech Capital and Tata Trust). In addition to electrical infrastructure the SUNRISE partnership includes activity on gasification of farming/crop wastes (a major cause of the incredible pollution in Delhi in November 2016) and the SPECIFIC IKC will support the practical on site demonstration of photocatalytic water purification using a linked programme with the Gates&apos; Foundation. A key driver for this project is not only demonstration of technology in real demonstration sites but the creation of a legacy of better Indian Industry/Institution collaboration through the creation of an Industrial Doctorate programme modelled on the success of the UK EngD programme started by EPSRC in 1992 and pioneered at Swansea.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swansea University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-27">1318920</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-27">4889748</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-27">4970361</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-27">3732654</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-27">3597175.17</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-27">6580123.394</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF RCUK Award to Swansea University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_P032591_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swansea University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FP032591%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
