<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N013913_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity building and PhD student partnership in the Marine and Maritime sectors</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The oceans cover ~70% of our planet and provide food, energy, environments, and resources that sustain life. Throughout history and into the future the oceans will be the principal pathways for human migration and commerce, with ships carrying more than 90% of global trade.  Ports and coasts remain magnets for human activity with more than a billion people living along the coast and almost half of the world&apos;s population resident within 150 km of the sea. The oceans provide significant resources but they also are increasingly a source of natural and human-enhanced hazards. We are the stewards of this vast ecosystem and require a pipeline of PhD scholars with a global perspective on these marine and maritime issues to ensure their sustainable development and exploitation.  3-6 month internships will be developed in both institutions to meet these strategically important needs for society; each internship underpinned by world-class facilities and excellent training environment provided by our funded Doctoral Training Programme SPITFIRE.  The UoS is a world leader in the marine and maritime sector and NMMU is emerging as a leader in South Africa in this domain.  PhD partnership activity will significantly enhance the skills and research capabilities of PhD scholars from both organisations; developing a cohort of 20 graduates that will have strong links to their hosting institution and a unique global perspective.  The PhD exchange activity will be developed into a sustained institutional collaboration by annual staff exchange activity including Professional Services staff and development of an ongoing joint PhD programme.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposal for PhD partnership activity between UoS and NMMU aims to build a new, sustained and strategically significant collaboration between both organisations in the marine and maritime realm. The Southampton Marine and Maritime Institute (SMMI) is an internationally recognised centre of excellence, bringing together research, innovation and education communities from universities, research institutes, industry and governments.  SMMI has over 1000 researchers working on cutting edge maritime projects, who have an ambition to change the world through their research collaborations with global partners.  In 2014, NMMU set up the South African International Maritime Institute (SAIMI) to focus and promote maritime education, skills development and research to support South Africa&apos;s potential to harness its untapped maritime resources.  Through this proposed Newton fund partnership, NMMU scholars will have access to world-class facilities and research training at the UoS, UoS scholars will broaden their research horizons, internationalize their thinking and globalize their ambition.   The specific objectives of the project are: 1. To provide economic and social benefits in South Africa through training and capacity building that will enhance this emerging knowledge economy. 2. Provide a total of 20 PhD students from the 2 organisations over the 3 year period of the project the opportunity to carry out a 3-6 month overseas research training that will transform their research experience and career trajectory. 3. Develop this cohort of 20 PhD scholars and sustain this early career researcher cohort as they move onto postdoctoral careers and operate in the global research environment. 4. Build sustained institutional collaborative links between UoS and NMMU researchers</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-07" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1029" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-18">26806.24</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-18">53829.58</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-18">54265.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-18">13621.13</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-18">162143.64</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC Newton Newton Fund Award to University of Southampton</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES/N013913/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FN013913%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-11-02"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
