<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003642_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A multi-disciplinary network of social scientists, policy makers, and civil society to fight TB epidemic in the Post-Soviet countries</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of the network is to facilitate the generation of evidence to inform public health policies to reduce the tuberculosis (TB) burden in post-Soviet countries and promote ongoing knowledge exchange among all stakeholders. The objectives of the network are:  1. Establish a vibrant community of policy makers, civil society and academics from various social science disciplines in the region and international experts to facilitate generation of evidence and formulate research agenda, which is able to support effective eradication of TB in the region. 2. Facilitate the use of existing data, which is both routinely collected by the government, academics or civil society organisations to inform TB-related policy making with local details, and identify needs for future data collection. 3. Build local research capacity via Young Scholar Programme, research training and engagement of network members with international funding opportunities (e.g. GCRF, EU, etc.). 4. Establish a platform for knowledge exchange, public awareness and policy dialogue around TB eradication to contribute to the development of future GCRF strategy and assist other funders in setting up TB-related research and development priorities in the region and world-wide.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tuberculosis remains one of the leaders of mortality causes worldwide, despite the fact that the disease is successfully treatable. Post-Soviet countries of Eastern Europe and Central Asia are on the list of high-priority countries for TB control. Exploring other existing networks around TB, we see that they tend to unite the key stakeholder groups among each other - researchers, the civil society or the policy makers with the researchers&apos; network focusing more on medical research and social research around the TB epidemic being not well represented. The proposed unique multidisciplinary network of social scientists (economists, public health researchers, sociologists, epidemiologists, psychologists, criminologists, public communication experts), civil society activists and policy makers will become a platform for ongoing knowledge exchange not only within the groups of stakeholders but across enabling effective adoption of what works best in fighting TB epidemic. This exchange will enable the use of existing research to inform current development of policies and interventions, while establishing a policy-relevant research agenda for the future and reliable venues for dissemination of the results. The key stakeholders of the Network are civil society organizations (representing TB, HIV/AIDS patients, healthcare and public health professionals), policy makers and researchers. The aim of the network is to facilitate the generation of evidence to inform public health policies to reduce the tuberculosis (TB) burden in post-Soviet countries and promote ongoing knowledge exchange among all stakeholders. To achieve this aim, we plan to:  1. Create a platform for network members to promote their existing activities (country case studies, working papers, popular blogs) and collect reference metadata. 2. Hold policy dialogue and networking meetings once a year over 2 days attached to research training meetings for young scholars to allow for them to participate in policy dialogue. The meetings will provide space to share ideas and discuss policies, as well as to develop agenda for the region.  3. Build capacity for early career researchers via the Young Scholar Research Support programme, which is a novel feature of the proposed network.  4. Support TB-relevant research in the Network countries by addressing training needs of the network members and young scholars via webinars and training sessions at the meetings, running of the working paper series and developing methodology for scoping studies and reference metadata  We foresee the following outcomes of the Network existence:  1. Developed common TB-focused social research agenda for the region and bespoke agendas for the participating countries,  2. Better understanding of the context nationally, within the region and internationally;  3. Improved local research capacity and policy dialogue,  4. Established collaborations within and across countries (closing the circle of researchers, civil society activists and politicians within countries and enabling within and multi-disciplinary collaboration across countries),  5. Better understanding of available data for research and future data needs.  The proposed network is unique and we expect to leave a lasting legacy in the form (i) of established collaborations to lead to future grant applications; (ii) an established network to enable new collaborations in the future; (iii) changed local research culture striving for higher standards of research integrity and engagement of stakeholders throughout all the stages of research; (iv) changed culture of policy dialogue, which incorporates both research evidence and views of civil society activists representing patients and professionals; (v) enablement of future research through access to reference metadata and evidence from scoping studies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-07">56502.39</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-07">25163.13</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-07">69617.74</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">18834.13</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003642_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Kent</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">18834.13</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003642_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Kent</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
