<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P015328_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building resilience along the Colombian Caribbean coast in the face of sudden and slow-onset environmental hazards</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our overall aim is to understand how to maximise the likelihood that responses to shocks, and the pathways of transformation followed, in a vulnerable and highly resource-dependent tropical coastal community, are positive rather than detrimental. This will require integration of social, political, cultural and environmental histories to track trajectories of resilience and identify the complex processes of adaptation over extended timescales. Building on the insights gathered from this analysis, we will make recommendations on the conditions and inputs needed to build resilience for the future.   In order to achieve this, we will focus on communities along Colombia&apos;s Caribbean Sea coast, in particular within the RAMSAR/UNESCO MAB Biosphere Reserve site of Cienaga Grande de Santa Marta (CGSM). Our study will span the last 200 years, a period which encompasses a time of rapid social, economic and political transformation in the Latin American Caribbean, alongside increasing environmental change.   Our specific objectives are to:   1. Analyse how the state of the CGSM community and ecosystem has changed over the last 200 years in response to multiple slow and shock environmental and socio-economic pressures, taking account of dynamic policy and cultural contexts;   2. Examine how various environmental, social, political, economic and cultural processes interact to shape system responses and resilience;   3. Identify outcome measures that can be used to represent system resilience over time; and  4. Propose ways in which resilience could be enhanced to protect the community against future environmental and societal pressures, taking consideration of the roles and responsibilities of different actors.  An important aspect of our approach is that we explicitly recognise the importance of social, political, cultural and environmental histories in shaping the nature of, and capacity for, resilience.  Our broader goals are to:  1. Build a cross regional (UK-Colombian), interdisciplinary team to develop international understanding and enhancing capacity in the area of resilience and environmental change  2. Deepen academic-end user partnerships in order to establish more effective political support, at local and national levels, for the introduction of measures that enhance resilience to environmental change.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resilience is at the heart of the current development agenda and underpins approaches to disaster risk reduction. It has a central role in the 2030 Global Goals. Fundamentally, resilience is about the ability of communities to resist and absorb the impacts of environmental hazards, so they can continue to function as successful societies. The frequency and severity of environmental hazards, such as floods and droughts, are increasing in many lower and middle-income countries, where environmental degradation (like water and soil pollution) can make recovery from such impacts more prolonged. The poor, marginalised ethnic groups and other vulnerable social sectors, including the old and the very young, are particularly vulnerable to such impacts. These groups lack the social, economic and political capital that underpins resilience and, consequently, the overall cost of environmental change is greater for these communities than for more privileged ones. It is particularly important, therefore, to understand how to build resilience in and for poorer communities in order to ensure that they are less vulnerable in the future.  One important influence on how communities and societies are able to adapt to environmental hazards is how they have developed in the past. Historical context, culture and political dynamics are all important factors affecting resilience and shape how it is locally understood and framed. However, most research on resilience fails to take account of the importance of past events and responses, and the timeframe of studies is a few decades at most. For this reason, in this project, we will bring together social, political, cultural and environmental histories to track resilience in a vulnerable tropical coastal community over a 200 year period.   The project will focus on communities along Colombia&apos;s Caribbean Sea coast, in particular within the Biosphere Reserve site of Cienaga Grande de Santa Marta (CGSM). The CGSM is Colombia&apos;s largest coastal lagoon system, and supports seven communities, all of which are heavily dependent on fisheries from the lagoon for their livelihoods. The CGSM system is under threat from a wide range of environmental pressures including sea level rise, warming climate and reduced precipitation, which combine to threaten the fisheries. These trends are overlain by impacts from the increased frequency and severity of floods and droughts, linked to weather patterns related to large-scale Pacific Ocean warmings (El Ni&#xF1;o events) and coolings (La Ni&#xF1;a events).   We will extract detailed environmental histories regarding drought and flood events, pollution and sedimentation rates from cores that we take from the mangrove forests that fringe the CGSM lagoon, plot historical representations of environmental change and identify historical political trends that have shaped resilience in the past. We will date key events such as floods and droughts from these cores and then use historical sources including literature and arts-based works alongside the lens of politics to identify the range of social, political and cultural factors that have affected the response and the extent of resilience of the communities over time. Finally, we will use this information to propose ways in which resilience could be enhanced to protect the communities against future environmental and societal pressures.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-31">112822.76</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-31">9673.6</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">62144.24</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P015328_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">9673.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P015328_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">41932.69</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P015328_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
