<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_R016429_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Fruit farming In the CAatinga: managing ecosystem service trade-offs as agriculture intensifies (SUFICA)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The SUFICA project aims to enhance the competitiveness, sustainability and long-term resilience of fruit farming in the S&#xE3;o Francisco valley in north-eastern Brazil, as it intensifies. The project will work with growers and international supply companies to co-design and test nature-based innovations on fruit farms, aiming to generate multiple environmental benefits whilst enhancing fruit yield or quality and reducing inputs. It takes a trans-disciplinary approach, bringing scientists, farmers and industry together to tackle the challenge of managing a sensitive agro-ecosystem at the food-water-environment nexus, in the context of economic development.   There are three major outcomes: 1) SUFICA experimentally tests &apos;ecological intensification&apos; as a pathway to sustainable intensive agriculture; 2) SUFICA establishes the necessary research infrastructure and tools to monitor and continually improve biodiversity and ecosystem services on farms in the S&#xE3;o Francisco valley; 3) SUFICA demonstrates how a partnership approach enables the benefits of agricultural growth and environmental protection to be combined. This approach can be applied in other developing countries.  The SUFICA partnership is a response to strong market signals in the agri-food sector that farmers should take action to support biodiversity. The project links this biodiversity objective with production-enhancing ecosystem services - pollination and water flow regulation - to assess the potential for management that benefits both biodiversity and production. The approach, termed &apos;ecological intensification&apos;, has shown promise in Europe and North America, but has not been experimentally tested in tropical semi-arid environments.  The underlying scientific hypothesis is that multiple regulating ecosystem services can be co-erced to flow in bundles, and thus be synergistically enhanced in semi-arid agricultural landscapes, with accompanying biodiversity benefits. SUFICA tests this hypothesis using a replicated, farm-scale, Before-After-Control-Impact (BACI) experiment, co-designed with farmers to monitor the effects of management actions that are feasible and attractive to growers in the region. The SUFICA experiment is the first scientifically robust, replicated test of &apos;ecological intensification&apos;, in which multiple environmental and agronomic outcomes are directly monitored. We include carbon sequestration, as climate change mitigation in agriculture is a development goal for Brazil. The research will use state-of-the-art mapping and modelling approaches to explore mechanisms and predict changes to natural capital stock and ecosystem service delivery.   The SUFICA experiment incorporates different landscape and farming contexts and builds capacity among farmers. Through carefully designed knowledge exchange processes, larger farms will learn from ecological and diversified practices of small farms, while small farms are supported to engage with international export markets. All farmers in the project will be involved in developing globally recognised farm-scale biodiversity assessment tools, through which they can demonstrate their positive actions.  The S&#xE3;o Francisco valley lies in the caatinga, a semi-arid ecoregion of seasonally dry tropical forest with globally important biodiversity. The caatinga is threatened by habitat loss and degradation due to agriculture, and predicted increases in aridity due to climate change. Agricultural development is key for both poverty reduction and long-term economic growth in Brazil. With old intensification trajectories, this growth will come at the expense of biodiversity and ecosystems, reducing long-term resilience and disproportionately impacting on smallholder farmers and the rural poor. SUFICA will establish a process and infrastructure to re-direct intensification to a more environmentally sensitive trajectory, aiming to reduce farm inputs and protect biodiversity in highly productive landscapes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-05-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-05-09">156539.14</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-05-09">167459.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-05-09">83659.33</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-05-09">30443.85</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The goal of SUFICA is to enhance the competitiveness, sustainability and long term resilience of fruit farming in the S&#xE3;o Francisco Valley in Brazil as it intensifies, through cutting edge research on agricultural ecosystem services and biodiversity. The project will work with growers and international supply companies to co-design and test nature-based innovations on intensive fruit farms, which generate multiple environmental benefits whilst enhancing profitability of farms through improved yield or quality and reduced inputs. The project thus uses an understanding of ecosystem services and functions to support the move away from unsustainable small-scale farm systems.  The project is ground-breaking. It tests ecological intensification using a replicated BACI experimental design, co-developed with the farming community in a specific landscape, to generate long-lasting impact. To our knowledge, this has never been done before.  We have the following objectives:   1. Establish a transnational community of practice focussed on introducing nature-based solutions to secure the long term sustainability of fruit farming in Chile and Brazil. Growers, suppliers, researchers and other stakeholders will meet regularly in the S&#xE3;o Francisco Valley and share information. The group will interact with a similar community in Chile, via shared international buyers, creating a transnational community of practice. This objective includes capacity building, achieved through training producers and technicians.  2. Co-design, experimentally implement and monitor effects of an innovation or set of innovations to enhance farmland biodiversity, biodiversity-based ecosystem services - pollination and carbon sequestration - and crop yield while reducing inputs of water and perhaps also pesticides. The appropriate innovation(s) will be selected by participating farmers and researchers at the second SUFICA workshop, on the basis of existing evidence, feasibility for farmers and fit to farming system. As examples, they might include adding organic matter to the soil, enhancing ground cover, or planting flower strips or hedgerows along field boundaries or irrigation channels.   3. Quantify ecological and agronomic impacts of nature-based innovation on 8 matched pairs of experimental and control farms and their surrounding landscapes. This includes baseline surveys in year 1 and measures of response to innovations in years 2 and 3. Data on biodiversity (plants, vertebrates and invertebrates), ecosystem services (pollination, carbon storage, crop yield) and farm inputs (water and pesticides) will be collected, to characterise the food-water-environment nexus.  4. Construct spatially explicit models to predict responses to nature-based innovations for one ecosystem service (pollination) and one element of natural capital stock (habitat quality). Validate predictions for baselines and responses, using data from objective 3.  5. Develop a globally-recognised online farm biodiversity assessment tool so it is applicable to Latin American farms, in partnership with the Cool Farm Alliance. This can be used by farmers to report and gain credit for efforts to support biodiversity, enhancing relationships with international suppliers.  The underlying scientific hypothesis is that regulating ecosystem services can be co-erced to flow in bundles, and therefore be synergistically enhanced in semi-arid agricultural landscapes by management actions within reach of individual growers. The research will explore mechanisms behind multiple service flows, using state-of-the-art mapping and modelling to predict changes to natural capital stock and ecosystem service delivery.  A parallel aim is to develop and strengthen a multi-actor, trans-disciplinary research community of fruit growers and researchers in the caatinga, which develops its own landscape-scale research infrastructure and outlives the SUFICA project."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
