<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T024801_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fostering Adaptive Governance and Resilience in Local Communities of Central Eurasia: From fragmented pasts to connected futures?</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The cluster has four overarching strategic aims, listed not in order of priority but in terms of sequential steps:: 1) To conceptually refine understandings of the multiple and interconnected fragilities and forms of resilience taking shape in contemporary Central Eurasia, in the face of regional socio-spatial transformations;  2) To conceptually refine ideas of adaptive governance and understandings of partnerships for resilience 3) To pilot methodological toolkits for adaptive governance based on those developed by each project: citizen juries and BBC Question-Time type debates from COMPASS, mediation forums from Gobi and &apos;CommuniTea&apos; from Silk Routes; 4) To make policy change based on best practices and communicate them through regional forums to external and internal decision-makers and other stakeholders  To achieve these it will synthesise and consolidate material from four constituent members including baseline data from &gt;270 interviews across Mongolia and Kyrgyzstan, 40 focus groups and surveys  from Azerbaijan, Belarus, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan, and participatory mappings being done in Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan and Pakistan. It will focus on the themes of fragility, fragmentation, resilience and connectivity in the context of the development of large scale &apos;economic corridors&apos; and transport infrastructures in two countries (in this this first phase call): Svetlogorsk in Belarus; and Angren in Uzbekistan.  It will empirically examine the resilience demonstrated in local communities and the different impacts to look to how to foster adaptive, rather than externally imposed, governance. It will pilot methods from the different projects to examine which might best serve to create room for local participation and representation in governance with key stakeholders in the CA region. It will explore the different potentials and limits for community engagement via citizen juries from COMPASS, mediation from Gobi Mediation Framework and &apos;CommuniTea&apos; participatory mappings practised in Resilient Silk Routes Heritages and Laajverd&apos;s Visiting Schools as response to the fragilities generated by the new infrastructural connectivity projects. Using material and experiences from these it will run workshops and events with local stakeholders (NGOs and policy communities) to surface with them both local issues but also explore with policy makers and practitioners what spaces and processes exist for participatory governance in Eurasia. From this we will develop a possible tool kit of approaches that might enable more adaptive forms of governance that are responsive to local situations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The region of stretching from the border of China to the edge of Europe is marked by a history of long distance trading routes, cultural connections and resulting cultural plurality. It was once the epitome of global trade through the ancient Silk Routes, whose relics dot the landscape. After the collapse of the Soviet Union however this is one of the few areas of the world where intra-regional trade flows have actually declined. States have struggled to fashion themselves with new nationalist imaginaries, under often authoritarian regimes. The fragmentation of (post-)soviet cultural and economic space hardened borders, limited mobility and reinscribed &apos;national&apos; identities rather than cross-regional commonalities.   This situation is rapidly changing as China&apos;s &apos;Belt and Road Initiative&apos; seeks to re-energise the old Silk Routes connecting its less developed West overland to Europe. The result, even before the infrastructure is fully developed, is new sets of hopes and fears in fragile states and societies. This GCRF cluster will map the discrepancies between projected (state-led, top down) infrastructures (and other pressures of globalisation) and imagined futures in the wake of the New Silk Roads.   The effects of these transit-led economic corridors are differentiated between communities , economic sectors, places and genders. They summon up distant connections and global flows, real and imagined, intended and unintended, desired and feared changing the connectedness of once separate places. But they can also disconnect existing local connections, cutting across local transport, they can bring passing trade and passing trouble - where, for instance, the Worldbank reports both of female economic gains but also rising sexual exploitation along highway development in Asia.  This cluster brings together 3 GCRF projects that span 7 countries across central Eurasia. Cumulatively they bring a powerful set of baseline data about changing senses of connectedness in the countries. Together in the cluster they will explore how participatory methods might open ways for more inclusive governance of economic corridors - looking for tools that might work in the cultural and governance contexts of Central Eurasia. We will explore how communities can find ways to articulate their different and clashing spatio-temporal imaginaries of connected futures.   The cluster will focus of two cases in this initial phase of the call - one at the Eastern and one at the Western end of the region. At the Eastern end, Angren in Uzbekistan is a heavy industrial town that suffered decline when Soviet era transport routes across Kazakhstan became international and subject to political barriers. Now a 19.2km Chinese built tunnel and rail link through 3000m mountains connects it to the rest of Uzbekistan promising a new future on E-W economic corridors stretching to the Caucasus, the Arabian Sea and Europe. But leaves it beholden to Chinese transport and flows both legal and illicit. At the Western, Belarus is the gateway for the Eurasian Land Corridor from Central Asia via Russia into Europe. New Chinese led developments in Svetlogorsk, bring the promise of new industries, new markets but also migrants.   The objectives are (i) to pilot communal participatory engagement models in the above-chosen cases, and (ii) to discuss best practice adaptive governance techniques with regional policy communities, in order to develop more sustainable modes of engagement with the wider region - at the local, sub-regional, regional, and international levels - in the future (phase II).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-06">101257.89</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-06">33752.66</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-06">135010.55</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF UKRI Award to Durham University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP/T024801/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">33752.63</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T024801_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">33752.63</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T024801_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=EP%2FT024801%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-06-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
