<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_V004077_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CreativeCulture 4.0 - Transforming 21st century teaching and learning of STEM in Malaysia through creative play and gamification towards Education 4</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to broaden and extend the impact of experiential learning through play and gamification as a creative, emphatic and inclusive pedagogical practice in Malaysia towards Education 4.0 responding to Industry 4.0. The project builds on a previous collaboration between Coventry University(CU) and Universiti Malaysia Sarawak(UNIMAS) via the Newton CreativeCulture project, which has produced a blueprint for Gamification for STEM education that includes a suite of playful pedagogical tools and gamified lessons created by teachers for teachers. We identified that sustainable and effective adoption can be achieved by enabling teachers to embed the approach in the curriculum and the empowerment of schools to review, redesign and progress their practices.  Aligning with (1)UNESCO&apos;s view that teacher upskilling is one of the most direct means to achieve inclusive and equitable quality education and, (2)STEM Education Policy under the Malaysia Education Blueprint (MEB, 2015-2025) that promotes hands-on inquiry, creative designs and open-ended exploration, we will (1)train teachers in partnership with local Departments of Education, (2)engage students with playful and gamified learning in partnership with local teachers and schools, and (3)investigate sustainable formal adoption, engaging with schools, policymakers, community groups and local industries towards informing policy.   Efforts to improve and maintain sustainable growth in economic development towards a developed status hinge on an updated education system that is more creative. Acknowledging that access to inclusive and equitable quality education is still an impending issue at rural areas in Malaysia, CreativeCulture 4.0 will expand our user engagement, build practices, capacity and sustain creative approaches in participating schools and facilitate continuing dialogues with local and national communities towards realising the impact of creative education on economic development and social welfare.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2020-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-29" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="MY" type="MALAYSIA"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-27">37303.95</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-27">37505.41</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Objectvies O1:Map the Gamification for STEM blueprint against the STEM Education Policy,responding to MEB and National Policy on Industry 4.0 to identify commonalities,gaps and opportunities and form intervention and evaluation pathways.   O2: Develop 3-phase pathway (1)onboarding - expand reach through teacher training and capacity building in creating gamified lessons (2)practice building - implement play and gamification in schools (3)consolidation - insights into adoption and sustainability for practice and policy recommendations.   O3: Implement the onboarding phase in partnership with local Departments of Education (4 locations involving at least 100 teachers each)to develop case studies for curriculum adoption(at least 10 case studies).   O4: Facilitate and evaluate the case studies adopted in schools during the practice building phase.   O5: Consolidate findings and practice, engaging schools, policymakers ,local communities and industries towards scientific, practice and policy publication  Outputs:  - Gamification for STEM blueprint (with updated impact case studies) - a working model for adoption in the curriculum  - Open Educational Resources - playful and gamified learning solutions (digital, physical or hybrid) produced through onboarding and practice building phases. Published and downloadable via project website.  - Gamification training framework- adoptable and adaptable for the Malaysia STEM Education agenda  - Scientific articles - on insights and lessons learnt on gamification for STEM, curriculum adoption and potential impact on Education 4.0 and Industry 4.0 (3 conferences and Quartile 1/2 journals).  - Policy dialogues - with schools, policy makers, community groups and local industries  - White papers - practice and policy recommendations on creative STEM education  - Media collection - videos and images, including feedback from the stakeholders to accompany case studies, accessible via the website.  - Press coverage -local and national press (print &amp; broadcast)."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
