<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M002179_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">District Health Management and Public Service Delivery: Evidence from India&apos;s Flagship Health Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is now a strong body of evidence of what interventions are most effective in improving health in low- and middle-income countries but little is known about how to ensure widespread coverage in the population. Weak public service delivery has long been regarded as the key obstacle, particularly in countries with the greatest gaps in service coverage. Nowhere is the issue more salient than India, where the state has struggled to deliver basic public services to its population, despite the presence of elite national institutions and a highly educated top brass of civil servants. One reason for the current status quo is possibly poor managerial quality in the civil service, yet there is almost a complete absence of evidence linking practices in civil service organisations to effective service delivery and outcomes.  The research aims to study the relationship between the management practices civil servants in district health offices operate under and the delivery of health services in Madhya Pradesh, India. We examine this question in the context of the National Rural Health Mission (NRHM), India&apos;s flagship health programme. Three phases of work are envisaged. The first phase (9 months) builds on previous research in economics to develop a tool that will ultimately provide a quantitative measure of managerial quality in our particular setting. The development of the tool will rely on qualitative methods of research to get perspectives from key informants on what dimensions of management are most important for staff productivity, as well as to provide a rich understanding of the bureaucracy in place. The second phase (3 months) involves the collection of management data from health bureaucrats in the 45 districts of Madhya Pradesh. The primary method of data collection will be phone interviews, in which interviewers score districts across a number of different dimensions of management. These will be complemented with face-to-face interviews in a subset of districts for the purposes of validation. In the third phase (6 months), the management practices data will be linked to household and health facility data from the District Level Health Survey to examine whether managerial quality is linked to better implementation of the NRHM and higher coverage of maternal and child health services.   The research has the potential to improve health outcomes by informing government policy on ways to ensure more effective health service delivery. It will lead to greater understanding of management practices in India&apos;s civil service and ultimately better implementation of key government health programmes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2014-09-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="IN" type="INDIA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">689</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-07-10">30474.38</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-07-10">51442.78</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The overall aim of the research is to study the relationship between the management practices civil servants in district health offices operate under and the delivery of health services in India&apos;s public sector. Specifically, there are three research objectives:  1. To develop a tool to measure management practices at the district level in the State of Madhya Pradesh, India 2. To collect data on management practices in all 45 districts of the state, using the newly developed tool 3. To analyse the relationship between district management and public health service delivery by linking the management practice data to secondary sources of data from established surveys"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">-46.65</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M002179_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
