<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_R014957_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF-BBR: West African bioactive plant products: pipeline for maximising potential</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aims.  The overarching aim of this proposal is to promote equitable collaborations between Ghanaian scientists and the global research community in the investigation and development of West African plant materials.  We propose a sustainable resource at KNUST which will hold, catalogue and distribute plant products and information, putting Ghanaian researchers at the centre of an initiative that will not only support and expand research capabilities, but will facilitate commercial development and interactions with regulators and other stakeholders, and in doing so support public health, wellbeing and local socioeconomic development.  This pump-priming activity will promote the identification, organisation, conservation and harnessing of a valuable but fragile Ghanaian natural resource. Importantly, this resource will enable larger scale funding applications to support collaborative research into the safe and sustainable use of plant products for a diverse range of applications, from agricultural products to cosmetics .  These aims were developed in partnership with Ghanaian academics at the University of Cape Coast and the Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology, with input from the Ghanaian Food and Drug Administration.  This gives us added confidence that we are addressing genuine development and research needs.  Objective 1.  Plant product storage and distribution.  To establish a resource to store and distribute bioactive plant products with demonstrated or purported bioactivity.  We are proposing a repository of active materials for research and development, in contrast to herbaria of archived non-recoverable specimens.  These active materials will be made available to the international bioscience community to promote and facilitate high level collaborations.  This resource will be integrated with the database outlined in objective 3.  Objective 2.  Bar-HRM protocol optimisation and training of a Ghanaian researcher. A Ghana based researcher will visit Nottingham for two months for training in Bar-HRM and to optimise protocols on exemplar species before returning to Ghana with equipment and knowledge to establish Bar-HRM capabilities.  Difficulties in identifying processed plant materials have been identified by Ghanaian researchers and regulators as significant barriers to research, commercial development and regulation of plant materials.  Although the approach is robust, protocols will need to be optimised for individual plant species.  Objective 3.  Database to hold information on identities and uses of plant products held.  This will be developed and hosted at the University of Nottingham, but populated by data from users, initially at UCC, KNUST and Nottingham, but ultimately by any member of the global research community.  The database will be built by University of Nottingham research IT staff using powerful yet flexible software based on the MOAS platform to allow secure sharing and archiving of data.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plant products are used traditionally for a huge range of applications, including as insect repellents and insecticides, bird, snake and rodent repellents, natural remedies, tanning agents, food preservatives, cosmetics, fertilizers, herbicides, detergents, paints and dyes.  This is especially true in Ghana and other West African countries, where the biodiversity of the forest ecosystems represents a valuable natural resource that has potential to support economic and social development of the region.  Ghanaian researchers at the University of Cape Coast (UCC) and the Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology (KNUST) are at the forefront of research into West African traditional plant products but international collaboration is essential to maximise the potential of these undoubtedly useful resources.  We have worked closely with academics and regulators in Ghana to identify that a major barrier to effective international collaboration is the absence of coordinated infrastructure to collate and distribute materials and information.  This proposal will provide such infrastructure.  This will enable researchers at KNUST and UCC to establish a sustainable repository of active plant materials in parallel with a web-based, user compiled database of knowledge and information about useful plant species.  The global research community will be able to search for information and request samples to stimulate international collaborations and speed up the development of traditional plant products for the benefit of local communities and beyond.    It will clearly be important to accurately identify the species of the plants used.  This is often difficult, as plant products are typically processed before use, for example by drying or grinding.  We propose to train Ghanaian researchers in DNA identification protocols, and establish this capacity in Ghana for use by academics and regulators in the region and beyond.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghana</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-18">102143.28</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC GCRF BBR Scheme Award to University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB/R014957/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-01">51071.64</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_R014957_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">25535.82</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_R014957_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">5509.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_R014957_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=BB%2FR014957%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-15"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
