<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008458_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shaping policy processes through citizen voice in Francophone West Africa: the arts as a vehicle for knowledge co-construction</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of this network is to understand how far arts and storytelling may be a relevant mode of citizen-policy engagement in West Africa. We ask: can citizens and policy makers co-create understanding about issues of concern through arts and storytelling? If not, can forms of artistic expression, including &apos;told stories&apos;, capture citizens&apos; experience, thereby conveying their concerns in a visceral sense to policy actors? Further, can co-creative storytelling address power relations between policy actors and citizens, as it addresses issues of power between researcher and participant?  We take a transdisciplinary approach to achieve this, linking local knowledge with that of the humanities, social sciences, and policy studies. A major activity is a workshop, where core and wider network members convene. The main objective will be met through a series of sub-objectives: 1: Identify relevant actors The first activity will be a stakeholder mapping activity 2. Understand the potentials for and limitations of using the arts for citizen communication to policy, and when these methods are and are not viable. In a set of interviews, and a discussion in the workshop, we ask the following questions: A. How do citizen-policy relations and concepts of citizenship differ across contexts? B. What forms of artistic and cultural expression; forums and spaces can release transformative power for social change in each context; in particular, what does storytelling mean in each context? C. Which challenges facing societies in the West African Sahel are amenable to analysis by citizens and policy actors through artistic mediums?  D. What may prevent or facilitate artistic expression, storytelling and knowledge co-creation acting as a credible means of policy engagement; what are alternative modes/ roles? 3. Develop proof of concept for a method through which arts may be used to express citizen voice to policy, from a practical workshop activity, resulting in artistic outputs In the workshop, we will trial an activity where policy makers and community members co-create understanding about an issue of mutual concern, through an artistic or creative activity mediated by cultural professionals, for example Photovoice, writing a story, illustrating proverbs, or participatory filmmaking. Outputs of this activity will be processed, by the artistic professionals with the inputs of arts scholars, into finished pieces which can be displayed in public in the workplaces of the network members, and in online spaces. 4. Build a network which is willing to work on the issues explored in this project into the future, and develop a practical plan for how they may do this, and 5. Produce a working paper and policy brief explicating the outputs and making them available to actors beyond the network.  There is a dedicated space in the workshop for developing a plan for forward action. This will be expressed in the project working paper and policy. Those documents will also set out the academic findings, and those relevant to actors beyond the network. 5. Disseminate artistic and academic outputs to a wider public body We will make use of online methods, physical hard copies such as books and posters, radio communication, and word of mouth to disseminate practical and academic findings to the wider public.  6. Raise capacity of the groups involved to engage with such creative activity and use it in their work.  The co-creative experimental activity taking place in the workshop, and the discussion of it, will particularly contribute this this. Interview participation and discussion of the ensuing data will also contribute.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This networking activity convenes research, policy, cultural and community engagement organisations from across Sahelian Francophone West Africa. In this context, many citizens have minimal opportunity to contribute to governance processes, and their voices are seldom heard in deliberative spaces. Meanwhile, creative and artistic methods such as music and drawing have been used elsewhere to represent citizen voice to policy, in ways which could be conceptualised as storytelling, such as photovoice, digital storytelling or participatory filmmaking. Co-creation of such outputs often occurs between participants and researchers. As a rich tradition of storytelling exists in West Africa, this network aims to discover whether artistic and cultural methods can be used similarly here and, going further, whether policy makers themselves can engage with communities and artists to co-create understanding about issues of mutual concern. The core group of interdisciplinary researchers from five research institutions will map policy and civil society stakeholders, as well as arts professionals. A subset will be interviewed to understand the conditions under which artistic co-creation could be possible. A further subset of interviewees will be invited to convene the wider network and participate in a workshop, where the answers to these questions, and to the overall research objective, will be debated.  Part of the workshop will involve an activity where policy makers and community and advocacy representatives attempt to co-create understanding about an issue of concern through a pre-determined but flexible creative activity, facilitated by artists, termed &apos;storytellers&apos; in the context of this activity and workshop.  The answers to questions and the results of the debate will be processed by IDS into a working paper and a policy brief. The artists will work to create a communicable set of outputs from the creative activity. These will be publicised through traditional and modern media, from radio to Instagram. Thereby, awareness of the agenda will be raised among other relevant organisation, who may be able to participate in researching them further, or adapting the techniques trialled in the practical domain. Capacity of the network members will be raised, but through the dissemination activities, the wider public and policy, advocacy and research communities will become aware of the network and the potentials for developing this kind of work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute of Development Studies</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-22">40348.44</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-22">13449.48</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-22">53797.92</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Research Networking Award to Institute of Development Studies</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008458_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute of Development Studies</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FT008458%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
