<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_S013768_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Determining the clinical and environmental impact, burden and cost of Extensively Drug Resistant Enterobacteriaceae in China (DETER-XDRE-CHINA-HUB)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Antimicrobial resistance (AMR) is now deemed to be the biggest global threat facing humanity in the 21C. AMR has taken center stage as a global health issue yet most non-specialists are unaware the impact AMR will have on global populations and the potential it has of taking the treatment of infections back to the &quot;dark ages&quot;. Therefore, in keeping with the general notion of &quot;One World Health&quot;, there clearly needs to a better alignment of thinking and closer co-operation between countries synergizing activities, knowledge and skills to better understand and prevent AMR.   Hitherto, most studies around the world studying the impact of AMR have been small, one dimensional and often biased - too focused on AMR bacteria as oppose to studying the whole bacterial population. Two years ago, we published an article with our Chinese colleagues heralding the breech of the last antibiotic, colisitin, that is used to treat the very serious infections caused by already resistant bacteria such as Escherichia coli (commonly known as E. coli). The difference with this new discovery is that the mechanism of colistin resistance (named MCR-1) is mobile i.e. can be readily passed around from one bacteria to another - even between distantly related bacteria. This article reached global acclaim and has been cited over 1000 times reflecting its broad impact.   Following on from this discovery and using the same network of Chinese colleagues, hospitals, farming and environmental sectors, we intend to use MCR (MCRPE) and carbapenem-resistant Enterobacteriaceae (E. coli and E. coli-like bacteria)(CRE) as markers to understand how AMR has spread throughout the Chinese human and animal populations (colistin is used in animal feed in China). Firstly, we have a comprehensive sampling platform:  work package (WP) 1, normal flora carriage; WP2, primary and secondary care infections; WP3, chicken, duck and pigs including slaughter houses; WP4, flies and wild birds; WP5, Water, soil and waste; WP6, Aquaculture; and WP7, Domestic animals. Pending the type of sample, we will analyze at least 100 samples every 3/6 months to examine seasonal variation and sample from three distinct provinces in China: Shandong, Guangdong and Jiangsu; additionally, we will also chose Qinghai as a control region. Bacteria will be analyzed by basic microbiology techniques and selected to be whole genome sequenced where we can interrogate the bacteria&apos;s whole DNA and compare it to other bacteria to see if they have spread from one sector (e.g. flies) to another (e.g. humans). This study will also sequence bacteria in the human gut (called the microbiome) to understand the dynamics of AMR bacterial populations. We will also undertake controlled experiments in chicken farms to monitor the spread on CRE and MRCPE and use mathematical models to understand how AMR spreads in animals. Importantly, the Chinese government has recently (2017) withdrawn the antibiotic colistin so this study is very timely in measuring that effect i.e. will withdrawing colistin impact on MCRPE rates in the environment, human gut levels and MCRPE causing human infections?    Unlike previous studies, this study is deliberately holistic in its approach to understand the dynamics and transmission of AMR across a broad range of environmental and human sectors. This study will let us understand the impact of CRE and MCRPE on human populations and the burden and cost to the Chinese health system. It will also help us understand the impact AMR on the chicken, duck  and pig trade by using mathematical models. The impact of this study will have immense consequences for the animal, human and economic sectors in China. Our network is well established, high successful and has a proven track record of working together in China and expertise to undertake this exciting and challenging proposal.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project addresses this critical need with the following objectives:   1. Determine the prevalence of CRE/MCRPE and assess the clinical impact (associations and outcomes) of CRE /MCRPE in patients across three Chinese provinces (Shandong, Guangdong and Jiangsu). We will examine UTIs and BSIs as exemplars of primary and secondary infections. With the removal of colistin from Chinese agriculture, we will determine the faecal carriage of MCRPE (and CRE) in Chinese healthy subjects across 4 Chinese provinces (Shandong, Guangdong, Jiangsu and Qinghai [Qinghai as a negative control region]) and the risk factors for AMR carriage (diet, sanitation, profession, proximity to farms etc.). Additionally, we will examine the microbiome of over 400 volunteers from our 4 sampling provinces.    2. Understand the main drivers of CRE/MCRPE transmission between animal production/retail/supply and human primary/secondary care by comparing resistance genes, plasmids and strain types/genomes. We will sequence over 2000 bacterial strains and compare genomes including deposited sequences to understand the aetiology and chronology of CRE/MCRPE in these sectors.         3. Understand the impact of MCRPE on therapeutic colistin use in humans (introduced in 2017) and whether MCR variants mediates clinical resistance. Different MCR types mediate different levels of colistin resistance; therefore which will dominate in Chinese nosocomial settings? We have a network spanning hospital across 34 provinces where we will collect standard clinical data and sepsis samples. For WP2 we will focus on more detailed demographic information and include urinary tract infections as an example of a community acquired infection.   4. Evaluate CRE/MCRPE spread in the Chinese agriculture and aquaculture, and how it is affected by seasonal variation i.e. the impact of flies on CRE/MCRPE dissemination? We will examine the prevalence of CRE and MCRPE in poultry, pigs, fish, shrimp, water and soil. We were the first group to highlight the importance of AMR being disseminated by flies in China and we shall continue to focus on insects as AMR contagion disseminators. This study is unique in that we will examine the Chinese aquaculture industry which are preliminary data indicates is highly contaminated with CRE/MCRPE.       5. Determine how rapidly CRE/MCRPE transmission occurs in chicken houses and commercial fish ponds and what factors influence transmission. We will apply mathematical models to understand the spread of CRE/MCRPE in chickens/fish and the effects of poultry/fish feeds.     6. Investigate the transmission, stability and fitness of common Chinese genes/plasmids transmitted to common local strain-types. We have devised a set of unique mathematical models that, together with genomic &quot;big data&quot; sets will allow us to predict CRE/MCRPEC trends to 2030 etc. These mathematical models are bespoke and will use MCRPE as an exemplar to examine and predict future trends based on resistance &quot;gain&quot; and &quot;loss&quot; using data from both in-vitro experiments and in-vivo models.   7. Develop mathematical fiscal models to predict the socioeconomic impact (dissemination in the animal and humans) of CRE and MCRPE on the Chinese farming and fishing industry, and the Chinese health sector in the medium to long term (2020, 2030).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-21">134443.26</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-21">566122.46</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-21">652489.34</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-21">1845389.06</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to Cardiff University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/S013768/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-01">134443.26</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_S013768_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-04-01">134443.26</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_S013768_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">134443.26</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_S013768_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-01">134443.26</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_S013768_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">162792.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_S013768_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">162792.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_S013768_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-01-01">489696.66</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_S013768_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-07-01">-881396.22</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_S013768_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FS013768%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-02-14"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
