<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003472_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF Resilience to Coupled Human-Natural Multi-hazards Network</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Network will focus on the need and ability to evaluate and increase the resilience to natural-human hazards of increasingly vulnerable populations in the hyper-expanding margins of cities, specifically in Vietnam and more generally in SE Asia.   The focus is aimed at the GCRF challenge &quot;resilience to environmental shocks and change&quot;, and directly supports key SDG targets within SDG 11 (Sustainable Communities and Cities)  and the implementation of the Sendai Framework for Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR). The Network will tackle specific targets 11.5 and 11.B, which respectively address the need to significantly reduce the loss of lives and livelihoods caused by disasters while protecting vulnerable populations, and substantially increase the number of cities and human settlements adopting and implementing integrated policies and plans towards mitigation and adaptation to climate change, resilience to disasters, and to develop and implement holistic disaster risk management at all levels. Similar challenges arise in SDG 13.1 (climate change and its impacts).  The environment within which coupled natural-human hazards occur and the people and institutions that are impacted by hazardous events comprise a complex physical and social system characterized by interactions across a range of time and spatial scales. Understanding how to increase the system resilience to adverse events means bringing all vested groups to the same table at the same time. This strategy allows Network members to both inform be informed about each other&apos;s perspectives, methodologies, and language, to understand and reveal assumptions and to generate a common articulation of a resilience plan or framework.  We will do this by developing a Network constituency that includes: researchers, decision and policy makers, managers (land-use, disaster, etc.), planners (city, rural, etc.), community leaders (particularly minority and historically under-represented communities), developers (private sector), investment banks, re/insurance, small and medium business enterprises (SMEs), and DRR specialists. And within &quot;researchers&quot;, we include the fields of complex systems, environmental historical analysis, cultural policy, socio-economic processes, behavioural sciences, psycho-visual arts, ecosystem services, environmental physical science, etc. This marriage of disciplines allows us to cross cultural contexts in both the vulnerable population and in the institutions that have responsibility for the management of natural hazards and - significantly - institutions responsible for ostensibly non-hazard issues (e.g. energy, industrial development, etc.). The long time-scales to be examined combined with the broad range of stakeholders will enable us to examine the role of culture and policy and trade-offs evident in the need for economic development.  The Network will add value to existing knowledge largely through the integration of researchers and stakeholders and through the atypically broad church of research disciplines to be engaged, which we demonstrate in the initial and committed membership.   We will deliver our objectives through three workshops (and related activities). The first will provide a forensic examination of selected disasters that will serve as the context of the second critical workshop that allows Network members to effectively teach other members about their perspectives, methodologies, language and assumptions.  A third workshop will present a synthesis (a road-map that articulates a common resilience approach or plan) to high-level decision makers from relevant cities in SE Asia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The current proposal is about developing a global network that will focus on the need and ability to evaluate and increase the resilience to natural-human hazards of increasingly vulnerable populations in the hyper-expanding margins of cities, specifically in Vietnam and more generally in SE Asia. The objectives are to tackle principally the UN Sustainable Development Goal 11 (Sustainable Communities and Cities) and specifically targets 11.5 and 11.B by:   1. developing a broad range of Network members from each of the impacted communities (government disaster management and research, relevant NGOs, government development and planning agencies (i.e. ostensibly unrelated to the impact of hazards)), including relevant researchers from both science and non-science disciplines (e.g. cultural policy, environmental history, etc.).   2. working towards an articulation of a resilience plan (or framework) that is co-designed by the Network membership and that acknowledges the diverse range of needs, approaches, and inevitable trade-offs among stakeholders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-22">18847.05</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-22">75540.86</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-22">56999.22</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">18847.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003472_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VIGMR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">18847.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003472_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VIGMR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">18847.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003472_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VIGMR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">18847.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003472_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VIGMR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
