<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T013389_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Identification of novel mechanisms of fetal-haemoglobin induction by common genetic variation in patients with sickle cell disease</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim to discover the molecular mechanisms by which benign common DNA variants at two genetic sites, BCL11A and HBS1L-MYB, influence fetal haemoglobin levels in adults. Fetal haemoglobin (HbF) is the oxygen-carrying molecule dominating red blood cells in the unborn. It is switched off around the time of birth and replaced with the adult form of haemoglobin. Since in patients with sickle cell disease (SCD) adult haemoglobin is defective, the ability of some adult patients to produce the fetal form will make the disease significantly milder. Much knowledge has been accumulated regarding the structure and function of the BCL11A and HBS1L-MYB sites. The HbF-affecting genetic variants reside in gene-regulating elements called &apos;super-enhancers&apos; that control the activity of neighbouring genes in red blood cell precursors and thus affect their development and haemoglobin content. Little is known about how the naturally-occurring DNA changes affect the function of these &apos;super-enhancers&apos;. Here, we aim to uncover novel regulatory pathways and identify transcription factors binding to genetically-variable enhancer elements. This will add to the arsenal of targets for new therapeutic approaches aiming at reactivating HbF in patients. In addition to guiding new gene therapy strategies, our results will help laying the groundwork for the development of new affordable drugs to benefit the patients suffering from SCD mainly in low-and-middle income countries, especially Africa, where more than 200,000 affected children are born annually. In the UK, the disease is present mostly through the African diaspora and shows significant clinical diversity, partially driven by the variable, genetically-determined presence of HbF.  Our experimental strategy will build on three major resources generated through collaboration: (1) four ethnically-diverse groups of well-characterised patients (n &gt; 3,000) from the UK, Tanzania and Nigeria, where we will assemble extensive genetic data; (2) access to 2,000 genetically and haematologically characterised subjects from the TwinsUK cohort, where we will be able to obtain progenitor cells from 16 individuals with specific genetic profiles at BCL11A and HBS1L-MYB and (3) red blood cell producing cell lines carrying individual critical DNA variants generated through genome editing of the red blood cell-producing cell line BEL-A in collaboration with its creator, Prof Jan Frayne. Our principal goals are: (1) to genetically and functionally dissect common genetic variability at the two major quantitative trait loci for fetal-haemoglobin levels, BCL11A and HBS1L-MYB in order to unravel potentially novel molecular mechanisms through which genetic variation controls gene expression, determines HbF levels and influences the generation of red blood cells. A post-doctoral researcher recruited from our collaborators in Tanzania or Nigeria will investigate transcription factor binding (the techniques used will be EMSA - &apos;electrophoretic mobility shift assays&apos;, ChIP - &apos;chromatin immunoprecipitation&apos;) and chromatin looping (a folding of the DNA that occurs in active cells to position regulatory elements next to their target genes, the technique we will use is called &apos;4C-seq&apos;) and gene activity in relationship with the genotype of the cells studied. (2) to identify the causal DNA changes at three independent subloci (HMIP-1, HMIP-2B, BCL11A-2) of the above through a combination of genetic mapping and functional studies. From these we will create a genetic score that can be calculated for each patient, aimed at predicting HbF levels and clinical severity in sickle cell disease. This score will become a parameter ascertained in genetic and clinical studies, including drug trials, helping to make such studies more informative; (3) to help build capacity and expertise for sickle cell research in Tanzania and Nigeria through training of researchers and building of extensive genetic datasets for their patient cohorts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim to understand a critical disease-alleviating biological system for sickle cell disease (SCD), the variable persistence of fetal haemoglobin in adults. SCD is a major public-health concern for LMIC regions, especially Sub-Saharan Africa and the novel regulatory pathways identified are intended to ultimately lead to therapeutic targets for HbF induction and the development of new affordable drugs. Our work will also help to understand fundamental erythroid biology and globin gene regulation as well as the effects of human common genetic variation occupying super-enhancer structures.  (1) We will genetically and functionally dissect common genetic variability at the two major quantitative trait loci for fetal-haemoglobin (HbF) levels, BCL11A (prioritised on the likely driver variant rs1427407) and HBS1L-MYB (prioritised on the (HMIP-1 sublocus, which has an unknown function) in order to unravel potentially novel molecular mechanisms through which driver alleles control gene expression, determine HbF levels and influence erythropoiesis.  Specifically, we will  - evaluate transcription factor binding at rs1427407 and key variants at HMIP-1 in silico and through EMSA and ChIP assays;  - investigate chromatin structure (&apos;looping&apos; of regulatory elements onto target gene promoters) by 4C-seq to find which gene or regulatory structure HMIP-1 interacts with and which parts of the locus are functionally active;  - assess the downstream effects of functional genetic variants on gene activity (BCL11A, MYB, HBS1L and globin genes) through qPCR and HPLC;  - establish two erythroid cell systems for above functional studies: (1) primary erythroid cell cultures from individuals carrying trait-relevant variant haplotypes at HMIP-1 and (2) create genome-edited versions of the human erythroid cell line BEL-A that carry alleles for rs1427407 and individual critical variants at HMIP-1 as homozygous genotypes.  (2) We will identify and evaluate novel driver alleles at three independent subloci (HMIP-1, HMIP-2B, BCL11A-2) of the above through a combination of genetic mapping in diverse ethnic groups and above functional studies, i.e.,  - utilise existing genome-wide SNP data from a UK (n=930) and a Tanzanian (n=1,400) group of patients with sickle cell disease and create new such datasets for two Nigerian patient groups (n=500 each) by array genotyping with the H3Africa chip and subsequent imputation;  - perform genetic association testing (adjusting for the effect of known covariates and population structure) with all common genetic variants in above three subloci and identify one or several candidate driver variants for each;  - use these results to guide subsequent studies to confirm their functional significance (EMSA, ChiP assays);  - create an advanced polygenic score from a combination of driver and sentinel genetic variants for the determination of HbF levels and clinical severity in sickle cell disease. This score is intended to be used to increase the power and informativity of clinical and genetic studies in Africa and elsewhere.  (3) We will help build capacity and expertise for sickle cell research with collaborating groups in Tanzania and Nigeria. Specifically, we will  - employ a post-doctoral researcher from Tanzania or Nigeria to perform the functional studies over three years  - host two further trainees for from either country for 5 weeks each  - train post doc and trainees in the statistical analysis of complex genetic traits  - provide our Nigerian collaborators with curated genome-wide SNP datasets for their patient cohorts, to be used in further studies and international collaborations (ownership of these data will be transferred to them after the three years of the project);  - create training material to be disseminated subsequently through existing mechanisms (workshops, online facilities), funded through the Sickle Pan African Consortium (SPARCO), SickleInAfrica, H3ABioNet and SickleGenAfrica.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000297" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-12">733814.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/T013389/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000297">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">60658.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T013389_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000297">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">60658.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T013389_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000297">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">60658.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T013389_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000297">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FT013389%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-03-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
