<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_P006167_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assessing the potential of civil organizations within regions affected by organized crime to hold state institutions to human rights-based development</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Although scholars and analysts suspect that civil society has the potential to mitigate the effects of criminal violence, few have conducted substantial research on the topic, and they have focused mainly on national (and international) civil organizations. We propose to focus on civil organizations based in the affected regions themselves, specifically within the west-central Mexican states of Michoac&#xE1;n and Jalisco, a region with high levels of criminal violence.  It is increasingly recognized that treating organized crime as a matter of security is insufficient and can even exacerbate the problem, and that organized crime must be addressed through holistic strategies that include development consistent with human rights, providing opportunities for a dignified economic, social and political life outside the sphere of criminal organizations. In the state of Michoac&#xE1;n, for example, after &quot;self-defence&quot; vigilante groups ousted local police accused of serving organized crime in 2014, the federal government established a Commission for Security and Integral Development promising to deliver equitable and participative development to the region.  Yet holistic strategies are notoriously difficult to execute when, as often in Mexico, state institutions in the affected regions are captured, wholly or partially, by the same criminal organizations and their associates. In these contexts, criminal organizations can for example use their hold over local (and state) government to frustrate the designs of national government, as well as of international agencies.  Researchers and policy-makers suspect that civil society has an important role to play in these contexts. Civil society can monitor the actions of state institutions, insist on participating in development projects, resist development that hurts or fails to benefit vulnerable groups, and advocate strategies that do meet the needs of the broader population, thus helping to offset the hold of criminal organizations over those institutions, as well as creating alternative livelihoods for the population. However, although there have been some studies of the role of national (and international) civil society in holding state institutions to account, the potential role of civil organizations within the regions themselves is little studied. This is our focus.  The few studies conducted, and initial research by the applicants, suggest that civil society organizations are often themselves hemmed in by organized crime, and find it difficult to resist penetration by organized crime, much less to advance an agenda contrary to its interests. This helps to account, indeed, for the reluctance of many researchers to conduct sustained fieldwork in these contexts.  Despite the forbidding panorama, the project will use comparative ethnography, following strict protocols designed to mitigate risk to researchers and research subjects, to identify and explain positive examples of organizations which have played an effective role in holding state institutions to a human rights agenda, and specifically one designed to offset the noxious effects of organized crime activities.  Project outputs will include an academic monograph co-authored by Guerra (CIDE), Maldonado (Colegio de Michoac&#xE1;n) and Stack (Aberdeen), and a volume edited by Stack to include papers from an international conference in London and others chapters co-authored by the applicants with the postdoctoral RAs.  Unusually for an academic research project, we have chosen to put the policy outputs on an equal footing with the academic outputs. To this end, we have incorporated 2 policy analysts Domingo (ODI) and Jesperson (RUSI) as Co-Investigators. We have followed their instructions from the outset to ensure that the data collection and analysis will be adequate to the task of producing a series of well-grounded policy briefs, applicable to other regions of Mexico (and the world) affected by criminal violence.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our aim is to assess through comparative ethnography in Mexico the role of civil organizations based within regions affected by criminal violence. We will consider whether and how civil organizations are holding state institutions to the goals of human rights-based development, in a way that could lead to a reduction in criminal violence as well as broader social justice.  In order to achieve this general aim, we propose the following specific objectives:  1. We will a) study through ethnographic fieldwork a range of civil organizations based within the west-central Mexican states of Michoac&#xE1;n and Jalisco, one of the regions most affected by criminal violence; b) identify which of these organizations are effectively monitoring and putting pressure on state institutions, with a view to human rights-based development, and c) explain through interviews and participant observation what makes these civil organizations able and willing to play such a role. 2. By conducting fieldwork in 7 sub-regions of the broader region, and comparing the results, we will reach a set of conclusions sufficient to ground context-sensitive policy recommendations about the potential of regionally-based civil organizations to contribute to holistic strategies to mitigate criminal violence and achieve a more just and secure society. 3. As academic outputs, a) Guerra, Maldonado and Stack will co-author an academic monograph in Spanish and English, and b) Stack will edit a volume of chapters selected from papers given an international conference in London (February 2018), as well as chapters that the applicants will co-author with each other and with the postdoctoral RAs. 4. As policy outputs, Co-Investigators Domingo (ODI) and Jesperson (RUSI) will draft a series of policy briefs, which the team will evaluate through further fieldwork and a policy-makers&apos; workshop, before disseminating them to a range of stakeholders including development actors and regionally-based civil organizations.  The project has an additional aim of building capacity among the individual researchers and their institutions, including by sharing expertise in writing policy briefs that meet global standards, managing inter-sectoral collaboration by including policy analysts on the research team, and developing innovative protocols for risky research.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-13" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-03">113768.42</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-03">231716.23</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-03">195042.03</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
