<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P007775_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development and Intellectual Property: The Impact of Seed Exchange and Replacement on Innovation among Small-Scale Farmers in India</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One of the major challenges facing global development is the question of how to arrange the laws and customs surrounding intellectual property (IP) in order to encourage innovation. Bringing together Radick&apos;s theoretical and conceptual work on IP over the long-run of the history of science and technology, Kochupillai&apos;s legal-empirical studies of IP and innovation concerning plant varieties in India, and the resources of the Art of Living Foundation, this project will study a sample of innovative Indian farmers in order to explore the comparative advantages and disadvantages of two ways of organising innovation in a developing nation.    Indian farmers have traditionally participated in an informal culture of keeping seeds season after season (seed saving) and of swapping seeds (seed exchange), and under this system, new varieties have periodically emerged and been cultivated. More recently, the Indian government has promoted a different system, changing the law to give enhanced IP protection to scientifically derived varieties from state-run institutions or private firms, and encouraging farmers to replace their seed stocks regularly (seed replacement) by purchasing seeds from the marketplace. A key question is whether this increasing promotion of policies of seed replacement and IP regimes that have &quot;exclusivity&quot; as their basic underlying rationale could have a negative effect on cultures of sharing, and therefore on seed-related innovations, among farmers in rural India.  The possibility of such an effect was dramatized by the case of the Indian farmer Dadji Ramji Khobragade. Collecting seeds and replanting them year on year, he eventually developed a new rice variety which became popular throughout the region. As is typical of the culture among small farmers of the regions, Khobragade was happy to share his seeds with farmers from other villages. But when university researchers took his seeds to conduct experiments, and four years later released an improved variety, they did not credit Khobragade.  Furthermore, under a law governing intellectual property (IP) and plant varieties, Khobragade was not entitled to any share of the profits from the sale of this new variety.  The project will have three phases. In the first phase, a project researcher based partly at the University of Leeds and partly at the Max Planck Institute for Innovation and Competition in Munich, will undertake systematic background study of the relevant scholarly literatures while at the same time using the Plant Variety Application database (freely available from the Plant Authority of India) to identify Indian farmers for interview.  The second phase will be a two-month field study in India, travelling from region to region in order to conduct in-depth interviews with innovative farmers - that is, farmers who have registered new plant varieties - in order to learn their views and experiences regarding the different cultures of IP surrounding Indian plant-variety innovation, as well as the related impacts on agricultural biodiversity. The researcher will also speak on local/regional radio in India to publicise the project.  In the third phase the researcher will return to Leeds to process the interview data and produce a journal article, one or more articles for trade journals etc., and a report for the Foundation. Throughout the project the researcher will use social media, the Foundation&apos;s website and related means to promote the project&apos;s findings.    The project will end with a conference taking place in Bangalore and involving the project team, farmers, policy-makers and plant breeders. With the UN having recently released a report (http://unctad.org/en/PublicationsLibrary/ditcted2012d3_en.pdf) stressing the importance of small-scale sustainable farming to the future of agriculture and the environment around the world, this research is particularly pertinent, and has relevance for small farmers and agriculture internationally.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-11-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="IN" type="INDIA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">689</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-19">48209.75</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="(1) To investigate the historical and scientific evolution of the culture of seed exchange/saving amongst small farmers in India, looking in particular at how, why and when the more recent concept of seed replacement - tied to the market purchase of seeds from commercial breeders, and new governmental policies on intellectual property (IP) protection of plant varieties - gained traction. More precisely, the project will examine:  -- How seed exchange/saving culture affects farmer-level innovation in the production of new varieties of plants, and relatedly how the Indian government&apos;s seed replacement policy and its recently adopted IP protection regime, the Protection of Plant Varieties and Farmers&apos; Rights Act, 2001 (PPV&amp;FR Act), affects innovation. -- The ways in which the goals and policies underlying the PPV&amp;FR Act affect in situ agrobiodiversity conservation. -- The relationship between seed exchange/seed sharing culture and in situ conservation and improvement of crop species (from a historical, philosophical and scientific perspective). -- The relationship between the above and a number of growing crises in international agriculture, including a rise in farmer suicides (a notable problem in India) and the dwindling numbers of young people willing to take up a way of life increasingly seen as mere, indeed menial, labour.      The findings of this research -- and especially their bearing on global development, intellectual property, and the importance of securing a role for sustainable small-scale farming in the future of agriculture (highlighted in a 2013 UN report, http://unctad.org/en/PublicationsLibrary/ditcted2012d3_en.pdf) -- will be disseminated to small farmers, breeders and agricultural policy-makers via the extensive network of contacts provided by the project partner, the India-based NGO the Art of Living Foundation (http://projects.artofliving.org/), through a conference at the end of the project.    (2) To examine the changing dynamics of seed sharing/exchange and seed replacement among farmers in India as a case study within the broader theoretical and conceptual study of IP, drawing in an integrated way on PI Radick&apos;s recently introduced analytic framework for studying interactions between different forms of IP and co-I Kochupillai&apos;s expertise in the legal and ethical dimensions of IP regimes governing plant variety innovation, with particular attention to:  -- How various forms of IP enable bodies of scientific knowledge to gain credit for producing true, useful knowledge; -- How different conceptions of IP and implementations of IP regimes influence innovation in different areas of knowledge production; -- The ways in which such case studies can contribute to the IP-narrow/IP-broad research programme by suggesting, for example, new types of ownership claims which can usefully be placed within the open-ended IP-broad category.  This research will be made available to the international academic community through an article in a high-impact peer-reviewed journal, such as the world-leading journal Research Policy.  (3) To provide new models of best practice in two major arts-and-humanities research areas relevant to global development:  -- Collaborations between arts-and-humanities academics, small farmers, agricultural policymakers and development NGOs which could be employed in other national contexts to benefit innovation and agrobiodiversity.  -- Academic research into the impact of IP regimes on innovation in other national or historical contexts.  (4) To promote the visibility of the project and enable other interested organisations to engage with it, notably through social media, radio appearances, and publications in trade journals etc.  (5) To offer a forum for sharing expertise and experience with academics, farmers or policy-makers around the world interested in the project&apos;s work on IP and innovation."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">48209.75</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P007775_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">32642.43</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P007775_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
