<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P023894_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development &amp; validation of a scalable mobile platform for screening of developmental neuropsychiatric disorders in low-resource settings</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to achieve the following objectives: 1) To develop a scalable, modular and extensible mobile platform that will use a combination of parent report and direct child assessment to detect probable cases of Autism Spectrum Disorders (ASD) in children aged 2-5 years 2) To create a pipeline for systematic curation and analysis of data generated through the platform. 3) To assess the usability, acceptability, and utility of the platform, delivered by non-specialist health workers in naturalistic environments (home or routine health-care settings) 4) To consolidate institutional capacity and partnerships within India and with the UK for research on improving the detection and diagnosis of neuropsychiatric disorders.  1) Mobile platform development for parent report and direct child assessment data collection Parent assessment: We have validated in India autism screening tools such as the Social Communication Disorder Checklist  (SCDC) and the Neurodevelopmental Screening Tool (NDST). These tools will be adapted for delivery on a mobile platform (Android). To facilitate parent report, these questionnaire measures will be supplemented with a video-based checklist depicting typical and ASD-related behaviours. Child assessment: In contrast to typically developing children, children with ASD on average take longer to disengage their attention from prior stimuli, and do not prefer social stimuli (e.g. faces) over nonsocial ones. Children will be tested for response to stimuli that capture these sensory-perceptual and social-behavioural aspects of autism. Eye-tracking, a promising technology for assessing ASD risk, will be used to measure overt attention as indexed by gaze. Additionally parent-child interaction will be videotaped and coded for signs of atypical behaviour. Eye-tracking tasks are usually presented on desktop displays in controlled settings. We will optimise task parameters for delivery on smaller, mobile platforms through iterative pilot testing. Parent report and child assessments will then be integrated into the same mobile platform, and pilot-tested in naturalistic environments with iterative refinement to optimize usability, acceptability, and utility.  2) Creation of a data transfer, storage, and analysis pipeline for the mobile platform Data will be uploaded through a secure link to a central data repository, where they will be curated and analysed. This pipeline will enable subsequent combination of data streams from large-scale studies, to build and optimise probabilistic classifiers for autism diagnosis and assessing need for referral to specialised diagnosis and care.  3) Evaluation of usability, utility, and validity of the mobile platform As proof of principle, the mobile platform will be used to collect a data (eyetracking, behaviour, questionnaires) from 120 children and their parents in and around Delhi (equal numbers of ASD, typically developing children and those with intellectual disability (ID) but no ASD. This data will analysed to assess the usability and utility of the mobile platform to end-users, as well as its validity in discriminating between the different groups of children.  4) Strengthening partnerships in global mental health This collaboration of world-class institutions in the UK and India capitalises on an interdisciplinary team of neuroscientists, public health researchers, clinicians, and computer scientists, representing an ideal combination of experience and expertise in eye-tracking, autism screening, portable computer-based interventions, and the conduct of large-scale population-based mental health studies in India. In the long term, this partnership will form the foundation of an ongoing programme of applied research to translate neuroscientific findings into scalable tools for detection of neuropsychiatric disorders in low-resource settings, and will establish an international research network that builds research capacity in LMIC institutions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Worldwide, 1 in 161 children are diagnosed or diagnosable with Autism Spectrum Disorders (ASD). In India, our own study found a prevalence just over 1% in children aged 2 to 9 years. Although parents may notice ASD symptoms as early as 24 months, social and economic barriers to access to qualified health personnel mean that most of these children do not receive early diagnosis or intervention - or indeed any diagnosis or intervention at all. Moreover, many parents are unaware of age-appropriate developmental milestones and therefore clinical opinion is sought only when symptoms become obvious and impossible to ignore. This avoidable delay is an unfolding tragedy in light of evidence showing that front-line worker-delivered, parent-mediated interventions (e.g. PASS) lead to better behavioural and social outcomes. Scalable methods to flag up probable ASD would promote early referral to scarce specialist diagnostic facilities, connecting families with affordable, scalable, community-based interventions. We will realise this goal by developing a low-cost mobile screening platform (&apos;Screening Tools for Autism Risk using Technology&apos; (START)) usable in the home or in a routine health facility by the same non-specialist health workers who deliver PASS or other front-line interventions.  START will collect data from multiple sources. First, parents will be asked simple questions about their child&apos;s everyday behaviour, based on established questionnaires that have been validated in the Indian cultural context. To help parents identify and report subtle abnormalities, these questions will be supplemented by videos illustrating typical versus ASD behaviours. This video-enabled questionnaire will be delivered on a tablet PC. Second, low-cost eye-tracking technology on the same tablet PC will be used to monitor the child&apos;s eye movements in simple tasks, such as those assessing preference for social versus non-social images, and measuring how quickly attention shifts to new objects appearing on the screen. Finally, a segment of parent and child interaction will be recorded using the inbuilt camera, and used to code for signs of atypical behaviour. This combination of multiple measures will provide independent channels of data collected on a single platform, potentially improving on current screening methods that rely on one technique solely. Combining these techniques becomes especially important in a setting where challenges such as poor awareness about ASD may impact on parent reporting of abnormal behaviour (for example, parents may not have noticed that their child avoids direct gaze).  START&apos;s central innovation is its integration with existing front-line workers in LMICs, by adapting methods successfully employed in high income countries (HICs) to LMIC environments and resources. By virtue of its design to require minimal training, it will promote task-shifting - a concept the World Health Organization defines as &quot;a process of delegation whereby tasks are moved, where appropriate, to less specialized health workers&quot; and thus will reach wider populations. This task-shifting approach reduces the burden on the small number of highly-skilled mental-health professionals in LMICs, who then are free to focus on confirming diagnoses and prescribing appropriate interventions which, in turn, can also be delivered by non-specialist workers. The resulting enhancement to detection of ASD may also help develop community awareness and, in the longer term, address the barrier of low demand for services in these areas.  The development and application of the START platform involves collaborations across the breadth of basic and applied sciences - including public health research, technology, clinical psychology and neuroscience, and will be led by world-class institutions in the UK and India. Such global partnerships will build research capacity in India to bridge these wide detection gaps for neuropsychiatric disorders in low resource settings.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-06">251346.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-06">190037.19</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-06">504729.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Reading</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/P023894/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-01">62836.7333333333</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P023894_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-01">62836.7333333333</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P023894_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-01">62836.7333333333</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P023894_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-01">62836.7333333333</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P023894_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-01">63345.7333333333</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P023894_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-01">63345.7333333333</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P023894_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">63345.7333333333</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P023894_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">18459.0166666667</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P023894_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FP023894%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
