<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S015825_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gendered Violence and Urban Transformation in India and South Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Though empirical evidence suggests that gendered violence is one of most important crises facing women across the globe, it has received surprisingly little attention through rigorous qualitative analysis of its contexts and their drivers. Although there is more attention being brought to gendered violence with the rise of a global #MeToo and associated movements, grounded and historically informed research has never been more urgent. Research in this area is currently fragmented across disparate fields such as criminology, public health, and demography, and lacks an integrated conceptual and theoretical framework. The prevalent emphasis on large survey data and epidemiological approaches, moreover, needs to be balanced by qualitative methodological approaches aimed at generating contextual, granular data that can address the local manifestations of a global problem.  The objectives of the proposed research are:  1. To take forward an ambitious project of &apos;second wave&apos; research on violence - specifically in this project sexual violence and domestic interpersonal violence  - that emphasizes historically contextual and granular data, with comparative and sociological of analysis. The emphasis on mechanisms of violence in specific cases and localized environments will be linked to urban transformation, inequality and emerging gender/racial/ethnic/class relations through a multi-scalar research design.  2. To develop a toolkit for future impact-oriented research that combines historical and comparative research on gendered violence, using ethnography, archival, documentary methods, participatory observation, and life history interviews.  3. To build upon epidemiological and quantitative research on violence through closer attention to the complex mechanisms that translate subjectivities and risk into acts of violence.  4. To focus on the multiple determinants of violence against women in the two major cities of Delhi NCR and Johannesburg which are located in countries (India and South Africa) which exemplify the trends we are examining. In particular, to focus on how historically sedimented, unequal city infrastructures, intersecting social inequalities, forms of state categorisation and policing, and moral economies play a role in violence against women.  5. To critically interrogate existing tropes in each of these cases of the &apos;frustrated male&apos;, &apos;cultures of violence&apos;, and exceptionalist theories that underpin popular accounts and imaginaries of violence in the two cities (and countries), and thereby influence attempts to reduce violence through informed, empirical research in different settings.  6. To capture the experiences of transition - from apartheid to post-apartheid, and liberalization in South Africa, and from state-led development to neoliberalization as manifested in urban India, and explore how the attendant shifts in security, ownership, rights, dispossession, and value are manifested in episodes and enactments of gendered violence in the two cities.  7. To generate systematic, comparative insights about the effects of urban transformation on the experience of gendered violence in the two cities though intense focus on specific neighbourhoods - Alex/Sandton in Johannesburg and Gurgaon within Delhi NCR (and neighbouring peri-urban villages), locating these neighbourhoods in the wide range of social relations that tie them to the often wealthy adjoining neighbourhoods, and the rest of the city.  8. To develop a new cohort of early career researchers trained in qualitative methods to address issues of gendered violence across different countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Violence against women affects almost 1 in 3 women across the world, and many scholars claim that it has risen over the past 20 years. This violence takes various forms ranging from rape, intimate/domestic partner violence, including emotional, financial, and physical abuse, female infanticide, sex-selective abortion, forced trafficking, and sexual harassment. These forms of violence affect women in families, workplaces, police custody, educational institutions, and various public spaces. The field of study on violence against women is currently fragmented across disciplines such as criminology, public health, and demography. The data and methodology of a large number of influential studies tends to be based on surveys and big data, although qualitative studies are increasingly common. These studies have filled a crucial gap by highlighting risk factors such as alcoholism, abusive family history, poverty, lack of basic infrastructure among others. However, with few notable exceptions there is a paucity of studies that demonstrate the mechanisms that translate risk factors into actual acts of violence, that build comparisons across specific cases, and that situate both the presence of violence and responses to it, in national, regional and local histories of gender formation.  Our research will push the frontiers of a &apos;second wave&apos; of research on violence by moving in the direction of deeper and more complex theorising of violence, of its causes and motivating factors. The two urban cases Delhi that are the focus of this project - Delhi NCR (India) and Johannesburg (South Africa) - have acquired a reputation for very high levels of sexual violence, both private and public. As cities within countries undergoing rapid transition - post-apartheid liberalisation in South Africa, and state-led development to economic liberalisation and Hindu nationalism in India - gender relations and enactments of violence in these countries have multiple, inter-related causes that vary across caste, class, race, and region. We will ask whether and how factors such as racial or class inequality, poverty, or other environmental, contextual and historical factors make a difference to actual enactments of violence - sexual and interpersonal - against women. How does urban transformation affect gender relations, women&apos;s autonomy, and the perceived clash between &apos;tradition&apos; and &apos;modernity&apos;? To answer these questions requires time-consuming and painstaking qualitative research, with long-term immersion in the field. Such immersion will elicit the deeper mechanisms beneath correlating factors such as class and violence, and allow us to better understand whether and how poverty, racism or other structural factors enable violence in particular families, or individuals&apos; lives, and furthermore to develop a better understanding of invisibilised middle-class gendered violence.  To understand the complex dynamics of violence requires an appreciation of how these major transformations are manifested in everyday life, and why in these daily rhythms of life, violence against women becomes so prevalent. The innovation of this project is the use qualitative methodologies requiring immersion of the researchers in the daily life of specific neighbourhoods, while at the same time looking at how local and national state agencies and policies frame the problem of gendered violence. The the project will seek to compare the particular insights from the two cities, to draw broader conclusions about the effects of globalisation and urban transformation on gender relations and violence.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-07" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-06" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-21">117007.89</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-21">351971.43</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-21">118911.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-21">119873.99</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-21">1535372.506</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S015825_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FS015825%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
