<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P022677_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Genomic approaches to increasing resilience in oilseed rape seedling establishment in the Yangtze River basin</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In China poverty is present predominantly in rural regions where annual incomes still depend heavily on returns from crops. A key cause of poverty is financial stress resulting from poor yields, which increasingly are affected by stochastic occurrence of extreme weather, particularly drought and flooding. The Yangtze River Basin is a globally-significant rapeseed growing area, using so-called semi-winter varieties drilled in the hot and seasonally dry month of September and harvested the following year. Around 14 million hectares are under drought stress (20 times the entire UK planting area), and drought during germination and seedling establishment is particularly detrimental to yields. Climate change is threatening rapeseed growing in the Yangtze River Basin because it is both increasing September temperatures, and increasing the frequency and duration of droughts. These conditions are hostile for seed germination and seedling growth, and can even induce dormancy and prevent germination altogether. To continue cultivation it will therefore be important to produce new varieties with enhanced tolerance to heat and drought stress during germination and early seedling growth. In the modern genomic era the availability of large genotyped populations is greatly accelerating the process of linking traits to individual genes and markers. The principal bottleneck for gene discovery has become our ability to perform smart high throughput phenotyping under relevant conditions for revealing crop properties. This proposal aims to exploit a new phenotyping platform at JIC which automates seed germination, root and shoot growth measurements and increases the frequency of scoring from the traditional once per day to once per hour. We aim to optimise conditions on the platform to mimic the temperature regime and water potential of the Yangtze River catchment in September and screen oilseed rape varieties for germplasm with enhanced ability to germinate and establish effectively under stressful conditions. We will then use statistical tools to identify genes and markers underlying the beneficial traits, and the identity of these genes will be used to form and test hypotheses for the underlying biological mechanisms. We aim to use one European population and one Chinese population derived from a F1 rapeseed variety developed by our partners in the Oilseed Crop Research Institute (OCRI), Wuhan, that will shortly be released onto the Chinese market. This use of elite close-to-market germplasm maximises our chances of translating initial discoveries into new varieties in the shortest possible time window. In order to understand whether improved material has a chance of mitigating climate change impacts it is also necessary to produce a theoretical framework that links crop establishment performance to weather variation. To do this we will produce hydrothermal time models of rapeseed establishment, modelling existing varieties and our best germplasm under Chinese conditions and test the models in a set of field trials. This will pave the way for a larger study aiming to understand for how long and under what emissions scenarios rapeseed cultivation can continue with current practises in the Yangtze River Basin.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of this proposal is to develop a collaboration that can exploit modern post-genomic techniques in rapeseed genetics to deliver biological mechanisms, alleles markers and germplasm for improved rapeseed crop establishment in the Yangtze River Basin in China. This will be combined with predictive approaches to modelling rapeseed establishment in existing and future climates so that the potential of improved germplasm for providing future resilience can be evaluated, and capacity building in the LMIC country. Because of the availability of genomic data and large genotyped populations in Europe and in China the principal bottleneck is phenotyping, and we have developed a new high throughput seed vigour phenotyping platform in Norwich that is ideally suited to the task.  The work will be achieved in five linked objectives.  Objective 1: is to optimise conditions on the high throughput seed vigour phenotyping platform at JIC, such that we effectively mimic the environment during September drilling in the Yangtze River Basin in China. Using several varieties, temperature and PEG concentrations (to lower the water potential) conditions will be optimised to give maximum resolution to a large scale phenotyping screen of Brassica napus varieties.  Objective 2: The aim of this objective is to identify alleles and germplasm linked to the tolerance of seedling establishment to high temperatures and low water potential. We will use the optimised conditions from (1) to conduct a screen of the Brassica napus Diversity Fixed Foundation Set for frequency and speed of radicle growth and post-germinative shoot growth. Using Associative Transcriptomics we will discover loci linked to beneficial seed traits and use existing knowledge of their gene function to formulate and test hypotheses as to the biological mechanisms important for efficient establishment under stressful conditions.  Objective 3:is to screen the dadi199 Double Haploid population developed at OCRI, Wuhan for seedling establishment under the same stressful conditions. This will enable us to detect close-to-market Chinese germplasm with enhanced seedling establishment characters. Because the population is associated with a high resolution (&gt;1.1 million) Single Nucleotide Polymorphism (SNP) genetic map, we can use the phenotyping data to directly identify candidate genes and markers linked to efficiency of germination and post-germinative seedling establishment under stressful conditions. Using existing knowledge of gene function we will formulate and test hypotheses as to the biological mechanisms important for efficient establishment under stressful conditions, as in objective 2, focussing on the gene targets most likely to be of relevance in field conditions in China.  Objective 4: is to establish a mirror phenotyping platform in OCRI Wuhan. This capacity building exercise will increase still further the phenotyping capabilities of the project, in particular allowing us to increase the number of temperature treatments we can simultaneously use. The OCRI platform will be built using Chinese funds and British expertise, and run by Chinese personnel external to the project.  Objective 5: is to produce a predictive model of rapeseed establishment in different climate and weather regimes. We will select control lines and two key high-performing lines and germinate them at JIC and OCRI under a range of temperature and water potentials. The aim is to produce a dataset that will enable us to parameterise a predictive hydrothermal time model of rapeseed establishment. We will then test the predictive power of the model using seedling establishment field trials in year 2 held both at JIC and OCRI, and at the same time understand how establishment of high performing germplasm identified in the lab compares to existing elite varieties in the field in China.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-16">157517.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-16">119095.23</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">39379.43</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P022677_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">John Innes Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">39379.43</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P022677_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">John Innes Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">39379.43</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P022677_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">John Innes Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">39379.43</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P022677_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">John Innes Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">39698.41</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P022677_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">John Innes Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">39698.41</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P022677_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">John Innes Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">39698.41</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P022677_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">John Innes Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">39698.34</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P022677_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">John Innes Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
