<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009778_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The geography of poverty in Latin America</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The geography of poverty is an understudied area in poverty research. However, knowing the distribution of poverty in a given country is vital for more effective poverty reduction strategies. The distribution of poverty tends to follow a geographical pattern: areas with similar poverty prevalence rates tend to be closer to each other. This opens up different questions such as: What is the distribution of poverty? Why is poverty distributed in this way? Questions about the distribution of poverty across space have been of concern since the first studies of poverty [1]. However, due to lack of data at small area level and computational limitations, it has been difficult to analyze poverty from a geographical perspective. Recent advancements in data collection and statistical breakthroughs have made possible to improve our understanding of poverty at small-area level [2,3,4,5,6]. Nonetheless, there is still a lack of knowledge about the spatial distribution of poverty in most developing countries.   One major obstacle is that producing poverty estimates at small area level requires a rare combination of methods and software from different disciplines (psychometrics, econometrics and spatial statistics). This increases the cost and prevents developing countries conducting regular and rigorous analyses about the geography of poverty. Therefore, it is necessary to make these analyses accessible and feasible to international institutions and governments so that they are able to produce and update geographical analyses of poverty.  Poverty is widespread in Latin America (LA) and although data is available to compute poverty at small area level, too little is known about its spatial distribution [7, 8]. The United Nations Economic Council for Latin America and the Caribbean (ECLAC) has adopted a new methodology to measure poverty at national level in the region [7]. However, this measure has not been empirically examined and it is unclear whether it results in a valid, reliable and comparable poverty index [10]. Therefore, a first task is to assess whether poverty is measured consistently (reliability) and accurately (validity) across countries (comparability). Drawing upon the resulting/adjusted poverty measure, the project will produce poverty estimates at small-area level (municipalities), map out both prevalence and severity rates in LA, and analyse the geography of poverty using a range of methods.   Data and Methods   The project will use two main sources from 17 countries in LA: 1) The Household Income and Expenditure Surveys (HIES) and 2) The population censuses for each country [9]. The most recent available survey/census will be selected for the analysis. Both the surveys and the micro-data from the Censuses can be freely obtained from the statistical offices of each country and/or via IPUMS International (https://international.ipums.org/international/).   The 17 countries are a group that are regularly studied by ECLAC as they have similar data availability and characteristics [7]. The project will focus on the data from the Census, however, it will use the HIES for robustness test. In particular, to compare the census-based measures with a model-based measure based on multilevel models. The study will use a wide-range of statistical methods: a) To produce a valid and reliable measure the project will empirically assess the statistical properties of ECLAC&apos;s measure using Confirmatory Factor Analysis (CFA) and methods that have been applied for a similar purpose in Europe [10,11] b) Comparability (poverty is measured equivalently across countries) will be assessed by testing Measurement Invariance [12] c) Poverty will be mapped out using spatial visualization methods- Choropleth maps and cartograms to adjust maps by population size.  d) The geography of poverty will use: Local Indicators of Spatial Association (LISA), local correlations and local associations with Geographically Weighted Regression [13].</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main aim of the project is to contribute to the measurement and understanding of the geography of poverty in Latin-America (LA). To achieve this aim the research objective are to:  a) Assess whether the international measure produced by the United Nations Economic Council for Latin American and the Caribbean (ECLAC) is valid, reliable and comparable poverty measure.  b) Adjust and produce a valid, reliable and comparable poverty measure for Latin America using data from the Census c) Map and analyse the spatial distribution of poverty in Latin America using spatial statistical methods and free software (R-software) so that the results can be reproduced without restrictions d) Produce a dedicated website with the results with a step-by-step guide so that regional institutions responsible for measuring poverty can reproduce and adapt the spatial analysis e) Disseminate the findings across relevant regional and local institutions in Latin America (ECLAC, The Latin American Faculty of Social Sciences- FLACSO, the Mexican National System for the Integral Protection of Children- SPINNA-Mexico).  f) Contribute to current knowledge about the distribution of poverty at small area level in Latin America and help to introduce the geography of poverty as a dimension in poverty studies in Latin America</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">0.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009778_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">0.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009778_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">0.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009778_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">-0.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009778_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">0.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009778_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
