<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S005749_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chittagong, Makerere, and York Application for Follow-on Funding</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project has the following seven objectives: 1) To build on and consolidate the LMIC partnerships established by a Creative Activism AHRC/GCRF network grant, by meeting the identified needs of practitioners and participants which have arisen from the original project in unforeseeable ways, and by expanding the network so that it reaches new audiences - academic, practitioner (especially grassroots), artistic and public audiences in LMICs and the UK (York; Makerere; Chittagong). 2) To integrate cultural expertise and arts-based approaches into development practice and planning, through an interdisciplinary boundary-crossing collaboration between UK and LMIC institutions. This will be done through partnerships with ActionAid and local development organisations, which will both model innovations and disseminate them within the development sector. 3) To contribute to development outcomes in Bangladesh and Uganda, specifically in challenging dominant development paradigms and contesting shrinking civic space. In doing so, the project will make both direct contributions to the SDGs (SDG 16.7) and indirect contributions (helping to create an enabling environment for the advancement of other SDGs). 4) To bring artists, activists, development practitioners and the wider public together with academics to engage in debate about the value of culturally-specific forms of expression in addressing vital political and development issues. This FoF has an important democratising function, spreading engagement and insights beyond mainstream NGOs, artists and languages.  5) To contribute to the promotion and protection of cultural rights, often neglected in development and human rights interventions, yet crucial for the welfare and wellbeing of populations. 6) To design and implement knowledge exchange strategies that help tackle cultural as well as policy barriers to change, and contribute to the equalisation of power in knowledge production.  7) To move beyond conventional approaches and narratives that often fail to generate the desired results, but are difficult to escape and reimagine, by using the arts to help practitioners and campaigners to see the world differently, and by identifying locally-consonant and hence more effective strategies and tactics for intervention and campaigning.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This FoF proposal builds on two University of York research streams: a network grant, &apos;Creative Activism, Art and Development Alternatives&apos; (AHRC/GCRF, AH/P006078/1), and an internal research strand on &apos;Political Forms&apos; (Centre for Modern Studies). This work has developed a strong network of activists, artists and researchers in Bangladesh and Uganda; theoretical insights into the ways development alternatives and political ideas are revealed and contested in cultural forms; and methodological innovations in participatory arts practice and models for engaging artists in development work.  The current proposal builds on the unexpected success, in the Creative Activism project, of street happenings/performances, public screenings and arts-based workshops for generating open discussion among diverse audiences on political issues and alternative approaches to development. A theory of change emerging from this work suggests that the arts can make space for critical thinking and exploration of political issues and alternative approaches to development in a way that somewhat mitigates the high levels of risk often associated with direct political speech, and contributes to building active citizenship and enhancing development outcomes. As such it aids in meeting the challenge spelt out in the Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) 16.7 on the need for responsible, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making. This proposal involves collaboration with the development organisation ActionAid and LMIC-based cultural organisations. Workshops supported by the AHRC/GCRF award and subsequent discussions revealed a strong local desire to take collaboration with artists and researchers in new directions and test methodological innovations in the research with new audiences. We have worked closely with partners in developing this proposal to create a theory of change, shape activities, and highlight the following priorities: 1) To further dissemination of the project&apos;s methodological innovations, and to test the methods with grassroots organisations and community groups.  2) To build on a commitment from the ActionAid training centre TCDC (Arusha, Tanzania) to integrate creative pedagogies in its new training programme and to run an artist-in-residence scheme. 3) To test ideas emerging from the research, specifically relating to the impact of arts-based interventions such as residencies and public happenings. 4) To support requests for training and advice on establishment of archives of art and politics in both Makerere and Chittagong.  5) To extend the reach of the project to audiences/users who do not speak fluent English, running events in Bangla and local languages in Uganda. To deliver on these priorities activities include support for the establishment of two interactive public archives; a cross-cultural creative labs initiative supporting artist exchanges; and local creative labs initiatives in Chittagong and Uganda. We will also adapt and test the innovative arts-based methodologies developed in the Creative Activism project in ActionAid local rights programmes, in collaboration with ActionAid&apos;s training centre (TCDC) in Arusha, Tanzania. Public engagement includes two public, interactive street art happenings - in Chittagong and Kampala. Dissemination will target relevant websites and toolkits, including revised versions of the ActionAid human rights-based approach handbook and the ActionAid web-based networked toolbox. This dissemination will reach the development sector beyond those involved in this project. These activities will produce a rich variety of outputs, including two funding proposals for archive development; two street art happenings; documentation of activities and process of collaboration; and a training programme and embeddable digital resources on using innovative arts-based methodologies with communities and activists.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-28">86256.63</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-28">86256.632</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Follow-on Funding Impact &amp; Eng Award to University of York</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S005749_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FS005749%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
