<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_N005058_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Poverty alleviation through prevention and future control of the two major socioeconomically-important pathogens in Asian aquaculture.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our tri-national collaborative project aims to alleviate poverty within poor farming communities in Bangladesh and India by developing a holistic understanding of the role of the environment in controlling disease risk in fish and crustacean aquaculture. We will quantify the role of physical pond conditions in controlling infection outcomes for two socioeconomically devastating pathogens of decapod crustaceans and freshwater fish in Asian aquaculture. Using this knowledge we will address two principle aims:  A) Within the lifetime of the project, we will identify novel and sustainable best practice for crop husbandry to prevent or minimize the risk of disease outbreaks in shrimp and fish farming by developing healthy and resilient aquaculture systems;  B) Use state of the art molecular methods to develop fundamental detailed biological understanding of host-pathogen interactions. This detailed new mechanistic insight will create a knowledge base and platform from which to develop future novel disease control measures. The maturation of intervention technologies will be the focus of future research following this project; the scientific and technical capacity built in all three countries by the current project will hence represent a highly significant legacy for the future.   To achieve these aims we have five specific Objectives:   1) To engage local farming communities in Bangladesh and India to identify their existing best practice, and their experience of poverty and the socioeconomic impact of disease outbreaks. With this Objective we will recruit participative research communities to identify the two key diseases and relevant crop species that will influence the focus of our subsequent work (Task 1 - addresses Overall Aim A).   2) To establish a farm-based participatory epidemiological study of crop disease in shrimp and fish in India and Bangladesh through one growing season, by weekly characterization of crop performance and pond physico-chemical conditions - including pathogen load, crop health, crop mortality and management activity. This study will empower farmers and produce a synthesis of the environmental conditions and management practices that correlate with infection outcome and inform the next Objective (Task 2- addresses Overall Aim A).  3) Use the participatory research and outputs from Objectives 1 &amp; 2 to inform controlled experimental infection studies under different environmental conditions. These will provide a robust evidence-base from which to propose novel Best Management Practices (Objective 4) for fish and crustacean culture in India and Bangladesh. This will involve:  i) transcriptomic analyses of host-pathogen interactions in response to a single model infection (Task 3.1 -addresses Overall Aims A &amp; B)  ii) quantifying changes in key gene transcription, immune phenotype and infection outcome in response to environmental change (Task 3.2 - addresses Overall Aim A)  4) To use our  data (from Tasks 1, 2 &amp; 3) in collaboration with the farming communities to build local capacity and help develop our novel Best Management Practice recommendations through a series of &apos;sensitization workshops&apos;. The target audience for this activity will include farmers, Fishery Officers, dealers and regulators in Bangladesh and India, but also representatives of the Office International des Epizooties (OIE), DFID and FAO. Our intention here is to test our recommendations in &apos;the real world&apos; before these are disseminated through India and Bangladesh (Task 4 - addresses Overall Aim A).  5) To create a resource of new data by employing bioinformatic approaches and molecular biology experiments to understand host-pathogen interactions. This will act as a scientific platform for the development of novel future control measures (e.g. breeding for resistance, oral vaccines for fin fish, or other interventions) that are poverty-focused, context-specific, and sustainable (Task 5 - addresses Overall Aim B).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recent estimates predict that the global population will rise to ~ 9 bn by 2050. Of that growth, the majority is predicted to take place within Africa, the Middle East and throughout Asia. As the available land for agriculture becomes limited and as wild fish stocks become depleted, it is essential that aquaculture production is sustainably enhanced to ensure global food security and poverty alleviation for all human kind.  Infectious disease outbreaks are the key limiting factor to the sustainable expansion of the aquaculture industry. Many diseases exist in wild populations but only become problematic when crop species are held at high densities and under stressful conditions. These conditions are often associated with aquaculture. Attempts have been made to meet the challenge of disease by developing vaccines or prophylactic treatments to prevent disease or &apos;boost&apos; the host immune system. Unfortunately, in the many cases in Asia these strategies have failed; vaccines have proved ineffective, too expensive, or are unrealistic to administer at farm scale. Immune stimulants and probiotics have often failed to provide consistent or sustained protection in shellfish. We argue that the approach to disease prevention must be radically rethought. We do concede that regulating the culture environment alone will be insufficient to reduce the impact of all future diseases. We also advocate the continued development of novel understanding of the fundamentals of host-pathogen interactions. This knowledge will identify pathways of pathogen infection that could be exploited in the future leading to the development of more universal and cost-effective control methods. We will quantify the socioeconomic impact of two key diseases of Asian aquaculture. This will inform the design of experiments to quantify the role of the pond environment (e.g.: temperature, salinity, diet, etc) in regulating the occurrence of infectious outbreaks. Outputs will be used to recommend novel Best Management Practice (BMP) for farmers in Low Income Countries (LICs). Through collaborative engagement, these new BMPs will be developed within the farming communities in Bangladesh and India to ensure their efficacy. The proposed approach represents a more economically realistic option for farmers working in LICs and will provide a first step towards poverty alleviation through minimising risk. We believe that this raised awareness of controlling environment quality to minimise disease has the potential to generate highly significant short term positive impacts. Simultaneously, we will use state of the art molecular methods to develop rigorous new understanding of the host-pathogen interactions in these diseases and use that knowledge in future projects to identify novel universal and sustainable intervention methods and for genetic improvement programmes for high health crops.  Likely targets for our research are the current most socioeconomically devastating diseases in Bangladesh and India: White Spot Disease (WSD) of shrimp, which is caused by White Spot Syndrome Virus (WSSV), and infection with the fungus-like oomycete Aphanomyces invadans (previously Epizootic Ulcerative Syndrome (EUS)) causing large-scale mortalities of farmed fish, especially major carps. Minimising the risk of these disease outbreaks under farm conditions in Bangladesh and other LICs is thus a vital short term priority. We therefore propose that there is an essential and urgent requirement to optimise novel approaches to good BMP.  Our trilateral consortium will facilitate real cross fertilization of expertise and ideas and will build scientific and aquaculture capacity in the three countries presented. We genuinely believe that our collaboration will support the sustainable enhancement of the aquaculture industry and alleviate poverty by developing a holistic view of the importance of a healthy and resilient aquaculture crop and culture system.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-29" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-11-19">381031.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-11-19">384117.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-11-19">314623.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
