<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P006655_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education in divided societies: Developing and researching shared education in the Republic of Macedonia, Bosnia and Herzegovina, and Croatia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is generally accepted that education has a significant role to play in societies transitioning from conflict. Indeed, the education system potentially represents the single most effective agent of social change with the capacity to bridge ethnic division in conflict affected countries (Petroska-Beska &amp; Najcevska, 2004). In Northern Ireland (NI), the education system is distinguishable by the degree of separation that exists between Catholic and Protestant faith communities. Currently, 93% of pupils attend predominately &apos;own&apos; religion schools. Similarly, following the dissolution of Yugoslavia, wider ethnic divisions are now reflected in separate education systems in the Republic of Macedonia (Macedonia), Bosnia and Herzegovina (BiH), and Croatia. In post-conflict societies, these divisions can contribute to social fragmentation and inhibit the development of a &apos;shared society&apos;.  In 2007 an innovative approach to facilitate reconciliation through schools separated on ethnic or religious lines was developed in NI. Informed by intergroup contact theory (Allport, 1954), shared education aims to break down boundaries between separate schools by providing sustained, curriculum-based engagement between pupils. A corpus of research demonstrates the effectiveness of the programme in promoting harmonious intergroup relations. Shared education has received significant political support in NI, and from 2015, is being extended across the region via a Signature Programme coordinated by the Department of Education. Outside NI, shared education is being implemented in Israel and Macedonia and the model has attracted interest from academics and policymakers in other divided contexts, including South Africa, BiH and Croatia, although to date it has not been instigated in these countries.   In view of the increasing internationalisation of the shared education model, we propose the creation of a strategic network across four jurisdictions (NI, Macedonia, BiH, and Croatia) of academics, practitioners, NGOs, and policymakers whose work contributes to peace building through the promotion of intergroup contact and intercultural dialogue in education, with a view to facilitate, promote, and develop models of shared education for each jurisdiction. The project employs a multi-stage design, beginning with a knowledge exchange seminar in NI providing network members an opportunity to learn more about the model and to see the implementation of the programme in NI schools. Further, it will facilitate initial thinking on the implications of shared education for partner countries, particularly regarding structural changes needed to facilitate programme implementation. This will be followed by a series of in-country knowledge exchange seminars in the participant States and capacity building activities to develop and support the implementation, monitoring, and evaluation of shared education programmes; including, but not limited to, professional development for teachers and practitioners, workshops on developing and enhancing research skills key to programme evaluation, and on using research findings to advocate for policy change.   The knowledge generated from these phases will inform the development of a research agenda to move forward shared education initiatives in each country, the establishment of a shared education advocacy group to advocate for policy change, and proposals to pursue pilot programmes in BiH and Croatia. Additionally, a comprehensive comparative research and evaluation programme will be developed to examine the impact of shared education in different educational and societal contexts, with a view to refining the model and developing best practice nationally and internationally. Ultimately, building the capacity of key stakeholders to develop and initiate shared education has the capability of fostering more harmonious intergroup relations to transmute the social landscape of participant societies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will create a strategic network of academics, practitioners, and policy makers in Northern Ireland (NI), the Republic of Macedonia (Macedonia), Bosnia and Herzegovina (BiH), and Croatia, whose work contributes to peace building through the promotion of intergroup contact and intercultural dialogue in education. This will be achieved through the following objectives:  1. Facilitate, promote, and develop models of shared education in societies affected by conflict and/or intergroup hostilities. In NI the promotion of school based intergroup contact has been offered as a means of facilitating positive intergroup relations in schools divided along ethno-religious lines. Informed by contact theory (Allport, 1954), shared education offers curriculum-based interactions between pupils attending differing school types, aimed at promoting the type of contact likely to reduce negative social attitudes and ultimately contribute to social harmony. Initial attempts to locate this approach within the wider conspectus of structural and curricular initiatives in divided societies have been positive. In Macedonia collaborations have led to an adapted model of shared education best suited to the unique challenges inherent within the education system there. By drawing together key stakeholders from each jurisdiction, this process of collaboration will adapt the model to BiH and Croatia. Further, advocacy groups will be established in each country to promote the mainstreaming of the model.  2. Enhance internal capacity within each jurisdiction to effectively develop the design, implementation, monitoring, and evaluation of shared education initiatives. Internal capacity will be supported and developed through the establishment of an infrastructure within and between each jurisdiction. In Macedonia, BiH, and Croatia a number of educational initiatives have been implemented by academics, practitioners, and NGOs. However, a framework does not currently exist to connect these stakeholders. We will use an online tool which offers a virtual &apos;shared space&apos; where network members can freely access one another to exchange knowledge, skills, and best practice, while in-country seminars offer a physical space in which the model and the unique education systems can be explored in greater detail to design and implement the model within each jurisdiction. Internal capacity is further enhanced through training events relating to implementation, monitoring, and evaluation. Specific training exercises may include professional development for school officials around school collaboration and teaching strategies within an ethnically mixed classroom, and monitoring and evaluation activities for academics around qualitative and quantitative methodological approaches.   3. Design a research project to undertake a comprehensive comparative research and evaluation programme to examine the impact of shared education in different educational and societal contexts, with a view to refining the model and developing best practice nationally and internationally. A growing corpus of work explores shared education initiatives within NI, however limited research has been conducted in other educational and societal contexts. Building upon the shared knowledge generated through the network a research agenda will be developed exploring the role of education in divided societies more broadly and the implementation of shared education initiatives more specifically. This is likely to include proposals to pilot shared education initiatives in BiH and Croatia, to evaluate the ongoing programme in Macedonia, and to compare the impact of shared education across each jurisdiction. In addition, it may involve proposals to undertake novel and innovative theory-based research to identify the psychological processes that underpin the approach, and the factors that strengthen the intergroup and educational outcomes of shared education in each country.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="EUROPE, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-15">24985.27</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-15">100143.46</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">49970.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P006655_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">24985.27</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P006655_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">24985.27</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P006655_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">25187.65</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P006655_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">18811.47</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P006655_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
