<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P007465_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Legal Regulation of Unacceptable Forms of Work: Global Dialogue/Local Innovation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Network on Legal Regulation of Unacceptable Forms of Work responds to the substantive and methodological limitations of the research on the regulation of precarious and low-quality jobs. The Network will support a rigorous, global, interdisciplinary and policy-oriented reflection on UFW. The aim is ultimately to generate crucial comparative insights into the challenges and potential of UFW regulation. The project will (1) establish an international and interdisciplinary Network of researchers and policy makers committed to an authentically global account of the regulation of UFW that fully incorporates the needs of developing countries, and (2) develop interlinked research agendas on key sites of regulatory intervention. The Strategic Network will nurture collaboration between researchers from multiple disciplines, developing countries and advanced industrialised countries, and policy-makers at all levels. The aim is to generate meaningful insights into the design and implementation of domestic and international laws.  The Network will centre on Global Regulatory Challenges (GRCs) in UFW regulation, identified as  among the most urgent and complex issues that face lower-income countries. Each Network Team will address labour market/regulatory phenomena in two paired countries across different income levels. The Teams will (1) map the existing &apos;state of the art&apos; on the GRCs and (2) devise research strategies that can identify the most effective regulatory and policy strategies to address each, with a particular focus on developing countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-01-02"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-15">28271.15</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-15">56542.3</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The UN International Labour Organization (ILO) has called for workers to be protected from unacceptable forms of work (UFW): jobs that &quot;deny fundamental principles and rights at work, put at risk the lives, health, freedom, human dignity and security of workers or keep households in conditions of extreme poverty&quot; (ILO 2013). This new policy agenda recognises that growing numbers in the global workforce are engaged in insecure and low paid labour. Sustaining productive and protected working lives in developing countries is among the pressing challenges of the early twenty-first century, recently confirmed by the inclusion of the Decent Work objective among the UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) (SDG8). Effective labour regulation is crucial. Yet the policy and regulatory strategies that can effectively eliminate unacceptable work, most crucially in Developing Countries (DCs), have not yet been identified. The Strategic Network on Unacceptable Forms of Work: Global Dialogue/Local Innovation will respond to this urgent need by supporting a dialogue and generating research agendas on the regulation of UFW.    The aims of the application are to (1) to establish an international and interdisciplinary Network of researchers and policy makers committed to an authentically global account of the regulation of UFW that fully incorporates the needs of DCs, and (2) to develop interlinked research agendas on key sites of regulatory intervention. The Strategic Network will nurture collaboration between researchers from multiple disciplines, DCS and AICs, and policy-makers at all levels. The aim is to generate meaningful insights into the design and implementation of domestic and international laws. The UFW project is therefore centred on two of the five GCRF key areas: dynamics of inequalities (3); and innovation and inclusive economic growth (4). Two of the other themes are also relevant: migration, mobility and development (2) is a cross-cutting theme of the project; and &apos;shocks, security, risks and resilience&apos; (5) is relevant in that Network activities will support effective and equitable responses to economic shocks."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">28271.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P007465_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">28271.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P007465_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">28271.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P007465_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">18012.38</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P007465_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
