<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N012380_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bacterial pathogenesis: dissecting the early stages of cellular invasion by the obligate intracellular bacterium Orientia tsutsugamushi</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scrub typhus is one of the leading causes of hospitalisation from high fever in many rural parts of Southeast Asia. The disease is caused when a patient is bitten by a small biting arthropod called a mite, which transmits a dangerous bacterium called Orientia tsutsugamushi. Infection with this bacterium causes a range of symptoms that include high fever, rash and muscle pain. If the infection is not treated quickly and correctly it can result in multiple organ failure and death. It is estimated that 1 billion people are at risk and 1 million people are infected with this disease every year. Because the symptoms are similar to many other tropical infectious diseases - such as dengue fever and other bacterial or viral infections - patients are often misdiagnosed and therefore not treated properly. This risks severe complications for the individual patient and it also contributes to the growing problem of antibiotic resistance due to misuse of antibiotic treatments. Given the high incidence and severity of this disease, it is very important that we study the bacteria that causes it in detail as this will help us to develop better diagnostics, vaccines, and treatments in the future.  In order to understand fully an infectious disease, and therefore improve patient care, it is necessary to understand the basic biology of the organism that causes the disease. In particular, it is important to understand exactly how that organism grows inside humans, and why it makes those humans sick. Humans have around 100 trillion bacteria growing on and inside them all the time, and the vast majority of them cause no ill effects and are actually beneficial. The study of &apos;pathogenicity&apos; explores how and why a small minority of bacteria cause disease in humans. In the case of O. tsutsugamushi, the bacteria that causes scrub typhus, the first step in its pathogenicity is its entry to the inside of human cells. Most bacteria can survive either inside human cells or free in the environment: O. tsutsugamushi cannot. O. tsutsugamushi can only survive and replicate when it is physically located inside another cell. Therefore the more we can understand about how this bacteria gains initial access into human cells, and then avoids being killed by them, the more we can explore ways to block this essential process and therefore eliminate the bacteria from the patient.  In this study we will explore the detailed mechanisms by which O. tsutsugamushi gets into humans cells and what it does in the first 24 hours after entry. Human cells have developed sophisticated strategies to eliminate most bacteria that get inside them, but O. tsutsugamushi has learned how to avoid these. We want to understand exactly how it does this. We will use a high-throughput screening approach to study these early events of pathogenesis. This means that we will systematically look at all the genes in the human genome to try and find the ones that the bacteria hijacks in order to get into the cells and survive there. Once we have identified these important human genes we will do more experiments to understand the details of exactly how the bacteria uses them in order to gain entry and then survive within the human cells.   The outcome of this study will be a more detailed understanding of exactly how the bacterium O. tsutsugamushi gets into human cells, and how it avoids being killed by them. This will help us develop new strategies to block these processes in the future.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-12" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="TH" type="THAILAND"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-17">16571.56</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-17">66420.48</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-17">66958.51</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-17">33682.22</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="AIM ONE: Identify host cell factors required for early stages of bacterial invasion (entry, escape to cytosol, intracellular motility) using an siRNA screening approach Background: Bacterial attachment and dissemination into mammalian cells is a complex process involving surface receptors, cytoskeleton rearrangements, kinase signalling, clathrin-mediated internalisation and microtubule binding proteins. Here we propose to identify those specific host factors and pathways involved in the process of attachment and intracellular localisation of O. tsutsugamushi. A. Develop an siRNA assay and screening strategy that will quantify bacterial invasion using high-content imaging analysis B. Perform siRNA screen to identify host cell factors required for binding and subcellular localisation C. Validate specific hits and test for off-target effects using secondary screening approaches  EXPECTED OUTCOME: The outcome of this aim will be a panel of candidate host genes that are implicated in the early stages of bacterial invasion.  AIM TWO: Explore the molecular mechanisms of bacterial invasion by performing follow-up experiments on candidate host cell factors identified in Aim 1 Background: The siRNA screen performed in Aim 1 will proved a list of genes that may be involved in bacterial attachment and subcellular localisation. In this second aim we will expand on these results using a range of assays previously developed in our lab. A. Use RTqPCR to determine the levels of candidate host genes in a panel of different mammalian cell lines B.  Use fluorescence microscopy techniques to study the specific role of identified host factors  EXPECTED OUTCOME: The outcome of this aim will be a better understanding of the molecular mechanisms by which host cell factors identified in aim 1 act to facilitate bacterial uptake and intracellular motility.   AIM THREE: Identify specific host cell surface receptors that mediate host-pathogen attachment using biochemistry and cell biology approaches Background: Bacterial and viral attachment to host cells usually involves specific interactions between two or more receptors on the surface of both organisms. This aim will complement and extend aim 1, by using alternative approaches to identify specific surface receptors on mammalian host cells that directly bind to O. tsutsugamushi. A. Perform protein pull-down experiments and identify host cell receptors that bind to whole O. tsutsugamushi bacteria or specific O. tsutsugamushi surface proteins  B. Employ a protein microarray screening approach to identify human plasma membrane proteins that specifically bind to O. tsutsugamushi bacteria C. Validate candidate proteins by protein purification and fluorescence microscopy experiments EXPECTED OUTCOME: The outcome of this aim will be the identification of specific receptors on host cell surfaces that physically interact with bacteria and that mediate the first step in bacterial invasion."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
