<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P023223_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Targeting virus transmission in a vital crop for African food security</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In East and Central Africa beans are a vital crop that naturally enriches the soil with nitrogen, providing natural fertilizer for other important crops such as maize and cassava. In the regional diet beans are important because they are rich in protein and critically important micronutrients. Since beans are mostly grown and traded by women, this crop provides important direct economic benefits to families &amp; children. Unfortunately, a number of viruses attack bean plants, causing severe crop losses from disease. Although some bean varieties have resistance to one of these viruses, bean common mosaic virus, a closely related virus that occurs widely in sub-Saharan Africa (bean common necrotic mosaic virus) causes plants of these &apos;resistant&apos; lines to die. Thus, many farmers prefer to plant susceptible bean lines despite the risk of crop loss and it is important to develop new strategies to defend this vital crop. The viruses are transmitted on the needle-like mouthparts of aphids. Importantly, the virus particles are lost by the aphid as soon as it feeds on a healthy plant; a weak link in the infection chain that we can exploit. Aphids are attracted to volatile chemicals released by plants. Virus infection can change these plants &apos;odours&apos; so that aphids are encouraged to land on infected plants, acquire virus particles and then transport them to healthy plants. However, some bean varieties emit odours that are more attractive to aphids even when the plants are healthy. This means that if we plant mixtures of bean plants that include &apos;attractive&apos; varieties we could decoy aphids away from the rest of the crop and slow disease transmission. Even better, if we can decoy virus-bearing aphids to land on plants that are resistant to the virus, then as soon as the aphid feeds it will lose the virus particles. This would effectively &apos;sanitize&apos; the aphids and stop them spreading the virus, as well as dumping the virus into plants in which it cannot grow. An additional benefit of using a mixture containing a limited number of resistant plants is that viruses will be under less pressure to evolve new strains that can overcome resistance and, in cases where virus infection kills resistant plants, only a small proportion of the crop will be lost. Since aphids and related insects transmit the majority of plant viruses the method could be applied to a wide range of crops.      Experiments under controlled conditions using varieties of a plant called Arabidopsis and an aphid transmitted virus called cucumber mosaic virus showed that aphid and virus spread can be altered using combinations of plants with different levels of attractiveness to aphids. A pilot field experiment in Uganda using mixtures of bean varieties with different degrees of attractiveness to aphids showed that aphids can be detained on more attractive varieties and inhibited from moving to other plants until close to harvest time, showing that our approach can work under farm conditions.      Our multinational team will: A. Screen bean varieties that are popular in bean-growing regions in Kenya &amp; Rwanda with respect to their attractiveness to aphids. We will identify the chemical odours emitted by plants that are most attractive to aphids. It is important to work with local varieties since farmers prefer certain bean types for hardiness under local conditions, cooking properties and local marketability. We will focus particularly on identifying aphid-attractive varieties carrying one or more virus resistance genes.    B. Mathematically model the consequences of different arrangements and mixtures of attractive/repellent/susceptible/resistant plant lines on aphid and virus spread in fields. This will not only help us design our field and lab experiments but also to analyze the data we obtain.     C. Test our models and lab experiments in Kenya &amp; Rwanda to devise the most effective &amp; practical field designs that minimize crop losses due to viral diseases.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OBJECTIVES We hypothesize that mixtures of crop plants containing a proportion of virus-resistant but aphid-attractive plants will slow or prevent dissemination of viruses by aphid vectors. Our rationale is that this is a more sustainable approach to protection against pathogens with a propensity to evolve resistance-breakage and/or when deployment of 100% resistant plants may be inadvisable due to the nature of the resistance (for example, systemic necrosis).  We will explore this hypothesis through pursuit of the following objectives:  1. Identify farmer-preferred common bean (Phaseolus vulgaris) varieties from Kenya and Rwanda that could be used in seed mixtures of susceptible and resistant plants to inhibit the spread of aphids and the viruses they carry; 2. Mathematically model the spread of non-persistently transmitted viruses and, 3. Experimentally validate these models under controlled conditions and in field experiments in Kenya and Rwanda.   IMPORTANCE Bean is a vital smallholder crop in east and central Africa that enhances intercropping with other major crops including maize and cassava (by providing fixed N and moderation of abiotic &amp; biotic stress). Bean is the major protein and micronutrient source in the regional diet and is also economically important for women who predominantly grow and trade bean and for their children who benefit nutritionally and economically. BACKGROUND Three aphid-transmitted viruses, the potyviruses Bean common mosaic virus (BCMV) and Bean common mosaic necrosis virus (BCMNV) and to a lesser extent Cucumber mosaic virus (a cucumovirus), are important constraints on bean production in east and central Africa. Limited genetic options are available for their control in Africa. For example, plants carrying a major BCMV resistance gene are susceptible to systemic necrosis induction by BCMNV, which is ubiquitous throughout the continent, and recessive resistance genes for BCMNV can be too strain-specific to provide broad resistance. Additional threats can arise from resistance-breaking viral mutants and BCMV/BCMNV recombinants. PRELIM DATA &amp; PROGRAMME OVERVIEW Differences in plant attractiveness to aphids affects virus transmission dynamics. Experiments using mixtures of Arabidopsis ecotypes under controlled conditions show that aphid movement and spread of aphid-vectored CMV can be decreased. Following from this, a pilot field experiment in Uganda using mixtures of bean lines that differ in aphid attractiveness indicate that spread and distribution of winged and wingless aphids within test plots of common bean can be manipulated under field conditions. Blocks of 100 plants containing 0-84% BCMV-resistant (but more aphid-attractive) plants were arranged randomly or as borders around virus-susceptible plants. Winged and wingless aphids numbers/distribution were monitored for 7 weeks post-planting (i.e. just prior to harvest). Aphid settling was low on infected susceptible plants as expected from experiments under controlled conditions, with settling (winged &amp; wingless) highest on plants of the aphid-attractive cultivar MC1015. This remained true for wingless aphids throughout the recording period and for winged aphids until week 6 at which point they became more evenly dispersed across plants of both cultivars. Thus, aphid settling behavior can be manipulated in cultivar mixtures. Through national and international collaboration (Cambridge/Rothamsted/BecA-ILRI Hub) we will expand on this work and authenticate whether or not virus transmission can be inhibited by characterizing farmer-preferred bean varieties from Kenya and Rwanda with respect to their interactions with aphids and bean-infecting viruses (Cambridge &amp; Rothamsted) and model (Cambridge) the effects of mixtures on propagation of aphids and the viruses they carry and authenticate models and experiments under controlled condition through field experiments in East Africa (coordinated by BecA-ILRI).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-21">299930.48</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-21">302359.89</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-21">602290.368</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC GCRF Standard Grant Award to University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P023223_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=BB%2FP023223%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
