<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_V043064_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF_NF335 COVID19: Greening the Social and Economic Recovery in Ghana and Zambia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will support a clean and resilient recovery from the Covid-19 pandemic in Ghana and Zambia. It will work with research partners, governments and other organisations in those countries to develop strategies that integrate economic recovery and climate change policies. Ghana and Zambia have been chosen because there is an opportunity to build on existing collaborations; there is a clear demand from policy makers for this research; and they have important differences that will enable lessons to be learned in other countries.  The project has five main objectives. It will: 1. Understand the drivers, challenges and opportunities for a clean, resilient recovery in Ghana and Zambia 2. Investigate options for a clean, resilient recovery through the co-creation of participatory pathways for future development 3. Quantify the socio-economic, energy and climate implications of a clean, resilient recovery 4. Support government decision-making on recovery, climate action and development planning, including through information-sharing and the adaption of clean, resilient recovery initiatives from other contexts 5. Strengthen capacity, share knowledge and create equitable and enduring partnerships  The project will focus in particular on the development and implementation of revised Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs). Revised NDCs need to be submitted to the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change before COP26, which will be held in Glasgow in late 2021. This integration is critical not only for social and economic recovery in the short-term, but also for avoiding lock-in to carbon intensive development pathways that could undermine long-term resilience.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2020-10-27"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-27" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-26" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="GH" type="GHANA"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="WESTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1030</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-19">166581.51</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-19">351638.75</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="This project aims to support a clean, resilient recovery from the Covid-19 pandemic in Ghana and Zambia. Covid-19 recovery in countries with ongoing and major development needs will have particular characteristics and requirements that call for context-specific research, collaboration and engagement. This will support decision makers to look beyond immediate responses to Covid-19, identify medium-term priorities for recovery, and integrate these with Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) for COP26.   Ghana and Zambia have been chosen because there is an opportunity to act quickly by building on existing collaborations; a clear demand from policy makers for this research; and they have important differences that will enable wider lessons to be learned (e.g. in their economies, electricity access rates and climate policy priorities).   The project objectives are to: 1. Understand the drivers, challenges and opportunities for a clean, resilient recovery in Ghana and Zambia 2. Investigate options for a clean, resilient recovery through the co-creation of participatory pathways for future development 3. Quantify the socio-economic, energy and climate implications of a clean, resilient recovery 4. Support decision-making on recovery, climate action and development planning, including through information-sharing and the adaption of clean, resilient recovery initiatives from other contexts 5. Strengthen capacity, share knowledge and create equitable and enduring partnerships"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">78393.81</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_V043064_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
