<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_R022755_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chemical study of insect-plant interactions: a contribution to biorational control of crop pests</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New solutions for managing insect pests are urgently needed due to evolution of resistance to current insecticides. This project focuses on development and bioactivity testing of novel nanotech formulations of plant secondary metabolites that could provide new options for crop protection. The Federal University of S&#xE3;o Carlos (UFSCar) group has strong preliminary data showing that nanotech formulations of certain plant flavonoids complexed with Mg (II) substantially reduce growth of insects. Preliminary experiments done by the Keele University (KU) group with PAA (poly(allylamine)) nanotech formulations of essential oils have shown highly significant repellent action, with greatly enhanced activity compared to conventionally formulated material. UK-Brazil collaboration would provide an ideal opportunity to strengthen this new and promising area of research. The project includes Workshops and exchange visits to build a research network between the groups. Both groups will share expertise and work together to create novel nanotech formulations of plant secondary metabolites (flavonoids such as Hesperidin and Naringenin, phenolic acids and essential oils). Parallel experiments will be conducted testing activity against selected insects, chosen due to their relevance to Brazilian agriculture and insecticide resistance challenges. Bioassays with Western flower thrips, Frankliniella occidentalis, and peach-potato aphid, Myzus persicae, will be conducted at KU; with whitefly, Bemisia tabaci, at S&#xE3;o Paulo State University (UNESP), and with fall armyworm, Spodoptera frugiperda at UFSCar. Antibiotic, antifeedant and repellent activity will be tested for using established methods. The experiments conducted in the pump-priming project will reveal the potential for use of nanotechnology to improve the formulation of plant secondary metabolites for use against insects. The project will benefit from the expertise in the KU School of Pharmacy Co-I who has considerable expertise in development of nanotech formulations for the medical sector. We will consider the extent to which low cost technologies already developed for medicines can be translated into the agricultural field. In addition to the programme of empirical research, we will also conduct a literature review of the area and submit this to a high quality scientific journal as a contribution to knowledge. We think there is considerable potential for cross-fertilisation between the disciplines involved in the project (chemistry, medicine and entomology). This has potential to allow agricultural formulation technology to &quot;leapfrog&quot; into nanotechnology by using approaches already developed for Medicine. Furthermore, there will, of course, be insights gained by sharing insights with the Brazilian scientists who are at the forefront of the development of nanotechnology for crop protection. The project has considerable potential to generate much needed new tools for managing insect pests of crops.  The project will allow us to test the hypothesis that bioactivity of plant secondary metabolites can be enhanced by delivery via novel nanotech formulations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-20">63802.99</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The overall objective is to explore how plant secondary metabolites, particularly flavonoids, can be delivered using nanotechnology for enhanced activity against insect pests. The project aims to develop a long-term collaboration combining the expertise of Keele University (KU) and Universidade Federal de S&#xE3;o Carlos (UFSCar, Brazilian PI) research groups. It will integrate chemistry, nanotechnology and entomology to provide new ways of delivering bioactive phytochemicals via nanotech complexes for use against insect pests.   Specific objectives are: 1. To share complementary expertise and share best practice between the research organisations in Brazil and the UK to strengthen the underpinning science for providing novel tools to manage insect pests of crops. This will be facilitated by two workshops, short high-level courses and mutual exchange of researchers between organisations. 2. To create novel nanotech formulations of plant secondary metabolites using expertise available at the KU School of Pharmacy and at UFSCar. 3. To test the antibiotic and antifeedant activity of the formulations, developed in objective 2, against target insect pests. These will be thrips and aphids at the KU School of Life Sciences, whitefly at S&#xE3;o Paulo State University (Brazilian co-investigator) and fall armyworm at UFSCar. 4. To review the potential for translation of nanotech approaches, including those being developed for medicines, into the agricultural crop protection sector. A major review on this subject will be submitted for publication.  New solutions are urgently needed for managing insect pests of crops as they evolve resistance to currently available insecticides and new environmentally benign products are required for future pest management. The pump-priming project will allow us to scope out the research and test some new ideas: It will allow us to test the hypothesis that bioactivity of plant secondary metabolites can be enhanced by delivery via novel nanotech formulations. If experimental results are as promising as expected, there will be huge potential for future research in the area of nanotech formulation of plant secondary metabolites which could revolutionise crop protection."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
