<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-EP_N034899_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster management and resilience in electric power systems</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Electricity infrastructure is key to sustain human and economic well-being since it supplies energy to industrial, commercial and financial sectors, critical services (health, traffic control, water supply), communication networks, and hence almost all activities in modern societies. Consequently, the effects of long electricity blackouts have demonstrated impacts on economic activities and social stability and security. A framework for disaster management and resilience of the power sector is needed, beyond the occurrence of &quot;average&quot; outages contemplated in current security standards. This framework should consider network management under the occurrence of natural hazards such as earthquakes and tsunamis that may cause major blackouts, and assess proper measures to manage the associated disasters. Developing and implementing such a framework will be crucial to increase the opportunities for Chile and other countries, especially developing and low-income ones located around the Pacific Ring of Fire which are particularly exposed to the risk of earthquakes and tsunamis.  In this context, this project will undertake holistic risk analyses associated with natural hazards on electricity networks along with identification of mitigation and adaptation measures that can allow us to manage the arising disasters. This holistic perspective of disaster management and resilience will be supported by development of mathematical models to firstly assess risks related to high impact low probability events, such as earthquakes and tsunamis, on the electric power systems. These models will then serve to identify an optimal portfolio of preventive and corrective measures that can support mitigation of impacts and compare different adaptation strategies. In particular, besides classical infrastructure reinforcement, we will assess how operational measures for disaster management, for instance though distributed energy systems, e.g., based on communities and microgrids, can provide system resilience.  Building on this last point, resilience can in fact also be built through citizens and communities and by how they prepare for, and respond to, power outages. Such preparedness could for instance be led by the electricity companies and targeted at the individual and community levels by sharing accountability for response across the official respondents, local officials, community groups, individual citizens, and the electricity companies. The aim is for households to have response strategies that are complemented by resilience measures prepared for (and by) the community. Such shared responsibility is becoming the response culture in the UK (with the very recent recognition of spontaneous volunteers as a source of untrained, unknown support which converges at the time of an incident). In developing countries, where the capacity of official respondents may be insufficient given the scale of the disaster, the reliance on community preparedness and spontaneous emergence of willing helpers is more acute to lessen the effects of an incident and quicken the return to normality. Thus, in addition to more technical features, the framework developed here will explicitly include community resilience as a way to lessen the impact of outages and manage disasters.  By analysing several case studies in Chile based on both data from past experiences and simulations, we will propose a general framework for disaster management and network and community resilience which can be applicable to other developing and low-income countries. We will use the research findings to develop networks standards following disasters along with a standard on community resilience to power outages. These standards will include socio-economic and engineering indicators that can support monitoring of network resilience and readiness to withstand natural, catastrophic events as well as quantifying impacts of such events after they occur, enhancing quality of post-morterm analysis.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This research Aims to:  - Develop a general socio-technical framework, bringing infrastructure and community measures together, to manage and therefore lessen the effects of power outages due to natural disasters - Develop techno-economic models for risk quantification and for assessment of optimal portfolios of measures to increase power system resilience to natural hazards, including the ability to manage the associated disasters via distributed energysystems based on communities and microgrids - Develop a quantitative understanding of the current good practices on technical (natural disaster modelling, infrastructure risk exposure, mitigation measures) and social (community resilience and citizen preparedness) options for disaster management and electrical infrastructure resilience to extreme natural events, and in particular earthquakes and tsunamis, and conduct a gap analysis of weaknesses in the current practices - Develop social models for community preparedness and response to natural disaster In order to maximise the impacts of the proposed project, the specific Objectives that we want to achieve are the following: - Understand consequences of earthquakes and tsunamis on power networks and citizen&apos;s experience, including their interactions under emergency - Study current good practices and gaps regarding community and citizen preparedness to respond to and manage disasters in Chile, developing countries and developed countries - Determine citizens&apos; experience and explore potential measures for effective community preparedness and response - Provide recommendations for security standards and socio-economic and engineering indicators for disaster management and resilience measures associated to power systems - Develop stochastic optimisation models for both (i) disaster management and mitigation measures in real-time operation and (ii) adaptation and planning decisions for investment and network design - Develop specific models to assess the contribution of distributed energy systems (such as community based systems and microgrids) to system reliability and resilience. - Develop a numerical simulation model of earthquakes and tsunamis suitable for infrastructure impact studies, which can be validated based on data available from real experiences in Chile - Study current good practices and gaps regarding spontaneous (rather than prescribed) measures and responses of power network and its participants (i.e. generators, network operators, general network users, etc.), including identification and population of alternative measures - Develop stochastic simulation models of the power system under occurrence of natural hazards, identifying critical electrical components and their systemic impacts and response - Determine scenarios and case studies based on Chilean experience - Determine risks and optimal portfolios of preventive and corrective disaster management measures, including with the support of robustness analysis.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-24" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-18">28351.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-18">128480.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-18">56163.22</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
