<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-EP_N004043_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton Fund - New Configurations of Power Converters for Grid Interconnection Systems</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This Newton Fund project will be a colaboration between the University of Nottingham, Uk and the Universities of Talca and Concepcion, Chile.  According the National Energy Strategy proposed by the Chilean Government in March 2012, the growing technological development in Chile has lead to the search of energy efficiency and the penetration of renewable energies and other generation systems to the electricity supply network. In this context, power converters play an important role for the management of electric energy, providing the interconnection between the generation and the distribution systems. This project will investigate new multi-modular power conversion architectures within such an integrated power interconnection system. Such architectures allow the grid interconnection of different types of generation and loads enabling a cost effective, clean and sustainable electrical transmission and distribution structure for Chile (which could also be extensible to the rest of South-America and even Europe) with improved power quality. Specific objectives of the proposal are small and lightweight multi-modular power converter structures to enable grid embedded generators. The development of advanced modulation and control algorithms are needed for conditioning in multi-parameter systems. The required control algorithms will be based on a study of the proposed embedded architectures and their behavior for different grid conditions such as low voltage, high harmonic content, voltage distortion, and frequency variations. Functionality of proposed converter architectures will be verified through hardware validation and testing. A smart electrical system as such should clearly address the two most important factors for secure, cost-effective energy: improving efficiency and maintaining supply.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2015-03-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-13" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="IN" type="INDIA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">689</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-13">58957.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-13">59435.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-13">29958.48</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The overall objective of this proposal is to investigate multi-modular architectures of energy conversion that would allow the grid interconnection of different types of generation systems and/or loads with a cheap, clean and sustainable transmission and distribution structure for Chile (which can be also extended to the rest of South-America and even Europe) with improved power quality. All power generating and consuming units are interconnected and cooperative. In such a way the different units are more embedded in the power grids, especially local or small grids with high penetration of renewable energies, making them &quot;smarter&quot;, more energy efficient and more adapted to variable customer needs. By introducing an agile and flexible way of balancing power supply and demand, the proposal addresses the issues of consumption fluctuation and the integration of renewable energies. This proposal is driven by industrial requirements and the teams involved are balanced between industry and academia. At the project end there will be a demonstration and validation phase with realistic uses and the publication of the results in high impact factor conferences and journals. The proposal is designed to cover the following specific objectives:  a) Modeling and integration frameworks - To investigate modeling techniques and comprehensive integrated tools to evaluate possibilities and benefits of solid state transformers (multiport bidirectional converter) integrated into distribution network, regarding all present technical limitations and latest achievements. - To evaluate converter impact on energy and voltage management within distribution network, especially taking into account influence of distributed generation facilities like rooftop photovoltaic plants and small wind generation plants.  b) Smart, cooperative and open system - To investigate possibilities of integration for a multiport multidirectional converter applied to distributed generation and consumption of energy, especially regarding new devices and technologies such as solid state isolated transformers, new switching devices, etc.  - To investigate issues such as the ability to respond in real-time to dynamic and complex situation while preserving control, system safety reliability and energy efficiency. The proposed architectures are sensitive to the physical environment, in this case grid and consumer needs, so enabling fast feedback loops between actuating and sensing, with cognitive and learning capabilities included is essential. The fast local actuators are distributed and autonomous but capable of facilitating seamless connectivity to upper control levels.  c) To strengthen the international scientific and technological cooperation between Chile and UK  - To strengthen the relationship and international scientific and technological cooperation between University of Nottingham (UK), Universidad de Talca and Universidad de Concepci&#xF3;n (Chile) through the development of joint research in the area of power electronics applied to smart grids. - To strengthen the formation of human resources in order to provide knowledge in the power electronics area applied to grid interconnection of generation systems, which is an important issue for national and global development. - To generate an instance of debate and discussion with experts from Chile, UK and around the world about power electronics in smart grids and advances in generation, transmission, and distribution of electrical energy."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
