<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_R020868_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dissecting global protective immune response to dengue virus at a single-cell resolution</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dengue virus (DENV) infection is a mosquito-borne disease that infects 390 million people each year. Despite a sharp rise in the number of infected case over the past decade, there is currently no available specific treatment. A vaccine has been developed but is of limited efficacy and has been shown to cause severe side-effects when given to young children. It has been observed that some individuals who are infected with the virus either develop no or very mild symptoms and clear the virus, whereas other individuals develop fever and severe symptoms such as bleeding and shock. Here we aim to compare infected individuals with and without these harmful symptoms to better understand which parts of the immune systems are responsible for clearing the virus and which parts are responsible for causing the often very severe symptoms without clearing the virus effectively.  Human &quot;innate&quot; immune response reacts to general danger signals such as those generated during a viral infection, whereas the &quot;adaptive&quot; immune response recognises the shape of an invader and mount a specific response against this. B and T lymphocytes are the mediators of the adaptive immune response. Each individual T and B lymphocyte carries a unique receptor that is able to recognise a different shape on the infectious agent. Therefore, ideally, immune responses need to be studied at the level of the single cell.  At the Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute (WTSI UK), cutting-edge technology has recently been developed that is able to profile immune cells at the single cell level. Complex &quot;transcriptomics&quot; data are generated, and computational tools for the successful analysis of this type of large-scale data have only recently been developed.   We now propose to apply single cell profiling techniques to one of the most comprehensive Dengue patient cohort assembled in Thailand, one of the main hubs of dengue cases By identifying specific differences in the immune response of individuals with and without disease, we will (1) identify the specific cell subtypes of both the innate and adaptive immune response that is responsible for clearing the virus, (2) provide a molecular description of the receptors in B and T cells that are able to bind the virus. The knowledge gained will help to develop more effective vaccines and anti-viral treatments. In addition, the project will allow Mahidol University (MU, Thailand) to develop a single-cell analysis platform that can be applied to study other infectious diseases in the future.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="TH" type="THAILAND"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-16">159473.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-16">120669.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-16">84435.05</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="We propose to combine multidisciplinary expertise from leading researchers in different fields to uncover how human immune system response to dengue virus (DENV) infection using a new technology called single-cell RNA sequencing. We will put together the single-cell genomics expertise of Dr Sarah A Teichmann&apos;s (SAT) lab at the Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute (WTSI), UK, with the tetramer technology provided by Dr. Juthathip Mongkolsapaya (JM) group at Imperial College (IC), UK, and apply these techniques to a unique dengue patient cohort that has been assembled by Dr. Ponpan Matangkasombut Choopong (PMC) at Mahidol University (MU), Thailand. Together with expertise in immune response to DENV of PMC and JM, transcriptional regulation/computational biology expertise of SAT, Dr. Varodom Charoensawan (VC), Dr. Kerstin Meyer (KM) and Dr. Oranart Matangkasombut (OM), we will profile different types of protective and detrimental immune responses against DENV infection.   Scientific aims and expected outcomes are as follow: - Comprehensive immune profile of protective (and detrimental) immune responses in human DENV infection, which could form the basis for assessing candidate vaccines (i.e. an effective vaccine should induce an immune profile that mimics this natural protective response) - In-depth protective T and B cell profiles, which could aid target discovery of DENV infection - Full-length sequence of specific protective TCR and BCR, which could lead to the development of T cell-based therapy and antibody treatment against DENV infection - A new platform to study immune responses to infectious diseases at the single-cell level"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
