<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P024025_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF-BBR: Beyond the genome: Enabling tropical livestock EWAS of infectious diseases</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cattle are a vital component of the economies of low and middle income countries across the globe. They are a source of meat and dairy products, provide leather and other by-products and are often used as working animals. Cattle can be grazed where crops are not easily grown, provide manure as effective fertiliser and can convert forage into high-protein food. Often cattle are the most valuable possession individuals in low and middle income countries own, but are susceptible to a range of infectious diseases, which not only inflict a heavy economic burden on these countries but can also often be transmissible to humans.  Over two-thirds of the global cattle population are in low and middle income countries. Reducing the burden of cattle infectious diseases would consequently have major benefits to these areas. However for many diseases no vaccine or treatment is available. Where they are available, poor veterinary services generally mean the livestock keepers must pay for vaccines and treatments themselves. Consequently these diseases are major barriers to escaping poverty.   Due to the co-evolution of pathogens and cattle there are various examples of cattle breeds that show natural tolerance or resistance to important infectious diseases. Although these breeds are often less productive, making them less attractive to LMIC farmers, if the mechanisms underlying their resistance could be identified and harnessed, then breeds of both higher productivity and tolerance could potentially be developed.  The aim of this project is to develop the framework to enable the identification of genomic regions linked to tolerance/resistance via epigenome-wide association studies (EWAS). Differences in the epigenome, chemical modifications that overlay the genome, are linked to phenotypes through their association with gene regulation. By comparing the epigenomes of tolerant and susceptible animals it is possible to determine regions linked to disease resistance. However, at present we lack even baseline information on the epigenomes of LMIC cattle breeds, and the tools and resources for undertaking blood-based EWAS. In particular, as blood samples are a composite of various cell types, each with a distinct epigenome profile, it is necessary to disentangle any epigenetic alterations linked to disease tolerance from differences resulting purely from variation in cell-type composition between samples. We will address this by generating an epigenome atlas of major immune cell types across the two major sub-species of cattle prevalent in LMICs. Using this resource we will create a web portal to enable users to estimate the cell-type composition in their samples, allowing downstream EWAS not confounded by between sample composition variations, providing a greater ability to identify true epigenome differences linked to infectious diseases.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-07-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="KE" type="KENYA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1027</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-28">38243.94</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The primary aim of this pilot proposal is to characterise methylation diversity in the bovine host, with a focus on breeds of cow relevant to Lower and Middle Income Country (LMIC) agriculture. We will characterise methylation in LMIC infectious disease-pertinent immune cell subsets and develop a cell-type composition correction framework to enable epigenome-wide association studies of tropical livestock infectious diseases. This will involve:  1) Generate and make available an atlas of whole-genome (Reduced Representation Bisulfite Sequencing; RRBS) methylation profiles for each of the following major nucleated bovine blood cell types (monocytes, B cells, natural killer (NK) cells, CD8+ and CD4+ T cells, gamma-delta T cells, macrophages and dendritic cells) in Bos t. taurus and Bos t. indicus animals (n=6), RNA from the samples being stored for follow-up work. 2) Assess the accuracy with which these reference panels can be used to infer cell type proportions in artificial cell mixtures of known composition using available correction protocols. Subsequently test these protocols on whole blood samples where cell type composition has been independently assayed via flow cytometry; the importance of the sub-species of origin of the reference panel to accuracy being assessed. 3) Develop a web portal, in close collaboration with the FAANG consortium, to provide wider access to this atlas of blood methylation profiles that allows user to estimate cell-type composition profiles of their own samples and perform bovine EWAS."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">12747.98</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P024025_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">12747.98</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P024025_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">12747.98</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P024025_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">22088.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P024025_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
