<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000720_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building the barricades: Three interdisciplinary studies on Mental and Substance Use Disorders in the context of armed violence in Brazil</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This multi-disciplinary project seeks to reveal social and cultural insights into Mental, Neurological, and Substance Use (MNS) Disorders in Brazilian urban communities made fragile by multiple stress factors (socio-economic exclusion, high levels of violence, limited access to cultural networks and institutions, etc). Three interconnected studies will explore possible resolutions that aim to bring mutual learning between scholars, policy makers, community activists, local residents and substance users. The project develops an innovative inter-disciplinary analytical and methodological framework that builds on the strengths of the research team to bridge geographical, social and disciplinary borders. It combines the analytical approach of the social sciences with investigative traditions in the humanities to explore integrated ways to produce, share and disseminate learning between multiple agents and audiences. Innovative coproduction and simultaneous generation of impact and knowledge exchange is central to the research aims and design. The research is rooted empirically in territorially specific community-based research in Mar&#xE9;, the largest favela complex in Rio de Janeiro - a city in which over 22% of the population (more than 6 million people) live in &apos;slums&apos;.  Objectives:  CONCEPTUAL: To investigate the context of MNS disorders and their impacts on fragile urban communities subject to multiple stress-factors as a means of developing municipal and national strategies that inform international debates about how to work towards UN SDG 3; to develop statistically relevant and artistically excellent research that explores how the Brazilian state&apos;s armed response to the illicit drug trade (part of the &apos;war on drugs&apos;) affects incidence and severity of, prevention of and resilience against MNS disorders in peripheral urban communities known as favelas (and similar territories across Latin America); to understand how social, cultural and territorial factors impact on the vulnerability and resilience of the mental health of residents, healthcare workers and those living with addiction to psychoactive substances on the streets in the vicinity of the Complex of Mar&#xE9; (estimated population: 140,000).  EMPIRICAL: To examine how insights into the narrative of people living with MNS disorders in marginalised communities can address stigma and discrimination; how researchers can increase awareness of the socio-economic and cultural contexts which affect - and are affected by - the ways illicit drugs are openly traded and used; how new learning can impact on harm reduction strategies and open up research trajectories that inform and improve public policy in LMICs; what factors concerning the social organisation and cultural capital of Rio de Janeiro&apos;s favelas offer opportunities to build community-based responses to MNS disorders; how these communities can be more effectively connected to and inform service provision addressing context specific issues of disability, quality of life, wellbeing, economic status and levels of social participation.  METHODOLOGICAL: To develop a quantitative and qualitative methodological framework to examine MNS disorders in fragile urban communities affected by violence that combines participatory appraisal, testimonies, service mapping, narrative and photographic studies as an effective way of understanding the lived realities in Brazilian favelas, treating participants as active agents; to share methodological tools across disciplinary and geographical borders between Brazil and UK; to build capacity among civil society organizations and academic partners.  POLICY INTERVENTIONS: To engage policy makers to increase knowledge about MNS disorders in health, public security, education and social care workers; to promote collaborations between policy makers, academics, health workers and civil society organisations to devise evidence-based strategies to maximize local resources in building resistance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This research aims to understand the impact of armed conflict on the mental health and wellbeing of people living in the context of violence in  the Complex of Mar&#xE9; - a conglomeration of 16 peripheral communities in Rio de Janeiro with a population of over 140,000 people*. By focusing on Brazil - a LMIC in which the state pursues a military-style intervention into peripheral urban territories (favelas) regulated by armed gangs trading drugs - the research seeks to locate an understanding of MNS disorders within the intensity of armed conflicts in peripheral territories that characterise many of the world&apos;s poorest and least developed countries. The research will seek to bring new understanding about the mental health and wellbeing of people living within a community subject to multiple stress factors (socio-economic exclusion, high levels of violence, limited access to cultural networks and institutions, etc) where daily lives are circumscribed by multi-faceted armed regulation and combat resulting from the so-called &apos;war on drugs&apos;.  While the situation of MNS disorders is acute in fragile territories on the peripheries of many major cities in LMICs, the favelas of Rio de Janeiro are characterized by a narcotic narrative of sale, consumption, conflict and abuse that makes the territorially-specific analysis at the heart of this research an appropriate means to open up new avenues for future research. In the absence of funding or state structures that can develop, evaluate and maintain complex mental health interventions in LMICs, civil society organizations that utilize existing personal and social resources that can be provided through trained lay people, volunteers, peers, and families. This proposal will learn from, and develop low-cost approaches that are found to be effective within the context of the urban battlefields of the war on drugs in Rio de Janeiro.  Locating the research in Mar&#xE9; is significant since it allows the contextualization of the research questions in a territory where there are 15 areas used for the open dealing of crack, known locally as &apos;cracolandias&apos;** [http://bit.ly/2moGPC4]; a lethality rate due to police actions in Mar&#xE9; in 2016 (12.8:100,000 inhabitants) eight times higher than that of Brazil (1.6:) and three times that of Rio de Janeiro state (3.9:) in 2015], as well as informal care networks for people living with MNS disorders. Mar&#xE9; is of the scale of a small city and has an organization, Redes da Mar&#xE9;, which has a long experience in the field of studies on violence and public safety and in the field of care for people who use crack, alcohol and other drugs.  The research proposes 3 studies: Study 1 on 200 crack-cocaine users living on or at risk of living on streets within and on the borders of the Mar&#xE9; communities, investigating existing mental health of the respondents, their knowledge and perception about MNS disorders, possibilities of self- and community-based care, existence of informal care networks. Study 2: an investigation of the mental health and wellbeing of people affected by high levels of violence and insecurity, with a focus on their mental health, patterns of drug use (legal and illegal), family and educational background, income generation and access to social, health and drug treatment programmes. It will include a survey of 1,200 residents of Mar&#xE9; with respondents from each of the 16 communities and 20 semi-structured interviews with respondents from the survey who are living with mental disorders and/or substance abuse Study 3: Arts-based practices to produce narratives and images that challenge stigma and exclusion associated with MNS disorders, resulting in of life stories and a public photographic installation.  * Population data source: IBGE - Brazilian Institute of Geography and Statistics&apos; Profile of Brazilian Municipalities 2011 http://bit.ly/2mgzu6M ** RUI, Taniele. Usage of &quot;Luz&quot; and &quot;cracolandia&quot;: fieldwork of spatial practices&quot;</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-03" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-27">185187.85</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-27">266031.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-27">294985.35</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">82799.48</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000720_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">82799.475</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000720_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">135508.17</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000720_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">82799.48</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000720_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">83470.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000720_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">83470.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000720_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">83470.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000720_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">83470.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000720_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">84865.86</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000720_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
