<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-29104</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NLB Tutunska banka, A.D. Skopje, Senior Loan Investment</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NLB Tutunska banka A.D. Skopje, (the Bank) is a joint stock commercial bank in the Republic of Macedonia and currently the third largest Bank by assets in the country. The Bank is a majority owned subsidiary of Nova Ljubljanska banka d.d., Ljubljana, Slovenia (NLB), which directly holds 60.26% and through its wholly-owned subsidiary NLB InterFinanz AG, Z&#xFC;rich holds another 26.72%.  The remainder of the shares is held by other investors.


The Project consists of an investment in a senior loan of up to EUR30 million to the Bank for up to 5 years and is one element of an umbrella facility which IFC will provide to NLB.  This umbrella facility represents IFCs commitment to support its existing relationship with NLB Group, an emerging bank with banking and leasing operations in regional markets key to IFC, as well as IFCs commitment to support SME financing in the Republic of Macedonia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed IFC investment will support SME lending activities of the Bank in a rather underdeveloped market such as the Republic of Macedonia.  In this country, where private sector credit/GDP is at significantly lower levels compared to EU, IFC will contribute to expanding access to term finance and support SMEs capital investment plans.  The SME sector is an important driver of the Macedonian economy still offering attractive growth opportunities. Increased availability of term financing through the domestic banking sector will support private sector credit growth.

As the Republic of Macedonia is a former Yugoslav republic, the Project will signal IFCs confidence in the long-term prospects of the countrys banking sector and economy and will help strengthen the countrys standing as an investment destination.  In the short-term, IFCs liquidity support will buttress the markets confidence in the Banks standing and credibility.

The Project is a good example of IFCs strategy to support intra-regional investments by NLB based in Slovenia, a transition country (albeit one that is now an EU member), into other countries in its region. The successful implementation of the Project will help an experienced strong local sponsor to grow further as a regional player, and facilitate transfer of capital and modern banking practices from Slovenia into the lesser developed markets, such as the Republic of Macedonia. At the same time, the Project supports a key player in the Macedonian banking sector to weather the ongoing global economic crisis and to continue providing essential funding to an economy, which has suffered under the effects of the worldwide crisis.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NLB BANKA AD SKOPJE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-29104" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-03-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-05-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NLB Tutunska banka A.D. Skopje 
Ul. Vodnjanska No. 1 
MK-1000 Skopje 
Republic of Macedonia

Ana Jancevska; Marketing Advisor; Control, Coordination and Marketing Department; Management Board Office; Phone: +389-5100-302; Fax +389-5100-681; E-mail:  a.jancevska@tb.com.mk

Vesna Ivanovska; Public Relation Advisor; Control, Coordination and Marketing Department; Management Board Office; Phone: +389-5100-865; Fax: +389-5100-681; E-mail: v.ivanovska@tb.com.mk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Macedonia, Former Yugoslav Republic of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="MK-Macedonia, Former Yugoslav Republic of">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Bank has its head office in Skopje, Republic of Macedonia, and as of October 2009, has 48 branches throughout the country, 20 of which are in the capital Skopje.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>41.6666720000 21.7500000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="5221" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Commercial Banking - General</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $34.91 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2010-03-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-03-31">34910000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-03-31">34910000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NLB BANKA AD SKOPJE</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/29104/nlb-tutunska-banka-a-d-skopje-senior-loan-investment">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
