<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>HK-CR-2091642-Migration Communications Campaigns</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="HK-CR-2091642" secondary-reporter="0" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Seefar Enterprise</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Migration Communications Campaigns</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men and women from Nigeria, The Gambia and Iraq aged 16-34 and interested in irregular migration, as well as their families and relatives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Seefar is implementing three migration communication campaigns in The Gambia, Nigeria and Iraqi Kurdistan. Seefar&#x2019;s research suggests that many potential migrants are not sufficiently informed about key aspects of the journey, such as travel costs, risks and the reality of life in Europe. While migrants are often confident that they know the risks of irregular migration, many doubt they will actually be impacted by these risks. Furthermore, migrants almost always underestimate the financial costs of the journey and the opportunities they will lose at home &#x2013; leaving them vulnerable to exploitation and other dangers. A communications campaign implemented in origin countries can help fill the knowledge gaps. Accurate and complete information provided by trusted sources subsequently enables potential
migrants to make informed decisions. The communications campaigns in The Gambia, Nigeria and Iraqi Kurdistan
deploy an integrated approach to drive behaviour change. They combine media engagement and online and social media
outreach with direct community influence at the heart of the campaigns.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the three campaigns is provide potential migrants in the three countries with factual and useful  information to help them make more informed decisions about migration. By providing this information, the campaign aims to protect vulnerable people from harm and exploitation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Seefar</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="GM" percentage="33.33"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="33.33"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="33.34"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="99820" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
