<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-523558</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EOFI MBA Ploymer</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MBA Polymers, Inc. (the company or MBA), is a materials recovery/recycling company in Richmond, California, USA.  MBA owns and operates an engineering thermoplastic (ETP) recycling facility in Richmond and plans to construct and operate a 40,000 TPY plant in Guangzhou, China.  The principal source of feedstock for this plant will be collected in and shipped from appliance, electronics, and office equipment recycling facilities in Japan.  The company has requested the Environmental Opportunities Facility (EOF) of IFC to provide an equity investment of $1.2 million in the company.   The proposed investment would support MBAs planned expansion into markets where costs of virgin materials are relatively high and materials take-back mechanisms have been mandated in producer countries.  MBA estimates that its proprietary recovery and refining process, producing high-quality recovered materials, is a minimum of two years ahead of any competing process.
MBA is providing a high-quality, market-driven product which addresses the environmental issue of  ETP disposal.  In those countries where take-back mechanisms have been legislated, ETP is usually burned in municipal waste incinerators or landfilled.  A very small percentage is currently recovered/recycled despite its high value  exceeding that of other recovered waste materials, including aluminum and PET bottles.  Where 1 kilogram of virgin ETP is replaced by recovered material, 2 to 3 kilograms of CO2 is prevented from entering the atmosphere, reducing greenhouse gases.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNKNOWN</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-523558" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2004-10-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">To contact the project company, please contact:

Susan Aumiller 
MBA Polymers, Inc.
500 West Ohio Avenue
Richmond, CA 94804
USA

Telephone: 510-231-9031 ext 107
Fax: 510-231-0302
e-mail: saumiller@mbapolymers.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="CN-China">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The GMP plant is located in an industrial zone in the Nansha Development Area of Guangzhou, China, nearby such factories as GE Plastics largest plant in China. The location of a second facility is still under discussion, though the current projection is that it would be in Northern China.  In addition, there is the possibility that MBA will allocate some of IFC/EOFs funds to develop a joint venture factory in an IFC eligible country in Southeastern Europe.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.0000000000 105.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AC - Other Plastic and Rubber Products  (Including Polypropylene Bags, Housing Components, Containers, etc.)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/523558/eofi-mba-ploymer">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
