<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-33120</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ENN Energy Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1)	Increase the accessibility of natural gas beyond the reach of gas pipelines by building an LNG distribution infrastructure independent of traditional piped gas distribution; (2)	Contribute to the development of an LNG vehicle market by making LNG available along major transportation lines while LNG availability has been the major bottleneck hindering the growth of the sector;  (3)	Help to reduce local pollution and GHG emissions by promoting the use of natural gas as a cleaner alternative fuel to diesel and gasoline in the transport sector; (4)	Increase competiveness of small enterprises by providing a cost competitive transportation fuel for truck and long-haul bus owners, most of whom are individuals or families from the rural area; and (5)	Increasing employment through the creation of a LNG fueling station network.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chinas rapid economic growth, industrialization, and urbanization over the last 30 years has lifted some 400 million people out of poverty, but also created new environmental challenges. China is now the largest source of SO2 and NOX emissions, and responsible for 60% of the global increase in carbon emissions over the last ten years. This is largely attributable to Chinas heavy reliance on coal (70%) and oil (17%), with natural gas only accounting for 4% of energy consumption. To address climate change and environmental degradation challenges, the Chinese government is promoting the use of natural gas and renewable energy, and clean technologies, as well as improvements on energy efficiency. In its 12th Five-year Plan on greenhouse emission control, China set its new goals of reducing carbon emissions per unit of national income in the next five years from 2010 by 17 % and called for pilot programs that aim to promote a low-carbon economy.   The proposed project is to build and operate around 500 liquefied natural gas (LNG) fueling stations with an objective to make LNG available as a cleaner and cheaper substitute of diesel for long-haul buses and heavy trucks along the key transportation lines across 14 provinces in China (the Project).   A typical LNG truck will have 90% fewer NOX and PM emissions than a diesel truck, 100% fewer SOX emissions, and 30% fewer Greenhouse Gas (GHG) emissions. LNG fuel also enjoys very favorable economics over petroleum with fuel cost savings typically reported in the 30% range as compared to diesel. The objective of the Project is to, together with other similar projects currently undertaken by other gas distribution companies, build a country-wide LNG distribution network in China that will make LNG available to thousands of long-haul buses and heavy trucks along the major inter-province highways and it is expected that the increased availability of the LNG will stimulate a broad conversion of heavy trucks and long haul buses from traditionally being diesel powered to gas powered.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ENN Energy Holdings Limited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-33120" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-05-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-07-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ENN Energy Ltd. (Corporate Office) Huaxiang Road, Economic and Technological Development Zone, LangFang Hebei Province China.P.C.065001 Telephone: 0316-2599503/00852 54185700 Fax: 0316-2597461 Contact: Christy Liang (General Counsel).</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ENN Energy Ltd. (Corporate Office) Huaxiang Road, Economic and Technological Development Zone, LangFang Hebei Province China.P.C.065001 Telephone: 0316-2599503/00852 54185700 Fax: 0316-2597461 Contact: Christy Liang (General Counsel).</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="CN-China">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Company currently operates around 100 LNG stations and plans to build additional 400 or so LNG fueling stations in the next three years.  These stations will be located along the key transportation lines across 14 provinces and municipalities in China, including Inner Mongolia, Yunnan, Guangxi, Hunan, Beijing Municipality, Anhui, Henan, Guangdong, Liaoning, Shandong, Jiangsu, Zhejiang, Fujian, Hebei.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.0000000000 105.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="211" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">B-AB - Oil and Gas Production (Includes Development)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $75.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-05-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-05-31">75000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-05-31">75000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ENN Energy Holdings Limited</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/33120/enn-energy-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/33120/enn-energy-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
