<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-24942</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zhejiang Glass Company</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will support Zhejiang Glass efforts to rationalize its balance sheet and return to financial health, so that it can continue to grow and become a leader in Chinas glass industry.  The Government is encouraging the glass industry to upgrade its technology and focus on high quality glass production, which is in-line with Zhejiang Glass strategy.  This project is also consistent with the Governments efforts by supporting a competitive local producer as it integrates upstream to better control its production cost with in-house soda ash. Finally, the companys major investment in a soda ash plant in Qinghai  an interior province where investment opportunities are scarce - is generating more economic activity in a small town, Delingha. The plant is adding significant value to the provinces raw materials and is employing about 1,500 people, composed predominantly of locals. Additional indirect impacts include more revenues for small businesses, such as truck owners, which are benefiting from increased activity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zhejiang Glass Company, Limited (Zhejiang Glass or the company) is one of the five largest float glass manufacturers in China, and listed on the Main Board of the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. Established in 1994 in Shaoxing, Zhejiang province, the company has grown rapidly in recent years. It currently operates five flat glass production lines with an aggregate daily melting capacity of 2,350 tons; and ix glass processing lines for the production of value-added products such as tempered and laminated glass as well as energy efficient low-emission glass.  In addition, the company has integrated upstream by investing into a 900,000-ton per year soda ash production line in Qinghai Province, in western China, which commenced operation in September 2005.  Most of the companys glass production is destined to the construction sector although it has diversified its sales to the automotive and electronics sectors.      Like many fast growing Chinese companies, Zhejiang Glass has relied on short term debt to fund a significant part of its capital expenditures. During 2004-5, the company has accumulated approximately $200 million equivalent of short-term debt.  The project involves the reduction and refinancing a significant part of its debt through a balance sheet restructuring plan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zhejiang Glass Company Limited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-24942" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2006-06-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2006-08-29" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">John Chung, Director and CFO   Zhejiang Glass Company Limited   Yangxunqiao Township, Shaoxing, Zhejiang, P.R.China   Telephone: +86-575-450-1087   Fax: +86-575-450-1655    The Environmental Review Summary (ERS) will be posted in the website of Zhejiang Glass, the administrative offices of Zhejiang Glass and Qinghai Soda, and in the municipal government offices of Shaoxing County, Zhejiang province and Haixi Prefecture and Delingha City, Qinghai province.</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="CN-China">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">All of the companys glass manufacturing facilities are   located in the county of Shaoxing in Zhejiang province. Shaoxing is about 35 kilometers from   Hangzhou  , Zhejiangs capital city and approximately 180 kilometers southwest of Shanghai.  The company&apos;&apos;s geographical position is convenient for transporting both raw materials to and finished product from the factory sites  as they are located in an industrial area, near the Hangzhou-Ningbo canal which links to the Ningbo port and is near several highways and national roads.     The companys soda ash plant is located at the outskirts of the city of Delingha in the western province of Qinghai.  Delingha is approximately 500 kilometers west of Xining, Qinghais capital.  The area around Delingha is quite rural with the primary livelihood being herding. The area is also rich in salt and limestone, the main raw materials for soda ash production. The plant has a rail track which leads to the main railway network of the province, facilitating the transport of the finished soda ash to its customers in different parts of China.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.0000000000 105.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CA - Glass and Glass Products (Including Glass and Mineral Wool)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $75.02 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2006-06-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2006-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2006-06-26">25020000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2006-06-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2006-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2006-06-26">50000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2006-06-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2006-06-26">50000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zhejiang Glass Company Limited</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2006-06-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2006-06-26">25020000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zhejiang Glass Company Limited</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/24942/zhejiang-glass-company">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
