<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-25665</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China Glass</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China Glass Holdings (CGH or the company), is a float glass manufacturer currently in the process of acquiring eight smaller glass companies across China. Once the acquisitions are completed, CGH will become the largest listed float glass company in China with 14 production lines and a melting capacity of 4,780 tons per day (tpd). CGH also plans to invest in a joint-venture to establish manufacturing of solar glass.   The float glass market in China is highly fragmented with currently 52 local glass manufacturers. Demand for float glass has grown at a strong CAGR of 14% between 2000 and 2005, with slowing growth in 2006. In parallel, substantial supply was added to the current stock, putting pressure on prices. The market however now appears to be stabilizing with a noticeable increase in prices in late 2006 and early 2007. Through its ongoing acquisitions, CGH will contribute to the consolidation of the flat glass sector in China, helping to reduce future volatility.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is part of the consolidation of the fragmented float glass industry in China.  Loss making float glass SOEs are being closed and the government is selling others. This process will put the industry on a commercial basis.  In addition, as a consequence of the scale economies of a large enterprise, CGH will implement cost reductions, gain efficiency improvements and operating synergies particularly in energy utilization.  The company will also lower its unit SG&amp;A costs by centralizing all marketing and logistic activities. The Project, with Pilkingtons shareholding will help bring more world-class technology to the glass industry in China and not only help meet the growing demand for high quality glass, but improve the efficiency/productivity in the industry.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHINA GLASS HOLDING CO LTD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-25665" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-05-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-05-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Jianmin Li (Tony) HONY Capital/China Glass Holdings Limited 7F, Tower A, Raycom InfoTech Park No 2, Kexueyuan Nanlu, Haidian District Beijing, China  100080 E-mail:    asingh@maxindia.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="CN-China">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The companys operations date back to 1958, when its first glass production facility went into operation in Suqian, Jiangsu province.  At that time, the company was called Jiangsu Glass Factory.  In 1994, with an aim to produce high quality float glass, the company upgraded its facility to achieve a melting capacity of 400 tons per day (tpd).  In 1997, the company was converted to a wholly state-owned enterprise and renamed the Jiangsu Glass Group.  During the period 1997 to 2003, the company went through various corporate and ownership restructurings.  In 2002, it added a second float glass line with a melting capacity of 500 tpd.  However, the modern incarnation of China Glass occurred in December 2003, when Hony became a controlling shareholder by purchasing approximately 83% of Jiangsu Glass shareholding.  The balance of ownership was with the management team of China Glass.  At that point, China Glasss operations consisted of 2 flat glass production lines with a melting capacity of 900 tpd located in Suqian.  In 2005, the Company built a third float glass line with a capacity of 600 tpd, bringing China Glasss total melting capacity to 1,500 tpd. In 2006, the Company embarked on an acquisition strategy, identifying 8 smaller companies in China as targets. Once all the acquisitions have been completed, China Glass will be one of the largest flat glass manufacturers in China, with 14 production lines and a melting capacity of 4,780 tpd.  A table showing China Glasss operations once the acquisitions are complete (excluding the JV solar glass project) can be found in the accompanying attachment.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.0000000000 105.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CA - Glass and Glass Products (Including Glass and Mineral Wool)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $75.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="912"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2007-05-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2007-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-05-16">15000000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2007-05-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2007-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-05-16">60000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2007-05-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-05-16">15000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHINA GLASS HOLDING CO LTD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2007-05-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-05-16">60000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHINA GLASS HOLDING CO LTD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="912"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/25665/china-glass">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
