<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-11384</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asia Strategic Investments Corporation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Group operates as an integrated entity supplying a wide range of automotive components (including foundry products, brake systems, diesel fuel injection systems, electrical products, and engine parts and accessories) to the Chinese and the international markets.    In 2001, it had revenues of about US$160 million, EBITDA of US$25 million, and a net income of US$1.8 million.  Total assets at the end of 2001 were US$400 million and shareholder funds were US$235 million (including equity and interest free shareholder loans).     	The project is to establish a new company (Newco) which will acquire the Funds&apos;&apos; ownership of the Group, thereby converting the Group ownership to a corporate structure.  The current fund ownership structure restricts the Group from upgrading existing operations, taking advantage of many new investment opportunities, and financing itself in an optimal manner.  Through this ownership restructuring the Group will be able to effectively increase its value added, by allowing it to develop its franchise as a reliable and comprehensive supplier of quality auto components, and to leverage its management and manufacturing infrastructure.      The acquisition of the Funds&apos;&apos; ownership of the Group will be effected by the Limited Partners converting about 30% of their ownership interest into shares in Newco, and Newco purchasing the remaining 70%.  The management of ASIMCO will become the management of Newco, and the ASIMCO staff that currently manage the operating units will be retained to manage the operations.       DEVELOPMENT IMPACT    The proposed project is expected to contribute to the transformation and rationalization of the industry, which has traditionally been dominated by inefficient state-owned enterprises. This is all the more important as China&apos;&apos;s entry into the WTO is likely to have a significant impact on the automotive component industry in China, both in terms of challenges and opportunities. Through the project, IFC will support a group of restructured SOEs, who can become successful examples of China&apos;&apos;s restructuring and privatization process.    The Group has been a pioneer in introducing modern management techniques, while relying on local managerial talent for plant operations. This has resulted in significant welfare benefits for local staff and the strengthening of local managerial skills and capacity. The Group was named one of the &quot;Ten Best Employers in China&quot; as part of the &quot;Best Employers in Asia&quot; study conducted by the Asian Wall Street Journal, The Far East Economic Review and Hewitt Associates. The Group possesses the management ability to provide leadership in the Chinese automotive components sector with regard to EHSS performance - and can drive these issues down to the next level of the supply chain pyramid, thus enhancing the development impact of the project.     IFC ROLE    IFC&apos;&apos;s assistance is targeted at supporting privatization and restructuring of the automotive component industry to better prepare it to meet the challenges of a more competitive market environment following WTO entry.  In the absence of IFC support, the restructuring of the Group is unlikely to move ahead, as the current diffused ownership structure and the diverse interests and objectives of the many parties involved make it difficult to agree and implement an appropriate strategy. Moreover, IFC&apos;&apos;s presence in the transaction is likely to be a source of comfort for co-investors which include development agencies and private investors  .    By assisting the Group in formalizing a performance based environmental management system, IFC is likely to play a vital role in improving its operating efficiency and in enhancing their ability to attract &quot;global customers&quot; that typically have environmental performance requirements for their suppliers. IFC will also continue to assist the Group with the identification of potential environmental technology products, for which there is strong demand in China.     Finally, IFC will assist Newco in adopting best corporate governance policies and practices.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asian Strategic Investments Corp. Beijing Representative Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-11384" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2004-02-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2004-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Michael Cronin   Phone: (8610) 6438-2750 ext 229     Fax:(8610) 6438 2735/6 ]   Email: henryh@asimco.com.cn</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="CN-China">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 10 operating companies are located in 8 provinces across China, including Beijing, Guangdong, Hebei, Anhui, Hunan, Hubei, Shanxi and Jiangsu.  Each of these sites is well connected by road to the company&apos;&apos;s customers.  The US based trading unit of the Group has an office in Beijing, and a sales/technical support office in the US located in Twinsburgh, Ohio.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.0000000000 105.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CG - Motor Vehicle Parts</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $15.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2004-02-27"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2004-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2004-02-27">10000000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2004-02-27"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2004-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2004-02-27">5000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2004-02-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2004-02-27">5000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asian Strategic Investments Corp. Beijing Representative Office</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2004-02-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2004-02-27">10000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asian Strategic Investments Corp. Beijing Representative Office</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/11384/asia-strategic-investments-corporation">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
