<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-16/3559/SA 2016/H/NGO/2736</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Healthcare in a Protracted War Zone</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim is to address fragmentation in healthcare services in a protracted war zone, enable better coordination and more continuous patient care, and to deliver more integrated services to everyone involved. By integrated care, we mean the organizing principle for care delivery that aims to improve patient care and experience through improved coordination. We will combine a set of methods, processes and models that seek to bring about improved coordination when it comes to both high risk and normal pregnancies and integrate it with a neonatal intensive care unit in very close proximity to the deliver ward. According to the HRP 01-12 2016, One priority in health sector of people affected by this protracted war in Syria continues to be to provide life-saving and life-sustaining humanitarian health assistance in specific interventions focusing on: provision of healthcare services (including maternal and child health.)  This project is addressing this specific healthcare need in an integrated model that will include basic and comprehensive emergency healthcare amp nutrition services to pregnant women, both high risk and general maternity care. This project also addresses the need for an improved and upgraded neonatal intensive care unit (NICU). The IMCI ,IYCF, amp malnutrition assessments will continue. Better more comprehensive prenatal care from the first trimester of pregnancy. This means we must do better more specific outreach to the people of Azzaz, by educating the locals and encouraging women to seek care as soon as they find out they&apos;re pregnant. This way, we can start monitoring both the mother and fetus throughout the pregnancy, do all the necessary blood work, start them on prenatal vitamins, and continually check on progression and/or regression of certain pregnancy related ailments, such as but not limited to pre-eclampsia, gestational diabetes, carrying multiple fetuses, anemia, obstetric cholestasis, preterm labor, and growth restrictions. Also, to set them up with social workers that will help with the social aspects of care, making sure the pregnancies go as smoothly as possible and that we don&apos;t miss anything else going on with the patient, such as violence in the home, history of mental illness, health problems etc. This integration is both basic and comprehensive emergency obstetric and new-born care. There isn&#x2019;t a single integrated model that will work in every context and in every circumstance and setting, and to add an unstable war zone to this will make things challenging, but making sure that we do whatever is possible so that the people don&#x2019;t suffer any more than they already have, and to decrease preventable deaths, is the idea behind integrating the healthcare system for the people of Azaz districts. This project will directly target 33,000 of the 47,250 women in the Azaz districts who are of childbearing age. We have a program manager and a program officer who will be working with a team of 15 outreach CHWs and 2 outreach nurse educators. The CHWs will operate in teams of 2 making 6 visits of assessment per month throughout Azaz then referring cases to the outreach nurse educators. The outreach nurse educators will then do the intake for the referrals of the pregnant women along with the necessary procedures: non-stress test, blood pressure monitoring, and other prenatal checkups. During the labor amp delivery, the labor and delivery nurses will take over the patients and assist the OBGYN doctors with the deliveries. A pediatrician will check the newborn and assess whether or not the baby needs to be referred to the NICU. If that happens, the NICU pediatricians and NICU nurses will take over the cases. However, the mother is set up with a social worker and helped with postpartum care amp any social work related problems she may have will be addressed by the social worker. The social worker will then document if the patient needs more assistance, especially in cases of GBV. This</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-17">236738.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-17">168940.45</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-2736">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-17">405679.37</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3301927919">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-28">162271.75</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302564814">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-03-27">121703.81</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302682495">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-23">73265.34</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
