<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-16/3559/SA2/E/NGO/3866</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Teaching the hard-to-reach students in the middle of Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">gtgtIn Homs&apos; governorate the north rural areas are under control of non-stated forces. Therefore, these areas were very tight in teachers because of being arrested or being fired from their jobs but they continued working as a volunteers (based on statistics from Homs governorate council which belongs to interim government and we have complete statistics for teachers) and the number that represents those teachers is really big considering all the teachers in the government. All of these consequences (arresting teachers-firing teachers from their work and continue working as volunteers) lead to assign some university&apos;s student to work as a teachers or graduated student from majors other than education major. Therefor, there is indeed need for teachers in those area to attend courses for refreshment courses. 
gtgtin addition, the conflict which is ongoing for the mean time at the sides of those sub-districts, made children of those areas discontinue their learning, and those children are estimated by the number 4430 children 2435 girls and 1995 boys ( (based on statistics from Homs governorate council ). in addition, the war which is waging since 2011 in Homs areas caused the following: 
-security situations is very high risk in these areas, 
-lot of difficulties to deliver aids and the mental health is very poor. 
- children and adolescents are the most vulnerable in those communities. 
Thus, those children in those 3 areas need psycho-social support. 
gtgtsome children from those areas are behind their peers since they misses some classes because of the bombing from airplanes and tanks so they need courses in schools to be able to follow up with their peers. 
pupils in these areas are also suffering from lack of transportation align with fearing of bombs and airplane shelling is one of the main reasons which obstruct them from going to schools. 

The project will establish 3 different learning centers in Homs governorate in 3 different besieged areas: 
1- Rastan 
2-Talbiseh 
3-Taldu 

After establishing the centers: 

1-Those centers will conduct courses for teachers to provision teacher&apos;s professional development for 150 teachers on EIE , INEE , PSS, emergency planning (as attached in documents) . these courses will last a month. 

2-after this month the centers will conduct courses for children from 6-12 who are not going to school and transportation will be provided and funded for the centers and we will emphasize that the children with disabilities will be centers&apos; priorities. in each center 125 children will take courses for 5 months to be able to get back to school again. total targeted children in all 3 centers are 375. 

3-in the centers in the noon time the center will provide PSS for 750 children will be selected based on their needs to get PSS and to be dis-aggregated by age and for 3 days a week. in each center, there will be 250 children each 125 of them will attend 3 days a week. 

4-  21 schools in those 3 Hard to reach areas will conduct 2 months catching-up lessons distributed as the following: 
7 schools in each area, 126 classes in 3 areas, 42 classes in each area.

5-  Let&apos;s get back to school campaign will be conducted in 3 areas for the communities and for children to encourage them ,the families to send their children back to school, and the community leaders, local councils, teachers...etc. 

6-project will provide transportation for students to ensure that they are safe in those areas and to encourage those who left the schools to get back. 


This project will target: 
1-Children who left the schools because of the situation in besieged areas in 3 different besieged areas in Homs governorate. 
2-Children who are already in schools but they are a little behind in learning process because of bombing and shelling in those areas. 
3-teachers who are already working in schools but some of them are not specialist or they do.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Homs</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.72996100 36.71973100</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-08">27908.53</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-08-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-08">225128.79</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-3866">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-08">253037.32</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302388160">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-22">101214.93</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
