<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-16/3559/SA 2016/H-N/NGO/2754</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health care services for conflict-affected populations in Aleppo governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will address the health and nutrition concerns of the displaced persons in 3 camps and moving IDP settlements of Azaz district, Aleppo governorate, northern Syria. This proposal will allow for the continuation of the HPF project Emergency health care services for conflict-affected populations in Aleppo governorate TUR-16/3559/RA/H/NGO/2432, funded through emergency funds following the mass displacement in February 2016. It plans to continue addressing the urgent and basic health care needs of the most vulnerable groups and reduce preventable mortality and morbidity of an estimated catchment population of100,000 IDPs and conflict affected host communities over the next 7 months. 

The project focuses on covering the running costs for the continuation of the following primary health care, nutrition and psycho-social care activities for IDPs and host communities and will not be used for any additions, expansion or purchase of equipment.

Continuation of primary health care services:
1.) Two mobile primary health care clinics will ensure access to basic healthcare services with a capacity so support 14,000 IDPs in spontaneous IDP settlements in northern Syria immediately following displacements (currently in Yazibag, Tel Alsham and Al Resalh), as well as the nearby host communities, until IDPs are settled in permanent IDP camps with established PHC services.
The mobile clinics will provide the basic general, reproductive and pediatric health care services and continue to be part of the functional referral system to secondary level health care. It will also continue providing public health awareness for preventive measures through outreach, health and hygiene education and disease and nutrition screenings by community health care workers.

2.) Two stationary pre-fabricated PHCs will continue to provide services in Shamareq and Al Rayan camps for an estimated catchment population of 20,000 IDPs and host community. The 2 PHC centers will provide the basic general, reproductive and pediatric health care services and continue to be part of the functional referral system to secondary level health care. It will also continue providing public health awareness for preventive measures through outreach, health education and disease and nutrition screenings by community health care workers. 

Continuation of emergency evacuations and referral system to secondary level health care:
3.) Two fully equipped ambulances which were purchased with the support of the previous HPF project (TUR-16/3559/RA/H/NGO/2432) will continue operating in the project area to ensure a reliable emergency evacuation of trauma cases and referrals to secondary level health care facilities for serious illnesses in coordination with other ambulance services for an estimated total of 800 patients over 7 months 

Continuation of secondary level pediatric services:
4.) Continue running the pediatric department in Bab AlSalama hospital for 7 months with 10 incubators and 2 ventilators. In collaboration with 3 other pediatric facilities in Azaz district, the in-patient pediatric needs for a catchment population of approximately 400,000 persons shall be covered. 

Continuation of IYCF and psycho-social support services:
5.) Ensure integrated IYCF and PSS support for pregnant and lactating mothers (PLW) and children under 2 years in 3 IDP camps ( Bab Al Iman, Shamareq and Al Rayan ) for 7 months through community outreach, screenings, running of IYCF/PSS spaces, individual and group education and counseling. The IYCF centers will incorporate breast feeding support, Breast Milk Substitute (BMS) training and individual  PSS in a safe, hygienic and private environment.

Based on TUR-16/3559/RA/H/NGO/2432 project funded by HPF, this project will provide funding needs to ensure the continuation of health care services for the conflict affected population for 7 month.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="75" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-02">420311.56</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-02">71200.32</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-2754">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-02">491511.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3301858489">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-08">294907.13</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302454824">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-25">196604.75</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
