<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-16/3559/SA2/WASH/NGO/3489</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Safe drinking water safe the human&apos;s life</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AL Resala Foundation (RF) established AL Resala IDPs camp in 2015 in area of 7 Hectare out of 180 Hectare near the Turkey border only 150 meters from the turkey border. Actually the area of the RF camp established,  it was agriculture productive location own by RF inside Syria  and one of the safer for the  IDPs from airstrikes, due ongoing fighting in wide areas from north eastern of Aleppo effected specially the villages north and east of Azaz lead to influx of IDPs (families) following the recent Aleppo situation. The current war has only served to exacerbate existing concerns include limited access to safe drinking water.
The total number of families in the RF camp is 1,755.
 The only sources of water available in the area,  two wells with depth 50 meter are standby, and the distant around 4.5 kilometers from the RF camp, and this will lead to  such conditions create an environment that is conducive to the rapid spread of infectious diseases that lead to high rates of morbidity and mortality war has only served to exacerbate existing concerns include limited access to safe water, it is critical that Syrian IDPs in need receive drinking water to ensure their survival, water is vital and necessary for humans and the beneficiaries in the RF camp depend on the water trucking supply , depending  to the  availability of fund from RF or the other international organization for continuation of providing water to the beneficiaries. The proposed project design to rehabilitation of the two existing boreholes in the RF camp, RF will connect the pump engines, ground tank, water pipes, chlorinated tank and other necessary parts to ensure proper functioning.
RF will provide training in WASH related activity, and also make WASH committee workers selected by voting from the IDPs.
The projects explain in details how and when the activates and the outcome will be fulfill 
For security reason and families protection, RF avoided the idea of making elevated water tanks in the camp for water network.
The elevated water tanks for the will easily armed group to measure and attack the camp, therefore RF using ground water tanks.
The proposed project of rehabilitation of the two existing boreholes in the RF camp, protect the children for collecting the water from far distant   to their family in the RF and avoided the security situation in the area  by providing safe drinking water in the RF camp.
The proposed project design connecting for rehabilitation the boreholes in the RF camp with main three ground water tanks, there will be connection to the beneficiaries&#x2019; distribution tanks, which is maximum walking distant of 20 meter for the person to collect water in the RF camp.
The total number of the beneficiaries in the RF camp 9,990 and they are receiving in a daily bases 252 cubic meters of water by water trucking and it is about 42 shifts. From the distant of 4.5 kilometers from the RF camp.
AL Resala Foundation depend on the donation and agreement with international organization fund to provide water to the beneficiaries in the RF camp, due to the limitation of the fund makes gaps  for continuation of the water supply  in the RF camp.
AL Resala Foundation active on attending the meetings and sharing the information with the WASH cluster, and a member on WASH Azaz partner. With reference to the WASH Azaz partner on 7th September 2016, one of the outcome of the meeting that World vision facing difficulties to continue providing water trucking in Azaz due to the number of the cubic meters which more than 40,000 a day.
AL Resala Foundation takes the responsibility   providing the water to IDPs in RF camp since the 1st of august 2016 by water trucking to the RF camp.
The rehabilitation of the two boreholes in RF camp will improved the safe drinking water and sustainability 
By rehabilitation of the boreholes in the RF camp the beneficiaries they will have sustainable safe drinking water.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-11">135978.55</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-11">134484.28</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-3489">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-11">270462.83</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302331258">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-01">135231.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302636262">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-04">135231.41</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
