<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-16/3559/RA/CCM/INGO/2473</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lifesaving Multi-Sectoral assistance to the new IDPs in informal sites in Azaz</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Turkey focuses on providing life-saving, life-sustaining and dignifying support in concert with other International Non-Government Organizations (INGOs) operating on the ground for newly arrived Internally Displaced Peoples (IDPs) in already established camps Sijjo and Shamarin, in the extension of Al Haramein camps, and in collective centres in Azaz city. 

With this project, World Vision Turkey aims to improve the living conditions of both newly displaced IDP&#x2019;s whom have recently arrived in Azaz sub-district and have settled in informal settlements by scaling up the ongoing response of World Vision in Azaz, as well as continuing to support IDPs with essential activities in Sijjo, Al Haramein, and Shamarin camps. Scale-up will include the provision of essential life-sustaining NFIs, and the improvement of emergency sanitation and shelter conditions, and water infrastructure. In total this project will reach 33,844 IDPs in informal settlements, and camps in Azaz sub-district.

The overall goal of the project is to support saving lives, alleviate suffering and increase access to humanitarian response for vulnerable people and those with specific needs in Northern Aleppo following the recent attacks of the Government of Syria (GoS) and its allies.

The expected outcomes of the project are 1) To scale up the provision of life-sustaining NFIs for emergency delivery, 2) To improve shelter and sanitation conditions among newly arrived IDPs living in informal settlements and 3) To improve access to essential water infrastructure among IDPs living in camps and informal settlements.

This will be achieved through the following main activities:
-	Emergency distribution of essential NFIs including mattresses, blankets, kitchen utensils, and solar lights to newly arrived IDPs
-	Emergency distribution of critical winterization NFIs including, heaters/cooking stoves and heating fuel, and household fire safety kits to newly arrived IDPs, as well as support for a civil defense fire truck to respond to fires 
-	Installation of pre-fabricated latrines and showers 
-	Implementation of sewage network and installation of septic tanks to support pre-fabricated latrines 
-	Provision of household and community level waste/rubbish bins
-	Maintenance of water systems in Sijjo, Shamarin and Al Haramein camps through provision of running costs and cleaning of latrines
-	Emergency water trucking, and water quality monitoring and management, to IDPs
-	Replacement of borehole pump to increase pumping capacity to facilitate water trucking 
-	Expansion of water network to Al Haramein camp extension and construction of water points
-	Solid waste management services in Sijjo, Shamarin and Al Haramein camps and in informal settlements
-	Hygiene promotion sessions in Sijjo, Shamarin and Al Haramein camps
-	Levelling and gravelling in informal settlements

World Vision will directly implement this project in Sijjo, Shamarin and Al Haramein camps and in informal settlements and collective centers in Azaz sub-district. World Vision already operates in the aforementioned camps, and already benefits from a level of acceptance among the local population, ensuring successful implementation of the project. World Vision plans to reach 9600 individuals (1528 households) in informal settlements adjacent to camps in 7 locations, and 24,244 IDPs living in Al Haramein, Sjjio and Shamarin camps.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-25" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-25" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-02-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-08-25"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-15">999905.3</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-2473">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-15">999905.3</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3301664697">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-23">799924.24</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302373391">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-19">199934.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
