<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-16/3559/SA2/H/NGO/3869</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Primary Healthcare services for conflict-affected populations in Jarablus district in Aleppo governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will address the health  concerns of the conflict-affected population in 2 districts include 55 communities. of Jarablus district, Aleppo governorate, northern Syria. It plans to address the urgent and basic primary health care  needs of the most vulnerable groups and reduce preventable mortality and morbidity of the target catchment population  over the next 12 months.

The project focuses on establishing, equipping and running 2 primary health care unit based on Essential Primary Health Care Package of Services ( EPHC) standers ( PHC level 2)  in Jarablus district for  IDPs and host communities by the health services and outreach services.

Two PHCs unit will provide services inJarablus and Al Gandurah sub-district for an estimated catchment population of 79.500 IDPs and host community. The 2 PHC units will provide the basic general consultation, reproductive, and pediatric health care services and continue to be part of the functional referral system to PHC Comprehensive Centre or secondary level health care. It will also continue providing public health awareness for preventive measures through outreach, health education and disease and nutrition screenings by community health care workers.

The clinical staff will include two general practitioners, 5 community health workers, 2 nurses, one midwife, one pharmacist in each PHC which is match with EPHC standers for the HR.
Basic equipment, consumables, diagnostic kits and medication will be available according to the standard list. Sampling sets and surveillance kits for Type A diseases, various media and RDTs will be available in the PHC Units as the staff will be responsible for the sample referrals to the surveillance laboratories and reporting on the priorities diseases under the early warning system. 
IDA will implement its HIMS system in the 2 PHCs and  for data collection and reporting, patient records will be kept by the medical team and reporting done.

The 2 PHCs unit will be located in allocated building in easily accessible areas. The authorization had taken from the local council in Jarablus to use these building as PHCs. 

Considering the accessibility, Within a continuous coordination and meetings with Turkish authorities and local authorities in Jarabulus, IDA had managed to secure an official access to Jarabulus through Karkamish gate with  for the commodities, materials and IDA&apos;s staff. through this accessibility, IDA is  capable to provided the necessary requirements to the activities in the region and facilitate the entrance the supply chain for the medical support in Jarabulus.
The other contingency option, IDA had the accessibility through Bab Al Salama gate where we have an alternative channel to support the activities in Jarabulus through A&apos;zaz district, but still, this alternative option will be used in the case of Karkamish gate have any issues in terms of security or safety of the supplies as well the staff.

The target area consider a stable area far away 45 km of A&apos;zaz city with free access road between the two districts, The risks of working in a war zone to provide life-saving measures is partly mitigated by IDA&#xB4;s local and intimate knowledge of the context and locality, strong field presence and related network of interlocutors, as well as the relatively high acceptance of IDA&#x2019;s humanitarian mandate among some stakeholders to the conflict in the target area. 
To address the currently volatile conflict situation of the target area,Contingency plans have been discussed and include predominantly the emergency evacuation of staff and equipment and shifting the 2 PHCs services to where the community moves, using public buildings where available to set up new PHC centers. Each center will be supplied with 1-month medicine stock able to cover the essential needs of services in case of inaccessibility to centers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-07">23156.98</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-07">257814.32</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="6305235125">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-19">668.75</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-3869">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-07">280971.3</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302287273">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-14">168582.78</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302970651">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-27">112388.52</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
