<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-16/3559/SA 2016/E/NGO/2750</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance TeachingLearning Capacities in Conflict-affected Communities of Aleppo and Idlib Governorates</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COSV is operating in the Syrian crisis since 2013 and the ongoing intervention is aimed at contributing to a peaceful transition in Syria through the strengthening of young local civil society actors. The strategy draws on COSV extensive experience in collaborating with local grassroots organizations in Syria before the crisis (2006). In 2015 COSV implemented the project &#x201C;Supporting the psychosocial well-being of Syrian Teachers and Students to cope with armed conflict&#x201D; funded by the HPF of the UNOCHA. The intervention aimed at supporting Syrian teachers through a training on life-saving skills and psycho-social support, recreational activities for children in both locations, and the rehabilitation of 10 schools, 7 in Aleppo city and 3 Al-Atareb. Additionally COSV is implementing the Food for Work project &#x201C;Support to food security in Idleb and North-Aleppo Governatorates&#x201D; for  the educational staff of the above-mentioned schools in the Aleppo Governorate, and additional schools in Saraqab (2), and Ariha (11) in Idlib Governorate funded by the Italian Cooperation for Developmet. The current proposal comes from the outcomes of the previously and ongoing actions and from the needs assessment carried out in March 2016 by COSV&apos;s network in 47 schools - in Aleppo (7), Atareb (3), Ariha (13), Saraqab (9), Maraat Al Nouman (15). The proposed project is built on the positive experience of the work COSV has been doing with its partners &#x2013;Kirmalek, Life Maker Team, So we Love the Life, Dot-Shabab, Sadad&#x2013; since 2014, not only throughout the implementation of the above-mentioned projects, but also throughout the two phases of the EU-DEVCO funded action on supporting Syrian civil society, where COSV has assisted the set-up of 21 youth-led groups forming a network of approx. 400 activists all over Syria. The successful outcomes of the previous action led COSV to scale up some activities in order to provide functional, protective and safe learning spaces for these crisis-affected schools and strengthen the coping capacity of teachers and students experiencing a prolonged conflict situation. The purpose is to mainstream psychosocial support and lifesaving skills into the schools and to enhance the capacity of the staff to render their classes more participatory through effective teaching and learning in emergency context (teachers&apos;, students, and recreational kits will be distributed in each of the targeted school). COSV&#x2019;s groups will continue engaging the children and parents in the recreational activities roll out in the schools. The proposal will also focus on schools&#x2019; building rehabilitation in Ariha, Saraqab, Maraat al Nouman to ensure a safe and adequate learning space for the children - re-establishing proper and separated sanitation facilities for girls and boys, repairing schools building and classroom-. Taking into account the protection needs of children, this intervention is required in order to tackle in a holistic manner their wellbeing inside the learning spaces. The (re)construction of the schools will directly engage the communities and, possibly, even the parents of the students, like in the previously-implemented action. The community-based approach is expected to increase the interest of the parents and relatives around the schools&#x2019; activities and the importance to maintain and preserve the education, in time of conflict. Consequently a series of thematic group discussions led by more experienced and trained teachers will be organized in the schools to engage mothers in the educational development of their children and also to boost discussions around the importance of the right to education. The awareness raising components will be completed by having COSV groups engaging teachers, parents and students over discussions on the right to education and on children&#x2019;s rights, where they will produce short-media content mainstreamed through the social media and through other COSV&#x2019;s channels such as http:/goodmorningsyria.org/home.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-01">436914.01</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-01">184611.56</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-2750">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-01">621525.57</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3301961572">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-13">372915.34</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Offset  SOM">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-19">248610.23</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
