<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-36050</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Siranjganj Power Company</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">-	Reducing Power Deficit: The project will help to address the chronic electricity shortages and to meet the growing demand for power in Bangladesh.  -	Low Tariff: The project is expected to contribute to reducing generation costs for the benefit of Bangladeshi consumers and users of power.  -	Private sector development: The project represents the first IPP project in Bangladesh by a foreign investors in several years, and is the first IPP in recent years to be financed on a limited recourse basis. The success of the project will demonstrate the sustainability of public and private sector partnerships in the power sector in Bangladesh to overseas power developers and operators, and help attract more capital flows into the country.  -	Employment generation: The Project is expected to generate employment opportunities (both direct and indirect) during construction and operational phases</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation (IFC) is considering up to US$ 110 million of debt financing for the construction of a  greenfield 414 MW (net capacity) dual-fuel (gas and high speed diesel,  HSD) combined cycle power plant to be located in Sirajganj, Bangladesh (the Project). The Project will be developed by a consortium of Sembcorp Utilities Pte. Ltd. (Sembcorp Utilities or Sponsor) and North West Power Generation Company Ltd. (NWPGCL) under a special purpose vehicle which will be established in Bangladesh for the sole purpose of developing and operating the Project (Project Company).   The 414MW power plant will include one Gas Turbine (GT) unit; one set of heat recovery steam generator; one steam turbine generating unit with associated auxiliary equipment; fuel gas transportation, compression and conditioning system; HSD system; cooling water system; and water treatment facility.  A 230 kV substation connects the complex to the national transmission system and the 30 East-West gas pipeline crossing the Jamuna Bridge is located 1.6 km away from the site. .   Construction is targeted to start in the second quarter of 2016 and be completed in approximately 27 months, with combined cycle commercial operations targeted to commence by August 2018. A consortium of EPC contractors will be appointed to undertake the engineering, procurement and construction activities of the project.   The Operation and Maintenance of the project will be undertaken by the Project Company with the support of a long term service agreement for the GT with the manufacturer.   The Sirajganj site was developed as a major power generation complex in the north-west region of Bangladesh; NWPGCL is already operating a 225MW plant within the same complex and will shortly commence construction of another project there in early 2016. The Project will thus be the third power project to be located within the Sirajganj complex.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SEMBCORP UTILITIES PTE LTD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-36050" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contact Person: Nazmul Ahsan Company Name: Sembcorp North-West Power Company Ltd Address: House No: 1, Road no: 9C, Nikunja-1, Airport Road, Dhaka-1229, Bangladesh Email:  mailto:nazmul.ahsan@sembcorp.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The full text of the ESIA report and the ESRS is available in hard copy at the company office located in Dhaka per the address mentioned below documents are also available locally at the following addresses:  Address:  Office of the Deputy Commissioner, Sirajganj, Bangladesh Contact Person: Protap Chandra Biswas, Additional Deputy Commissioner (Revenue)</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="BD-Bangladesh">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project is located in Soydabad, near the town of Sirajganj in the Rajshahi Division. The site is accessible by road and is located approximately 135 kilometres north-west of Dhaka on the banks of the Jamuna river.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>24.0000000000 90.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="5622" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">V-CA - Integrated Utilities</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $126.20 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/36050">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/36050">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
