<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41AAA-00082711</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41AAA" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting the Afghanistan Nat</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Under the framework of this Project UNOPS has been requested by DGCS ( the Directorate General for Development Cooperation of the Italian Ministry of Foreign Affairs)to provide Technical Assistance services to the Ministry of Public Works (MPW) and the Ministry of Transport and Civil Aviation (MoTCA) with respect to on-going and new projects funded by the Government of Italy. The brief description and current status of these projects as well as the scope of required UNOPS services to support the projects&#x2019; implementation are outlined below:

REMABAR II PROJECT
DGCS is presently financing to MPW the rehabilitation of the road from Maidan Shar to Bamyan. Within this project UNOPS has been carrying out technical assistance, certification and audit services to the MPW, specifically to the Project Management Unit (PMU). Funds have been almost completely used during the five-year period of REMABAR I.
The second phase of the project, REMABAR II, from Onai Pass to Bamyan, started in 2010, with works actually commencing early in 2011. The project is scheduled to last another two years, plus an additional third year for the liability period and technical and financial closure. In order to continue and complete the REMABAR II project UNOPS shall provide the following services:
- Continue providing technical assistance to the PMU/MPW;
- Carry out certification of documents and reports prepared under the REMABAR project;
- Organize and support costs for audits of the project&#x2019;s document to be submitted to DGCS through special reports, for funding;
- Organize community projects and / or food distributions along the road, as already done for REMABAR I and the Musahi Valley Road, to improve relations with local villagers;
- Define an appropriate road maintenance strategy to be used for Italian funded roads, based on local Department of Public
Works (DPW) and including routine, preventive and corrective interventions;
- Carry out a survey of the area between Maidan Shar and Onai Pass, in order to assess social and economic changes related tothe completion of the road and its use by local villagers.

HERAT TO CHISHTI SHARIF ROAD PROJECT

This is a new project aimed at rehabilitation of the road from Herat to Chishti Sharif, up to the location of the Salma Dam, estimated to be approximately 155km. The road is the first part of the east-west corridor, connecting Herat with Kabul. The corridor is an important part of the national plan and its rehabilitation will open up the central area of Afghanistan to social and economic development. It is associated with the Herat economic resource corridor, including &#x2013; along the Harirud River and to the Salma Dam - the development of agricultural land and products for the local, national and international market. The road also opens possibilities in the mining sector, such as the marble quarries in Chisht and other resources on the eastern side of the corridor. DGCS is currently discussing with the Afghan MoF the provision of funds as a soft loan towards the rehabilitation of the 155km road from Herat to Chishti Sharif. The road has already been the subject of two different studies: a feasibility study carried out by SIDA in 2005, and an Economic Resource Corridor Survey carried out by USAID in 2011. In addition, MPW has already contracted out the design of the road to a Turkish company. The design is supposed to be completed in June 2012.

In order to initiate the project, UNOPS shall carry out the following services:
a) Revise the two studies in order to confirm or rearrange dates for producing a credible and dependable reference framework for the social and economic assessment of this road project;
b) Revise designs and estimated quantities produced under the SIDA study, in order to come up with a credible figure for
construction costs, together with standard designs and estimated quantities by major bills;
c) Prepare a project document to be submitted to DGCS for funding, including both social and economic data and technical
specifications, quantities and related estimated costs for both a consultant for supervisory services and a contractor for construction works;
d) Support MPW in organizing a Project Implementation Unit (PIU) for the corridor project, defining the required personnel and
related terms of reference and costs;
e) Support MPW in preparing and publishing the tender dossier for the selection of the Consultant for Supervisory services.

HERAT AIRPORT PROJECT
This is also a new project aimed at upgrading Herat airport in order to bring it up to international, though basic, levels according to ICAO standards. The airport will be the referral point for national airports in Qala-e Now, Chaghcharan and Farah, becoming a civil aviation hub for the western area of Afghanistan, with flights connecting to countries in the region, such as the United Arab Emirates and Saudi Arabia, and facilities for air transport.

DGCS is discussing with MoF a second soft loan in order to carry out construction works, equipment procurement and staff training for the upgrading of the Herat airport up to the standards set by ICAO for international airports. The Italian Ministry of Economic Development has provided a master-plan which could be considered a long-term guideline for development and thus is neither a feasibility study, nor contains sufficient elements to start design and technical definition of activities.

In order to initiate the project UNOPS shall provide the following services:

a) Revise the master plan together with MoTCA and possibly with ADB airport PIU, in order to confirm, modify and finalize the project according to needs and to meet the ICAO standards to classify Herat airport as an international facility, bearing in mind available funds from the Italian soft loan;
b) According to results of the previous step, break down the master-plan into phases for construction, procurement, institutional
changes and staff training;
c) Contact and assess the development projects for Kabul International and Mazar-e Sharif international airports with regard to their institutional set-up, internal organization &amp; management and technical specifications;
d) Contract an engineering firm in order to carry out a social and economic feasibility study dealing with:
- Defining the institutional framework for the airport, its property, and management;
- Assessing existing Afghan legislation on civil aviation related issues, including airports management, customs rules and regulations, other legal requirements (standards, etc.);
- Assessing the effects on the project and on the establishment of the &#x201C;Herat International&#x201D; of the future set-up of a civil aviation authority;
- Surveying market opportunities for passengers and freight to and from Herat, national and international;
- Assessing financial and institutional options for future economic sustainability of the airport;
- Defining costs of the airport upgrading according to different development options and bearing in mind available Italian funds;
e) Prepare a project document to be submitted to DGCS for funding, including both social and economic data and technical
specifications, quantities and related estimated costs for both a consultant for supervisory services and a contractor for construction works;
f) Support MoTCA in organizing a PIU for the airport project, defining the required personnel and related terms of reference and costs;
g) Support MoTCA in preparing and publishing the tender dossier for the selection of the consultant for supervisory services.

PROJECT OBJECTIVE:
To contribute to the efforts of the Government of the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan in achieving a safe, integrated transportation network that ensures connectivity, and that enables low-cost and reliable movement of people and licit goods. To achieve this objective, this project focuses on the UNOPS&#x2019; Technical Assistance services towards the construction of 237km of asphalt paved roads in the western and central parts of Afghanistan and the upgrading of Herat Airport to ICAO standards.

DESIRED OUTCOMES:
-The project for improvement of 155km road from Herat to Chishti Sharif Road in the western part of east-west corridor is initiated;
-The project for improvement of 82km road from Onai Pass to Bamyan City in the central corridor is completed;
-Increased market access and opportunities for rural households are created, thereby contributing to the reduction of poverty and vulnerability of the population living in the project focus areas;
-Capacity development of local government and institutions and contractors is mainstreamed through provision of targeted technical assistance, quality oversight and on-the-job training;
-An appropriate road maintenance strategy is developed for the roads built under Italian funded projects;
-The project to upgrade Herat Airport to international facility standards is initiated;
-Employment opportunities
UNOPS is providing a variety of project management, procurement, infrastructure and human resources services to this bundle of projects to support the development of Afghanistan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Italy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41AAA" role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41AAA" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cillian Domhnall OCATHAIL</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>4535467600</telephone>
   <email>info@unops.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNOPS HQ, PO Box 2695, 2100 Copenhagen, Denmark</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="679" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Asia, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
   </description>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.939110 67.709953</pos>
   </point>
   <location-class code="4"></location-class>
  </location>
  <sector code="21020" percentage="100" vocabulary="DAC">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Road transport</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-31">4462106</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="00082711_201212">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-01">135753</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2012</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="00082711_201312">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-01">846735</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2013</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="00082711_201412">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-01">893585</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2014</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="00082711_201512">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-01">408415</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2015</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="00082711_201612">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-01">355397</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="00082711_201712">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-01">1083322</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2017</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="00082711_201812">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-01">336615</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="00082711_201912">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-01">1686</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="00082711_202012">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-01">242891</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2020</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="00082711_202102">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-01">25493</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2021-February</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="00082711_202101">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">5474</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2021-January</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="00082711_202103">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-01">45556</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2021-March</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="00082711_2013_2023">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">4462106</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total partner commitment</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="41AAA">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://data.unops.org/index.htm#SegmentCode=ORG&amp;FocusCode=DATA_PROJECTS&amp;EntityCode=PROJECT_ID&amp;EntityValue=00082711">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
