<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-56083459-wpp29141</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-56083459" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Peacemakers Program</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Powerful agents of change: supporting women&apos;s resilience for prevention and community security</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The program strengthens community security and prevention in the MENA region by supporting women&apos;s civil society capacity and space. The program contributes to: - Increased awareness on the importance of maintaining an enabling space for women&apos;s civil society in the MENA region. - Increased engagement of women peacemakers in prevention and community security in the MENA region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29141" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Peacemakers Program</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Peacemakers Program</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>merle@womenpeacemakersprogram.org</email>
   <website>https://www.womenpeacemakersprogram.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laan van Meerdervoort 70, 2517 AN Den Haag</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-09-01">110910</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="complete funding commitment">
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-09-01">310070</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29141" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="Women Peacemakers Program" type="21"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="First instalment">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-09-27">137802</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29141" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="Women Peacemakers Program" type="21"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="Travel Cost Partner Delegation">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-01">1193</value>
   <provider-org ref="Women Peacemakers Program" type="21"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Accommodation Cost Partner Delegation">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-01">1507</value>
   <provider-org ref="Women Peacemakers Program" type="21"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="Travel Costs MENA Consultation">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-01">4967</value>
   <provider-org ref="Women Peacemakers Program" type="21"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="Venue/Housing/Food costs MENA Consultation">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-01">5597</value>
   <provider-org ref="Women Peacemakers Program" type="21"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased policy awareness on the importance of maintaining an enabling space for women&apos;s civil society in the MENA region.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of international policy documents addressing the importance of maintaining an enabling space for women&#x2019;s civil society.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the project period, WPP is contributing to a research publication, providing data on how women&#x2019;s organizing is affected by shrinking civil society space, including in the MENA region. The research provides recommendations to address this, including at policy level.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the end of 2017 (end of project), at least 4 international policy documents demonstrate increased policy awareness, by addressing the issue of the importance of maintaining an enabling space for women&#x2019;s civil society.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The research recommendations have been integrated into 7 international (UN) policy bodies around Women, Peace and Security.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of international policy events addressing the importance of maintaining an enabling space for women&#x2019;s civil society.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the project period, WPP is contributing to increased awareness on the importance of maintaining an enabling space for women&#x2019;s civil society.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the end of 2017 (end of project), at least 6 policy events have contributed to increased policy awareness at the international level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The issue of enabling space for women&#x2019;s civil society has been integrated in 10 high-level (UN) events around WPS.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of civil society organizations indicate increased policy awareness at national level, due to their involvement in advocacy around the importance of safeguarding an enabling space for women&apos;s civil society in the MENA region.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="14">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the end of 2017, at least 14 civil society organizations from the MENA region have engaged in national advocacy to support awareness raising about the importance of maintaining an enabling space for women&#x2019;s civil society.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">8 civil society partners from the MENA region have been actively engaging in (inter)national awareness raising and advocacy efforts around the importance of safeguarding an enabling space for women&apos;s civil society in the MENA region.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity building on inclusive prevention and community security for civil society organizations in the MENA region.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of civil society organizations from the MENA region participating in a community of practice (CoP) for awareness raising and (inter)national advocacy.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="16 civil society organisations participate in the MENA Consultation and commit to continued advocacy engagement via the establishment of a CoP; CoP produces 4 advocacy strategies (1 international, 4 national)."></target>
     <actual value="13">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">13 organizations participated in the MENA Consultation and commited to continued engagement to the CoP. During the consultation all of the participants, representing four countries developed country strategies (advocacy) as well as one international advocacy strategy.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of civil society organizations from the MENA region participating in a Training of Trainers on inclusive prevention and community security.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the end of 2017, 20 civil society organizations from the MENA region participated in a Training of Trainers on inclusive prevention and community security.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Due to receiving fewer applications than expected the final number of selected trainees added up to 13 representing 11 organizations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of civil society organizations implementing local initiatives for inclusive prevention and community security in the MENA region.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="16">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">16 Civil society organizations are implementing local initiatives for inclusive prevention and community security, reaching approximately 3,000 beneficiaries by end of 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Measured by December 1, four months after the implementation of the training. More initiatives will be rolled out in the upcoming months. 7 out of 11 have already reached out to several hundreds of beneficiaries.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advocacy efforts by civil society organizations from the MENA region in (inter)national policy arenas to address the importance of maintaining an enabling space for women civil society organizations.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of civil society representatives from the MENA region participating in international policy events to increase policy awareness on the importance of maintaining an enabling space for women civil society organizations.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the end of 2017, 9 civil society representatives from the MENA region have participated in international policy events to increase policy awareness on the importance of maintaining an enabling space for women civil society organizations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">: 9 representatives of 7 civil society partner organizations from the MENA region have participated in international awareness raising and advocacy strategies around enabling space for women civil society organizations, and have been providing policy recommendations during high-level international (side) events and policy briefings with (UN) policy bodies related to enabling space for women civil society organizations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of national advocacy efforts to increase policy awareness on the importance of maintaining an enabling space for women civil society organizations in the MENA region.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="14">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the end of 2017, 14 organisations will have engaged in national advocacy efforts to increase awareness on the importance of maintaining an enabling space for women civil society organizations in the MENA region.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="not clear">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the MENA consultation 4 national strategies were produced. Although 8 partner organizations have actively participated in international advocacy efforts, WPP has not been able to verify the implementation at national level yet.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased engagement of women peacemakers in prevention and community security in the MENA region.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of civil society organizations surveyed reporting their community initiatives are contributing to increased women&#x2019;s engagement for prevention and community security.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">WPP&#x2019;s capacity building programming (Training of Trainers) includes the trainees organizing local initiatives upon return to contribute to inclusive prevention and community security.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the end of 2017, at least 80% of civil society organizations report that their community-based projects for peace and community security support increased women&#x2019;s engagement.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="65%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Measured per December 1, 65% of the MENA partner organizations are actively mobilizing local civil society and community representatives for inclusive prevention and nonviolent conflict resolution, indicating these contribute to increasing women&#x2019;s participation in community-based prevention and nonviolent conflict resolution efforts. This was measured 4 months after implementation of the training. It is expected that more initiatives will be implemented the upcoming months.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of women&#x2019;s civil society organizations surveyed reporting increased capacity to engage in inclusive prevention &amp; community security in the MENA region.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the end of 2017, at least 80 % of the civil society organizations trained have reported a significant increase in capacity (knowledge and skills) to engage in inclusive prevention and community security efforts in the MENA region.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">All of the trainees indicated the training had contributed to their knowledge on inclusive conflict prevention and community security efforts (60 % indictated &#x201C;a lot&#x201D;; 40 % indicated &#x201C;some&#x201D;).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outreach produced to raise awareness on the importance of maintaining an enabling space for women&#x2019;s civil society in the MENA region.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of policy-making bodies and civil society organizations receiving outreach materials on the importance of maintaining an enabling space for women&#x2019;s civil society in the MENA region.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50 international organizations receive the research publication; 3000 representatives from policy-making bodies, civil society representatives, general public receive the research publication."></target>
     <actual value="More than 250 international organizations, ten thousands of representatives from policy-making bodies, civil society representatives, general public.">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct outreach includes media, international policy making bodies, CSO&#x2019;s, donors, financial institutions, research institutions. Indirect outreach was achieved by WPP&#x2019;s and Duke IHRC&#x2019;s partners mentioning and circulating the research in their newsletters, social media and blog posts, website and platform updates (does not include social media, for example over 100.000 twitter impressions achieved).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of outreach products addressing the importance of maintaining an enabling space for women&#x2019;s civil society in the MENA region.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2 (research) publications; 16 blog articles; 4 policy briefs, 1 video; weekly social media outreach."></target>
     <actual value="1 research publication;16 blog articles; 4 policy briefs; 1 video; weekly social media outreach">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final lessons learnt publication not achieved, due to WPP closing.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
