<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-22999</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Algerian Cement Corporation 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Algerian Cement Company (ACC, or the company) is Algerias first and only private cement plant, and is an existing IFC client company. The project consists of increasing ACCs capacity from 2.0 million tons per year (tpy) to 4.0 million tpy, at an estimated cost of $187 million (named Line II).  The project represents the second phase of the original ACC project (Line I), which was completed in February 2004 within budget and in a record time of 22 months.  The project will be a replicate of the original 2.0 million tpy production line which was supplied by F.L. Smidth (FLS), Denmark.  It will be adjacent to Line I at ACCs production site in Msila, central Algeria, 240 km southeast of Algiers, and will share site infrastructure and utilities already developed for Line I. Construction for Line II started in January 2004 and is expected to be completed in 20 months.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Algerian Cement Company</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-22999" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2004-06-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2004-08-26" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Algerian Cement Company (ACC), 
3 Bis rue Raoul Payen, 
Hydra, Alger.</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="DZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Algeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="DZ-Algeria">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The plant site is located near route CW25 (Bourdj Bourerdj  M&apos;sila) about 25 kilometers north of M&apos;sila, 7 kilometers south east of Hamman Dalaa.  Wilaya of M&apos;sila is in central Algeria some 240 kilometers from Algiers. The site is located on arid (rock dominated) land and the surrounding land is extremely marginal and is not used for agriculture or cultivation.  The location was originally chosen based on technical evaluations and the result of a public consultation, including a focus on avoiding sensitive habitats and avoiding land otherwise used by the local population (hereby avoiding any resettlement), while being as near as possible to high quality raw materials.The sponsor has built a new site access road from the CW25 main road to avoid heavy traffic in the nearby settlement (Debil). Private landowners provided right-of-way access for this purpose and were consulted and provided compensation based on a willing-buyer willing-seller basis. There has been no further physical resettlement or economic displacement caused by the initial project or its infrastructure connections and the expansion will be kept within the existing plant area.

The limestone quarry, which is in operation, is located adjacent to the plant, while the clay quarry is located 17 kilometers from the plant site. High quality gypsum is currently bought from domestic commodity suppliers (there are several supply options), but might later be supplied from deposit located 180 kilometers from the plant site.  The project includes progressive quarry reclamation plans for gradual implementation during the lifetime of the quarries. As an example the limestone quarry has till date had 3,000 m2 of overburden removed and stored for later application in connection with reclamation to create a landscape (profile) in harmony with the existing and surrounding landscape.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>28.0000000000 3.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Cement</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $20.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2004-06-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2004-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2004-06-25">20000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2004-06-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2004-06-25">20000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Algerian Cement Company</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/22999/algerian-cement-corporation-2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
