<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.plan-uk.org/iati" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-1364201-SDN100344</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-1364201" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated life saving education, GBV and Child protection for vulnerable flood  affected and refugee in El Salam, Kosti, Al Jabalain, AD Diwaim and Guli localities in  White Nile State(GBV 25%,CP 25%).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project targets prioritized localities Guli, Kosti, Ad Dweim, El Salam Al Rawat and El Jabalain- El Genaa camp 
with under-funded sectors CP, GBV and Education. This project targets 4947 individuals of which 1497 are 
refugees 90% of them children who require case management, CP referral and family placement for UASCs; 2527 
are children(1000 boys and 1527 girls) and 3450 other flood affected community members. It aims to support 
women, girls and boys so that they feel protected and safe and are willing to return to education. This will be 
achieved by increasing access to education facilities and improving child protection and GBV services to support 
children and survivors of GBV in four localities in White Nile, specifically, El Salam, Al Jabalain, Kosti, AD Diwaim 
and Guli. Plan International will rehabilitate 8 classrooms in the White Nile, provision of recreational and teacher 
kits, classroom furniture, and teachers&apos; and Parent Teacher Training (PTA)s training in Teacher in Crisis Context 
(TiCC). This will be done with the aim of increasing school enrolment. Gender sensitive latrines will also be 
rehabilitated ensuring the needs of children with disabilities are considered. The schools will also be safe spaces 
for children through adequate COVID-19 prevention measures as well as establishing Child Protection (CP) and 
GBV referral systems that link schools to community protection structures. Furthermore, Plan International will 
provide case management services for unaccompanied and separated children, other vulnerable groups such as 
child headed households, child and adolescent survivors of GBV, capacity building mentoring of frontline workers 
Community Based Organisations (CBO)s and Civil Society Organisations (CSO)s on CP minimum standards, 
caring for child survivors of GBV, psychosocial support services, mental health and life skills interventions for 
children and adolescents/ referral pathway for child protection will be updated in the two localities through service 
mapping. Plan will provide life-saving services to vulnerable women and girls including GBV survivors (referrals), by 
strengthening referral pathways in the two localities that lack such mechanisms. Frontline GBV service providers, 
social workers and CBO/CSO members will be trained on Prevention of Sexual Harassment Exploitation and Abuse 
(PSHEA), GBV, gender main-streaming, psycho-social support, and case management including clinical 
management of rape using case management and GBV minimum standards. Women will be supported to organize 
into groups creating safe spaces around community centres to actively work against GBV among their peers, 
demystify the social stigma of reporting such cases and empower them by establishing, linkages informal and 
formal system between women&#x2019;s groups, community based child protection networks (CBCPN)s, family and child 
protection units (FCPU), other relevant police departments, trauma centres, and clinics treating GBV survivors to 
ensure GBV survivors are referred to appropriate services in the targeted localities. The project will ensure 
accountability to affected populations through tailored CFRM mechanisms that are accessible to children, women, 
PSNs.
The project will target 4947 persons [1136 male, 1284 Women, 1000 boys and 1527 girls], 1497out of them are 
refugees, the project will provide life saving education, GBV and child protection for vulnerable flood affected and 
refugee in El Salam, Kosti, Al Jabalain, AD Diwaim and Guli localities in White Nile State</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OCHA Country Based Pooled Funds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Inc. (Sudan Country Office)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-1364201" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>iati@plan-uk.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-01">424999</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
