<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.plan-uk.org/iati" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-1364201-NPL100498</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-1364201" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anticipatory Action for Landslide Risk Management in Nepal</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Landslides are among the most prominent and recurring hazards in Nepal, often resulting in disasters. Most of the rain-induced landslides occur during the monsoon season (June-September) when Nepal receives 80% of its total annual rainfall. However, shift in rainfall patterns and increased intensity and frequency of heavy rains is contributing to landslide events beyond the Monsoon seasons. Additionally, heavy rains might reactivate earthquake-induced landslides.
At the moment, available precipitation forecast data include Nepal&#x2019;s Department of Hydrology and Meteorology (DHM) 3-day and 5-day lead time forecast, and RIMES forecast. The information is not disseminated to the Local Governments, communities and households. Additionally, no risk data are available at the local level.
The proposed system will help trickle down the precipitation forecast data, and ensure its contextualised and actionable to affected communities and households. Together with the precipitation forecasts, the tool will provide household (HH) level categorisation and early action planning to landslides risks based on HH vulnerability and capacity so that anticipatory actions will be targeted on the basis of actual and specific needs considering exposure, gender, age, caste, and other specific identities of the affected population rather than taking a blanket approach.
The tool will involve the development of a digital application for the optimal integration of gender sensitive digital Vulnerability Capacity Assessments (VCA) and gender sensitive Household Disaster Preparedness and Response Plans (HDPRP) with precipitation forecast information as the basis for the Community Based Landslide Early Warning System (CBLEWS). The CBLEWS will incorporate gender considerations &#x2013; e.g. setting threshold, triggers and messages will be informed by various groups to ensure warnings are received, understood and acted upon by all groups depending on the HDPRP &#x2013; and will trigger a warning when the threshold of rainfall increases to hazardous level in proposed landslide prone locations. Strong gender considerations will be integrated into the whole process, also including the VCA conducted, and customised HDPRP.
The project will be implemented in Kathmandu and Kalikot districts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-1364201" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>iati@plan-uk.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="41050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-03-01">35000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-03-16">31818.2</value>
   <provider-org ref="GB-COH-1364201">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="No Identifier">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Inc. (Nepal Country Office)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-02-21">-3181.8</value>
   <provider-org ref="No Identifier">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">START</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-1364201">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-02-21">-31818.2</value>
   <provider-org ref="No Identifier">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">START</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-1364201">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
