<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.plan-uk.org/iati" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-1364201-SDN100354</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-1364201" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of the lifesaving emergency Child Protection services to Ethiopian refugees and host community in Um-Rakuba, Tunaydbah and Babikri refugee Camps and Hamdayeet and Village 8 transit centres.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will provide life-saving assistance to newly arrived refugees in areas of child protection with focus on responding to children (boys and girls) including adolescent affected by psychological distress through establishment of two new Child Friendly Spaces (CFS), one in Tunaydba camp and one in Babikri camp as well as keeping operational and maintain the current five CFSs in Um-Rakuba and Tunaydbah camps, based on the CPMS and equip them with play/art, stationery, furniture and engage refugees to identify capacities in their communities to support the vulnerable children and those at risk and help on functionality of the space; Awareness rising activities, case management for 1000 (500 boys &amp;amp; 500 girls) child including Family Tracing and Reunification (FTR) and alternative care for the unaccompanied and separated children (UASC) and other children at risk, referrals will be provided to affected children in structural activities. Moreover, girls, women, men and boys will be reached through awareness raising on CP , Human Trafficking and GBV prevention including early reporting and referral to available services; the project will provide clear and accessible information on available complaint mechanisms to communities of concern; and. UASC will be supported through provision of Family Tracing and Reunification (FTR) services and alternative care and foster family support to UASCs; the support will focus on identification, registration, tracing and re-unification and part of case management to the individual cases identified in coordination with other stakeholders. Total of 30 volunteers, two volunteers per zone in each of the targeted locations, will support foster families on alternative arrangement, referral, and response to protection concerns. Nine Community-Based Child Protection Networks, three in Tunaydbah, two in Um-Rakuba, two in Hamdayeet, one in each of Village 8 and Babikri, will be maintained and established to monitor and risks associated to children within their communities in coordination other stakeholders.
Incentives will be provided and capacities of staff, partner, stakeholders, volunteers and CBCPN will be strengthened to ensure they are capable to undertake their roles and responsibilities, where 90 animators &amp;amp; volunteers (10 in each of the 8 CFSs in targeted camps in addition to 5 in each of Hamdayeet and Village 8 transit centres) will receive training/refresher training on CFS management, Psychological First Aid, PSS and FTR along with provision of monthly incentive to run PSS and mange UASC cases, two awareness sessions will be conducted on child rights and protection against violence facing children, for all concerned staff and partners personnel. The CBCPN will focus on upskilling youth male and female to play a strong role in child protection activities, providing case management services, identification of at-risk children, mentoring target children, providing documentation, referral and follow up activities as well as establishing child rights clubs in Tunaydbah, Um-Rakuba and Babikri camps. This is expected to engage young people in community activities as constructive partners and key driving in delivery protection services and to provide them with basic life skills and prevention of sexual exploitation and abuse awareness program. Visibility materials will be provided international days and events will be celebrated in coordination with other actors and government interlocutors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Inc. (Sudan Country Office)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-1364201" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNHCR</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>iati@plan-uk.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11120" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">424999</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
