<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.plan-uk.org/iati" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-1364201-SDN100359</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-1364201" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection Response for South Sudanese, Eritrean, and Ethiopian Refugees in Khartoum</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is designed around two outcomes - each representing CPiE responses and interventions which build on the  appropriate lifesaving services such as case management interventions to the most at risk girls and boys, including UASC, girls and boys living with disabilities, and out of school children by facilitating access and referral to services, family tracing and reunification, cash or in-kind assistance, and placement in alternative care as needed. This project will also include psychosocial support services (PSS) for individuals and group as part of the case management interventions. Under the second outcome, the project will strength community engagement and participation through establishment and strengthening the existing Community-based child Protection networks/committees  (CBCPNs) that will monitor and respond to individual cases of girls and boys affected by any type of abuse, exploitation or neglect. Referral systems will be improved as part of strengthening local protection systems in the urban areas. The project will also train relevant staff members and stakeholders. 

This project will also provide full and non-discriminatory essential protection services for Persons with specific needs (PSN), including persons with disability, through proper identification assessment, facilitating access and referral to services. Further, it will support the most at risk and marginalised refugee, asylum seekers, and host community members with multi-purpose cash based on established vulnerability criteria based on UNHCR CBI strategy and SoPs. All these interventions will be based on the Child Protection Minimum Standard (CPMS), Plan International guidelines on Gender and Inclusion as well as the IASC Gender and Age Markers and Sudan SoPs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Inc. (Sudan Country Office)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-1364201" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNHCR</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>iati@plan-uk.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-15">30888</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="SDG" value-date="2022-03-15">35442682</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
