<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.plan-uk.org/iati" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-1364201-SLE0088</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-1364201" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hygiene  Sanitation and Water Supply in Port Loko and Moyamba</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan Sierra Leone and its local partners are implementing a five year hygieneand sanitation and water supply project to cover Koya and TMS chiefdoms of Port Loko district and Kowa and Fakunya chiefdoms of Moyamba district. The project supports the Community Led Total Sanitation  CLTS_ methodologyand a participatory approach whereby community members analyse their own sanitation status and change their collective behaviour to bring about safe
sanitation. Whilst supporting communities to become Open Defecation Freeand the project aims to increase access to waterand increase adoption of key hygiene practices and strengthen the District Health Management Teams and District Councils to deliver their water and sanitation responsibilities.

The project employs participatory methodologies that promote inclusionand community decision making and local ownershipand and is building the capacity of community based organisations including Community Health Clubs and Water Committees. Water supply components are being implemented using the Community Management Approachand whereby communities select and manage appropriate water supply systems for their communities. Plan and its local partners are building dialogue between communities and local government in order to increase government support for and investment in hygiene and sanitation and water supply interventions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DFID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PLAN International UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Inc. (Sierra Leone Country Office)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
