<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="0" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.plan-uk.org/iati" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-1364201-UKR0015</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-1364201" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increasing the resilience of Syrian refugees in the Bekaa through integrated protection programming</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The action contributes to the provision of protection to the most vulnerable Syrian refugees in the Bekaa Region through an integrated protection approach
as per 2017 DG ECHO HIP strategy and ECHO Protection Strategy. This encloses&amp;#58;
Result 1&amp;#58; Enhanced community resilience through strengthening of community based protection mechanisms, improving capacity on WASH, Protection and provision of life-saving information
Result 2&amp;#58; Vulnerable households and individuals have access to life-saving and basic essential PROTECTION and WASH services
Result 3&amp;#58; Enhanced protective environment for all persons affected by the Syrian crisis through social stability measures and evidence-based advocacy actions
A total of 12.000 beneficiaries will be direct beneficiary of the action
through multiple activities, those are in North Bekaa and in Central Bekaa
where life-saving measures have been assessed as essentials; 95 ITSS will benefit from Community-based protection interventions which direct beneficiaries are 7944. The communities have been targeted taking into consideration
socio-economic vulnerability criteria, WASH vulnerability criteria and number of households.   
The action will also consider as indirect target 300 ITSs in the area of Central Bekaa as beneficiaries of identification and referral mechanisms,
Protection Mobile Unit interventions and emergency response measures such as WASH, SHELTER and ad-hoc Protection Cash Assistance; 640 adolescents are specifically targeted by this action through learning and life-skills activities. The action contributes to promote coordination with national and
international actors as well as strategic national stakeholders to enhance the response and advocacy actions within Lebanon.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-EC_ECHO" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ECHO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GVC (Gruppo Volontariato Civile)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-1364201" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>iati@plan-uk.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-01">15471</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-01">4776</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
