<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="0" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.plan-uk.org/iati" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-1364201-SSD100129</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-1364201" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DEC East Africa Appeal Phase 1 (South Sudan)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will be implemented by Plan International in Lakes State (Rumbek East and Rumbek Centre and Wulu Counties) and aims to provide immediate emergency
livelihood support to the most vulnerable households to increase their food security and reduce the risk of further humanitarian crisis. Vulnerable targeted households will receive crops, seeds and tools for the next planting season expected in May/June 2017. The 3,800 HHs will be trained during the  distribution phase of the supplies on good agricultural and farming practices with a specific emphasis on the optimal use of inputs, grain storage and improving market access as well as practical nutrition education for all members of the household, including food preparation to enhance the consumption of the food.    
The targeted vulnerable HHs with under five children will be sensitized on nutrition, IYCF (Infant and Young Children Feeding), malnutrition and hygiene to increase community awareness on nutrition knowledge, attitude and practices in order to enhance malnutrition prevention and nutritional behaviour and to
strengthen their abilities to take care of their young children and share nutritional good practices.
   
 5,000 parents/caregivers (both male and female) will be also sensitized on child protection mechanisms and (S)GBV related practices (early marriage,
early pregnancy, traditional harmful practices, child labour, etc.) and child rights. They will also participate into parenting education sessions to increase their knowledge to provide the necessary care and differentiated protection to girls and boys and young people. In addition the most vulnerable adolescent girls (500) will be receiving dignity kits (soap,
t-shirt, pair of slippers, underwear, reusable sanitary pads, multi-purpose agreement and solar flashlight). A referral system of child protection cases will be put in place.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-CHC-1062638-EACA-2017" ref="GB-CHC-1062638" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DEC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Inc. (South Sudan Country Office)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-1364201" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International UK</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>iati@plan-uk.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-15">727339</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
