<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-25136</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IPI Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will supply various grades of jumbo rolls to Middle East, Europe and African markets for the conversion into tissue paper products, which will further promote Egyptian exports.  Its exports to Europe will benefit from low backhaul rates.  The project is also expected to use world class production technology to process domestic recycled waste paper and imported virgin pulp.  This will increase incentives of its suppliers to collect and recycle more waste paper.  The benefits of recycling include reduction of pollution, salvage forest trees, energy and water savings.  The project is expected to create 170 direct jobs at the mill and an additional 1,000 jobs indirectly in local wastepaper collection in Egypt, where the unemployment rate is approximately 10% in 2005.    The sponsors of the project have been active in the communities in which they operate and IPI will adopt a similar approach.  The bulk of INDEVCO Groups community engagement is handled by the INDEVCO Foundation (recently renamed the Georges N. Frem Foundation after the recently deceased founder of INDEVCO Group).  The Georges N. Frem Foundation is active in the education, civil society, social welfare, community and economic development areas.  Furthermore, the INDEVCO Group has a strong record in Egypt in Unipak Nile, with a focus on quality control, ISO and other certifications which have a continuing positive demonstration effect in raising the quality of local manufacturing companies.  The project will reinforce this effort and provide an ongoing model for business success.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project involves the construction of a greenfield tissue mill in Egypt by a newly formed company, Interstate Paper Industries SAE (IPI or the company).  IPI will be 99% owned by the Frem Industrial Group SAL (Holding) (FIG or the sponsor), 0.5% by INDEVCO SAL, and 0.5% by Unipak Nile Ltd., which are part of the INDEVCO Group of Lebanon (the Group).    The group owns and operates a profitable 30,000 tons per annum (tpa) tissue mill in Lebanon, selling to clients in the Middle East and the UK.  This tissue mill, despite a recent increase in capacity from 18,000 tpa to 30,000 tpa, is finding it difficult to keep up with demand, hence the Groups decision to construct another tissue mill in Egypt, where electricity, energy and labor costs are lower.  The project will be manufacturing jumbo tissue rolls and mainly exporting to converters outside Egypt.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSTATE PAPER INDUSTRIES SAE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-25136" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-03-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-06-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Fadi Freiha, Corporate Financial Manager Tellet Al-Assafir,    P. O. Box 11-2354,  Indevco Building,    Ajaltoun, Lebanon  Telephone: +(961-9) 230-130 Fax: +(961-9) 235-646</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt, Arab Republic of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="EG-Egypt, Arab Republic of">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will be located in Sadat Industrial City under the regime of private free zone company, mid-way on the desert road between Cairo and Alexandria.  The Government of Egypt sponsored three industrial cities (6th of October, 10th of Ramadan, and Sadat City), to attract the population away from Cairo in order to alleviate the citys congestion and pollution.  Basic infrastructure (roads, electricity, water, sewer collection and treatment, phones etc.) and services (residential housing, schools, commercial centers etc.) are provided by the developers.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>27.0000000000 30.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AD - Paper Tissue</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $26.40 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2007-03-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2007-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-03-26">26400000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2007-03-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-03-26">26400000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSTATE PAPER INDUSTRIES SAE</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/25136/ipi-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
