<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014140517</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Promote the Citizen Rights of Transgender  (Hijra) Community</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Raising awareness, information, education and advocacy for Hijras? rights. Hijras are a group of transsexuals, who feel that they represent the third sex. Hijras are usually abandoned by their own families and communities. Bangladeshi Hijras live in their 
own communities in almost complete isolation from the rest of society. Hijras do not have access to education, health care, or to participate in cultural events. Hijras have traditionally been forced to earn their living by dancing and prostitution. In add
ition to the discrimination, Hijras suffer from direct sexual and other physical violence not only by the community, but also by the police. Acts of violence are almost always to be elucidated. There are an estimated 100 000 Hijras in Bangladesh. Sexuality
-related topics traditionally in Bangladeshi culture have not been subject to public debate, which is why the sexual and gender minority rights have been neglected in the country, including in the activities of the human rights organizations. The project g
oal is to promote the respect for human rights and the reduction of discrimination against transgender people by human rights education and training. The project specific objectives are the awareness raising about the Hijras? rights among human rights defe
nders and educators, as well as important reference groups,  to impact the surrounding community in such a way that it recognizes hijras human dignity, hijras empowerment of human rights through education and training so that they would advocate for their 
rights . The project legal focus is the promotion of the rights of gender minorities. The primary beneficiaries of the project are the Hijra community members and their leaders whose status and social participation is expected to improve . The indirect ben
eficiaries are the parents of transgender people who get more information about hijras. The project is expected to benefit the wider community leaders, legislators, NGOs, teachers and doctors by raising awareness of gender minorities and their rights. Loke
nattya O Unnayan Kendro Sangashkritik (LOSAUK) is a non-governmental organization founded in 1987 whose aim is the promotion of the situation and culture of indigenous people and other minorities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO Foundation for Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">4872</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
