<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014140509</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Promoting the implementation of the constitution</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The evaluation of legislation of ESC rights, Public interest litigation, advocacy , the organization&apos;s support . Hakijamii, in its project, focuses on the right to health, water and sanitation, and implementations of these rights. The Constitution defines 
the part of health care as a fundamental right for all citizens, but especially among the poor the unavailability of services is a major problem. The development process of the nationwide network of water distribution network, in turn, has suffered from in
efficiency, corruption and mismanagement. One of the downturn was, when  along with the Water Act in the 2002, the water privatizations occurred. From the lack of clean water and sanitation suffer both rural and urban slums, and in particular the marginali
zed groups. Kenya&apos;s estimated population of 42 million, about 30% now live in cities, and the urbanization is rapid. Slums have been incorporated into urban planning and budgeting, and residents have very little chance of the health, education and other ba
sic services. It is estimated that only 20 per cent of slum residents have the opportunity to have permanently clean water and slum residents also pay out of the water several times more compared to other residents. The project aims to promote economic and
 social rights implementation. The aim is both to improve the State&apos;s procedures for new policies and legislation, as well as through the adoption of improving the economic and social rights, the implementation of fundamental rights through the bringing of
 the action. The project beneficiaries are the most vulnerable groups whose needs are taken into account in the content promoted laws, women, the elderly, the disabled, children, young people and minorities, and other vulnerable groups. Hakijamii was found
ed in 2004 to fill the gap in Kenya to deal between the organizations, which focuses on the human rights field, and on the other hand the organizations that handle the economic and social problems in a non-legal perspective.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO Foundation for Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">6422</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
