<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2013130535</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: IndustriALL Union Building through HIV/AIDS Workplace Action, evaluation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project reduces effects of HIV/AIDS among industry workers, mainly in the mining sector. In the project training will be continued for HIV/AIDS support persons who will after work as peer support group leaders. The project also implements information, 
counseling and testing campaigns at workplace level in cooperation with health care professionals and employers? representatives, covering also the communities around the workplaces. Union leaders and officials are trained about the contents of ILO?s recom
mendation no 200, on the basis of which unions develop their HIV/AIDS programs and policies.The role of the trade union movement in HIV/AIDS work is related on the awareness rising about prevention of infections and on ensuring equal treatment of HIV posit
ive people in working life and trade union activities. Unions are in many countries part of civil society HIV networks, but their special feature is the possibility to reach large groups of workers and their families and to get employers to participate in 
HIV work. Talking about sensitive issues is usually easier to start with the shop steward or other union friend. The cooperation of unions and health care professionals ensures competent support and assistance to those who need it. For the employer it is a
 positive asset to have reasonably healthy employees capable of working despite their infection, therefore more and more companies support the unions? counseling and testing campaigns. The companies also contribute to medical care expenses of their workers
 where the governments do not (yet) guarantee free medication for all citizens. For unions HIV/AIDS campaigns have in many cases been the gate of access to negotiation tables and on the other hand due to their visibility and concrete benefit significant at
tractions in organising workers to unions.Results of the project are better information, peer support, testing and counseling, dealing with discrimination cases becomes easier, HIV clauses such as health care services and anti-discrimination will be includ
ed in collective agreements, as well as wider visibility of unions will affect membership figures positively.Beneficiaries are industrial, especially mine, workers, other residents of mining communities, union members, activists, shop stewards and health a
nd safety representatives in Cote d?Ivoire, Ghana, Guinea and Zambia.The project is implemented by IndustriALL Global Union and its affiliates in the project countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, SASK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="12250" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">8500</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
