<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2013130025</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building the Western Saharan Civil Society of Tomorrow</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will continue the activities started in 2014 aimed at strengthening the Western Saharan civil society and processes of democratic and peaceful conflict resolution. The target group is Sahrawi youth that live dispersed in different areas: occupi
ed territories under Moroccan rule refugee camps in Algeria and diaspora mostly in Algeria and Europe. This dispersed group lacks the connections necessary to build a united civil society movement.The first objective of the project is to increase the youth
 participants? knowledge about democracy and political participation and increase their capacity in advocacy and networking. The project also strengthens networks between the Sahrawi youth and the youths? connections to civil society actors. The third obje
ctive is to increase partner&apos;s capacity to continue organising  the activities after the project. The last objective is to establish relationships of international solidarity and to support peer-to-peer-exchange between Sahrawi and Finnish youth. The activ
ities of the continuation project are divided into four main activity types. In the first activity type  facilitators? training for youth leading the workshops as well as training for the project partner in participatory methods will be carried out as a pa
rt of the capacity-building of the partner.  The second will comprise of the five workshops organised around the themes of democracy rule of law human rights and the building of civil society activities. The third will involve peer-to-peer models aimed at 
distributing the learned results and therefore broadening and deepening discussion on workshop themes. This part will also include monitoring of peer-to-peer activities through communications fora created by participants and Finnish project volunteers. Fin
ally the fourth activity type will involve the strengthening of networking within Western Saharan civil society by bringing together Sahrawi and external civil society and organisation actors present in the camps during a final seminar that will close each
 workshop.The training and workshop activities will take place at the refugee camps in Tindouf. Peer-to-peer distribution activities will happen in all different locations where the youth live and in addition between the Sahrawi youth and Finns.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Kansainvalinen Solidaarisuustyo ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-03" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="189" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location ref="Algeria,Morocco"></location>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">26630</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">26630</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
