<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2010100031</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community-based action against tobacco in Kyrgyzstan 2014-2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The current escalation in tobacco use and tobacco-related death and disease can only be reversed by comprehensive tobacco control policies. Like other low-income countries Kyrgyzstan is facing massive challenges in this respect. This project strives to com
bine a public health and health system?s approach in tobacco control by implementing intensified community-based actions in Issuk-Kul Naryn and Talas Oblasts in Kyrgyzstan during the years 2014-2016. The pilot phase of the project in Chui Oblast in 2011-20
13 has provided a model for successful intervention that WHO and Kyrgyz experts recommend to be expanded nationwide. Through activation and training of Village Health Committees (VHC) primary health care teachers and students in schools mass media as well 
as local authorities and politicians the project reach better understanding among adults and children of the health hazards of active and passive smoking increase the number of smokers who make a quit attempt as well as change social norms regarding tobacc
o use. The target group of this project is the whole population of the Kyrgyz Republic equally including both adult men and women as well as boys and girls in the school environment and families. All project material is prodcued both in Kyrgyz and Russian 
language. The Kyrgyz-Finnish project strives to improve the health of the Kyrgyz people by raising awareness on health hazards of tobacco and helping tobacco users to quit. Health is a fundamental human right. The project is environmentally sustainable. Wh
en tobacco use declines there are positive effects on the environment including less environmental burden caused by tobacco farming as well as less waste from used tobacco products in the environment.The project will be conducted under the local leadership
 of the National Centre for Health Promotion (NCHP) with input also from the Ministry of Health and the Ministry of Education assisted by the Centre for Continuous Medical Education (CCME) the Kyrgyz Association for Lung Health and the Association of Villa
ge Health Committees (VHC). The project will not create a new institution but will work through and strengthen the existing structures by integrating new methods via the VHC:s health care system schools mass media and local self-governments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-153" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish Lung Health Association (Filha ry)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="67302601" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-11-04" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12281" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">93865</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">80686</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">93865</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
