<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014140091</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Land and Livelihood Advocacy Development Project (LLAP)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia&#x2019;s 2001 Land Law attempted to limit encroachment into state land (technically about 80% of Cambodia&#x2019;s land area) while providing for legal expansion of smallholder agriculture through the distribution of up to five hectares of state land as &#x201C;
social land concessions&#x201D; which would be eligible for title after five years of continuous occupation and use. In 2003, Sub-Decree 19 on Social Land Concessions (SLCs) was enacted which provided for a locally initiated and managed process of planning and 
implementing SLCs. In late 2005, the State Land Management Sub-Decree provided the legal basis for district and provincial levels of Government to work with communes to identify and officially allocate state lands for SLCs.Land and Advocacy Development Pro
ject (LADP) has been prepared to provide capacity building on Alternative Dispute resolution (ADR) Land Rights and Land Registration, Advocacy, Women Rights, and relevant laws to ensure that the people are aware of ADR and the responsibilities of governmen
t and other duty-bearers to fulfill, to protect and respect communities&#x2019; rights. In addition, the capacity of the duty bearers will be strengthened to be able to fulfill their obligations to realise concerned communities&#x2019; rights. Objectives:&#x2022; To prom
ote democratic participation and human rights at the grassroots level by educating and supporting vulnerable groups, victims of land dispute and local government (Commune Councils) to become more effective at advocating their communities&#x2019; needs.&#x2022; To en
sure the most vulnerable groups are able to access to their agriculture land and control over productive resources and assets for enhancing their livelihood activities. Rights- holders /beneficiaries: Approximately 1 000 households located in 25 villages a
t selected LWD programme areas in Kampong Speu, Kampong Chhnang, Pursat, Battambang provinces will benefit from the project. The district Cadastral Commission, local authority and LWD staff will benefit from the project through capacity building on Alterna
tive Dispute Resolution. Implementing partner: Life with Dignity (LWD)LWD has been working together with FCA in partnership for over 20 years to improve the livelihoods of the poor and marginalised in rural Cambodia, engaging both rights-holders and duty-b
earers. Since 2011, the partners have been implementing a land rights awareness project in Kampong Chhnang and Kampong Speu provinces with the aim at increasing awareness on land rights and land registration of vulnerable households who have received land 
through Social Land Concessions. Land rights and land registration trainings were also provided to district authority representatives, Commune Councils, village leaders, Advocacy Group and implementing partner staff in collaboration with the Ministry of La
nd Management, Urban Planning and Construction (MLMUPC).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finn Church Aid</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kirkon Ulkomaanavun S&#xE4;&#xE4;ti&#xF6;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2014-2014140091" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Provinces of Kampong Speu, Kampong Chhnang, Pursat"></location>
  <sector code="43040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="243066" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">15000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2014-2014140091" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
