<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014140789</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promotion of education right of indigenous peoples in the Santiago del Estero Province and supporting sustainable development of communities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to strengthen and consolidate functions of an agroecology school in Quimili in the province of Santiago del Estero whose students come from Vilela Lule-Vilela Sanaviron and Guaycuru indigenouspeoples communities. The school is located in t
he grounds of the community Pueblo Vilela Pampa Pozo. It is maintained by these four indigenous peoples which also have established it for the purpose of giving integrated education for their young aged 16 to 25 to guarantee social and sustainable developm
ent of communities and enable conditions for the young to stay in the region through advantages obtained by agroecology that enables livelihood and sustainable growth.The school provides the technical knowledge needed for the position of assistant in agroe
gology. The local environment and its requirements are  considerated in the education as well as the traditions and values of indigenous peoples. The school was established to fulfill educational needs of indigenous peoples&apos; young and it is directed and de
veloped by the four indigenous peoples in coordination with its students.The provincial government has granted the school with partial recognition but it doesn&apos;t finance its functions. The students travel once a month to the school to take part in the clas
ses during one week while living in the school facilities. Rest of the month they practice  in their communities what they have learned transfering knowledge right to the field. Once graduated they get technical support and the tools needed to fully implem
ent the knowledge acquired to enable their own source of livelihood through sustainable small scale agriculture.The question of equality between men and women is taken into consideration and the participation of women is encouraged and promoted in all acti
ons. Also the matter of equality is being dealt with in workshops that take place once a week during the school week. The aim is to reach 50 % of female students of new students.The goal is to increase the number of student from the current 80 per grade to
 120 students and hence gain greater impact in the communities. To accomplish this and to assure the continuity of school&apos;s functions the objective is to obtain institutional support and official recognition for the school by the provincial government whic
h is needed for state subsidy. Its required to enable the increase of the number of students since the capacity of the school and the communities is already fully utilised.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11000" ref="11000-1" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="42500511" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-07-28" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="AR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="The Province of Santiago del Estero"></location>
  <sector code="31181" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">14371</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
