<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2015150081</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FLC: Participatory Conservation of Environment and Local Natural Tourists attractions  in Mwanga and Same Districts</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania Environmental and Tourism Educational Organization (TETEO) is liaising with other stakeholders to initiate develop promote and actively participate in activities that contribute to the conservation of nature and the improvement of the better life 
of Tanzania society.The previous project (2013 - 2014) aimed at establishing and promoting Community Based Nature Tourism for community better life in Mwanga District. Activities were successfully implemented but the challenge of conserving crucial attract
ions was raised by by stakeholders during Mwanga Tourism Conefence and project evaluation meeting. in 2014. the meeting recommended that strong initiatives must be taken immediately to conserve forests environment and all attractions in Mwanga and Same so 
as to make Community based Nature Tourism sustainable and profitable to the community. Also it was recommended that more education   and awareness on nature based tourism customer services and tourism entrepreneurship should be increased among the communit
y. Further TETEO came to realize that there is limited capacity of communities and district officials to undertake conservation and sustainable use of natural resources and tourist attractions; limited community focused joint programmes on conservation; li
mited established mechanism for cooperation networking and exchange of information for management of natural forests and tourism attractions and limited programmes for sensitizing communities on the importance and links between conservation livelihood and 
poverty alleviation. There are also limited alternative income generation activities that are friendly to environment and that return a higher value to the degraded environment and increase income to the community as well as create employment..TETEO would 
like to address the mentioned problems through; Capacity building in environment conservation Community Based Nature Tourism Service Production and Hospitality and entrepreneur skills; Also through awareness creation and promote alternative income generati
on activities( handcraft for women and youth tree nursery establishment and tree planting beekeeping biomass charcoaling cage and pond fish farming). Restoration of fragile Ecosystems for Nature Based tourism; Marketing and promoting local tourist attracti
ons products and services (mapping attractions distributing promotional materials and formulation of Village nature based tourism steering committees.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="23000" ref="23000-1" role="3" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kehitysmaan kansalaisj&#xE4;rjest&#xF6;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-09" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-09" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="33210" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is the main prio
rity area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights sensitive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeudet huomioiva</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 4, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving food security, access to water and sustainability is the secondary priority area in t
his activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="9999999" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Muut momentit</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other budget lines</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">68800</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">68800</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">61920</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
