<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014140581</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Global Citizenship Education</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Seeks to address the following challenge: Influencing the fulfillment of child rights and related global development requires comprehension of the complex challenges, the underlying cause effect relations and the role of Finland as a member of the internat
ional community. Without the comprehension, the general public or the decision makers are not able to advocate for the fulfillment of child rights and global responsibility.Aims to enforce global civic responsibility contributing to realization of human an
d child rights. PlanCitizen provides opportunities for people to participate and get engaged. PlanCitizen consists of Children&#x2019;s Board, Young adults&#x2019; network and General Volunteering. Children&#x2019;s Board aims at raising awareness of child rights and adv
ocating for the rights of children in developing countries. The Board organises events and campaigns such as Beat the Violence. International co-operation with Vietnamese youth enforces mutual learning and exchange of information. Young adults&#x2019; network m
otivates young adults to take action for global justice. The network is a facilitating platform for youth volunteering and youth participatory advocacy. Nationally, it advocates and raises awareness on global youth unemployment especially. The cooperation 
with youth group YACAN in Sierra Leone enables mutual learning on global issues, advocacy and different cultures.General Volunteering aims to increase interest in child rights and offer opportunities for civil society engagement. Volunteers participate in 
campaigns and organise events and exhibitions. Regional coordinators coordinate the volunteer activities around Finland. In 2013 volunteers worked on Right to learn -campaign advocating for the funding of education in development cooperation. The project i
s implemented by Plan Finland with the following partners for different actions: the Winyls band, schools, Plan Vietnam, YACAN, Trade Union of Education PlanGlobalSchool aims at strengthened skills and knowledge of children, young people and education prof
essionals in Finland on children&#x2019;s rights and development, for them to be able to engage themselves as active global citizens. Cooperation with schools and other educational institutes. Plan Finland&#x2019;s Child Rights&#x2019; Ambassadors visit schools, day-care
 centres and youth groups to raise awareness on the UNCRC. A study module comprising of ten lessons, &#x201C;Child rights&#x2019; ten&#x201D;, is offered for 5th and 6th graders through the Child rights&#x2019; ambassadors. The technical and vocational education subsector, in
cluding the students and their teachers, is reached through Plan&#x2019;s Turpa Auki! project on the use of rap lyrics in voicing one&#x2019;s opinions and discussing development issues. Children&#x2019;s participation in schools is enhanced through collaboration between
 pupils and their teachers in Uganda and Finland. Teacher trainings on child rights are provided to strengthen the capacity of teachers to introduce and mainstream global education in classroom activities. The trainings focus on media education from child 
rights perspective. Educational resources are developed for teachers to implement global education independently.The development impacts and direct beneficiaries: increased awareness on child rights and development among pupils and students who participate
 the child rights lessons; increased understanding on child rights and development, and enhanced skills on active global citizenship among pupils and students who participate in long term cooperation; empowered teachers and other educators, who have skills
 and high quality resources for child rights education; increased comprehension on child rights and skills on active global citizenship among Child rights&#x2019; ambassadors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan Suomi s&#xE4;&#xE4;ti&#xF6;</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Plan Suomi s&#xE4;&#xE4;ti&#xF6;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2014-2014140581" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="243066" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">411061</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2014-2014140581" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
