<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2010100123</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KOS/Forest Sector Support</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finland supports the forest sector reform in Kosovo. The project channelled through FAO supports the implementation of the Kosovo national forest strategy (2010-2010). The support directed to institutional development integrated forest management and pract
ices and climate change mitigation. The intervention supports the decentralization process and promotes participation of local communities in municipalities especially in rural areas. The goal in supporting multifunctional and sustainable use of forestsis 
an increase in the share of the forest sector in Kosovo&apos;s national economy. In the first phase of the project 2011-2014 (3 million euros) the coordination in forest issues has been improved. Support is given to the establishment and functioning of the Fore
st Management Board consisting of high representatives of different ministries. In addition Kosovo Forest Information System Monitoring and Evaluation System Kosovo Forest Health System and National Afforestation and Reforestation Programme have been devel
oped. Participatory forest management and planning have been introduced. The above mentioned tools and participatory principles have been incorporated in the new draft forest law. In 2013 a Mid-Term Review of the project was conducted. The MTR highlighted 
the importance of the activities on the grassroot level. This was taken into account in the implementation and in plans of the project. In order to ensure the sustainability of the results and integration of the forest management of Northern Kosovo under K
osovo administration the project is proposed to be extended with 1 million euros for the years 2015-2016. The support to the North is politically important because it supports the implementation of the agreement between Pristina and Belgrade.  In the imple
mentation of the extension phase also UNDP participate. UNDP has experience in livelihood and employment projects and also in projects in Norhern Kosovo.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="41301" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agricultural Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-11-29" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="RS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31210" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">1000000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
