<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014140114</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Support to small entrepreneurship and income generation for the vulnerable youth in Goma, DRC</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lack of access to formal education and skills trainings and the lack of employment opportunities for the youth make them particularly vulnerable to exploitation and abuse and limit the opportunities available to them. To address these challenges, the proje
ct will support the vocational training and small business support to the targeted youth, including demobilised child-soldiers, single- mothers, girls formerly associated with armed forces and groups, street children, and orphans. The project provides a sm
all-scale credit facility through M-PESA mobile money system, because most microfinance institutes do not reach out to the territory of Masisi. Also, in most cases the targeted youth are not eligible for credit in banks or MFIs. Therefore, the project prov
ides them an important start-up capital to build their businesses.In DRC, girls and women often face systematic discrimination and to address this, the project has a specific focus on promoting women&#x2019;s empowerment and enhancing their livelihood opportuni
ties and income generation. The objective is that they will become economically empowered and in the longer run increase their self-esteem, social status and participation in decision-making in their families and communities. At least 50% of the targeted s
mall businesses are run by women, but the project targets that 80 % will be girls. Objectives: The targeted trained youth are engaged in sustainable and profitable socio-economic activities and integrate professional life through the creation of small busi
nesses.  In 2015, the targeted youth will continue to receive skills training in the profession of their choice (transformation of agricultural products, livestock development), in small business management, life skills, savings and loans, and will be supp
orted to develop and monitor their business plans. Others, who have graduated in 2014, will benefit from the 12 month long business incubator period. ETN will continue to grant loans ranged from 300 and 700 EUR/per individual) to the youths&#x2019; businesses t
hat were established in 2014. The amount of the loan is fixed according to the established needs of the business, the quality and feasibility of the proposed business plan, and the number of persons participating in the business. ETN has contracted Vodacom
 M-PESA mobile money system to be technically in charge in distributing and receiving the reimbursements of the loans. First loans are of small scale, and gradually the youth can receive bigger loans.In total 80 youth will be receiving loans (minimum 50 % 
will be girls) and 50 girls will be trained in a profession. This youth include demobilised child-soldiers, single- mothers, girls formerly associated with armed forces and groups, street children, and orphans.The project is implemented by FCA and FCAs lon
ger term partner, ETN (Equipe d&#x2019;education et d&#x2019;encadrement de traumatises de Nyiragongo) who is running vocational training centres in Goma and Masisi in the Democratic Republic of Congo. FCA has cooperated with ETN since 2010.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finn Church Aid</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kirkon Ulkomaanavun S&#xE4;&#xE4;ti&#xF6;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2014-2014140114" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Province of North Kivu, The Democratic Republic of"></location>
  <sector code="24040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="243066" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">1000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2014-2014140114" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
