<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014140819</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transitioning Afghan Special School to Inclusive Education (TASSTIE)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inequality and inequity in education remain matter of great concern in Afghanistan. Approximately 50% of children remain out of school and many who are enrolled in school drop out or do not attend due to the lack of inclusiveness.  With support from Serve 
the Ministry of Education (MoE) has just completed their first Inclusive + Child Friendly Education Policy in order to ensure access to and quality of education for all children regardless their gender abilities disabilities backgrounds and circumstances. 
 The MoE has already begun trainings in Inclusive Education (IE) in several areas in Afghanistan including Nangahar province.SHIP school was established in 1991 to serve the educational needs of deaf children.  The school later expanded to educating childr
en with intellectual disabilities and then recently in 2012 we began our reverse inclusion where the disabled and non-disabled children could be educated together in the same classroom. Many said this would not be possible. However SHIP has proven that it 
is possible. Serve&apos;s goal from its beginning has been to create inclusive communities.  We now believe the community is ready to begin handover of the SHIP school to the MoE as an example of inclusive education.  In order to make this a reality we will wor
k with students parents community and other relevant stakeholders to begin advocacy with the government to take complete responsibility for the education of the students.  We believe this is possible because the government has already taken the responsibil
ity for other special schools.  To accomplish the objective of SHIP handover the following steps will be taken:1. Preparation of MoE schools by implementing Serve Inclusive Education (IE) model2. Preparation of SHIP students for inclusion in the prepared i
nclusive MoE schools. 3. Preparation of SHIP teachers parents and community for the handover4. Ensure normal and smooth operation of SHIP during the transitional periodWe will gradually release responsibility to the government after they have been trained 
and equipped with the necessary skills and tools to provide sustainable and quality education for all students. After the handover Serve will continue to follow-up and support the inclusive MoE schools through the CBR (Community-based Rehabilitation) funct
ion of SHIP capacity of which will be increased to support increased number of clients.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Operaatio Mobilisaatio ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-27" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">142890</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">155935</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">142890</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
