<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014140749</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Security Management and protection for Human Rights Defenders in Tanzania, implementing year two of operational plan 2013 - 2014</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Tanzania Human Rights Defenders Coalition (THRDC) is a Coalition in Tanzania with both individual Human Rights Defenders and Human Rights Organizations membership working towards enhancing the security and protection of Human Rights Defenders (HRDs) in
 the country. The main objective of this project is to build protection and security management capacity of HRDs in Tanzania to enhance the security and protection of HRDs in the country to be able to evacuate and reallocate HRDs at risk and to advocate fo
r the recognition of HRDs in  Tanzania through lobbying and advocacy work. The Coalition therefore seeks some funds to support the following activities, Advocacy in terms of media coverage, Annual General Meeting and Universal Periodic Review meeting with 
THRDC members, Conduct security and risk assessment training for 30 new human rights defenders from all 10 Zones of Tanzania, Conduct security and risk assessment training for 30 pastoralist humsn rights defenders, Maintaining Protection desk by providing 
fund for legal/protection officer, Emergence protection fund for evacuations reallocation and legal support for HRDs Preparation of 2014 annual report and 2014 situation report on the state of human rights defenders in Tanzania. The target group in yhis pr
oject include, the most HRDs at risk such as journalists HRDs pastoralists HRDs minority HRDs human rights lawyers whistle blowers and women HRDsThe expected final results include, community capacity to address HRDs rights improved, HRDs and CSOs security 
management and protection capacities improved/enhanced, security management self protection at individual level and National protection system improved, Networking and information sharing among HRDs improved, The number of people joining the work of human 
rights promotion increased,Threats and attacks towards HRDs decreased, Emergence and hotlines are in place, Coalition Good governance and accountability improved, Coalition management capacity increased and Coalition&apos;s visibility improved and accessed by t
he target group.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11000" ref="11000-1" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="28235792" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-09-04" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">8000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
