<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2010100618</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Empowering Partners to Respond to Environmental and Climate Change</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The purpose of the Project is to increase the capacity of the partner on environmental conservation and food security so as to improve the livelihood of ten Communities in Kenya. The Project seeks to address the destabilized livelihoods of the communities 
due to environmental and climatic change as a result of harmful human action. The Full Gospel Churches of Kenya is the Fida Partner in Kenya. The Church has a membership of 1.2 Million members and is administratively organized in 12 regions and 83 district
s in throughout the Country. The target communities live in the most difficult places in arid and semi-arid lands which have harsh climatic conditions caused by increased global warming. Deforestation through human activities has also contributed to the re
duction of forest cover in Kenya in a great way. The Communities in these areas have encountered great challenges in their lives due inadequate food and water. The project will focus in the areas of food security, environment protection through alternative
 livelihood strategies and formation of Children Clubs for their participation purposes. The will sensitizing the communities on their rights to the basic needs and encourage them to increases environmental conservation. The communities will be empowered b
y providing them with adequate knowledge on how to respond to the impacts of climate change and increased food production. The communities will be trained on modern skills for establishment of tree nurseries and water harvesting which allows a network of p
artners to be engaged. The project intends to continue intensifying interventions in the former pilot areas and add 4 new areas. The empowerment process will include establishment of tree/fruit nurseries, environmental management training, Farming in God&apos;s
 Way, soil erosion control, poultry keeping, bee keeping, improving livestock breeding and production of energy saving Jikos to reduce deforestation. Through the partner, the well-being of the communities in arid and semi-arid areas of Kenya will have impr
oved in the way of increased food security and forest cover. Members of the community will continually access enough and nutritious food adequate for their lives and realize healthy living. Farmers have practiced agro-forestry which has increased forest co
ver as they grow their food.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Fida International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="41081" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">149832</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
