<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2011110011</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Poor women&apos;s and girls&apos; right to own income and food security II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is a continuation of an earlier cooperation between Cameroonian Home Economists&apos; Association ACESF-CA and the Martha Association in 2012-2014. The development goal of the project is raising the quality of life (both material well-being and abil
ity to participate) of poor women and their families. The project will contribute to this goal through providing the women with increased knowledge and skills in good nutrition local food and home economics entrepreneurship. The new phase also focuses on a
 new vulnerable group: school girls that have chosen home economics as their career often without knowing how it can help them earn a living and be empowered.The project will mostly develop already existing structures such as training and mentoring of poor
 women entrepreneurs. These structures will be introduced also to three new regions.The project will have four strategic targets: 1. Educating on nutrition2. Improving the income of beneficiaries3. Promoting gender equality and empowering girls of the Home
 Economics field4. Building ACESF-CA?s institutional capacities The main beneficiaries are 1080 poor women in 6 towns and their surroundings in Cameroon (Yaounde Bamenda Maroua Douala Bertoua Bafoussam) as well as 450 young girls. The indirect beneficiarie
s are the family members of direct beneficiaries estimated to be 8 930.The main activities will be background research and identifying of beneficiaries production of training materials trainings of trainers training of women in nutrition and good entrepren
eurship forming of home economics clubs for schoolgirls to discuss professional issues and empowerment and to carry out study visits. Capacity building of counterpart association ACESF-CA and evaluation are also activities that will be carried throughout t
he project.The main partners for this project are the Martha Association and ACESF-CA. The latter shall work in collaboration with the external services of the Ministry of Women Empowerment and the Family (MINPROFF) and the Ministry of Secondary Education 
(MINESEC).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Marttaliitto ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-11-09" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="32130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">108214</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">82468</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">72853</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">108214</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
