<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2008080372</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Primary Dental Care Support Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Primary Dental Care Support Programme. The cooperation seeks to promote dental health among young generations in Pyongyang area by increasing the awareness of the causes to dental diseases and their preventive acts, supporting the daily home care possibili
ties among the target population and by providing the cooperation hospitals with some material aid. Fida?s partner is The Korea Education Fund (KEF), a non-governmental organization to support education approved by the government of the DPRK. The initiatio
n to the work came from the local authorities and it was launched autumn 2007 in Pyongyang?s two districts. Because the work was expanding successfully, the Primary Dental Care Support Programme was established in the beginning of 2009. The awareness of th
e programme has spread also to the other districts leading to several enquiries to the partner how to get along.  The preventive work is based on the World Health Organization?s (WHO) Oral Health Promotion Programme where the education comes close to the t
arget population when given by community trainers while the professionals serve as mentors and supervisors. Tooth brushes, pastes and educational material are distributed to the target group children in order to strengthen the education. The cooperation ho
spitals are provided with the mostly required equipment needed to treatment procedures. The project goal is to strengthen the basic knowledge of dental diseases and their prevention among the whole DPRK population. After the initiative phase, the work is g
oing to be shifted to the locals. Fida?s representatives had a privilege to participate in a presentation seminar arranged by the partner in October 2008.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Fida International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Pyongyang"></location>
  <sector code="12261" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">176367</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
