<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2012000076</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Opetuksen laadun parantaminen maaseudun alakouluissa Thyolossa ja Blantyressa Etela-Malawissa vaihe II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Primary School education in Malawi though being one of the priority areas of the Malawi Government?s development strategies is still facing many obstacles in terms of quality and child-friendliness maintaining high illiteracy and school drop-out rates and 
their connected long-term effects. One of the main factors leading to low quality of primary education is low quality of teachers especially in rural areas.In an effort to address some of the problems of the sector DAPP Malawi in partnership with the Malaw
i Government embarked on a programme of improving the quality of teaching. In 2013 DAPP started implementing the Teachers Network project in Blantyre rural and Thyolo districts with funding from the Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland and UFF. This pro
ject will end in 2015.UFF and DAPP propose a continuation to the project. The second phase of the project will target 80 Primary Schools in the two district (40 new schools and 40 schools from phase I) with approximately 64000 learners.The overall objectiv
e of the project is to complement existing efforts of Government of Malawi to improve learning outcomes. The project aims at improved education equity as well as quality and relevance of primary school education in Thyolo and Blantyre rural Districts.The s
pecific objective of this project is: Decreased drop-out rates increased retention rates of especially girl learners and those with disabilities up to standard eight and improved learning results in 80 rural primary schools for approx. 64000 learners in Bl
antyre rural and Thyolo districts.The expected results are:  1. Increased capacity and better teaching skills of primary school teachers2. Improved learning environment and access to quality education especially for girls and children with disabilities3. I
ncreased cooperation and engagement of communities surrounding the 80 schools in primary education management and child supportThe teachers in the 40 schools from phase 1 will consolidate what they have learned and become able to independently plan and imp
lement activities to foster development and improve the learning environment. The teachers will also be trained in how to teach and include children with disabilities.The teachers in the 40 new schools will follow the basics of the first phase adjusted bas
ed on lessons learnt from Phase I. These teachers will also undergo training in inclusive teaching and improving education for girls and children with disabilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-810" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, U-landshjalp fran Folk till Folk i Finland rf (UFF)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="25302205" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-08" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Blantyre Rural and Thyolo Districts"></location>
  <sector code="11130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">258303</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">258303</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
