<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2008081082</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Campaigning for Core Labour Standards + Quality Public Services in ADB</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project ensures that public sector unions will be able to understand Asian Development Bank (ADB) funded large scale infrastructure projects and to monitor that CLSs are respected at all phases. The aim is to ensure that the infrastructure will produce
 quality public services, and these services will have decent workplaces.ADB?s megaprojects employ hundreds of thousands of workers. Trade union rights and decent work principles are not always respected and fully applied in these projects. Neither can one
 guarantee that the new infrastructure will result in producing quality public services and decent work opportunities. Decent work, ILO core labour standards and quality public services will reduce poverty and will promote the achievement of Millenium Deve
lopment Goals.In every cooperation country, operational capacity, organizing and networking of the unions is strengthened. In India, the lobby strategies of the unions are strengthened, so that basic labour rights are taken into account already at the plan
ning phase of ADB energy sector projects. ADBs operations in the energy sector are also targeted in Indonesia. In Mongolia, a partnership agreement is made with ADB so that the privatization of services is tackled and quality public services are promoted i
.a. through a joint research project. In the Philippines, quality water services are promoted as well as partnerships for public service providers (Public-Public Partnerships). The realization of labour rights through the government, worker organizations a
nd companies are promoted. In Tonga, the aim is to ensure that the reform of the Tonga Public Service Enterprise leads to positive developments for workers and communities.       The beneficiaries are the representatives and union management of the member 
organization sin the PSI target countries.  Other beneficiaries include the international trade unions coordinating the ADB work (in particular BWI, UNI and ITF) as well as central NGO networks. In a wider perspective, the project benefits the public secto
r workers whose work, benefits and rights are threatened due to ADB projects. The partners are Public Services International (PSI) and their affiliated public sector unions in Tonga, Mongolia, the Philippines, Indonesia and India.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-30" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, SASK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="4605" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">86100</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
