<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014141003</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unesco</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNESCO is known as the intellectual agency of the United Nations. UNESCO&apos;s mandate is to build peace and sustainable development deminish poverty and confirm human rights through education culture and freedom of expression.Supporting education of girls and
 women developing the vocational and technical education and contributing to the freedom of expression media development and access to information is the thematic focus for the Finnish funding to UNESCO.  The education of girls and women is promoting gende
r equality in education human rights and sustainable development.  Unesco&apos;s TVET policies and programmes support the member states&apos; capacity for developing the vocational and technical education improve youth transitions between education and the world of 
work and promote poverty reduction social inclusion and gender equality.  Freedom of expression and pluralistic and free media are critical for building healthy democracies and societies.The Finnish funding to the Education sector of UNESCO is channelled t
hrough the Capacity Development programme. The CapEFA is an extra-budgetary funding mechanism and programme approach created in 2003 with the objective of translating global advocacy for Education for All (EFA) into concrete action in particular in countri
es most at risk of not achieving the goals by 2015. In 2013 the CapEFA Programme covered 31 priority countries mainly located in Africa and Asia and two sub-regional programmes. The CapEFA contributes to UNESCO?s overall efforts to strengthen Member States
? capacities for policy formulation and planning focusing on promoting the right to quality education and gender equality and opportunity for lifThe strategic objective of the Communication and information programme is promoting freedom of expression media
 development and access to information and knowledge.  The special emphasis in the programme is on gender equality Africa least developed countries (LDCs) and small island developing States (SIDS) as well as youth. The Finnish funding is channeled through 
the Internationd Program for Development of Communication (IPDC). The projects of the IPDC enhance the capacity of national and local media institutions support the development of independent media as well as develop the education of journalists with speci
al attention to the safety of journalists. elong learning for all.The funding for 2014-2015 is 2 400 000 ? CapEFA programme 2 milj. euro IPDC 400 000 euro.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="41304" ref="41304-2" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Educational Scientific and Cultural Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="89892407" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-06-02" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430664" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maittain kohdentamaton kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Non-region specific development cooperation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">1200000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-05-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">1200000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
