<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014140149</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Holistic Women&apos;s Empowerment Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Populations Fund (UNFPA) has gathered statistical evidence from gender-based violence in the Democratic Republic of the Congo. Relative recently published data show no abatement in sexual violence cases. In North Kivu alone, 4689 cases were 
reported in 2011 and 7075 in 2012. Same tendency has been witnessed in South Kivu (2713 cases in 2011 and 5028 in 2012). According to UNFPA, DRC has the world&#x2019;s highest number of reported gender-based violence cases.  The role of woman in the Congolese s
ociety is still very weak. Project Specific Objective: The role and participation of women in managing public affairs has improved in selected Provinces of North Kivu, South Kivu and Oriental ProvinceExpected Results:&#x2022; Legal structures at Provincial leve
l of North Kivu have improved to better address the issue of sexual violence&#x2022; The awareness of community members in selected target communities on women&#x2019;s and children&#x2019;s rights has improved&#x2022; Vulnerable women in selected communities participate acti
vely in saving and credit groups and have their own income generating activities.&#x2022; Local communities are part of and contribute to formal and non-formal peace support structures, on local, sub-national, national and international levelActivities: &#x2022; Sup
porting legal structures in North Kivu in data management of sexual violence cases&#x2022; Training on the International Protocol on the Documentation and Investigation of Sexual Violence in Conflict&#x2022; Awareness-raising in selected communities on women&#x2019;s and
 children&#x2019;s rights&#x2022; Working with men and boys as change agents to combat sexual violence&#x2022; Supporting the existing Village Credit and Saving Associations of vulnerable women including survivors of sexual violence&#x2022; Providing training on entrepreneurs
hip and creating small-scale income-generating activities&#x2022; Advocacy programme in like with the advocacy plan developed for RAFEJE in 2014 to empower women in the DRCRights-holders /beneficiaries: &#x2022; Survivors of sexual violence in the Province of North 
Kivu.&#x2022; Currently there are about 20 Village Saving and Credit Associations created having on average 20 members in each; new groups will be established. &#x2022; The key duty-bearers will be the representatives of the judicial system, specifically in the prov
inces of the North and South Kivu and the Oriental Province. Local authorities in selected communities as well as community members in target areas will be addresses. &#x2022; In 2014 the RAFEJE has also prepared an advocacy plan up to the end 2015, including a
 stakeholder analysis. The key stakeholders for the project are DRC National Assembly and Senate, the Governors of the three Provinces, and Gender Ministry and Division at the Provincial level.Implementing partner:Dynamique des Femmes Juristes (DFJ); Femme
s Juristes pour les Droits de la Femme et de l&#x2019;Enfant (FJDF) ; RAFEJE.FCA has been supporting DFJ and FJDF since 2009-2010 and RAFEJE (advocacy network of lawyer organisations) since 2011.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finn Church Aid</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kirkon Ulkomaanavun S&#xE4;&#xE4;ti&#xF6;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2014-2014140149" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="North Kivu, South Kivu and Oriental Province, The"></location>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="243066" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">51171</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2014-2014140149" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
