<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2013130607</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Food Security for Small Scale Farmers</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project purpose is to increase food supplies for 600 families of Giharo and Bukemba in Rutana Province of Burundi through promotion and facilitation in better farming methods and practices that will enhance increased food production in the community. T
he Project will build the capacity of the community in sustainable land management, mobilization of local resource and adaptation to climate change.The Community of Pentecostal Churches in Burundi (CEPBU) is the main Fida partner in this program. During th
e past 4 decades, Burundi has undergone through destructive civil wars that caused a great damaged to the country?s economy. During this period, more than 500,000 fled the country to the neighbouring countries especially Tanzania. After a long process of p
eace talks between the rebels and the government, peace agreements were signed and the repatriation process was initiated in which a massive flow back of returnees were settled back to their origin places in Rutana province of Burundi. The resettlement pro
cess has faced a lot of challenges in meeting the needs of the returnee who were poor, illiterate, without food and shelter, and lacked farming inputs to start up their normal living. CEPBU and Fida have partnered to empower the community in understanding 
their rights in response to these challenges. The Project will conduct church leaders training on food security/environment protection techniques and the formulation of food security and Environment protection policy.  The partner will influence the commun
ity on matters related to food security and environment protection practices. The project will train the Community Coordinating Teams (CCT) who will be a representation of the 600 families on food security and environment protection.  The CCT will establis
h farmers&apos; groups in the community and train them on saving and credit methods, effective livestock management, preparation and development of tree nurseries and engage them in tree planting and protect of forest areas with contour lines. The project will 
provide the Community Coordinating Teams with training materials, seeds for demonstration tree nurseries and links to other environment protection organizations. The overall objective of this project is to contribute to the wellbeing of the returnee commun
ities in Burundi. It is expected that, at the end of the project the returnees will increase their food production that is enough to sustain their family needs and support their children education</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Fida International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2027-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BI" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Rutana province, Burundi"></location>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">88503</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
