<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2015150221</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">It&apos;s our mines: no matter where they are - Problems in global mine industry for the youmg</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this project we produce teaching material educate volunteer school visitors and teachers and visit schools.The teaching material we will produce deals with global mining industry and it is meant to be used in Finnish comprehensive school on grades 7-9. 
The material will be produced by a working group formed of volunteers and the hired coordinator who facilitates the project and makes sure the material is pedagogically appropriate.School visits made by volunteers are based on the teaching material produce
d in this project and the material is also offered to teachers and others who are interested for free. The volunteers are educated using the material in a trainings that will take place in autumn 2015. Volunteers may also arrange non-formal meetings locall
y where they meet each other and share their ideas and best practices.Teachers will be nationally offered an opportunity to order a school visitor to her/his class. During the visit we will talk about global mining industry its impacts on environment and p
eople&apos;s everyday life and our role in a big picture as a western citizens and consumers. The idea is to examine the phenomenon on a global scale with local aspects in Finland and global South. Methods use in school visits will be activating because we real
ly want to make the pupils think critically. The theoretical base in the project is critical pedagogy (Freire 1970) and critical global citizenship education (Andreotti 2006) so we consider the pupils active actors in their own lives. We will also educate 
teachers and other professionals who work with young people because they are often role models and can affect more students than we can ever reach with volunteer school visitors. In trainings for teachers we use the same material as in school visits but fr
om a different point of view, the idea is to find out how teachers can deal with mining and other global phenomena in their work in a way that enables the young people to understand better.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maan ystavat ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-23" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="99820" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="H01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">51030</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">51030</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">51030</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
