<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2012000267</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mental Health Training Centre Mazar</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Among the mental illnesses affecting Afghans most are depression anxiety and posttraumatic stress disorder. While the factors are numerous the path to treatment is troubled with obstacles ranging from the shame felt by family members to old traditions that
 compete with modern methods and a huge deficiency of professionals and facilities equipped to deal with the situation. The International Assistance Mission (IAM) has worked in Afghanistan since 1966 and since 1996 on improving mental health care. In 1996 
it started a Primary Mental Health Project  in Herat. To date this project has continued and trained primary health care providers at three levels (i.e. community health supervisors nurses/midwives and doctors) to carry out mental health services in the he
alth facilities throughout the Western Region. It engages directly with mentally ill in running a busy psychiatric out-patient clinic.It has been very successful in raising awareness of mental illness in the community and reducing stigma experienced by peo
ple with mental illness through sustained and locally relevant awareness programs. Community involvement in raising awareness is systematically built in and it has an awareness of equity issues related to gender and social class.The proposed Mental Health 
Training Centre Mazar (MHTC Mazar) builds on the foundations laid in the Western region by starting a similar approach for the 7 provinces of the Northern region. MHTC Mazar aims to the develop a Mental Health Training Centre for the professional treatment
 of the mentally ill according to evidence based standards and the mental health training of medical professionals. MHTC Mazar will further develop and contribute to maintaining through training the mental health care capacity of the public Health Centres 
in Northern Region in order for it to provide mental health services in rural and urban areas according to the Ministry of Public Health of Afghanistan  requirements.It aims at introducing in the Northern Region effective evidence based ways of promoting g
ood mental health into the school system to mullahs to governmental entities and possibly civil society entities. This will be done through training activities media and advocacy work. This project will be part of the National Mental Health Programme of IA
M in Afghanistan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-820" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Evankelis-luterilainen Lahetysyhdistys Kylvaja ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="62507315" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-08" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12181" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PP3 is primary priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">183033</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">110000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
