<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014141197</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Story from lawyers in Karens&#x2019; life case: They are at risk! Handbook for help.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project includes the translation of the guidebook produced by Thai Human Rights Lawyers Association into English, and layout and printing of the book in Thai and English. Activities are divided into 3 stages: 1. Translation from the original Thai versi
on into English by a translator or an institution specialized in civil society work in order to communicate the story naturally and reach out to the public; 2. Production: contracting a producer specialized in pocket book to design graphic arts and story f
ormat in order to avoid serious contents for presentation to the general public.3. Distribution of the publication to various agencies through distributors of well-known printing press, post and by hand. The contents of the book is divided into 3 parts inc
luding 1) essence of the case (background of Mae Om Ki community), 2) analysis of the court case, and 3) academic articles on community/ethnic rights. Siemenpuu&#x2019;s partner in this project is the Human Rights Lawyers Association (HRLA) of Thailand, which h
as helped two Karen farmers in litigation process over the past years. The rotation farmers were accused of producing climate change and sentenced to prison in a lower court, but the sentence has been since overruled. Now the case is in the Supreme Court o
f Thailand. The Karen case is a watershed case in Thailand and in Southeast Asia, and thus HRLA wants to highlight the discrimination and prejudice towards ethnic minorities that are common in the Thai society. The book also gives guidelines how to support
 the (community) rights of the ethnic minorities and how to proceed in the court cases. The primary beneficiaries of the project are the karens and other forest dwelling ethnic minorities, but the publication is targeted to public organizations (esp. fores
try agencies), non-governmental organizations and social activists, lawyers and legal practitioners, people living in the forest areas, scholars and universities. The English version is distributed especially in Southeast Asia, where the challenges of ethn
ic minorities/indigenous people are similar. The immediate results of the project are expected to be the increase of knowledge and awareness of the situation of the forest minorities and their rights, and the increase of practical work to help them in lega
l processes.Human Rights Lawyers Association (HRLA) has been established in 2008 by a group of lawyers and attorneys aiming to upholding the rule of law, social justice and Human Rights in Thailand. The objectives of HRLA are: 1. To enhance the idea of jus
tice and its implementation approach amongst human rights lawyers in Thailand; 2. To achieve standard institutionalized of human rights and rule of law into the society through strategic litigation; 3. To conduct strategic litigation/ public litigation cas
es related to community rights, anti-torture, freedom of expression, those three areas HRLA will continues disseminate including provide legal assistance to affected and effected community and develop the curriculum regarding litigation for those cases; 4.
 To enhance and empower the collaboration and participation among educational institutions, academics-researchers, students and community and other stakeholders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Siemenpuu - Kansalaisliikkeiden yhteisty&#xF6;s&#xE4;&#xE4;ti&#xF6; sr</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Siemenpuu Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2014-2014141197" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="243066" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">500</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">194</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2014-2014141197" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
