<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2010100121</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farmers&apos; Clubs in Kunene Province Angola Phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the project is to promote environmentally sustainable human development in Angola. The project contributes to eradicating extreme poverty in rural areas of Kunene province. The purpose is to increase the food security and income of
 1530 farmers and their families through training in environment friendly production methods literacy training and strengthened organization thereby consolidating and up-scaling the activities and results of the first 3 years of the Farmers? Club project.T
he project will improve the human rights status of the participants by increasing their food security and standard of living. It will provide access to education enabling the participants to become literate. The project will promote gender equality and inc
lusion of the disabled in all project activities and will seek to enable participants to exercise their civil rights in the local society. Introduction of conservation farming methods and crop diversification will work towards climate proofing the farmers.
The project will both develop the existing 20 Farmers? Clubs and create 10 new ones with 500 farmers as members. Main beneficiaries are 1530 farmers and their families approximately 10000 people.The 20 existing clubs with 1030 members will be supported in 
becoming legally registered as associations and hereby getting access to government guaranteed micro credit schemes. The project will support the farmers in developing their production and common sale systems further and in successfully exploiting the micr
o credit opportunities for making productive investments.500 farmers of whom at least half are female will be organized in 10 new Farmers? Clubs. Each club of approximately 50 farmers will elect a Farmers? Club Committee of 5 members who will be trained in
 project activities and leadership skills including practising inclusion and transparency. The Committees will be responsible for guiding the rest of the club members and will gradually take over the ownership of the club activities. Club activities includ
e monthly training sessions on sustainable agricultural methods basic business skills basic health hygiene and sanitation, monthly club meetings, literacy and numeracy training, health campaigns and more. Each group of 10 farmers will establish a model fie
ld where new methods are demonstrated trained and proved. The clubs are encouraged to organize common transport and/or systems for sale of the produce.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-810" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, U-landshjalp fran Folk till Folk i Finland rf (UFF)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="22504601" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-11-04" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="AO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31140" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">161951</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">156461</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">178236</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
