<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2015150101</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Alliance of Civilizations, Youth Solidarity Fund 2014-2015</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The United Nations Alliance of Civilizations (UNAOC) Youth Solidarity Fund (YSF) was established in 2008 to support the work of youth organizations in developing countries and to advance the mission of the UNAOC within their communities.  The YSF programme
 aims to strengthen human development and promote peace in developing countries. The programme is implemented mainly in developing countries of Asia Sub-Saharan Africa and MENA regions.The objectives of the YSF meet the requirements of Finland&apos;s Developmen
t Policy Programme by emphasizing equality and diminishing of inequality and marginalization. The programme is in line also with the priorities of Finland&apos;s UN strategy underlining conflict prevention contributing to gender equility by confirming the polit
ical and financial opportunities for women.The results of the YSF projects have indicated that the youth can significally influence the national policy and the awareness of local decision-makers and link the generation gap of cultural and religious stereot
ypes. Based on the results and recommendations of the previous YSF projects the UNAOC has launched a 4th edition of the Youth Solidarity Fund in December 2014 aiming to select and support up to 20 youth projects.The objectives of these projects are:- foste
r understanding and cooperative relations among youth at the local national and international levels- foster involvement of marginalized youth in decision making processes- enhance the skills among youth willing to contribute to their contry&apos;s social econo
mic and civic development.The activities of the project meet the ODA requirements, they will be carried out in Africa and Asia. The DAC objectives are participatory development good governance and gender equility.The main beneficiaries of the project are t
he youth living in those developing countries where the projects will be carried out as well as the youth of the alumni network and the marginalized youth. The objective of the project is also women&apos;s involvement in the education thus the beneficiaries of 
the project are also the women in the region. The funding of Finland will be directed to the youth projects implemented in the developing countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41000" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Alliance of Civilizations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-16" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">200000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-04-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">200000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">80000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
