<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014140165</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Strengthening of Domestic Workers&apos; Rights</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project improves the capacity of domestic workers to defend their rights and prepares them to lobby and influence politically to improve the working conditions of domestic workers in Ecuador. One of the biggest challenges is the lack of knowledge among
 domestic workers about their legal rights and inability to defend themselves against the employers. In general this is because the low education level and and lack of basic knowledge on rights. The project intends to respond to this challenge by empowerin
g young girls and boys who work as domestic workers to know their legal rights and to defend them with the help of Domestic Workers? Union ATRH. Besides, the project tries to improve the general appreciation of their work, and to improve the profile of dom
estic workers by professionalizing their work which is often invisible in the society. The activities consist of training, diffusion of knowledge on rights, organizing workers in the ATRH union, advocacy work towards the authorities, and legal assistance t
o domestic workers in conflict situations. As a result of the project, domestic workers in six provinces (Guayas, Esmeraldas, Los Rios, Pichincha, Jipijapa ja Machala) have better knowledge on their labor rights, young activists in ATRH have capacity to us
e the information about trade union rights, labor legislation, social security, occupational health and safety and know how to work with authorities. ATRH union members get legal assistance if they have problems with the employer, the membership of ATRH ha
s increased and ATRH is a stronger player in national level, and the public knowledge on domestic workers rights has increased. The direct beneficiaries are the 300 ATRH members who participate in project activities and training. In the long run, all 300 0
00 domestic workers in Ecuador will benefit from the improvements in labor legislation that ATRH has advocated. The project is implemented by Domestic Workers Union (ATRH). The union is a relatively strong player in Ecuador, although the sector it represen
ts is one of the most difficult to organize. ATRH has managed to negotiate and advocate very important improvements to the work and rights of domestic workers and it has a working relationship with the government.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, SASK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="EC" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">42200</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
