<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014140830</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening biofarming approaches for additional income and social security of farmer families</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The problem which will be addressed is developing farming communities in southern India especially in regard to ecological farming. The agricultural education will be strengthened. Training and demonstrations for 300 women beneficiaries in the farming comm
unity will be organised yearly in six villages. The objective is to train the women in taking better use of chemical free manures insecticides pesticides and to cultivate organically and eco-friendly. Economically important plants and trees will be planted
 on the hedges of the farming area and the dwelling places. Through trainings and demonstrations multiple and intercropping patterns are used.  Preparing of compost and vermicompost for recycling of farm wastes will be demonstrated and made on the farms. T
hus farming is made profitable and suitable for future generations and ecologically beneficial to the community as a whole. Establishment of demonstration units for horticulture floriculture and poultry are organized as well as a beekeeping unit in the par
tner&apos;s premises.Awareness trainings are planned in timely insemination of livestock awareness of ill effects of open defecation and drinking of polluted water. Other training issues are hygiene health and nutrition. The importance of education is stressed.
 Children from 5 to 15 years go to school. During three years 900 women beneficiaries will be empowered to unite and form self help groups. Within self help groups the women beneficiaries are encouraged to regular savings and individual entrepreneurial act
ivities. Through self help groups linked to Commercial Banks for subsidy loans and savings the women from six different villages will get additional income become economically self reliant and acquainted with social activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Suomen Caritas ry Caritas Finland rf</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-27" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="32130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">30000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-02-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">30000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
