<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2009091199</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HIV/AIDS Prevention care and support project of Jimma town and Jimma zone Ethiopia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2013: HIV/AIDS is one of the major social factors limiting the realization of the Millennium Development Goals (MDG) in Ethiopia. To assist the national efforts in reducing the spread of HIV/AIDS and mitigating its impact the project is targeting to improv
e and sustain the living standard of orphans and vulnerable children (OVC) people living with HIV/AIDS (PLWHA) and vulnerable groups in Jimma town and Agaro town. The cross-cutting development policy objectives will be taken into account since the project 
will be working with people living with HIV/AIDS orphans vulnerable women children and youth trying to fight against stigmatisation and trying to give them their full place in the community they are living in focusing especially on women. In addition to th
at the project will offer needy children the possibility to go to school.The beneficiaries of the project will be selected from all the cultural and religious backgrounds. The project will not create any new structure but will work in close collaboration w
ith the goverment bodies the town administration and the community based organizations.The main beneficiaries of the projects are people living with HIV/AIDS orphans and vunerable children high risk groups including unemployed youth and vunerable women and
 in extension the whole community.The key project activities are:- Orphan care and support program: monthly financial and material support medical help life skills training and income generating activities for guardians.- PLWHA rehabilitation care and supp
ort program: monthly financial and material support medical service counseling life skill training and income generating activities.- High risk women and youth self-reliance program: small scale business/micro-enterprise training and income generating acti
vities.- Voluntary Counseling and Testing (VCT) program and community mobilization.- Information Education and Communication (IEC) program/Behavioural Change Communication (BCC).- Capacity building/trainings.For the second phase of the project the number o
f catchment areas will be reduced to two: Agaro town and Jimma town. During the first phase of the project the working area was very wide with long geographic distances and the work could not be as efficient as it should. The latest data we collected from 
the different areas showed that the HIV problem is very big in Agaro and Jimma whereas it is not as obvious in the other places.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Suomen Evankelisluterilainen Kansanlahetys ry (SEKL)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-10" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="16064" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">130000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">85000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
