<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2015150749</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Human Rights and Forced Eviction Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Many slum dwellers are under constant threat of illegal and forced evictions and displacement. In 2004, started the Kenya Slum Upgrading Programme to improve the conditions in slums, but the slum dwellers have not been included in the program and the imple
mentation of the program involves many risks. The 1972 Public Health Act, determine the standards of living and quality of water, but authorities did not enforce the law regarding to its implementation in the slums. The draft law Eviction and Resettlement 
Bill 2012, about the forced evictions and resettlement, is approved for the Parliament processing. The bill guarantees citizens the humane treatment of such cases before the eviction, during and after it. KISORA has been involved in the preparation of the 
draft law and in its lobbing. The objective is to strengthen the community-based advocacy in the realization of ESC rights: the aim is to strengthen the capacity of slum dwellers to demand the implementation of economic and social rights, particularly the 
right to adequate housing, and lobby for the administration to run according to the requirements of the main international human rights instruments. In addition, the project aims to increase the knowledge of members of the community about the economic and 
social rights. The aim is to strengthen the cooperation in the grass-roots level and to increase the KISORAn internal capacity to take action so that it would be a strong and responsible actor. Project&apos;s direct beneficiaries are the communities living in s
lums under the threat of eviction. In addition, the project is targeted at 33 grassroots organizations in Kisumu East District. Indirect beneficiaries are the other residents in the slums of Kisumu East District. KISORA (Kisumu Social Rights Association) S
elf Help Group was established in 2007, and it is a network for human rights lobbying groups operating in grass-roots slums.http://hakijamii.wordpress.com/hakijamiis-partners/kisumu-social-rights-association-kisora</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO Foundation for Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">15120</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">22680</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
