<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014140097</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Right to Peace (R2P) in the Central African Republic</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Due to the sporadic nature of the conflict in CAR, as well as the weak authority and reach of the Transitional Government, it is necessary to look into empowering communities themselves to build resilience to conflict. By directly engaging members of commu
nities to reflect on narratives, problems and prerequisites to reconciliation, communities begin to enable themselves to process the consequences of conflict and establish ownership over recovery, as well as prevention of further conflict. This project?s o
bjective is to enhance the capacities of communities to recover from, reconcile and prevent violent conflict. A further key objective of FCA?s Right to Peace approach in CAR will be to build bridges between the youth and the traditional/religious leadershi
p, in order to nurture more holistic collaboration and foster an improved sense of belonging and representation within communities. To capitalise on its comparative advantage in the education sector and to ensure a sustainable approach to social cohesion t
hat engages both youth and elders, Finn Church Aid (FCA) will couple its peace activities with education activities. In view of social cohesion and peacebuilding, it is particularly pertinent to engage the youth, who constitute half of the population in CA
R today. FCA is currently the only organisation taking on such a mutually reinforcing approach to education and social cohesion.FCA?s R2P activities will be based on: ? Discussion groups, engaging 1. the (Parents Association, PTA) active in the community, 
2. the youth of the community, 3. the women of the community: 4. the community leadership (religious, traditional, mayor), ? Encouraging a balanced representation women in all groups,? Separate and joint thematic discussions and workshops, ? Thematic aware
ness-raising (incl. HR, IHL, SGBV, RoL, Justice) and mediation training (as well as possibly practical livelihood skills training)Identified beneficiaries are the targeted communities as a whole, but through a focus on youth and their families (PTAs), as w
ell as religious and traditional leaders.On a secondary level, the project aims to influence national authorities by inviting them to recognise and engage with community level peace support structures.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="20000-2" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Finnish Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="11516" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Bangui, Central African Republic"></location>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">84965</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
