<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2011110039</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sahansaho ? against desertification in Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sahansaho is a joint project coordinated by the Finnish Somalia Network (FSN) addressing the sustainable use and management of the natural resources in Somalia. The key development problem which the project aims to find solutions to is the desertification 
leading to loss of livelihoods poverty and forced migration. The project is implemented at 3 sites in northern and central Somalia with the FSN&apos;s four partners in Finland and three partners in Somalia. The innovative cooperative model enforces the civil so
ciety in Somalia and creates new networks promoting in that way peace and stability. As an environmental project it promotes also climate sustainability.The long-term objective is the secured livelihood of the communities and the restored vegetation cover 
in the project areas. The project has been planned for 10 years (1 + 3x3 y) and this continuous project will be the second 3-year phase. The immediate objectives of the next phase are:1. Soil and water conservation enhanced2. Pressure on natural vegetation
 decreased3. Existing environmental centers developed into regional hubs4. Collaboration and partnerships between local national and international actors in environmental sector strengthenedThe beneficiaries include the partner NGOs 1500 households communi
ty members farmers and women participating in trainings regional administrations school children and teachers. The final beneficiaries are the local communities at large that benefit from the rising awareness on environmental issues and finally from the be
tter condition of the environment which will improve their livelihood in general. The project promotes gender equality by enabling the participation of women in the trainings and activities. The poorest people in poor fragile states feel the negative impac
ts of climate change most severely. By finding sustainable solutions to the environment problems and by helping people to adapt to the climate change the project thus reduces inequality considerably. The reduction of inequality is also taken into considera
tion by enabling local minority groups who are sometimes discriminated to participate in the trainings and to benefit from the project?s results. The main activities include tree seedling production and tree product development agroforestry practices water
 harvesting energy saving stove promotion trainings and facilitation of the environmental policy development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-345" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish Somalia Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="27311701" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-11-09" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="41030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">136000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">136000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
