<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2010100609</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Community Development and Capacity Building Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of the programme is the partners&apos; improved project management and community development by quality project execution. his is an ongoing project that was developed in order to help increase Fida International development programme&apos;s impact among its
 existing local partners. Due to programme&apos;s increased invitations by partner organisations to have training on Community Health Education (CHE), Financial and Project Management and Thematic issues, the nature of programme has changed to contain more wide
 topics and audience, hence there is a need to define the program with wider concept. The Community Development + Capacity Building Programme will be used as training platform for its components during the planning and implementing phase. This project has 
four main components in India. The components would be empowered with tools and knowhow to see about the establishment of community training approach and skills, Financial Management and Thematic Training. The local components and Fida International both e
xpressed the need for capacity building of components, which will help to increase components knowledge, tools and knowhow. Our aim is to see the successful implementation of capacity building of components, which will directly improve the impact of the co
mponents in the communities. The impact is expected to cover all the components of Fida funded development cooperation projects, and even beyond. The partners as organisations will be benefited by increased quality and quantity in their social work. That i
s lifting partners&apos; reputation in the civil society. The legal status of the partners will increase and become stronger which will help them in the self-funding process. The partners as a whole will improve their financial management as a result it will he
lp them in getting the needed registrations to maintain the legal status. Partners will get the proper, contextualized teaching tools. Provided training on how to use will improve partner&apos;s skills what will directly improve their work. Their impact in comm
unity will increase. Community skills will be also improved what will increase community work. As a natural result it will lead to better life. Thematic Training will focus on people with disabilities, HIV/AIDS issues etc. which will uplift the community a
s a whole. The project plans to mainstream HIV/AIDS and people living with disabilities. The project is not discriminating anyone; it is including children in its activities. It is encouraging the partners to have Children CHE&apos;s. Improved capacity of the p
artners towards quality holistic community development to create transformational impact in the targeted communities. This is a regional capacity building project, which enables Fida&apos;s partners to become capable to implement and manage the development assi
stance in their local areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Fida International ry</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fida International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2014-2010100609" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="243066" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">176524</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2014-2010100609" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
