<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014140910</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">VoRAE/After school support to RAE children and creation of employment opportunities for RAE youth</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operational in Kosovo since 1998 Voice of Roma Ashkali and Egyptians NGO (www.vorae.org) (until 2011 Office in Kosovo of the International NGO Voice of Roma) has initially been providing humanitarian assistance and humanitarian transport to the Roma commun
ity. The mandate of the Office has changed parallel with changes in society. The Organisation switched its focus to education employment and improvement of infrastructure in Roma settlements. All social and economic indicators clearly highlight the deplora
ble living conditions of Roma Ashkali and Egyptians in Kosovo. They face multiple discrimination extreme poverty and exclusion and remain one of the most vulnerable minorities in Kosovo.During the previous phase VoRAE have introduced and made experiences w
ith pre-school and after-school classes intervention tools. Offering homework assistance to 800 children per year in 15 (fifteen) different locations made it obvious that these interventions are effective and shall be continued and replicated. The project 
targets the following result: further increase of registration of children in pre-school and primary school, further decrease of drop-out of children from school, further increase of quality of education of children in school, further increase of mobilizat
ion of parents, Concerning employment and education the reality shows that self employment is often the only realistic option for Roma to generate income as the readiness of public and private companies to hire them as employees is still very limited or ju
st not existent. The project expects the following results: increase of capacities of RAE through professional training, creation of job opportunities thorough advocacy and lobbying for employment in public/private companies or self-employment. Beneficiari
es of the project are:-1?000 Roma children 5-18 years benefiting from supplementary educational support,-2?000 children form regular schools benefiting from joint intercultural activities,-50 RAE individuals provided with technical assistance and professio
nal trainings,-15 RAE individuals employed by private/public institutions companies, etcThe project is co-funded with HEKS Foundation (Swiss Development Cooperation)The overall objective of the project is to improve the level of participation in education 
for RAE in Kosovo as well as to increase their employment possibilities while contributing to better social inclusion of RAE in Kosovo.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11000" ref="11000-1" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="89201525" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-21" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="RS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">9955</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
