<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014141013</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CIVICUS, The Big Development DataShift</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Big Development DataShift is an ambitious multi-stakeholder initiative to leverage the potential of new technologies for more creative and effective social accountability. It brings citizen voice to the heart of sustainable development by building a co
mmunity of people and resources prepared to harness the data revolution. It is a movement and a tool to monitor and shape progress on the new global development agenda by Promoting People-Powered Accountability.What Civicus Is Doing: Truly sustainable deve
lopment requires a paradigm shift ? one in which citizens have a voice. The Big Development DataShift is a bold project to create a new system of monitoring and shaping development progress by Promoting People-Powered Accountability.How Civicus Is Doing It
: New technologies present remarkable opportunities to democratise how information about development is collected curated and used. The Big Development DataShift will harness this potential by enhancing coverage of citizen reporting empowering comparabilit
y of data emancipating tools for campaigning and Promoting People-Powered Accountability.What Civicus Wants To Achieve: The Big Development DataShift seeks to change the global development arena. It is a bottom up approach designed to put citizens at the c
entre of the development agenda from 2016 and beyond. This journey toward a more people-centred and planet-sensitive world starts with Promoting People-Powered Accountability.This Big Development DataShift is led by CIVICUS the global civil society allianc
e and supported by technical advice from the engine room. As an initiative with global significance the project concept was launched at the High Level Meeting of the Global Partnership for Effective Development Cooperation (GPEDC) in Mexico City in April 2
014. Over the next two years CIVICUS will work with members and partners from across the globe to deliver on the vision and potential of the DataShift. By 2016 and the next High Level Meeting of the GPEDC  the DataShift will be a broad movement to empower 
citizen monitoring in development and a set of new tools for promoting people-powered accountability at the local and global levels.The primary beneficiaries of the Big Development DataShift will be the civil society organisations in developing countries a
round the world.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="21000" ref="21000-4" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other INGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="89892442" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-06-27" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PP3 is primary priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">400000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
