<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2014141206</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Strengthening community forestry organisations&apos; governance in Peten</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at strengthening the capacity of ACOFOP&apos;s member organisations to prevent and control forest fires in the community forestry areas managed by them within the Maya Biosphere Reserve in Peten, Guatemala. The organisations possess a basic cap
acity to prevent and control the fires, whereas the threat of forest fires has increased during the past two years in some of the areas managed by them due to illegal activity. Hence special measures and additional equipment is needed. The state of Guatema
la has granted community based forest management concessions for the Multiple Use Zone of the Maya Biosphere Reserve in order for the local communities to be committed to governing the natural resources of the Reserve. This model, which has been recognised
 for its environmental, social and economic achievements respects local peasants&apos; and indigenous peoples&apos; historic rights to govern their territories. The communities are granted the right to make use of the timber and non-timber forest products, as well a
s community tourism as long as they respect the sustainable forest management plans. At places agroecological subsistence farming is also permitted. Along the community forestry process cutting forests for agricultural purposes and human settlements, as we
ll as forest fires have drastically reduced. ACOFOP is an umbrella organisation of community forestry organisations in Peten, Guatemala. It was founded in 1994. Its community based member organisations manage forests in the Multiple Use Zone of the Mayan B
iosphere Reserve within forestry concessions admitted by the government. Forest management by the communities themselves strengthens their ownership of the area, and supports the protection of the most significant Mayan forest area. ACOFOP&#x2019;s role in rela
tion to its members is to support the implementation of the natural resources management model, guarantee dialogue between the community organisations, represent them and advocate for their interests.ACOFOP&#x2019;s mission is to consolidate its integrated mode
l of natural resource management, which has proven to be a successful strategy to protect the environment, reduce poverty and improve the quality of life within the communities. ACOFOP&#x2019;s objectives in relation to sustainable community forest management a
re: i) to strengthen the democratic leadership of the community organisations, ii) advocacy in order for the community forestry agenda to be included in the larger development agenda of Peten, iii) adjustment of the community forestry company to respond to
 its members&#x2019; needs, iv) more profound processes of the integrated natural resource governance and further diversification of income generation, v) strengthening of ACOFOP&#x2019;s capacity to analyse the context in Peten and vi) making sure that outside tech
nical assistance results in local capacity development.  acofop.org</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Siemenpuu - Kansalaisliikkeiden yhteisty&#xF6;s&#xE4;&#xE4;ti&#xF6; sr</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Siemenpuu Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2014-2014141206" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="GT" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="41030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="243066" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">4000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">3979</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2014-2014141206" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
