<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2006060145</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sinsibere ? Combating desertification with women?s sustainable livelihoods</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Sinsibere project supports the women in rural communities South of Bamako to develop their resilience to climate change and to protect their environment. This is done by supporting alternative sources of income to the firewood trade that accelerates de
sertification. The last phase of the project concentrates on ensuring the permanence of project impacts by 1. reinforcing the economic viability of the women?s cooperative  2. strenghtening the tree protection spirit and tree planting possibilities in the 
project area. The direct beneficiaries are 300 women who are the members of the Sinsibere cooperative based in Bougoula village. The members of the cooperative form a board which coordinates the production activities. Cooperative activities empowers the wo
men to work as active members of their communities. From a human rights perspective the Sinsibere project enhances women&apos;s right to income by supporting the cooperative as an environment which enables women to actively work and network to achieve this righ
t. In the project the livelihoods are generated by sustainable use of natural resources and  women&apos;s right to income is understood to require the women&apos;s  responsibility of the cooperative activities.The project objectives are reached bya) improving the co
operative?s central actors? economic administration skills with education and by learning by doing supported with project workers.b) raising the amount of shea butter produced by guaranteeing access to a larger amount of nuts. Nut storage trainings in the 
project villages will give the women who collect nuts abilities for better processing and also increases the availability of nuts for the cooperative. The price of nuts is monitored and the nut collectors will be offered a competitive fee.c) diversifying t
he income sources of the cooperative by chicken and sheep growing and by reinforcing the previously started henna and peanut farming.d) involving the members of the cooperative more closely in the activities by improving the economic benefits by strengthen
ing the board members? ability the monitor the cooperative?s revenue and expenditure by organizing inclusive annual meetings networking opportunities and forums for cooperative members.e) establishing a shea tree nursery and plantationf) providing support 
for the cooperative members to initiative action in influencing tree protection in the area.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Dodo ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2006-11-07" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ML" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="43040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">45044</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">45044</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
