<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2015-2015150061</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Team of Experts on Sexual Violence in Conflicts Project in South Sudan phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The UN Team of Experts on Rule of Law/Sexual Violence in Conflict is a body created to assist governments in conflict and post-conflict situations to address impunity for sexual violence. The mandate of the Team of Experts is focused on supporting local in
stitutions to address such crimes and it works in close cooperation with other UN organizations. In this project the Team of Experts provides technical assistance to the Sudan People&apos;s Liberation Movement/Army in Opposition (SPLM/SPLA-IO) to implement an a
ction plan to prevent sexual violence. In December 2014 the Chairperson of the SPLM/SPLA-IO signed a Communique to commit to a range of activities to address conflict-related sexual violence in the activities of the movement and the army and to request sup
port from the UN to assist in taking forward the Communique. The Team of Experts has already started with Finland&apos;s financial support a project to assist South Sudan&apos;s government in the prevention of sexual violence in the building of national capacity and
 in the helping of victims of sexual violence. This project is directly linked to said project. In this project phase technical assistance is provided to  the SPLM/SPLA-IO. To ensure a holistic response to the problems faced in South Sudan it is important 
to engage with the different parties of the conflict. Activities include organizing workshops and trainings developing command orders and disseminating knowledge within the SPLM/SPLA-IO as well as establishing a special investigation unit within the Milita
ry Justice Directorate. Finland&apos;s contribution focuses specifically on activities relating to the fight impunity for sexual and gender-based violence not on the training of military forces. The project supports Finland&apos;s priorities relating to development 
cooperation and human rights as it contributes to the enhancement of the rule of law the fight against impunity and reduction of inequality. South Sudan is a fragile state in which sexual violence is a serious threat to human rights and peace. The project 
is implemented by the end of 2016 with Finnish support amounting to EUR 150000.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-24" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">150000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">150000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">150000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
