<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-011388-02-0</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH for an Inclusive and Sustainable Development of the Population of the Provinces of Herat, Farah, Ghor and Bamyan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">L&apos;obiettivo generale dell&apos;intervento &#xE8; quello di migliorare le condizioni di salute e il benessere generale della popolazione nelle aree target e di ridurre le discriminazioni di genere. L&apos;obiettivo specifico del progetto &#xE8; quello di ridurre la mortalit&#xE0; infantile degli under5, i casi di diarrea grave, i casi di malattie correlate all&apos;uso acqua non potabile, alla mancanza di gabinetti e ai comportamenti non igienici e la discriminazione di genere nelle aree target</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project aims at increasing access to clean water, sanitation and adequate health education among the population, in schools and health facilities, in the provinces of Herat, Farah and Ghor and Bamyan in the Western and Central Highlands regions of Afghanistan. The project will achieve a reduction in child mortality in cases of severe diarrhea and gender discrimination. The Project will be implemented in 240 community (60 in each province) benefiting directly 35,000 households for a total of 210,000 direct beneficiaries, of which 45 female, disabled, nomads, returnees and IDP (Internally Displaced People). The initiative will be executed by the Afghan Government and implemented by the Rural Water, Sanitation and Irrigation Program (RU-WatSIP) of the Ministry of Rehabilitation and Rural Development (MRRD). The project has the overall objective of enhancing the health conditions and general welfare of the population in the target area. The specific objective is to reduce under5 child mortality, cases of severe diarrhea, cases of disease related to unsafe water, unsafe human excreta disposal and unhygienic behaviors, and gender discrimination in the target areas. The following are the expected results: R1. RU-WatSIP, and other WASH Actors&apos; capacity to plan, coordinate, deliver, monitoring and evaluate community WASH projects to address unsafe water, unsafe human excreta disposal and unhygienic behaviors related diseases increases R. 2 Demand for WASH project (Water sanitation and Hygiene) by the target population to address unsafe water, unsafe human excreta disposal and unhygienic behaviors related diseases increases R.3 . Under5 child mortality, cases of severe diarrhea, cases of disease related to unsafe water, unsafe human excreta disposal, unhygienic behaviors, and gender discrimination in the target areas decreased.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11001" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11001" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="011388/02/0" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2019000080" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BASIC DRINKING WATER SUPPLY AND BASIC SANITATION</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14081" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EDUCATION AND TRAINING IN WATER SUPPLY AND SANITATION</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="40" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WATER SECTOR POLICY AND ADMINISTRATIVE MANAGEMENT</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="6.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, achieve universal and equitable access to safe and affordable drinking water for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end preventable deaths of newborns and children under 5&#xA0;years of age, with all countries aiming to reduce neonatal mortality to at least as low as 12 per 1,000 live births and under&#x2011;5 mortality to at least as low as 25 per 1,000 live births</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, reduce the global maternal mortality ratio to less than 70 per 100,000 live births</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-21">225000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2017</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-011388-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
