<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-MYA228</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care and support for Human Rights Defenders in Myanmar</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The coup led by the Myanmar Military (Tamadaw) directed by Min Aung Hlaing on February 1st cut with the transition period that started in 2010 and that had brought the National League for Democracy to power in 2015 after general elections were conducted. The people in Myanmar have not accepted neither remain submissive to the military coup and the actions taken by the Tamadaw. Since the first week of February several numbers of actions have been coordinated by different organizations and individuals seeking to express their dissatisfaction with the current situation and to demand the military to step down of government. Human Rights defenders have been active mobilizing the communities and expressing disagreement against the dictatorship. Most of them leading the advocacy efforts at community level to raise awareness and denounce abuses perpetrated by security forces. 
In this sense, SEM aims to support and assist Human Rights defenders in order to strengthen community resilience and a long term strategic engagement for development and peace in Myanmar. In this project SEM expects to identify and provide required assistance to HR defenders as well as to ensure they can build sustainability and foster advocacy for dignity and justice in Myanmar. SEM team will build on an assessment and design phase to make sure of what is the most appropriate way to support and to fulfil needs of the people and movements on the ground. This will be done through their existing network of CSOs and CBOs across the country as well as religious leaders, teachers, activists and other social actors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="MYA228" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="MYA228" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spirit in Education Movement</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="MYA228" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="80" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-01">11628</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54811">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-11">11628</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
