<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RURALBANIA Initiative to support and promote traditional agricultural  productions for the sustainable development of Albanian rural  areas</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RURALBANIA aims to support and promote traditional agricultural productionsfor the sustainable development 
of Albanian rural areas.
The action supports the Albanian authorities and civil society to implement the Agenda 2030, concerning SDG 
2 and the promotion of sustainable agriculture (Target 2.3). In this sense, the Project also supports Albania&apos;s 
accession path to the EU, of which adaptation to the CAP represents a fundamental element. Albanian territory is mainly mountainous, and over 40% of its surface is used for agriculture, one of the most 
important economic sector in the country (23% of GDP) and source of income for the majority of the population. 
Agricultural production has increased significantly over the past decade. However, low productivity remains an 
obstacle to sustainable growth, as Albania still imports a significant amount of agri-food products. Of the 
approximately 350,000 farms present, 86% are small producers with less than 2 hectares of available land. The 
available macro-economic indicators indicate the remote areas of the North as the most backward of the 
country.
Therefore, the action has the objective of increasing the productivity of family-run farms operating in high potential value chains in disadvantaged mountain areas of Northern Albania.
The increase in productivity is achieved by guaranteeing access opportunities for small agricultural producers 
to 3 elements, the cornerstones of the intervention strategy:
&#x2756; effective agricultural and rural assistance services
&#x2756; qualified professional training in agricultural production
&#x2756; concrete and sustainable assets for production and sales
In the medium to long term, the action combines an increase in productivity with a rise in disposable income. 
The new resources will lead small producers to further investment in their farms and, hopefully, an increase in 
their size. An increased income will correspond, at the socio-economic level, to a reduction in farmers living 
below the poverty line.
The action, lasting 3 years, focuses on adjoining and homogeneous mountain areas of North-Eastern Albania 
and limited production chains, intending to maximize the socio-economic impact on target communities:
&#x27A2; Eastern region of Shkodra: beekeeping, small mountain fruits
&#x27A2; Kukes region: sheep and goat farming
&#x27A2; Dibra region: fruit trees
The Project supports the action of the following public and private actors involved in the development of the 
target territories:
Agricultural trade associations
Regional Public Agencies for Agricultural Extension
Smallholders and family farms
Municipalities
Privileged support is guaranteed to farms managed by women, young people, and returning migrants, 
identified as strategic actors for the sustainable development of rural societies. Furthermore, specific support 
measures are envisaged for farms active in rural tourism, a category particularly affected by the crisis generated 
by Covid-19.
The partnership represents the great added value of the Initiative and rests on 3 pillars:
1) Previous experience of collaboration in Albania between the adhering actors;
2) Enhancement of cooperation between private and public actors;
3) Expertise of the actors involved in the specific area of action and the tasks entrusted to them. It is structured as follows:
&#x25AA; Volontari nel Mondo RTM, an NGO with twenty years of experience in rural development programs in 
the Western Balkans and with its Albanian office in Shkoder, guarantees the coordination of the Project;
&#x25AA; CIA - Agricoltori Italiani, one of the largest trade organizations in Italy and Europe, is in charge of 
capacity building actions in favour of local actors in the field of agricultural assistance centres and 
professional training in agriculture;
&#x25AA; RER - Emilia Romagna Region, international excellence in the enhancement of typical agri-food 
productions, takes care of the capacity building of Albanian public and private actors in the field of 
geographical quality</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">RURALBANIA &#xE8; un&#x2019;iniziativa di sostegno e promozione di produzioni agricole tradizionali per lo sviluppo 
sostenibile delle aree rurali albanesi.
L&#x2019;Intervento sostiene le autorit&#xE0; e la societ&#xE0; civile albanese nell&#x2019;attuazione dell&#x2019;Agenda 2030, con riferimento 
all&#x2019;OSS n.2 e alla promozione di un&#x2019;agricoltura sostenibile (Target 2.3). 
In tal senso, il Progetto supporta anche il percorso di adesione dell&#x2019;Albania all&#x2019;UE, di cui l&#x2019;adeguamento alla PAC
rappresenta un tassello fondamentale.
Il territorio albanese &#xE8; prevalentemente montuoso e oltre il 40% della sua superficie &#xE8; utilizzata per 
l&apos;agricoltura, uno tra i pi&#xF9; importanti settori economici del Paese (23% del PIL) e fonte di reddito per la 
maggioranza della popolazione. La produzione agricola &#xE8; aumentata significativamente nell&apos;ultimo decennio. 
Tuttavia, la bassa produttivit&#xE0; rimane un ostacolo per una crescita sostenibile, visto che l&apos;Albania importa 
ancora quantit&#xE0; significative di prodotti agro-alimentari. Delle circa 350.000 aziende agricole presenti, l&#x2019;86% &#xE8; 
rappresentato da piccoli produttori con meno di 2 ettari disponibili. Gli indicatori macro-economici disponibili 
indicano le zone remote del Nord come le aree pi&#xF9; arretrate del Paese.
L&#x2019;Intervento si pone, pertanto, l&#x2019;obiettivo di aumentare la produttivit&#xE0; e il valore aggiunto conseguito dalle
aziende agricole a conduzione familiare operanti in filiere ad alto potenziale in aree montane svantaggiate del
Nord Albania. 
L&#x2019;aumento della produttivit&#xE0; viene raggiunto garantendo opportunit&#xE0; di accesso per i piccoli produttori agricoli
a 3 elementi, perni della strategia d&#x2019;intervento:
&#x2756; servizi efficaci di assistenza agricola e rurale
&#x2756; formazione professionale qualificata sulle produzioni agricole
&#x2756; asset concreti e sostenibili per la produzione e la vendita
Nel medio-lungo termine l&#x2019;Intervento &#xE8; concepito per associare a un aumento della produttivit&#xE0; anche un
aumento del reddito disponibile. Le nuove risorse condurranno i piccoli produttori a ulteriori investimenti nelle 
proprie aziende e auspicabilmente a una crescita della dimensione delle stesse. A livello socio-economico, a un 
aumento del reddito corrisponder&#xE0; una riduzione degli agricoltori che vive al di sotto della soglia di povert&#xE0;.
L&#x2019;Intervento, di durata triennale, si concentra su aree montane confinanti ed omogenee dell&#x2019;Albania 
nordorientale e su filiere produttive circoscritte, al fine di massimizzare l&#x2019;impatto socio-economico sulle 
comunit&#xE0; interessate:
&#x27A2; Regione orientale di Scutari: apicoltura, piccoli frutti di montagna
&#x27A2; Regione di Kukes: allevamento ovicaprino
&#x27A2; Regione di Dibra: alberi da frutto Il Progetto sostiene l&#x2019;azione dei seguenti attori pubblici e privati impegnati nello sviluppo dei territori target: 
Associazioni agricole di categoria
Piccole aziende agricole di produzione e trasformazione
Agenzie Pubbliche Regionali per l&#x2019;Assistenza Agricola
Municipalit&#xE0;
Viene garantito un supporto privilegiato ad aziende agricole gestite da donne, giovani e migranti di ritorno, 
identificati come attori strategici per lo sviluppo sostenibile delle societ&#xE0; rurali.
Sono previste, inoltre, misure specifiche di supporto alle aziende agricole attive nel turismo rurale, categoria 
particolarmente colpita dalla crisi generata da Covid-19. 
Il partenariato rappresenta il grande valore aggiunto dell&#x2019;Iniziativa e si fonda su 3 pilastri: 
1) Esperienza pregressa di collaborazione in Albania tra gli attori aderenti;
2) Valorizzazione della cooperazione tra attori privati e pubblici; 
3) Expertise degli attori coinvolti nel settore specifico d&#x2019;intervento e nelle mansioni ad essi affidate.
Esso si articola nel seguente modo:
&#x25AA; Volontari nel Mondo RTM, ONG con ventennale esperienza in programmi di sviluppo rurale nei Balcani 
Occidentali e una propria sede in loco a Scutari, garantisce il coordinamento del Progetto;
&#x25AA; CIA - Agricoltori Italiani, una delle maggiori organizzazioni di categoria in Italia e in Europa</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">REGGIO TERZO MONDO ONLUS ONG</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/03/6" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="31181" percentage="18" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural education/training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31166" percentage="35" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural extension</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31150" percentage="47" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural inputs</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, double the agricultural productivity and incomes of small-scale food producers, in particular women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers, including through secure and equal access to land, other productive resources and inputs, knowledge, financial services, markets and opportunities for value addition and non-farm employment</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-09">1800000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">REGGIO TERZO MONDO ONLUS ONG</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-20">1080000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">REGGIO TERZO MONDO ONLUS ONG</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
