<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-17/DDA-3474/1st Standard Allocation 2017/H/NGO/6028</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Responding to the critical  live saving primary health care needs of returning IDPs in return areas of North Waziristan Agency FATA.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHEF International conducted a rapid assessment and on the basis of secondary data and prior assessments done with the consent of Agency surgeon Office in North Waziristan Agency, the immediate health needs of the returning IDPs communities were identified and on the basis of which project intervention were designed to provide quality and timely Primary health care services to vulnerable men, women, boy, girl, elder people and person with disability with dignity and participation. 5 areas for intervention were selected due to non-availability of critical life-saving health services at primary level making returning community more vulnerable. Three identified 5 non-functional health facilities, 2 BHU&#x2019;s (BHU Nowal Kot, BHU Gharioum) and 3 Civil Dispensaries (CD Hussain Ahmed, CD Haji Zarkum kot, CHC Said Ali shah) in Tehsil Razmak. Currently these BHU&#x2019;s buildings need repair amp maintenance and are highly non accessible physically for elderly women, men and Person with disabilities. The services proposed will be provided in parallel to necessary repair and physical accessibility work in BHUs. In identified BHU&#x2019;s catchment area, the revitalized health facilities will provide treatment to the patients from the affected population on prevailing health conditions such as diarrhea, dysentery, fever, cough and cold (air borne and water borne diseases), other communicable and non-communicable diseases, provision of Antenatal and postnatal care, safe delivery, immunization and health and hygiene awareness and education. The Human resource in each health facility will comprise of 1 Doctor (Only in BHU), 1 LHV, 1 Medical Technician,1 guard and 1 support staff, while 2 Psychosocial counselors and 1 Pharmacist support will be available on rotation basis. Primary health care medicine including MNCH, RH medicines and supplies will be procured and provided in OPD. Besides this, to reach the unreachable community, medical camps will be held on need basis (1 camp every week). Strong referral mechanism will be established from community to first level care facility (FLCF) amp from FLCF to secondary or tertiary level care facility by ensuring dedicated ambulance service. The Women and family members will receive counseling services and psycho-social support. For Person with disabilities the accessibility will be ensured and their data will be recorded and will be provided assistance and referral. The LHV&#x2019;s will provide awareness session in OPD on Birth preparedness and prevention of complications. The staff will be trained amp training material will be provided on antenatal and postnatal care, safe delivery, immunization, use of modern methods of contraceptives, early detection amp prevention of childhood disabilities, efficient referral mechanism and disease reporting (DEWS). Training will be provided to TBAs on Nutritional support (including iron and folate supplements), Prenatal recognition of danger signs and treatment or referral as needed, Clean delivery (hand-washing, clean space, clean cord care) and efficient use of safe delivery kits further enabling them to play vital role in reducing morbidity and mortality rate (MMR and IMR) in the areas of intervention. Health Advisory Committees will be formed to Initiate community mobilization for each health facility with membership from 8 to 10 in the catchment area of the selected health facilities. The HAC members will be trained on record keeping, their role in project implementation and monitoring, brief orientation of PHC and MNCH services and will provide social support to the health facilities. 288 health sessions will be provided to community by social mobilizers/Hygiene Promoter (with average of 10 to 15 participants in one session) to men and women separately and culturally appropriate manner to educate them about best hygiene practices i.e. personal and environment hygiene for their own safe health and protect them from common communicable and water borne diseases.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive Health and Education Forum International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive Health and Education Forum International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sohail Ayaz Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cheif Executive Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0092-3038886666</telephone>
   <email>sohail@chef.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK4">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fata</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.18320000 70.41980000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-09">241427.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-09">258570.48</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-04">1.64</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive Health and Education Forum International</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-6028">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-09">499998.16</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive Health and Education Forum International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302834207">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-15">299998.9</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive Health and Education Forum International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303160007">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-31">199999.26</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive Health and Education Forum International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
