<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-17/DDA-3474/1st Standard Allocation 2017/N/UN/6044</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Ready to Use Supplementary Food (RUSF) commodities to support life-saving nutrition services for moderately acute malnourished (MAM) girls and boys (6-59 months) and pregnant  lactating women (PLW) in Orakzai and North Waziristan agencies of FATA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to UN-OCHA return updates (Dec-2016), a total of 284,374 IDPs families returned during the year 2016 including 15% from North Waziristan (41,566) and 5% from Orakzai (14,471) agencies. 
Considering the emergency nutrition needs in the areas of return, WFP proposes for urgent ERF support for NWA and Orakzai. The overall objective of the proposed project is to ensure improved and equitable access to life saving nutritional services for moderately malnourished (MAM) girls and boys (06-59months) and pregnantamp lactating women that meet national and internationally recommended minimum standard of care for a population affected by an emergency.

The proposed interventions are in line with Strategic Objective (SO1) of Pakistan Humanitarian Strategic Plan (HSP, 2017) i.e. &#x201C;To Support the humanitarian and protection needs of IDPs that remain displaced and those that have returned, ensuring a smooth transition to longer-term recovery and development&#x201D;. Particular focus is given to the areas of return within North Waziristan (NWA) and Orakzai Agencies of FATA. In case of access and NOC challenges, WFP is requesting flexibility for distribution of food commodities under the proposed funding for other priority areas of FATA and IDPs hosting districts of KP in consultation with nutrition cluster and OCHA. Furthermore, in case of NOC challenges for the PHPF NGO partners, WFP is proposing for delivery of nutrition services through the department of health staff in FATA. With the proposed PHPF funding support, World Food Programme will purchase and distribute specialized, Ready to use supplementary food (RUSF AchaMum and Maamta) to support the operations of life-saving nutrition services for moderately malnourished girls amp boys (6-59 months) and Pregnant amp Lactating Women, through the NGO partners. In addition to direct benefits for MAM girls, boys and malnourished PLW, the interventions will indirectly benefit the women of child bearing age through community and health facilities based education on benefits of improved Maternal Infant and Young child nutrition practices (MIYCN). The MIYCN approach doesn&#x2019;t entitle any food support and is based on context specific behavior change communication approaches to improve awareness level of the women to improve maternal and young child feeding practices, complimenting UNICEF&#x2019;s MIYCN activities through timely referrals and consultations. 
 
WFP nutrition services remained functional in NWA with WFP funding support through a national NGO till end May 2017, with significant agency level capacity to start-up the activities with PHPF funding support on urgent basis. Similarly, nutrition services remain functional in the Orakzai agency in collaboration with the Department of Health FATA and the National program for Lady health workers. LHWs from Orakzai agency are already trained on TSFP nutrition services. Coordination mechanism is in place for Orakzai agency with active role of agency coordinators and project management unit FATA. These existing functional coordination structures and delivery platforms will facilitate the timely and smooth kick start of the PHPF support activities. 

The proposed PHPF funding support will directly benefit 2,704 moderately acute malnourished girls and boys (boys: 1,409, girls: 1,295) and 2,631 pregnant and lactating women over the next 12 months through timely provision of 71.7 MT (AchaMum: 24.34 and Maamta: 47.36) locally produced lipid based nutrition supplements. For timeliness WFP may allocate the required ready to use supplementary food from other areas of FATA or KP and will replenish the resources with PHPF funding accordingly.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-29" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Amin Ahsan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Finance  Budget Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+92 51 8312232</telephone>
   <email>Amin.Ahsan@wfp.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KP  FATA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Officer Nutrition</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>Ijaz.habib@wfp.org</telephone>
   <email>Dr Ijaz habib</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>Tahir Nawaz</telephone>
   <email>Islamabad</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cecilia GARZON</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Nutrition</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0345 8560175</telephone>
   <email>cecilia.garzon@wfp.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK4">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fata</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.18320000 70.41980000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-08">117288.67</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-08-29"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-08">132706.9</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-6044">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-08">249995.57</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302894945">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-20">249995.57</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
