<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-CVR-20074035-LotHUM_Syria</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DK-CVR-20074035" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADRA Danmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vulnerable Communities Live in Dignity in Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of ADRA Denmark&#x2019;s intervention in Syria is that vulnerable communities in Rural Damascus, Quinetra, Homs and Aleppo employ positive coping strategies, are more self-reliant and live with increased dignity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="20000" ref="DK-CVR-20074035" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADRA Danmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="23000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADRA Syria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11000" ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Denmark - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="73010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The focus of the project is the rehabilitation of basic WASH services and education facilities in conflict-affected areas. There is also a small livelihoods component with a focus on economic rehabilitation.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="4">
   <budget-item code="CHANGE AREA 1: BASIC SERVICES ARE REHABILITATED INCLUDING SCHOOLS, WATER AND SEWAGE SYSTEMS IN AREAS DAMAGED BY CONFLICT OR FACING INCREASED PRESSURE DUE TO THE INFLUX OF IDPS" percentage="52" vocabulary="4"></budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2019-01-17">2950000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2019-01-01">3000000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2019-01-01">3000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Incoming Commitment Danish MFA 2018">
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2018-01-01">2950000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment under SPA Lot HUM 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="Denmark - Ministry of Foreign Affairs" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="DK-CVR-20074035-LotHUM_2017-12478-2" ref="ADRA Denmark" type="22"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Funds Transfer Syria Q1_18">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2018-02-23">1314418</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funds Transfer VCD Project Lot HUM</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="DK-CVR-20074035" ref="ADRA Danmark" type="22"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="ADRA Syria" type="22"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Funds Transfer Syria Q3_18">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2018-08-31">1086875.97</value>
   <provider-org ref="ADRA Danmark" type="22"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="ADRA Syria" type="22"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Funds Transfer Syria Q4_18">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2018-11-01">408442.49</value>
   <provider-org ref="ADRA Danmark" type="22"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="ADRA Syria" type="22"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Total Expenditure 2018">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2018-12-31">2899729</value>
   <provider-org ref="ADRA Syria" type="22"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall objective: Vulnerable communities in Homs employ positive coping strategies, are more self-reliant and live with increased dignity.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on identified needs, ADRA provided basic, yet essential, assistance to hose most vulnerable in newly-accessible and hard-to-reach areas of Homs. In addition, ADRA focused on re-establishing the livelihoods and wellbeing of targeted individuals, in order to strengthen the capacity of individuals as well as their communities. The areas targeted were selected based on high number of returning families, the level of damage to basic services, as well as the intensity of the conflict. Livelihood beneficiaries were mainly from areas where there was a flourishing market which was halted or damaged due to the conflict or where many families were returning and needed to re-start their income generating activities. In this manner, ADRA aimed to create effective resilience and meet the needs of the affected population. Through the VCD project, ADRA in 2018 impacted a total of 14,186 individuals across the Homs governorate.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of beneficiaries interviewed in target areas report having access to basic services (health / education / water / sanitation)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-01-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="75"></target>
     <actual value="93"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of livelihood beneficiaries reporting a reduction in negative coping strategies</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-01-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="75"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Change Area 2: Vulnerable communities engage in sustainable livelihood strategies and move towards early recovery</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Syrian conflict has had a significant impact on the economic situation of the country. Since the onset of the conflict the level of poverty has increased due to loss of livelihoods, unemployment, loss of assets and/or recurring displacement. At least 85% of the population has fallen into poverty and 65% into extreme poverty (WFP, 2018). The livelihood component of the VCD project was designed to protect and restore livelihoods for the conflict-affected individuals in Homs, by re-establishing their businesses and jobs and strengthening their resilience. Those selected participated in pre-intervention surveys in order to assess the impact of the livelihood grants on their wellbeing and to measure a reduction in negative coping mechanisms. It was learned that before the intervention, 60% of the participants borrowed money from a family member or friend, 26% relied on assistance from humanitarian organizations, and 14% had moved in with a family member or friend to save money. A post-intervention survey was done following the completion of the project in order to assess the effects of the project and it was found that beneficiaries believed the intervention was sustainable as the grant covered the start-up costs (28% of responders), they improved their self-confidence and independence (28% of responders), job opportunities increased, products were diversified, and assets restored (11-14% of responders). Beneficiary evaluations have thus far indicated that the training was very practical and useful in improving and raising their capacity in business management and that the training also provided them with a means to be independent.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of individuals benefiting from improved income (including household members of direct beneficiaries)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention focused on selecting beneficiaries who had lost their businesses and, with business training, would be able to re-establish and grow their livelihood. After a thorough assessment process, a total of 90 individuals were selected and trained in small-business management. By the end of the training, each participant presented a business plan with a list of material requirements out of which 57 individuals (35 males, 22 females) were selected for livelihood grants to help establish their businesses. Selection was based on the presentation of a good proposal, business plan and commitment demonstrated throughout the training.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-01-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="250"></target>
     <actual value="256"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of beneficiaries reporting improvements in income as a result of project activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The provision of business training and in-kind grants to the livelihood beneficiaries contributed to increasing their capacity in business management, building of resilience and improvement of family income. The initial target for the livelihood activity was to train 50 individuals in business management and to provide 50 in-kind grants. ADRA exceeded the target by training 90 individuals (45 females, 45 males) on entrepreneurship and business management. Participants reported that they felt empowered by the training as they were able to learn new skills and tools, which could help their businesses succeed. Upon successful completion of the training, 57 individuals (22 females, 35 males) were selected to receive in-kind grants to support the establishment of their businesses (including; confectionary, hairdressing, mechanics and carpentry). Through this activity, ADRA was able to turn business plans into real businesses, enhance the competencies of local communities in Homs, thus strengthening the market of the Governorate, and providing initial financial support without interfering with the independence of the individual. A total of 91% of households reported increased income.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-01-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="91"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Change Area 1: Basic services are rehabilitated including schools, water and sewerage systems in areas damaged by conflict or facing increased pressure due to the influx of IDPs.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of individuals accessing health care</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The majority of health facilities in Homs sustained significant damage to infrastructure, have a shortage in health are staff and limited medical supplies. The Shin Health Center was damaged during the conflict in Homs in 2013. The center remained open as it is the only health facility in the town of Shin, also serving the surrounding villages. However, families were unable to receive appropriate health are due to poor conditions, use of old medical supplies and the lack of a sanitary environment. To support the vulnerable community of Shin, ADRA rehabilitated the health facility, providing the population of 30,000 individuals with access to improved health care. Thus far, a total of 9,930 individuals have accessed the rehabilitated health facility. Upon completion, the Ministry of Health provided new medical equipment and supplies, enhancing the quality of service each patient will receive. The rehabilitation of the center is significant to the host community, IDPs and returnees, as they now have access to health services in a safe and improved environment. This intervention has also helped to re-establish the health system capacity of Homs, creating job opportunities, providing better quality medical services, and building resilience among the community. The VCD project has contributed significant improvements to the health care provided to the 30,000 inhabitants of Shin, Homs as well as those living in the surrounding villages. Individuals had limited access to health care and were served in poor environments. With the rehabilitation of the health facility, 9,930 individuals thus far have received health care in the rehabilitated center. In addition, the Shin health center is the only facility in the area and is therefore significant to the community. The capacity of local staff is enhanced as they deliver quality health services with new equipment delivered by the Directorate of Health (DoH).</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-01-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7000"></target>
     <actual value="9930"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of individuals benefiting from improved water and sewerage facilities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the VCD project, ADRA rehabilitated a main sewerage network in Shin, western rural Homs, which is one of the areas that was highly impacted by the conflict. The population (approximately 30,000 individuals) is comprised mostly of IDPs coming from surrounding towns and some from neighboring governorates. During assessments, it was learned that there was a pressing need to rehabilitate the main sewerage network as there was contamination of water sources by the waste water, resulting in waterborne diseases, sewage odor and the presence of roaches and rodents, negatively affecting the health and wellbeing of the population. The rehabilitation of the network improved access to safe and clean water for a total of 400 families (2,000 families). Thus far, the population of Shin has reported that there is significant improvement in the sanitation situation of their community. In addition, it is anticipated additional individuals will benefit from the intervention as the number of returnees increase. The rehabilitation of the sewerage network in Shin, Homs helped improve access to safe water and sanitation while also improving the hygiene and health of an estimated 2,000 individuals. Post-intervention interviews conducted with the beneficiaries revealed that there was improved sanitation in the community as the main sewerage network was functioning and residue sewage has been removed from the streets.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-01-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5000"></target>
     <actual value="2000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of boys and girls accessing formal education</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the aim of restoring education in Syria, ADRA conducted light rehabilitation of three schools (61 classrooms), allowing 2,940 children (1,655 boys and 1,285 girls) to continue learning in an improved and safer environment. Rehabilitation included repairs, provision of furniture, rehabilitation of WASH facilities, allowing for gender segregation, as well as access to safe and clean water, and provision of ramps to allow children with disabilities to access their school in a safe manner. With the rehabilitation of the schools, the number of students per classroom has been reduced as classrooms which were not previously used due to damaged infrastructure are now being utilized. This helped improve the quality of education provided to the children. Staff in targeted schools shared with ADRA that the rehabilitation made a big difference, not only in the building but in the psychosocial health of the children &#x2013; they show feelings of joy when coming to school, concentrate more and are optimistic about their future.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-01-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1500"></target>
     <actual value="2940"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
