<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-261488-ETA40WF</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-261488" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amref Health Africa - UK</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resilient Economy and Livelihood (REAL) Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amref&#x2019;s project in Wolaita Zone, SNNP Region, Ethiopia is to improve access to and use of integrated health services for communities who are vulnerable to drought, communicable diseases and malnutrition. The project&#x2019;s activities focus on improving sexual reproductive health and rights (SRHR), by improving quality of services and strengthening demand by young people, women and families. The full project is delivered by Amref Ethiopia and primarily funded by the European Commission (from 2017-2022); the Waterloo Foundation grant fulfils the co-funding need (Jan-Dec 2019), with technical support by Amref UK.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project outcomes are: 50% of households (12,500) are informed and positive about modern family planning options; 6,000 women of reproductive age utilise long acting family planning by the end of the project; 2,303 adolescents receive improved youth-friendly SRHR services by the end of the project; increase contraceptive prevalence in 25,000 households, from 68% to 80%.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This funding will support the project activities of: &#x2022; Training for health workers at 12 health centres on provision of LARCs to 2,500 women under 49, including implant and Intrauterine Contraceptive Device (IUCD/the &#x2018;coil&#x2019;) &#x2022; Support for outreach services at lower level health posts, through trained health workers to serve 1,300 LARCs users in communities &#x2022; Training for health workers in Basic Emergency Obstetric &amp; New born care (BEmONC) to serve 354 women of reproductive age, essential to support ongoing reproductive health &#x2022; Training for 18 health workers on provision of &#x2018;youth-friendly&#x2019; (age-appropriate and sensitive) SRHR services, to serve for 2,303 young people at health facilities &#x2022; Support for the establishment and strengthening of youth-friendly services in six health centres; the project will refurbish, design and maintain youth-friendly spaces &#x2022; Material support for eight maternity waiting rooms to promote SRHR services &#x2022; Support with establishing a revolving fund for medical equipment, consumable supplies (including LARCs) and medicines to health facilities. For example, new supplies of implants will prevent patients from having to be referred to other, distant health facilities &#x2022; Strengthening laboratory and diagnostic capacity for health facilities, including HIV testing and diagnosis of STIs &#x2022; Comprehensive Sexuality Education (CSE) for 500 school children in six schools &#x2022; Awareness raising campaign on sexual and reproductive health in targeted communities &#x2022; Support for HIV/AIDS clubs in schools, through materials and mentorship for young leaders. In addition to the activities above, the budget also includes funding towards M&amp;E.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amref Health Africa - Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-261488" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amref Health Africa - UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Waterloo Foudation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wolaita Zone</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>+6.54 37.45</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-01">98000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-14">98000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-04-30">91589</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-06-30">10583</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
