<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=GLO/15/11/NLD" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-105283-1170-2017-GLO603</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decent work in global supply chains</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of this project is to contribute to achieving decent work in GSCs through expanding and disseminating knowledge about strategies to improve working conditions as well as productivity and competitiveness in different sectors of the global economy. A three part strategy has been designed for achieving this outcome, which would enable the ILO to undertake preparatory work for the 2016 ILC general discussion that would otherwise not be carried out. First, a comparative analysis of social and economic upgrading in GSCs in selected economic sectors will be conducted. These could include i.a. electronics, mining, media and culture, financial services, textiles, commerce, agro-food, telecommunications, and/or transport. Several studies will be featured in boxes in the conference paper to inform the ILC discussion. This will give visibility to the results of this part of the project. While economic upgrading is important for decent work, it does not necessarily lead to improved working conditions for workers. The comparative analysis would therefore cover both economic and social upgrading, including issues such as social protection, working conditions, and living wages. Contrary to the studies funded by the Ministry of Social Affairs and Employment in the Netherlands, this comparative analysis would not be limited to showcasing good practices by multinational enterprises, but would also touch on government interventions . The proposed output will build knowledge regarding the social and the economic implications of supply chains within the context of the changing global economy. It would also highlight sector-specific risks and opportunities for a selected number of sectors. Second, an in-depth review of strategies that build on multiple, complementary approaches to achieving workplace compliance will be conducted. This would include reviews of the following: (a) governance frameworks; (b) various modalities of compliance; (c) the impact of trade policies as an incentive for compliance with international labour standards; (d) collaborative public-private labour inspection initiatives; and (e) roles and responsibilities of ILO&#x2019;s constituents, and, in addition, not ignoring the important role of global buyers. The mapping and assessment of strategies would contribute to making progress toward achieving decent work in global supply chains by highlighting good practices for governments, employers&#x2019; and workers&#x2019; organizations. The Sector Risk Analysis introduced by the Dutch Government as a tool to engage with Dutch companies in their efforts to manage their supply chains properly would also be considered under this output. The review will be shared with tripartite constituents for their information. Third, in the run-up to the International Labour Conference of 2016, consultations with tripartite constituents will be organized on decent work in global supply chains. A series of consultation workshops aimed at promoting common understanding of the key challenges for decent work in GSCs in the various regions will be organized for government officials from various ILO regions. The workshops could be organized in cooperation with Dutch Embassies, particularly those in development cooperation partner countries, and would contribute to joint work in the effective preparations for the ILC discussion. The workshops would align well with the policy priorities of the Dutch development cooperation, particularly the focus on &#x2018;security and the rule of law&#x2019; and improved compliance with labour standards in supply chains. Several webinars will be organized to disseminate information on the knowledge products developed under the project. The knowledge shared, based on solid research, will help prepare constituents for the ILC discussion, and will also yield an inventory of steps that the constituents could take to contribute to decent work in Global Supply Chains.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-region code="GLOBAL" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.ilo.org/dashboard"></recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">19272</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="GLO/15/11/NLD-2017-GLO603 - Towards sustainable growth and development in key sectors-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">19272</value>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands, Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="GLO/15/11/NLD-2017-GLO603 - Towards sustainable growth and development in key sectors">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">19272</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=GLO/15/11/NLD">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Decent work in global supply chains</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
