<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=JOR/17/03/GBR" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-106265-76541-2017-JOR109</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting the strategic objectives of the London Syria Conference 2016 Ph 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TThe purpose of the project is to increase the number of decent work opportunities for Syrian refugees and Jordanians in Jordan in the agriculture and construction sectors. By the end of the project, 4,000 Syrians and Jordanians will have benefitted from improved access to decent work in the construction and agricultural sectors through: (a) work permits and participation in the Jordanian social security system; (b) employment services (career guidance and placement); (c) certification of skills through Recognition of Prior Learning; and (d) financial and technical support for Joint Business Ventures. 1. The Centre for Accreditation and Quality Assurance and training providers will design/upgrade the curriculum and tests for at least three targeted occupations. Training providers will prepare test applicants on the job and in classroom, put them through the tests and retrain those who failed in order for them to be retested. Potential Jordanian and Syrian candidates will be recruited through field campaigns and job fairs, tested and referred to short-term skills upgrading programmes. Graduates will be placed mainly in the companies in which they undertook their training. 2. Training programme among cooperatives, placement agencies and other stakeholders are organized and rolled out with the aim to provide better services and improve working conditions. The establishment of placement agencies in particular will assist with the recruitment of Syrians and Jordanians, securing their work permits and placing them in construction companies. Currently no other agency is performing this task and the establishment of these agencies will be a new pilot innovation to inspire public-private partnerships to potentially take this role in the future. These organizations will implement the core services in the framework to be approved by the Ministry of Labour. Both placement agency and cooperatives will agree with each employer on specific plans related to improvement of work conditions, while at the same time providing technical expertise for improvement of productivity. The project also carries out awareness-raising campaigns towards refugees, employers and the host communities in order to improve understanding of labour rights and occupational safety and health, manage expectations of each group and prevent tensions. It will rely on this aspect on both traditional media and social media. 3. Joint business ventures are established between Syrian and Jordanians with the aim of providing them with the knowledge and skills to create their own business plan. Special attention is be paid to women&#x2019;s participation in the programme. Practical challenges will be tackled with direct measures while cultural barriers will be tackled by direct interactions with their families to try to overcome them.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="JO">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="JO" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="JO" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-08-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">79440</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="JOR/17/03/GBR-2017-JOR109 - Enhanced youth access to employment among Syrian refugees and Jordanian host communities-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-22">79440</value>
   <provider-org ref="GB-GOV-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Kingdom, Foreign and Commonwealth Office</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="JOR/17/03/GBR-2017-JOR109 - Enhanced youth access to employment among Syrian refugees and Jordanian host communities">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-22">79440</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=JOR/17/03/GBR">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Supporting the strategic objectives of the London Syria Conference 2016 Ph 2</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
