<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=MMR/15/02/NOR" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-105327-1173-2017-MMR101</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to the Peace Process in Myanmar through an integrated livelihoods approach</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ILO &#x2013; Government of Myanmar&#x2019;s Joint Strategic Action Plan (JSAP) to eliminate forced labour has acknowledge the widespread use of forced labour across the country particularly in ethnic areas and the root cause if it is a disrespect of human dignity. The JSAP requires that the ILO is working toward overturning the Myanmar authorities&#x2019; attitude of disrespect of human dignity &#x2013; in that the JSAP. To eliminate the use of forced labour the ILO is required to work with government authorities at all levels so to encourage positive change from within the structure of power to respect the principle of human rights and human dignity. This work is supported by the EU stability fund. In the meantime, the ILO is required by the JSAP to work with local population to clarify their rights and responsibility before the law with regard to forced labour. The building of an environment of rule of law requires confidence from the part of the local community in demanding a respect of law, and from the part of the authority an understanding of accountability and responsibility before the law. This project is aiming at bringing about changes and confidence toward some 2,742 people of 496 households from 9 villages, who had been internally displaced due to conflict between the NMSP and the Myanmar Government/Tatmadaw in the past will be supported through this project. Forced labour practice was part of the severe plight that the people in this areas suffered and went displace to safe themselves. They are currently residing in the NMSP Kroeng Batoi ceasefire area. A needs assessment in 2013 revealed that the majority (over 90%) of the villagers are planning to stay in their current place of settlement. All of the villagers in the 9 target villages will benefit directly from all project activities. To officially endorse the 2nd phase of the pilot project, KBPPWG will conduct an inception workshop for 3 days with all relevant stakeholders. Stakeholders will include the GoM (with necessary regional government) and its military (Tatmadaw), the NMSP and its armed wing the Mon National Liberation Army (MNLA), IDP village leaders, local NGOs and CBOs, the ILO, the KBPPWG team and MPSI representatives. It is in the project expectation that the workshop such as this would assist in arriving at refining the M&amp;E plan, training delivery plan, defining the number of beneficiaries, construction activities and conception of prospective sustainability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-27" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MM">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="MM" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="MM" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-09-15"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">256363</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="MMR/15/02/NOR-2017-MMR101 - Protection against unacceptable forms of work is strengthened, in particular Forced Labour and Child Labour-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">256363</value>
   <provider-org ref="NO-BRC-971277882">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norway, Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16064" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="MMR/15/02/NOR-2017-MMR101 - Protection against unacceptable forms of work is strengthened, in particular Forced Labour and Child Labour">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">256363</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16064" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=MMR/15/02/NOR">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Support to the Peace Process in Myanmar through an integrated livelihoods approach</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
