<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=JOR/16/50/RUS" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-106110-417566-2017-JOR110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Applying the G20 Training Strategy (Jordan)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is a second phase of the project &#x2018;Applying the G20 Training Strategy: A Partnership of the ILO and the Russian Federation&#x2019; based on the agreement signed between the two Parties in November 2012. The Project covers Armenia, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, and the Russian Federation within the CIS countries, as well as Jordan in the Middle East and Viet Nam in Asia, referred to in the Project Document as the countries-beneficiaries or the Project Countries. The first phase of the Project completed in 2016, and was designed to strengthen Skills Development systems, develop and test tools, and facilitate knowledge-sharing on Human Resources Development (HRD) issues. In 2016, the Russian Federation, represented by the Ministry of Finance, has agreed to further contribute USD 12 million towards the implementation of a second phase of the Project for the period covering 2016-2019. An agreement was signed in December 2016 between the ILO and the Russian government. The second phase is a continued response of the Russian Federation and the ILO to support the application of the G20 Training Strategy to the Skills Development and employment needs in a defined range of countries. During Russia&#x2019;s Presidency of the G20 in 2013, HRD was identified as a main objective of its Development Working Group. Gender equity will be an essential strategy element of all aspects of the Project. The phase is intended to continue the support for implementing the G20 commitments on HRD agreed at the Leaders&#x2019; Summit in September 2013, namely: to enhance national capacities to meet labour market needs, and to develop regional and international cooperation for training. These objectives include assistance for the developing and middle-income countries to assess their Skills Development needs and build up national capacity in delivering quality training, including through inclusion in the training programmes of specific components raising participants&#x2019; awareness and equipping them with the knowledge and practical skills that would allow them to pay special attention those groups facing the greatest barriers to finding or remaining in employment such as youth, women, long-term unemployed, low skilled workers, single parents, people with disabilities and older workers. The major focus of the Project is not on producing the ready-made training products for countries-beneficiaries for their use but rather on &#x201C;development of national, regional, and sectoral capabilities&#x201D; to analyse and improve their national and sectoral Skills Development systems. In Phase 2 over 1,460 participants in the training initiatives and pilots to be conducted by the Project, including overall at least 30% females.Development of Phase 2 was built on the results and the lessons learned from the first phase while fully taking into account the findings, conclusions and recommendations made in the independent mid-term evaluation and in the final evaluation of the first phase of the Project which, in particular, insisted on the involvement of all key stakeholders in overall project planning and design.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="JO">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="JO" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="JO" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">23030</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="JOR/16/50/RUS-2017-JOR110 - Increased LM relevance of the national skills development system as part of the national HRD Strategy-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">23030</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Russian Federation, Ministry of Finance</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="JOR/16/50/RUS-2017-JOR110 - Increased LM relevance of the national skills development system as part of the national HRD Strategy">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">23030</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=JOR/16/50/RUS">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Applying the G20 Training Strategy (Jordan)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
