<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=BGD/15/05/DEU" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-105493-1107-2017-BGD301</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementation of the national employment injury scheme of Bangladesh - A legacy to the Rana Plaza accident</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the project is the adoption of a sustainable national employment injury insurance (EII) scheme for workers employed in the formal sector in Bangladesh, starting with the ready-made-garment sector (RMG). The partnership will ensure that the legacy of the Rana Plaza accident includes sustainable long-term national capacities and systems are put in place, including the effective coverage of all workers to be protected by a national employment injury insurance scheme, so that accidents with unprotected workers such as in the case of the Rana Plaza and Tazreen Factories never happen again. The partnership builds upon the fruitful collaboration with the Government of Germany in Bangladesh since the Rana Plaza accident of April 2013 in the RMG sector in general. Efforts have largely contributed so far to the Sustainability Compact for Continuous Improvements in Labour Rights and Factory Safety in the Ready-Made Garment and Knitwear Industry in Bangladesh (8 July 2013). Development Objective This project proposal intends to support: (1) the advocacy work that is yet necessary to reach a commitment from among key actors to the development of an EII scheme based on principles that are both in line with C.121 and acceptable to them; (2) the completion of the on-going feasibility study that will serve as a basis for engaging a tripartite national dialogue and for the drafting of a legal framework; (3) the development of a bridging solution for the period until the EII scheme is operational and; (4) the activities leading to the adoption of the legislative framework for the EII scheme. (5) the creation of greater gender equality in support to the National Development Plan of Bangladesh, namely the vision of the Perspective Plan 2010-21 &#x2018;to build Bangladesh into a resilient, productive, innovative and prosperous nation with a caring society consisting of healthy, happy, and well-educated people. It is expected that the operationalization phase of the new public EII administration will start after 2017; first covering workers of the RMG sector and gradually extending coverage thereafter to all wage earners in Bangladesh. Various specific areas of work are proposed as mentioned below. Project Coordination The establishment of an EII scheme in Bangladesh involves many actors: first of all theGovernment (Ministry of Labour and Employment, Ministry of Finance, Ministry of Health,Ministry of Commerce, Ministry of Justice, Cabinet), Employers (BEF, BGMEA, BKMEA),Workers (NCCWE, IBC) and NGOs (BILS, OSHE, CARITAS, CRP). These Bangladeshi partners will be supported by ILO, BMZ, GIZ, DGUV, other providers of development assistance, global buyers etc.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="BD">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="BD" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="BD" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">482504</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="BGD/15/05/DEU-2017-BGD301 - Coverage of social protection improved.-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">482504</value>
   <provider-org ref="DE-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Germany, Federal Ministry for Economic Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="25010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="BGD/15/05/DEU-2017-BGD301 - Coverage of social protection improved.">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">482504</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="25010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=BGD/15/05/DEU">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Implementation of the national employment injury scheme of Bangladesh - A legacy to the Rana Plaza accident</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
