<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=CIV/16/50/SWE" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-105738-1207-2017-CIV110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensuring a gender responsive approach to decent work in Cote d&apos;Ivoire</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the ILO report Women at Work: Trends 2016, millions of women are losing ground in their quest for equality in the world of work, with significant gender gaps including in employment, pay, job quality, social protection, and with respect to care responsibilities. As highlighted in the 2030 Sustainable Development Agenda, much more needs to be done to ensure decent work for women. In this context, the ILO/Sida Partnership Programme (Phase II, 2016-17) will focus on key policy areas to advance gender equality and women&#x2019;s empowerment. This work operationalizes the cross-cutting policy driver on gender equality and non-discrimination, leading to results under the Programme and Budget 2016-17. The project will advance the inter-related priorities of the ILO&#x2019;s Women at Work Centenary Initiative, which represent key aspects of the 2030 Sustainable Development Agenda namely: increasing women&#x2019;s access to work; making work pay; women, work and care; and combatting violence at work. It will provide targeted, results-oriented support to ILO constituents in Cambodia, Cote d&#x2019;Ivoire, Jordan and in the Inter- American region. Country Programme Outcome: CIV110 - Les mandants &#xE9;laborent et mettent en &#x153;uvre une strat&#xE9;gie int&#xE9;gr&#xE9;e de transition de l&apos;&#xE9;conomie informelle vers l&apos;&#xE9;conomie formelle The project advances C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire&#x2019;s DWCP priority of &quot;decent jobs for young people, girls and boys, in the context of sustainable development&quot; and more specifically under Outcome 1.1: &quot;The government, in consultation with the social partners, implements job creation measures which operationalize socioeconomic integration programmes for youth, women and other vulnerable groups, which puts a particular emphasis on the elimination of discrimination in employment and occupation.&#x201D; It also falls under the &quot;governance&quot; of the UNDAF, one target of which is on strengthening the economic participation of women and respect for their rights. The project will work to strengthen the capacity of constituents and partners to promote gender equality in the workplace by ensuring that promoting gender equality is at the centre of policies to transition from informal to formal work. In synergy with the ILO&#x2019;s Employment Promotion and Poverty Reduction (APERP) project it will work to develop a basic understanding of gender equality and to ensure it is integrated into employment policies. The project will facilitate the composition of a national committee on integrating gender into the formalization of work. The Committee will oversee research, capacity building and the development of a national programme of action on gender equality at work. In this endeavour it will strengthen the collaboration between the ILO and United Nations Agencies in C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire, particularly with UN Women. As part of this collaboration it will work with UN Women and civil society groups to mark a national day of action against violence, sexual harassment and violence in the workplace.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CI" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="CI">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="CI" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cote d&apos;Ivoire</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="CI" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">43461</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="CIV/16/50/SWE-2017-CIV110 - Les mandants &#xE9;laborent et mettent en &#x153;uvre une strat&#xE9;gie int&#xE9;gr&#xE9;e de transition de l&apos;&#xE9;conomie informelle vers l&apos;&#xE9;conomie formelle-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">43461</value>
   <provider-org ref="SE-0">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden, Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="CIV/16/50/SWE-2017-CIV110 - Les mandants &#xE9;laborent et mettent en &#x153;uvre une strat&#xE9;gie int&#xE9;gr&#xE9;e de transition de l&apos;&#xE9;conomie informelle vers l&apos;&#xE9;conomie formelle">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">43461</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=CIV/16/50/SWE">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Ensuring a gender responsive approach to decent work in Cote d&apos;Ivoire</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
