<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-BAN237</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate induced migration and modern slavery in the Sundarbans region of Bangladesh and India</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The south-west border region of Bangladesh with India, close to the Sundarbans mangrove forest has some of the most vulnerable districts to climate change. At the same time the region is a hot spot for trafficking and modern slavery. On the Indian side of the border there are high levels of trafficking and in Bangladesh forced labour, child exploitation and trafficking are rife. The whole area is hugely vulnerable to climate change, including high intensity cyclones and sea level rise. Floods and tidal surges frequently breach embankments, flooding areas with saline water which destroys crops and drinking water. The loss of land, livelihoods and decreasing productivity trigger migration. With more and more people looking to migrate, they rely increasingly on trafficking networks. Those most vulnerable are women from women headed households, children, and men from extreme poor families. Victims are forced into hard labour working in sweatshops or in construction with others being forced into prostitution. Modern slavery conditions can also be found in the Sundarbans region, including labour exploitation through fish and shrimp production and processing, as well as brick kilns where debt bondage is common. 

With this in mind, CAFOD has developed an 18-month pilot initiative which aims to support research and then scale interventions which address issues of climate change and modern slavery in the Sundarbans (both in Bangladesh and India). The project will start by forming a partnership with a leading academic institution  or organisation to conduct a detailed assessment of the link in the Sundarbans (both in Bangladesh and India) between climate change, environmental degradation, migration and modern slavery. The findings of this study will be used to inform and refine project activities with aim to reduce the prevalence of people most affected by climate change and environmental degradation falling into modern slavery.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="BAN237" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas India National Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="BAN237" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="BAN237" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31130" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-04-01">20074</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="55858">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-03-11">20074</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
