<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-011756-02-1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Do not let the curtain fall - Conservation, management and enhancement of the Faculty of Theatrical Arts</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Il progetto si propone di lavorare in continuit&#xE0; con gli impegni assunti dalla cooperazione italiana a Cuba presentando un&apos;iniziativa che intende contribuire alla valorizzazione del patrimonio storico-culturale e allo sviluppo culturale della societ&#xE0; cubana. L&apos;incipit dell&apos;iniziativa, a partire dal quale si sviluppa il Progetto, &#xE8; dato dal recupero architettonico e funzionale della sede originaria della Facolt&#xE0; di Arte Teatrale (FAT), edificata all&apos;interno dell&apos;area che, prima della Rivoluzione del 1959, ospitava il Country Club de la Habana. La Escuela Nacional de Artes (ENA) venne infatti realizzata per volont&#xE0; di Fidel Castro e Ernesto Che Guevara nel parco dell&apos;ex Country Club de la Habana che, da luogo esclusivo della &#xE9;lite cubana, divenne uno spazio destinato all&apos;insegnamento delle arti, aperto ai giovani di tutte le classi sociali.Il 29 ottobre 2015, durante una la visita ufficiale a Cuba dell&apos;allora Presidente del Consiglio dei Ministri della Repubblica Italiana Matteo Renzi, venne evidenziata e sostenuta la importanza di restaurare la sede della Facolt&#xE0; di Arte Teatrale dell&apos;ISA, con un supporto finanziario italiano. La strategia utilizzata per lo sviluppo del programma rimanda all&apos;approccio RA (Ricerca-Azione), orientato non solo ad approfondire delle conoscenze teoriche, quanto piuttosto ad analizzare le problematiche relative ad uno specifico ambito con lo scopo di introdurvi dei miglioramenti. Tale approccio caratterizza tutte le fasi del Progetto che si retro-alimentano  costantemente. Il programma si compone di due parti: una di restauro, consolidamento e ampliamento della struttura dellaScuola di arte teatrale della Avana - edificio progettato dall&apos;architetto italiano Roberto Gottardi come sede della FAT all&apos;interno del complesso di Cubanac&#xE1;n - (componente &quot;A&quot;), e l&apos;altra di formazione di eccellenza e approfondimento delle conoscenze professionali ed artistiche in ambito architettonico e teatrale compreso il monitoraggio e controllo del processo di restauro (componente &quot;B&quot;).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project intends to contribute to the cultural and human development of the Cuban society by provide artists with an&lt;br&gt;excellent academic preparation and a high social commitment. The project has two specific objectives, each related to a component. The first is to restore and strengthen the Facultad de Arte Teatral of the Instituto Superior de Arte to achieve a complete university education and support a process of continuous improvement in artistic creation and cultural management. The second objective is to contribute to the capacity building of those who work in the fields of documentation,&lt;br&gt;conservation, management and enhancement of cultural heritage, both tangible -the ISA architectures and the territory&lt;br&gt;of the Municipio de Playa - and intangible - theatrical arts - and the monitoring of all the interventions necessary to&lt;br&gt;rehabilitate the building in order to guarantee its correct execution. The first component will involve the restoration, consolidation and adaptation of the Facultad de Arte Teatral of the Superior Institute of Art in Havana. The program will&lt;br&gt;also focus on the educational offer and the relationships that the new Faculty will establish with the community and with&lt;br&gt;other universities. The second component is focused on the acquisition and exchange of skills in architectural restoration&lt;br&gt;and dramatic arts, as well as on the monitoring of the Faculty design and rehabilitation It is aimed at improving the knowledge of all those working within the university and professional system, through the realization of a series of theoretical / practical activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="12001" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="12001" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="12001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTERIO DE CULTURA (MINCULT) CUBA ALT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="011756/02/1" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2020000086" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CU" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="41040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Site preservation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="11" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Make cities and human settlements inclusive, safe, resilient and sustainable</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthen efforts to protect and safeguard the world&#x2019;s cultural and natural heritage</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-04">2000000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTERIO DE CULTURA (MINCULT) CUBA ALT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-16">650000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2020</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTERIO DE CULTURA (MINCULT) CUBA ALT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-011756-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
