<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-25384</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KIC NewCo Investment</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is expected to have a high impact contribution on residential infrastructure development and financial sector development in KSA:  Increased Access to Housing Finance:     The NewCo will provide increased affordability of housing finance for middle-income Saudi households, currently underserved by developers, who tend to focus on the wealthiest segments of the population.  Access to housing is a major problem in KSA, with demand consistently outstripping supply and the housing deficit increasing each year.  By 2020, there will be an estimated demand for 7 million houses, an increase of 3.9 million units from current levels.  The major constraint on the development of the real estate sector is the lack of sufficient availability in housing finance.  Establishment of Replicable Business Model in the Region:      The business model of the NewCo will send a powerful signal on the best practice of the corporate governance and the operations to current and potential market participants.  KIC/NewCo is completely on board with these views, as shown by its negotiations with HDFC for capacity-building technical assistance.  Capital Markets Development:     The IFC Loan would provide the NewCo with access to long-term funds to acquire and lease a steady stream of properties initially financed by the IFC Loan. The revolving nature of the IFC Loan provides support for the NewCos potential securitization activity, and further accelerates the development of mortgage finance/MBS securitization market in the country.  Introduction of Sustainability Standards in Housing Construction:     The acceptance and implementation of sustainability standards by DAAR and other developers whose residential products will be the source of origination for the NewCo will send an important and industry wide signal to the real estate sector in Saudi Arabia.  If this initiative is successful, it could lead to broader acceptance both voluntarily by other competing builders and by regulatory authorities through inclusion of such standards in building codes.  The experience gained in this connection could be used to introduce similar initiatives in other emerging markets.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed transaction consists of a green field investment in a new specialized mortgage finance institution (the NewCo) that is proposed to be established in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia (KSA).  IFC is planning to invest a total of c.a. $27 million of minority equity investment in the NewCo.  The NewCo is planned to offer various housing finance products, targeting middle-income customer segment in Saudi Arabia, and grow to the nations largest specialized mortgage finance institution over years.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saudi Home Loans Company</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-25384" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-04-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-10-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Simon Stockley, Chief Operations Officer Kingdom Installment Company P.O. Box 105633 Riyadh 11656,    Kingdom of Saudi Arabia    Telephone: +9661 206 1100 ext. 1177 Fax: +9661 206 1100 ext. 1178</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saudi Arabia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="SA-Saudi Arabia">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The NewCo will be headquartered in Riyadh, and will establish several branches across Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.  Investments can be made throughout the country.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>25.0000000000 45.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA - Primary Mortgage Institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $26.66 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2007-04-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2007-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-04-04">26660000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2007-04-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-04-04">26660000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saudi Home Loans Company</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/25384/kic-newco-investment">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
