<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-37452 -1138 -2013-CHN252</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting Rights and Equality for Persons with Disabilities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following consultation with key stakeholders during January and February 2012, China was selected for participation in the second ILO/IA PP for two main reasons. Firstly, the Government is paying increased attention to policies, programmes and services catering to persons with intellectual disabilities, as reflected in part in support requested in Phase 3 of the first ILO/IA PP. PROPEL-China will provide technical support to and arrange capacity building for the China Association of Persons with Intellectual Disabilities and their Families, a member of the CDPF, and staff of the recently introduced Sunshine Home Programme for persons with intellectual disabilities, to strengthen their capacity to promote training and employment opportunities for both women and men in this group, in two selected provinces. In this regard, PROPEL-China will build on work carried out in Phases 2 and 3 of the first ILO/IA PP relating to persons with intellectual disabilities both in China and internationally, and will collaborate, to the extent possible, with the ILO Global Business and Disability Network. Secondly, measures to eliminate discrimination in employment and occupation are being prioritized by the Government, following on China&#x2019;s ratification of the ILO Convention No. 111, in addition to China&#x2019;s obligations following the ratification of the UN CRPD in 2008. Building on achievements and materials and publications produced in Phase 3 of the first ILO/IA PP, PROPEL-China will arrange capacity building, technical advice and awareness-raising in the area of discrimination and disability inclusion, including a focus on the additional disadvantages faced by women with disabilities. More broadly, ILO will support the Government of China in measures to eliminate discrimination against women and men with disabilities in employment and occupation, in line with the provisions of the ILO Convention No. 111. In support of both of these factors, PROPEL-China will continue to work with the media, to build capacity to report accurately on the legal rights and the working capacity of persons with disabilities in general, with a particular focus on people with intellectual disabilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-05-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="CPR/12/50/IRL-2013-CHN252 - Skills development increases employability of workers-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">178486</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="11330" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="CPR/12/50/IRL-2013-CHN252 - Skills development increases employability of workers-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-31">178486</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="11330" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
