<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-33377 -1165 -2012-IDN103</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting income security and return to employment for workers in vulnerable employment and the formal sector in ASEAN</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ILO/Korea Partnership Programme (hereinafter referred to as the Programme) under its social security component has since 2006 been providing substantive technical support to a number of countries in Asia in the establishment of Employment Insurance (EI) and Employment Injury Insurance (EII) schemes. With synergy of technical expertise and resources from the ILO and Korean partner institution, the Korea&#x2019;s Compensation and Welfare Services (COMWEL), the Programme has been able to assist countries such as for instance Cambodia to successfully set up and run its first national EII scheme for the workers. In response to the current financial &amp; economic crisis and labour trends, and given the past experience of the Programme in implementing social security schemes in the region, the Programme thus intends to support a project on &#x201C;Promoting income security and return to employment for workers in vulnerable employment and formal sector in ASEAN&#x201D;. This project will focus on both informal economy workers and formal sector workers and aim at developing research as well as designing and implementing concrete and adapted income security measures for working age population. For workers in the formal sector the Programme will mainly support the design and support to implementation of Unemployment insurance schemes as well as the development of linkages between UI and employment services, to facilitate return to employment. For workers in vulnerable employment that have to work in order to survive the Programme will support the development of income security measures as well as the establishment of services to increase employability and facilitate return to employment. The Programme will support interventions both at regional level (research) and country level (concrete design and implementation of schemes). For the country level interventions Indonesia was selected as its government has shown their firm interest and commitment on the issue of income security and return to employment issues as stated in its DWCP, Indonesian Jobs Pact and UNDAF. In 2010, the Indonesian government requested a support from the Programme to conduct a feasibility study on EI scheme. Immediate objective 1 (regional level): By the end of the project, current situation in social protection floor and employment service in ASEAN will be better understood and the result of the findings will be shared among stakeholders. Outcome 1.1. Research on social protection and employment situations is produced and results are available (countries such as Cambodia, Indonesia, Lao PDR, Philippines, Thailand and Vietnam). Outcome 1.2. Research findings are publicized online through the ILO / GESS platform and other key networks. Immediate objective 2 (country level): Income security and return to employment for workers in vulnerable employment and the formal sector will be promoted in Indonesia. Outcome 2.1. Income security and active Labour market policies for workers in the informal economy as well as linkages between the two are promoted in Indonesia. Outcome 2.2. Technical advice is provided on the introduction of unemployment insurance scheme for formal sector workers in Indonesia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="RAS/11/53/ROK-2012-IDN103 - Government and social partners have greater capacity in designing and implementing social protection policies and programmes-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-01">127332</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="ID"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="RAS/11/53/ROK-2012-IDN103 - Government and social partners have greater capacity in designing and implementing social protection policies and programmes-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-31">127332</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="ID"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
