<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-28298 -1270 -2012-SYR103</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Programme on the Elimination of the Worst Forms of Child Labour (WFCL) in Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Programme on the Elimination of the Worst Forms of Child Labour (WFCL) in Syria 1. Executive Summary Child labour in Syria is prevalent in poor households and poorer regions, where it is estimated there are approximately 200,000 child laborers aged 10-14 and 420,000 aged 15-17 working today. Despite the government&#x2019;s efforts to improve the quality of education and decrease school drop-outs, non-enrolment and early drop-out rates continue to increase. Approximately 25 percent of students drop out of Basic Level before completing it, while 67 percent of students do not continue their formal secondary school education at all. To address this issue, the Syrian Government, and especially the Ministry of Education has taken some serious measures to prevent child labour and enforce compulsory education. However further mechanisms and steps still need to be taken prevent early dropout and ensure the continuation of enrolment of working children. The National Programme on the Elimination of the Worst Forms of Child Labour (WFCL) in Syria is a three year programme (2010-2013) implemented by the International Labour Organization in partnership with UNICEF, focusing on the prevention, withdrawal, rehabilitation and provision of alternatives for child laborers and children at risk. The total budget for the project is $1,050,000. To provide a solid quantitative and qualitative basis for the program, the ILO and UNICEF commissioned a study to assess the extent and characteristics of child labour in Syria. The Study analyzes the socio-economic factors that affect child labour and the legislation governing it. The study also provided an overview of the main characteristics of child labour including the working conditions of child laborers. The study, which was completed in September 2010, conclude with a set of recommendations, the results of which will be used to establish the priorities of the National Policy and Programme Framework for the Elimination of Child Labour, and will be integrated in the Government&#x2019;s 11th Five Year Development Plan. The findings of the study will also establish the priorities of the Project, including geographic locations and targeted programmes. The priority focus of the Project will be on the worst forms of child labour. The Project strategy will combine upstream policy-related interventions with downstream service-oriented activities at the community level. At the policy level, the Project will work to: &#xBF; Mainstream child labour into national policy development frameworks: The Project will seek to integrate child labour concerns in broader national action plans and policy frameworks aimed at poverty reduction, social protection, employment promotion and similar frameworks that have a bearing on child labour. &#xBF; Enhance the capacity of social partners to advocate on child labour issues: The Project will work to train and capacitate the Government, particularly the Ministry of Labour and the Ministry of Education, national employers&#x2019; organization and trade unions, as well as NGOs to become active partners in the combat against child labour. &#xBF; Raise Awareness among the general public about child labour issues: Advocacy efforts will be geared toward social mobilization to create a broad alliance of civil society organizations working to highlight the plight of child laborers toward the elimination of WFCL. The Project will also work directly with child laborers through downstream service-oriented interventions, working on the withdrawal, referral and rehabilitation of children laborers. This integrated area-based approach will be applied in Aleppo and will provide direct services to children including the opportunity for formal education and basic literacy, transitional education, vocational education and training, life skills and recreational activities. In cases of displaced and refugee children, where possible, children will be returned to their families of origin, taking into consideration the be</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="SYR/10/02/CEF-2012-SYR103 - Enhanced capacity of the government and social partners to reduce worst forms of child labour-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-01">35516</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="15160" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="SY"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="SYR/10/02/CEF-2012-SYR103 - Enhanced capacity of the government and social partners to reduce worst forms of child labour-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-31">35516</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="15160" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="SY"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
