<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-10801 -1277 -2012-TGO103</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Combating Exploitative Child Labour through Education in Togo</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3. Project objectives: Development objective: To contribute to the elimination of the worst forms of child labour in Togo, especially child trafficking, through the creation of strong institutional educational and socio-economic bases for dealing effectively with all child labour in the country. Summary of strategic and immediate objectives (IOs): &#x2022; I/O#1: By the end of the project, models of intervention for withdrawal, prevention and rehabilitation of children in WFCL will have been implemented in targeted areas and ready for replication and scaling up at national level (Direct interventions). &#x2022; I/O#2: By the end of the project, the Togolese society is mobilised to support the fight against child labour through better education services, networking and community participation (Promote higher access to education). &#x2022; I/O#3: By the end of the project, the GoT and the Togolese civil society will have the the capacity to undertake effective action against the WFCL with minimal external assistance and will have mobilised to support the fight against child labour through networking and platforms of action (Capacity building and community mobilization). &#x2022; I/O#4: By the end of the project, the legal framework is strengthened for dealing effectively with child labour and the trafficking of children, with the main emphasis on the implementation and enforcement of existing laws and regulations (Legal framework). &#x2022; I/O#5: By the end of the project, the knowledge base and systems for monitoring child labour trends and characteristics, including WFCL and the effects of HIV/AIDS on child labour, will have been enhanced (Knowledge base). 4. Project outputs: Outputs related to Immediate Objective #1: 1. Main sectors/WFCL, localities, and strategies (model interventions) for addressing the WFCL, especially child trafficking, reviewed and agreed on by major stakeholders; 2. Education and non-educational services for prevention, rehabilitation and reintegration of children withdrawn from WFCL provided to identified children; 3. Apprenticeship and skills training systems enhanced and expanded to contribute to the elimination of the WFCL by expanding opportunities for decent work and providing alternatives for children found in the WFCL; 4. Economic empowerment services (IGAs) provided to selected families of targeted children. Outputs related to Immediate Objective #2: 1. Nationwide awareness raising campaign and advocacy program on the importance of education in the fight against child labour and child trafficking, with a focus on positive aspects of education and family well being, developed and implemented; 2. Local community networking and local community mutual support system on education developed; 3. The reopening and scaling up of the government&#x2019;s rural literacy program especially in the areas covered by the project; 4. Local education inspectorate strengthened and reinforced with a higher role of teachers&#x2019; unions and parent-teacher associations; 5. With the contribution by the local communities, the project will support the construction of 5 primary schools in selected remote rural areas of the project. Outputs related to Immediate Objective #3: 1. An integrated and time bound policy framework for addressing child labour is in place; 2. Capacity of the civil society to plan, implement, monitor and evaluate and participate in all interventions against child labour strengthened; 3. The needed platforms of agreements with national and international actors in the country developed ate all levels, including at local community level; 4. Child labour issues integrated into the national poverty reduction strategy; 5. A platform of agreement for all actors at community level is developed to support the work of the LVC, to support alternatives services to child labourers such as education services or IGAs to their parents and community; 6. A community-based child labour monitoring system is tested and scaled up at leas</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-09-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="TOG/07/01/USA-2012-TGO103 - Des strat&#xE9;gies, programmes et plans d&apos;action visant &#xE0; &#xE9;liminer le travail des enfants en ciblant les pires formes sont &#xE9;labor&#xE9;s et mis en oeuvre-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-01">643418</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="15160" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="TG"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="TOG/07/01/USA-2012-TGO103 - Des strat&#xE9;gies, programmes et plans d&apos;action visant &#xE0; &#xE9;liminer le travail des enfants en ciblant les pires formes sont &#xE9;labor&#xE9;s et mis en oeuvre-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-31">643418</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="15160" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="TG"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
