<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-34826 -1311 -2012-LBR101</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture and infrastructure development project (AIDP)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ILO project will provide: 1. Support to Ministry of Public Works (MPW) to enable them to take full responsibility and continue the work after the ILO project and its training: (i) capacity building for MPW staff and local contractors in feeder road rehabilitation; (ii) capacity building for MPW and local contractors - pilot surfacing of rural secondary roads using labour-based methods; (iii) capacity building for community-based maintenance groups for routine maintenance. 2. Engineering study of roads and preparation of contract packages: involving design review of originally surveyed roads, including inventory and condition survey update, design of newly surveyed additional road length, preparation of bills of quantities, engineer&apos;s estimate, packaging of contracts, and preparation of simplified works contract documents. During phase 1 - Pre-construction phase, the ILO project will: (i) carry out field surveys to determine and quantify extent of deterioration of the different road links, determine repair requirements of drainage structures for existing structures and additional drainage structure requirements, identify quarry sites for gravel base materials and determine quantity and quality of available material for each identified quarry, and carry out labour availability surveys to establish the existing labour force for labour-based works taking special precautions to ensure labour will not be diverted from agricultural activities to road works; (ii) estimate quantity of work involved for each of the road work activities by road link; and (iii) develop cost estimates for each rehabilitation activity from basic data, provide cost estimates for each typical drainage structure, and develop total cost for each road link. 3. Supervision of road works: the ILO project shall supervise 200km of road rehabilitation works in Lofa, Bong and Nimba Counties. During phase II - Construction supervision: the ILO project will, among other tasks, ensure that all works are carried out expeditiously and be responsible for the accuracy and completeness of the works, providing expert technical advice and skills for the sound inspection and certification of the works. The MPW will delegate to the ILO project the authority to act on its behalf and to make final decisions on certain matters, especially with regard to design, tests, verification of owrk done and preparation of draft payment certificate, acceptance of equipment and certification of completed works.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="LIR/10/03/IDA-2012-LBR101 - Enhanced Local Economic Development through labour-intensive infrastruture development-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-01">819855</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="LR"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="LIR/10/03/IDA-2012-LBR101 - Enhanced Local Economic Development through labour-intensive infrastruture development-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-31">819855</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="LR"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
