<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-74015 -1477 -2013-SOM101</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN joint programme on local governance and decentralized service delivery Phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EXECUTIVE SUMMARY The overall objective of JPLG is to promote improvements in local governance quality that can contribute to peace consolidation, development and equitable service delivery. The Joint Programme, which has five partners including ILO, UNCDF, UNDP, UN-HABITAT and UNICEF, is aligned with the UN Somali Assistance Strategy (UNSAS), 2010 &#x2013; 2015 and contributes to at least five of the Millennium Development Goals (MDGs). JPLG II focuses on strengthening local government as a means of enhancing the delivery of services to citizens and restoring confidence and credibility in the state and improving state-citizen relations by linking local governments to their constituent communities and engaging the private sector transparently and accountably. To achieve this, the programme outcomes are structured around three mutually reinforcing strategies: 1. Supporting policy and legislative reforms for functional, fiscal and administrative decentralization that clarify and enhance the role of local government, its relationship to central government, and as a means to improve local service delivery: Outcome 1 will focus on policy and legal frameworks across Somalia and is initially designed to address weaknesses in current laws on decentralization in Somaliland and Puntland. These provide an incomplete account of the responsibilities and functions to be devolved to local government, ignore the fiscal implications and lack supporting regulations for implementation. These issues need to be clarified in order to resolve disputes between central line agencies and districts, and to provide a stronger foundation for local governments to move forward; 2. Improving local government capacity for equitable service delivery: Outcome 2 aims to address the weak capacity of most local authorities in Somalia by providing a comprehensive package of training and technical support covering basic elements of local administration. It also seeks to improve coordination between districts and the centre in planning and programming to ensure better consistency and use of resources. A third output is concerned with increasing locally generated revenues and strengthening the role and coverage of the LDF; and, 3. Improving and expanding the delivery of sustainable services to citizens in an equitable, responsive and socially accountable manner and promoting local economic environment: Outcome 3 focuses on improving the delivery of local services. This is to be achieved by collaborating more closely with central line departments, engaging more directly with non-state providers, and enhancing the accountability of local governments to their constituents. Another element relates to strengthening the local economy, promoting private investment and enterprise, and creating more and better job opportunities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="SOM/13/04/UND-2013-SOM101 - Access to productive employment, decent work and income opportunities for women and men facilitated.-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">6783</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="SO"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="SOM/13/04/UND-2013-SOM101 - Access to productive employment, decent work and income opportunities for women and men facilitated.-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-31">6783</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="SO"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
