<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-38753 -1312 -2013-KEN104</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STRENGTHENING HUMAN SECURITY IN THE BORDER COMMUNITIES OF TURKANA, KENYA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Summary This project addresses the human security concerns of pastoralists living in extreme hardship and vulnerability to numerous human security threats. The proposed activities aim to improve human security in a context of UN inter-agency coordination including UNDP, FAO, WHO, IOM, UNICEF, ILO and OCHA, and building on the capacities of local CBOs such as Lopedo (Loima Peace and Development organization), the Riam Riam Turkana Peace Network , local peace committees, local government and the governmental Arid Lands Resource Management Project (ALRMP). The proposed activities take into consideration the threat to the socio-economic well-being of vulnerable groups affected by food, economic and health insecurity. Activities building on local capacities are to preserve the human dignity of the target populations, reduce inter-communal, cross-border tensions and promote social and economic development through the delivery of basic health care, the stepping up crucial water initiatives for populations and livestock, the support to the pastoral production system, access to basic education for out of school and vulnerable children as well as alternative livelihood skills training. The project is focused on strengthening the resilience of the dominant livelihoods in the face of natural disasters and other shocks, while providing alternative coping mechanisms through coordinated, sustainable interventions in the livelihoods, food security, education and health sector. Considering the mobile nature of pastoral border communities, the project will target the most vulnerable of the Turkana Central population as well as selected neighbouring cross-border communities by providing opportunities to interact in a peaceful manner through joint training and the establishment of a joint markets and trade opportunities. The project activities support the MDGs by targeting poverty reduction, health and education, while being in line with the government&#x2019;s objectives of poverty reduction and Disaster Risk Reduction for the region, as outlined in the National Policy for the Development of the ASALs. The activities are also in line with UNDAF outcome two on empowering people who are poor and reducing disparities and vulnerabilities. The UNTFHS offers a unique funding source that is integrated, holistic, multi-sectoral which is aptly suited to addressing the multi-facetted problem at stake. The project benefits from the input and guidance of different UN agencies, local partners and most importantly, local community beneficiaries themselves.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="KEN/12/02/HSF-2013-KEN104 - Capacity of ILO constituents and partners strengthened to effectively address child labour-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">61825</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16064" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="KE"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="KEN/12/02/HSF-2013-KEN104 - Capacity of ILO constituents and partners strengthened to effectively address child labour-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-31">61825</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16064" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="KE"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
