<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-32597 -1270 -2013-MOZ106</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Joint programme on social protection in Mozambique</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government of Mozambique has recently passed a number of key Social Protection documents, culminating in the approval of the multi-sectoral Basic Social Security Strategy in April 2010. The approval of this strategic document is of crucial importance in order to take the Social Protection agenda forward and render Social Protection as a key strategy in the Government Poverty Reduction Strategy. The implementation of this strategy will build on the achievements of the Government, and in particular the Ministry of Women and Social Action, over the past three years. The main accomplishments in this area are: &#x2022; The establishment of the Social Action Working Group for the Absolute Poverty Reduction Strategy (PARPA) as a cooperating and coordination body for government and partners who are active in the field of social protection and as a body that monitors government progress in this area. &#x2022; The elaboration and approval of the Social Protection Law, the Basic Social Security Regulation and the Basic Social Security Strategy. &#x2022; Improvements in the implementation of the most expansive social protection programmes of the National Institute for Social Action (INAS): Cash Transfer Programme (PSA). The present UN Joint Programme proposal for the Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency would build on these achievements and take the implementation of the Basic Social Security Strategy forward by further strengthening the institutional capacity of INAS (with a specific focus on targeting the most vulnerable, and on monitoring and evaluation of programme impact) and by implementing two social protection programmes: a Public Works Programme (PWP) and a Malnutrition Programme (MNP). While these two programmes are foreseen to enhance the reach of the current constellation of social protection programmes to the most vulnerable households, the proposed institutional capacity building component of the programme will seek to ensure a major impact on the cooperation and coordination capacities of INAS and MMAS, thereby greatly enhancing the direct impact and the sustainability of the PWP and MNP programmes, with a multiplier effect on other programmes implemented under INAS&#x2019;s responsibility. The capacity building component is being proposed due to the fact that INAS has historically had to cope with a weak implementation capacity due to limited state fund allocation to social protection programmes. In parallel, the Ministry of Women and Social Action has had an equally weak coordination position vis-&#xE1;-vis other key state and non-state partners. The multi-sectoral dimension of the proposed support is envisioned to improve the capacities of these institutions with a long-lasting effect on programme implementation. The initiatives that the UN Joint Programme on Social Protection is proposing to support are programmes that are reflected in Government strategies and plans, were approved by the Council of Ministers, and are foreseen to be implemented from 2011.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="MOZ/11/01/CEF-2013-MOZ106 - Advice on the National Social protection system-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">464940</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="25010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="MZ"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="MOZ/11/01/CEF-2013-MOZ106 - Advice on the National Social protection system-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-31">464940</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="25010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="MZ"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
