<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-34303 -1278 -2012-IRQ127</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bridging for local area development program phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Summary The goal of the Local Area Development Programme (LADP) is sustainable local social and economic development. This programme is proposed as a Bridging Phase linking work to date on LADP and transitioning into a Phase II. It is aiming to build on the lessons from the LADP (2007&#x2013;2010) and consolidate the LADP model, thereby allowing mainstreaming and replication of the methodology in Governorates throughout Iraq in Phase II. The programme targets support to the Governorates through promoting inclusive and participatory planning practices to promote the prioritization of development programmes and annual budgeting while providing focused technical assistance to the Governorates to improve essential service delivery. In addition, two further work streams are proposed, focusing on citizen empowerment to promote an active voice in governorate affairs and engagement with ministries at a national level to institutionalize an agreed devolved framework for improved local planning and service delivery. Preparatory work is proposed around three areas anticipated in the final design of a Phase II. These are (i) inclusive local participatory planning and improved service delivery (ii) local citizen empowerment and civic engagement and (iii) developing a national framework and institutional structure for devolved local planning is. LADP II will continue to build synergies with other relevant UN initiatives to support the Government&#x2019;s plans for improved services delivery and local governance. ILO will act during this Bridging Phase as Area Coordinator for the Governorate of Suylaymaniyah responsible for the coordination of UN interventions and capacity development initiatives and will provide lead technical support for the: i) Governorate to plan and manage sustainable socio-economic development; and ii) Empowerment of local men and women to participate in that process and identify and address their needs and priorities for poverty reduction. The ILO will, in addition be the technical lead and will provide technical assistance to five participating governorates in: i) establishing sustainable system and processes for local employment and economic development and service improvement; ii) Identifying priorities and project for incorporation in provincial consolidated and development plans. The work to be performed by the ILO will be linked to: Output 1 Governorate and district officials have strengthened institutional capacities to plan and manage sustainable socio-economic development in five governorates. Output 2 Local men and women empowered to identify and address their needs and priorities for poverty reduction.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-09-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="IRQ/75/169/33-2012-IRQ127 - Access to job opportunities and livelyhood increased in selected regions-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-01">169121</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="IQ"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="IRQ/75/169/33-2012-IRQ127 - Access to job opportunities and livelyhood increased in selected regions-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-31">169121</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="IQ"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
