<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-29777 -1107 -2012-RER902</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Combating Child Labour in Central Asia. Commitment becomes Action (PROACT CAR Phase III). Award No. 500794 (GLO/10/19/FRG). 2011 and 2012 contribution.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan and Tajikistan are among the countries in Central Asia seriously affected by the Worst Forms of Child Labour (WFCL). The prevalence of WFCL in these countries has disastrous consequences on the safety, health and well being of children. Despite the encouraging results of the efforts to eliminate child labour in Central Asian countries, in particular its worst forms, it remains rampant in the countries and urgent action against the WFCL is still required in order to eliminate these practices. The ILO&#x2019;s International Programme on the Elimination of Child Labour (ILO IPEC) has been working in Central Asia since 2005 to provide technical and financial assistance to the ILO constituents in Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan in the implementation of the ILO child labour conventions: The Minimum Age Convention (1973) No 138 and the Worst Forms of Child Labour Convention (1999) No 182 as well as in the design, implementation, monitoring and evaluation of national child labour strategies, policies and programmes. Although the projects have made important strides towards universal recognition of the existence of WFCL, yet, urgent action against the WFCL is still required in all the countries of Central Asia. The countries still need further technical assistance in their efforts to prevent and eliminate the WFCL by focussing more on policy level interventions, capacity building for social partners and awareness raising on the risks and hazards of child labour at the agriculture sector, with focus on cotton and tobacco. This project proposal is designed to operate over a two years period and will build on the outcomes and achievements of the previous interventions, lessons learned and on the experiences acquired in the sub-region in working with the Government, social partners and other stakeholders in addressing child labour. The main strategy of this new project will be on the combination of policy-related interventions to create a conducive environment with service-oriented activities at the community level . The priorities of the ILO-IPEC in the region will be guided by: a/ the framework provided by the Global Action Plan (adopted by the ILO&#x2019;s Governing Body in 2006) which sets the internationally agreed goal of eliminating the worst forms of child labour by 2016 b/ the Decent Work Country Programmes, by supporting the implementation of the National Action Plans on child labour and other relevant programmes in Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan and Tajikistan, c/ the implementation of national efforts to prevent and eliminate child labour by supporting the ILO Global Jobs Pact which outlines strategies to guide a recovery from the present economic crisis. The project consists of two main components: a national and a regional, - with four Immediate Objectives. Component I: At the national level, the project will focus on policy mainstreaming and up-scaling activities through the institutionalization of models of intervention previously tested; building the capacity and stimulating a greater involvement of the ILO constituents (government, workers&#x2019; and employers&#x2019; organizations) in specific activities against child labour, and awareness raising on the causes and consequences of child labour and possible strategies to address the issue. The project in the three countries is planning to withdraw and to prevent working children from involvement in the worst forms of child labour through provision of a comprehensive package of services. Thus, the immediate objectives (I/O) at the national level, are the following: Immediate Objective 1: By the end of the project, child labour will have been mainstreamed into national policy development frameworks and National Action Plans on the Worst Forms of Child Labour will have been supported in their implementation . Immediate Objective 2: At the end of the project, up-scaling of IPEC tools and models of intervention through capacity building of key stakeholders a</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="GLOBAL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="RER/11/51/FRG-2012-RER902 - TEMP, to link TC projects RER/02/01/FRG, RER/02/08/FRG, RER/02/11/FRG, RER/03/12/GER, RER/03/13/GER, RER/03/14/POL, RER/07/51/FRG-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-01">824473</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16064" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="GLOBAL"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="RER/11/51/FRG-2012-RER902 - TEMP, to link TC projects RER/02/01/FRG, RER/02/08/FRG, RER/02/11/FRG, RER/03/12/GER, RER/03/13/GER, RER/03/14/POL, RER/07/51/FRG-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-31">824473</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16064" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="GLOBAL"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
