<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-44198 -7535 -2013-SOM102</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joint Programme on Local Governance and Service Delivery Phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">After decades of warfare, Somalia has been undergoing a peace and national recon&#xAC;ciliation process creating a &#x2018;development moment&#x2019; with an unique opportunity to consolidate and extend the significant development achievements that have been made in many parts of the country especially in northern areas, as well as to seize the opportunity to bring lasting peace and stability to the many areas made accessible in southern Somalia, thus opening up development space there. Somalia&#x2019;s international partners have expressed robust commitment to assisting the Somali people in seizing the development moment, encouraging a new Somali-owned and led partnership, which will work towards a compact between the Somali authorities and the international community inspired by the principles outlined in the New Deal agreed in Busan, 2011. With UN being one of the largest and most persistently engaged partners to Somalia it has a special responsibility to deliver on this promise and is increasingly doing so as one UN, empha&#xAC;sised by UN&#x2019;s Secretary General. The UN Joint Programme on Local Governance and Decent&#xAC;ralised Service Delivery for Somalia (JPLG) has established an important platform for seizing the development moment and is also a programme that has translated many of the ambitions of the &#x2018;One UN&#x2019; principles into tangible improvements in aid and wider development effectiveness. It is against this background that JPLG, launched in 2008 for a period of five years, is to be continued fora second phase of five years running from 2013 through 2017 referred to as JPLG II. The Joint Programme, which has five partners including ILO, UNCDF, UNDP, UN-HABITAT and UNICEF, is aligned with the UN Somali Assistance Strategy (UNSAS), 2010 &#x2013; 2015 and contributes to at least five of the Millennium Development Goals (MDGs). JPLG II will build on the successes achieved during the past five years and will maintain the same focus of strengthening local government as a means of enhancing the delivery of services to citizens and restoring confidence and credibility in the state. It will also improve state-citizen relations by linking local governments to their constituent communities and will engage the private sector transparently and accountably.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="SOM/13/02/UND-2013-SOM102 - Creation of immediate job opportunities for young men and women through infrastructure development-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">726612</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="SO"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="SOM/13/02/UND-2013-SOM102 - Creation of immediate job opportunities for young men and women through infrastructure development-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-31">726612</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="SO"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
