<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-32697 -7535 -2013-EGY153</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pro-Poor Horticulture Value Chains in Upper Egypt</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt&#x2019;s recent economic growth has not sufficiently been pro-poor. Rather, poverty has expanded, especially in rural Upper Egypt which is facing two mutually reinforcing problems; one that has to do with the overall efficiency of the value chain, and the other one has to do with the marginalization of the majority of small landholders. The purpose of the programme is to promote viable equitable partnerships between small farmers and private sector investors in efficient pro-poor horticulture value chains in three locations in the poorest Upper Egyptian Governorates. This shall be accomplished upon achieving the following outcomes: 1. Small farmers and agricultural workers are more equitably integrated into domestic and international value/supply chains of horticultural products through enhanced efficiency, productivity and viable business partnerships with private sector investors. 2. Entrepreneurial forms of organization established by small farmers. 3. Policy and regulatory changes to promote pro-poor private sector-based growth in Upper Egypt&apos;s horticultural sector identified and discussed with the GOE. Previous donor assistance has organized small farmers in some locations in Upper Egypt in farmers&#x2019; associations (FAs). The Programme shall select three local FAs; one in each governorate, representing 800 - 1000 small farmers growing horticultural crops from amongst the poorest governorates of Assiut, Sohag, Minya, Beni Suef and Qena. Some of these associations have established Post Harvest Centers (PHCs). The programme shall facilitate cost sharing arrangements between the small farmers and private investors to establish new PHCs or improve existing ones. The programme shall broker/facilitate partnerships between the small farmers and different kinds of private investors (exporters, domestic retailers, touristic facilities&#x2026;etc.), by virtue of which the private investors shall: &#xBF;&#xBF;Purchase via forward contracts the crops of the small farmers at fair prices. &#xBF;&#xBF;Through a management contract with the FAs field professional management for the PHCs. &#xBF;&#xBF;Train FA staff in PHC management. &#xBF;&#xBF;Supervise the provision of various extension services to the small farmers. &#xBF;&#xBF;Co-invest with the small farmers in upgrading the PHC, if needed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="EGY/11/50/UND-2013-EGY153 - Technical assistance on setting wage policies provided-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">350480</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="EG"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="EGY/11/50/UND-2013-EGY153 - Technical assistance on setting wage policies provided-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-31">350480</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="EG"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
