<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-25496 -1278 -2012-SOM101</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Employment generation for early recovery in South Central Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Summary The programme will focus in the Mogadishu region and the two adjacent districts of Afgooye and Baalad, as they are two major production centres that help Mogadishu in sustaining a good level of agricultural and food commodities while the same time being major recipients of IDPs from Mogadishu. The programme will also initiate activities in Bay, Hiran and Lower and Middle Shabelle. Depending on the (security) situation and funding issues, other areas in the South-Central region, such as Baikol, Galgadud and Mudug, shall also be considered. The programme is well in line with the priorities of the Somali Reconstruction and Development Plan. It is further included in the CAP 2008 as well as in the UN Transitional Plan 2008. Specifically, the programme will contribute to the achievement of the UNTP Outcome 5, &#x201C;Vulnerable and marginalized groups have improved sustainable food security and economic opportunities&#x201D;. The programme is part of the Agriculture and Livelihoods Cluster of the Somalia Consolidated Appeal Process (CAP) for the components addressing the most urgent needs within the programme. Moreover the programme will contribute toward the attainment of several MDGs including: Eradicating extreme hunger and poverty; Promoting gender equality and empowering women; Ensuring environmental sustainability; and Developing a global partnership for development The programme addresses the urgent issue of income generation and job creation in South Central Somalia, through a community based approach, aiming to build permanent capacities and increased skills levels, while addressing direct income generation priorities for the most affected parts of both IDP and host communities. By applying a community based approach and involving the beneficiary communities in all phases of project implementation it is aiming for local ownership of the project works, thus enhancing the sustainability of the programme. The programme addresses short term income generation issues, as well as vocational training, grants, micro credit/revolving funds and capacity building. In light of the unstable security situation in Somalia, the implementing structure is designed to be flexible, both in terms of geographical area and in terms of implementation structures. The programme aims to involve to the maximum extent local capacities, such as existing networks of Non Governmental Organizations and contracted monitoring capacity. The programme will build on existing UNDP and other initiatives and will be jointly implemented by UNDP and ILO, whereby UNDP will assume overall management responsibility and implement some selected components, while ILO, and possibly other specialized Agencies, will implement specific components, in line with its core competencies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-08-05" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="SOM/10/01/UND-2012-SOM101 - Access to productive employment, decent work and income opportunities for women and men facilitated.-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-01">9632.7</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="SO"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="SOM/10/01/UND-2012-SOM101 - Access to productive employment, decent work and income opportunities for women and men facilitated.-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-31">9632.7</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="SO"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
