<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-27097 -1334 -2012-RAS151</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A Pilot Scheme on Promoting the Circular Migration of Health Care Professionals and Skilled Workers through Specialized Employment Services and Skills Certification and Testing</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall objective: To promote the circular migration of professionals and highly skilled personnel in the health care sector through the development of a pilot scheme of specialised employment services and a system of skills testing and certification. Specific objective(s): (a) to design and test a pilot scheme involving the online registration, skills testing and certification, preparation and counselling, placement for European employment and upon return, their re-employment in home countries and alternative destinations; (b) to improve the collection and analysis of labour market information on the demand and supply of professionals and skilled workers in the health care sector in selected EU countries and other destinations and in the source countries of India, the Philippines and Vietnam; (c) to foster policy dialogue to promote circular migration and mitigate the risks of brain drain in a pro-active manner. Countries covered: The Philippines, India and Vietnam as pilot countries and selected activities in main destination countries in Europe. Project target group: Relevant government and private sector officers from employment services and skills testing facilities in participating countries and in selected countries in the EU; associations of professionals in the healthcare sector, starting with the nursing sector. Final beneficiaries of the project are skilled migrant workers in pilot countries interested in or already working in nursing and health care professions in the EU. Partners: Workers&#x2019; and Employers&#x2019; Organizations, Associate partners will include the overseas employment authorities, accredited training providers and skills certification institutions, associations of professionals in health care, as in nursing institutions in the pilot countries and their counterpart organizations in the selected destination countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="GLOBAL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="INT/09/11/EEC-2012-RAS151 - Improved Capacities of Governments and Social Partners to Manage Labour Migration-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-01">407957</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="15160" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="GLOBAL"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="INT/09/11/EEC-2012-RAS151 - Improved Capacities of Governments and Social Partners to Manage Labour Migration-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-31">407957</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="15160" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="GLOBAL"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
