<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-34747 -1356 -2012-RER801</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening social dialogue and industrial relations in Europe through the capacity building of workers and employers</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This new Joint Management Agreement is signed in the context of the implementation of the 2011 Industrial relations and Social dialogue EU budget heading (04.03.03.01), and the strategic partnership between the EC and the ILO as agreed upon in the Exchange of Letters of 14 May 2001. The objective is to promote cooperation on social dialogue and industrial relations in EU member states, and EU candidate and potential candidate countries, in the context of the financial and economic crisis. In a first twelve-month phase, the Commission and the ILO intend to carry out a joint project in the area of social dialogue and industrial relations, taking advantage of the global expertise of the ILO in these areas. The joint project will cover both capacity building actions in support of workers&apos; and employers&apos; organizations and analytical work. The latter will include strands relating to: the strategies pursued by public authorities and social partners in response to the crisis; the impact of the crisis on wages and inequalities; on social dialogue and trade; on decent work. The outcomes of this project will be used in the Industrial Relations in Europe report 2012 and will contribute to the work of the unit to support social dialogue. The indicative amount allocated to this project is 1,050,000 Euros. The joint management project will include five components: (1) capacity building of workers organizations in the context of engaging in EU and EU enlargement social dialogue and implementing its outcomes, (2) capacity building of employers organizations in the context of engaging in EU and EU enlargement social dialogue and implementing its outcomes, (3) adjustments in the public sector in Europe (4) promoting a balanced and inclusive recovery from the crisis in Europe through sound industrial relations and social dialogue (with a particular attention to EU countries in the periphery) and (5) a stocktaking of social dialogue in a number of EU Member states that joined the EU since 2004.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="GLOBAL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="RER/11/54/EEC-2012-RER801 - Strengthened institutional capacity of employers&apos; organisations-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-01">777496</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="25010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="GLOBAL"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="RER/11/54/EEC-2012-RER801 - Strengthened institutional capacity of employers&apos; organisations-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-31">777496</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="25010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="GLOBAL"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
