<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-21497 -7535 -2013-BRA108</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Security with Citizenship: preventing violence and strengthening citizenship with a focus on children, adolescents and youth in vulnerable conditions in Brazilian communities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Summary: The joint programme seeks to develop actions directed at achieving a reduction of the violence that affects children, youth and adolescents in a situation of vulnerability, through the voluntary compliance with rules, the self-regulation of behaviour and the promotion of mechanisms of social control. The programme also intends to build and strengthen capacities among local actors to ensure that actions are carried out within the framework of full citizen coexistence and a security plan, as well as the strengthening of conditions of local governance that ensure the sustainability of the actions. The programme is targeted at children, youth and adolescents, young men and women, between 10 and 24 years, who are especially vulnerable because they are excluded from the educational system, are victims of domestic or intergenerational violence are involved in drug-related activities, such as traffic, or belong to a community affected by the presence of perverse or detrimental social capital. The actions will be developed in specific areas of three municipalities chosen on the basis of socio-cultural criteria and violence and crime rates, so that they reflect the different realities of Brazil (high, medium and low violence rates). The programme and its components have been established giving special consideration to the different roles, behaviours, aspirations and needs of children, adolescents and young women and men in vulnerable situations, or at risk of becoming victims or agents of violence. Thus, during the development, monitoring and evaluation phases, the programme will analyze its impact on the security situation, victimization and security perception of young men and women. The programme seeks to guarantee the commitment of municipal authorities through the provision of financial compensation and, especially, management. To this end, the participating municipalities will be selected through public contest, an objective and transparent selection process in which the local commitments will be a defining variable in the final choice. The programme involves the participation of six agencies of the United Nations system in Brazil: UNDP, UNODC, UNICEF, UNESCO, UN-HABITAT and ILO. The joint initiative will share and build on the specialized knowledge and experience of each agency and guarantee the quality of the planned actions. In order to ensure effective gender mainstreaming in the development of the programme, the United Nations Development Fund for Women (UNIFEM) will provide support and advice. The programme responds to the established objectives of cooperation of the UN system in the country and to the need for action towards strengthening public policies adopted by the federal government, in particular the National Programme for Public Security with Citizenship - PRONASCI.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-10-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="BRA/09/50/UND-2013-BRA108 - Public policies to stimulate employment and income opportunities for youths are implemented.-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">98454</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="11330" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="BR"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="BRA/09/50/UND-2013-BRA108 - Public policies to stimulate employment and income opportunities for youths are implemented.-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-31">98454</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="11330" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="BR"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
