<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-39553 -1351 -2013-IND104</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Rural Development in India</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In India, roads have come to occupy a dominant position in the transportation system of the country. It is considered an infrastructure critical to economic growth and social development. The total road network in India today stands at 3.4 million km of which 2.8 million km comprise low volume rural roads (including roads constructed and upgraded under the PMGSY programme). Rural roads comprise over 80 per cent of the road network and their being kept in serviceable condition is crucial to the agricultural growth on the one hand and affording means of access on a sustainable basis to millions of our rural people to social facilities such as schools, health centres as also to markets on the other hand. There are several challenges being faced by the country in regard to ensuring sustained maintenance of rural roads. The project development objective of the World Bank supported initiative is to enhance the systems and policies of the national PMGSY rural roads program; and improve and expand the provision and maintenance of PMGSY (Prime Minister&apos;s Rural Roads Scheme), all-season access roads to beneficiary communities resulting in enhanced economic opportunities and social services for residents in Jharkhand, Himachal Pradesh, Rajasthan, Meghalaya, Uttarakhand, Uttar Pradesh and Punjab over a period of five years. The project is structured around two components: (i) Component A &#x2013; PMGSY program financing contributes to the finance of civil works expenditures in the seven participating states associated with providing new all weather access to unconnected habitations and upgrading key through routes in rural areas. The project will strengthen implementation efficiency and the sustainability of program roads through improved maintenance; and (ii) Component B &#x2013; Institutional strengthening will support a technical assistance program designed to strengthen the capacity of relevant agencies to implement the program. As such the project has two priority objectives: . Enhancing operations and improved service delivery of the PMGSY to provide more cost effective, efficient and transparent delivery of infrastructure. &#xB7; Sustainable maintenance and preservation of PMGSY infrastructure assets through improved policies, institutions, systems and implementation mechanisms</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="IND/12/01/IBR-2013-IND104 - National rural programmes that contribute to decent work and productive employment are expanded through effective national and state partnerships.-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">539931</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="IN"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="IND/12/01/IBR-2013-IND104 - National rural programmes that contribute to decent work and productive employment are expanded through effective national and state partnerships.-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-31">539931</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="IN"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
