<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-21696 -1334 -2013-GLO351</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving safety and health at work through a Decent Work agenda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving safety and health at work through a Decent Work agenda Executive summary Overall Goal: To contribute to a more inclusive and productive society through a reduction in occupational accidents and work-related diseases. Specific objective 1: A systematic approach to improving occupational Safety and Health (OSH) is taken on board at the highest political level, including consideration of OSH concerns in national development policies in the pilot countries. Specific objective 2: Practical OSH management measures are introduced and implemented at enterprise level in accordance with national action plans Specific objective 3: Promotion of global knowledge sharing on OSH tools and good practices towards a systematic and sustainable approach to OSH improvements. Expected results: &#x2022; A national dialogue process on OSH is established and functioning in the six pilot countries (Honduras and Nicaragua, Moldova and Ukraine, Malawi and Zambia). &#x2022; Advocacy tools developed by the project are used by stakeholders who are motivated to promote and prioritise OSH as a national issue. &#x2022; National OSH programmes/action plans are adopted in the six pilot countries. &#x2022; Stakeholders are capable of using tools and methodologies to improve OSH management at the workplace. &#x2022; Methodologies used and the good practices developed in the pilot countries are acknowledged and taken up by more countries. Through mobilising and promoting responsibility of governments and social partners to work together, a national programme on OSH will be developed and implemented. This will be developed on a step-by-step basis by the tripartite partners in the participating countries. Specific outputs include: &#x2022; A tripartite national dialogue process with functioning tripartite national OSH committees in six pilot countries &#x2022; National OSH profiles (situational and needs analyses), including evaluation of OSH inspection services, adopted and published in six pilot countries &#x2022; National action plans on OSH, including on OSH inspection, adopted and launched at highest political level in six pilot countries &#x2022; A number of policy-makers trained on prioritising OSH in six pilot countries &#x2022; A practical tool published on calculating costs to national economy of poor OSH practices &#x2022; A tool published on determining the real extent of occupational injuries &#x2022; A number of trained labour inspectors and managers capable of promoting more efficient and effective OSH inspections and ensure implementation of the OSH action plan &#x2022; A number of trained trainers in OSH management and the WISE and WIND methodologies, capable of expanding the WISE and WIND programmes &#x2022; Locally-produced WISE and WIND materials for future training &#x2022; Two awareness-raising campaigns in each project country, based on the ILO World Day for Safety and Health at Work &#x2022; One synthesis report of the project conclusions, lessons learned and recommendations for a systematic and sustainable approach to improving OSH in a national context &#x2022; One global conference.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="GLOBAL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="INT/09/08/EEC-2013-GLO351 - [2014-2015]: Increase national competences to strengthen national OSH systems and promote safety and health culture-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">14471.94</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="GLOBAL"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="INT/09/08/EEC-2013-GLO351 - [2014-2015]: Increase national competences to strengthen national OSH systems and promote safety and health culture-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-31">14471.94</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="GLOBAL"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
