<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-32197 -5435 -2013-EGY828</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Combating Worst forms of Child Labor by Reinforcing Policy Response and Promoting Sustainable Livelihoods and Educational Opportunities in Egypt (CWCLP)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EXECUTIVE SUMMARY Project title Combating Worst forms of Child Labor by Reinforcing Policy Response and Promoting Sustainable Livelihoods and Educational Opportunities in Egypt (CWCLP) Name of the Applicant: World Food Programme (WFP) Proposed Subgrantees/Partners&#x2019; International Labor Organization (ILO) and United Nation&#x2019;s Children Fund (UNICEF) Funding amount requested from USDOL USD $9,500,000 Total dollar value of matching funds, in-kind contributions, and other forms of cost sharing ______________ Summary of the proposed project design and key project activities Objectives, Immediate objectives and Expected Results: Drawing on the extensive experience and success of the currently implemented Combating Exploitative Child Labor in Egypt Project (CCLP), WFP, in partnership with UNICEF and ILO, proposes to implement a coordinated programming strategy to address the extensive problem of child labor in Egypt by providing opportunities for children, especially girls, to attend school. The new project will address the root causes of child labor and promote alternative livelihood and income earning opportunities for households vulnerable to placing their children in labor, particularly in the agricultural context. WFP, ILO and UNICEF have successfully developed an approach to increased child education participation as a springboard for addressing the extensive problem of child labor in Egypt. The program allows children, especially girls, to attend school. The new project will continue to promote and implement activities aimed at increasing child enrolment in schools but will also intensify efforts at identifying and promoting livelihood options for poor households in targeted communities in rural Egypt. ii The overall development objective seeks to combat child labor, with special attention to the worst forms of child labor in agriculture, by supporting strong child labor policy and legislation and promoting sustainable livelihoods and educational opportunities for 16,000 children in the Egyptian governorates of Assiut, Menya, Sohag, Fayoum, and Sharqiyah. The four interconnected immediate objectives correspond to the first four goals of USDOL projects. The fifth USDOL goal &#x2013; ensuring long-term sustainability of these efforts &#x2013; represents the overall approach and is ingrained throughout all of the CWCLP immediate objectives, outputs, and activities: WFP, UNICEF, and ILO propose to provide direct educational services and address the root causes of child labor through the promotion of sustainable livelihoods of target households (immediate objective 1). In addition to increasing educational opportunities for children, this immediate objective promotes a new livelihoods and income generating approach for households of children at risk. The project proposes to strengthen policies on child labor, support the review of relevant legislation on child labor, and strengthen the capacity of national institutions to combat child labor and address its root causes (immediate objective 2), by increasing the capacities of government and nongovernment partners to implement and enforce National Action Plan to combat and eliminate child labor and to review and revise relevant child labor legislation, especially as it applies to agriculture. The Combating Worst forms of Child Labor Project (CWCLP) also proposes to raise awareness of worst forms of child labor and its root causes and the importance of education for all children to mobilize a wide array of actors to improve and expand education (immediate objective 3). This immediate objective will increase awareness of the problem of child labor in agriculture and amongst policy-makers at the national, governorate, community and household levels. Finally, to support the immediate objectives outlined above, the project proposes to oversee research, evaluation and the collection of reliable data on child labor, its root causes and effective strategies, policies and good practices to promote livelihoods</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="EGY/11/01/WFP-2013-EGY828 - Capacity of Egyptian government, workers and employers&apos; organizations strengthened to combat Child Labour-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">866792</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16064" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="EG"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="EGY/11/01/WFP-2013-EGY828 - Capacity of Egyptian government, workers and employers&apos; organizations strengthened to combat Child Labour-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-31">866792</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16064" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="EG"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
