<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.ilo.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" linked-data-uri="http://www.ilo.org/legacy/english/pardev/iati-data/ilo2012-13rbsaxbtc.xml" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-26577 -7535 -2012-PAK103</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Empowerment of vulnerable groups through employment, education and training</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Empowerment of Vulnerable Groups through Employment, Education &amp; Training (EET) Since the 2005 World Summit of the United Nations General Assembly, international and national leaders have agreed that if their countries are to overcome poverty and achieve sustainable development they need to ensure full and productive employment and decent work for all. The ILO is thus helping member States adopt the decent work goals as national objectives. In accordance with national characteristics and possibilities, the ILO combines advocacy, demonstration and cooperation in helping countries define and implement Decent Work strategies. Decent Work Country Papers define the ILO&#x2019;s contribution within the One UN framework. Each country programme enables the ILO and tripartite constituents to work closely with the United Nations and donors to integrate the objectives of full and productive employment, poverty alleviation and decent work into policy dialogue and programming cycles. The Government has provided needed support for piloting UN reform in Pakistan in terms of leadership and ownership of the process, line ministries are actively and systematically engaged in the process, donor community has reiterated its support to the process, concepts and modalities of joint programming have been established, and in various cases, interventions have started on-ground. It is imminent for the sustainability of joint programs that these are founded on the principles of Social Justice and decent work agenda so that the dividends of development are fairly distributed among all relevant beneficiaries. The present Project aims to support the One-UN Program by enhancing its relevance and effectiveness. The Project has three main components, i.e. 1. Mainstream entrepreneurship &amp; Business Start-up Education Programme for Pakistani Youth in Secondary schools and training institutes; 2. National capacity enhancement to promote Decent Work, implement employable Skills Programs and Labour Market Information &amp; Analysis; 3. Education and Legal Empowerment of Poor and Vulnerable Groups focusing Forced &amp; Bonded Labour and Child Labour The Project is funded through &#x201C;Expanded Funding Window (EFW)&#x201D; a part of which is coming from Dutch funds for One-UN Program interventions. Project interventions would promote decent employment in the country. The project activities are in line with approved Joint Program Documents (which has substituted UNDAF for year 2010-2012) and supports various Outcomes and Outputs of different Joint Programs. The Project also supports the Government Development plans and policies including PRSP, National Employment Strategy and National Education Strategy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-02-06" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>http://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction ref="PAK/10/03/OUF-2012-PAK103 - Access to better jobs promoted especially for vulnerable groups-C">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-01">465364</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="PK"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="PAK/10/03/OUF-2012-PAK103 - Access to better jobs promoted especially for vulnerable groups-E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-31">465364</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="PK"></recipient-country>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="100"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
