<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-18995887</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Seeds 4 Needs project is innovative Bioversity concept helping to address some of the challenges facing the world&apos;s poorest smallholder farmers. Having tested the Seeds 4 Needs approach in Papua New Guinea and Ethiopia, Bioversity is now seeking to apply the concept to the Mekong River Basin. Working with partners in Laos and Cambodia, local communities and women&apos;s groups, Bioversity will help identify climate-ready collections of crops, and match them with the areas where they will continue to produce yields under predicted climate conditions. The project will identify, test and disseminate seed varieties that are best adapted to a broad range of environmental conditions, using GIS technology, environmental data and information management. Indigenous farming communities will be equal partners, and will be supported to apply their traditional knowledge. Research scientists will engage with and involve local communities in identifying and testing suitable planting materials. These collaborations will be essential to understanding and strengthening local seed systems by building the knowledge and physical systems that provide farmers with increased access to a diversity of adapted seed varieties. We will support and develop the capacity of government decision-makers and technical staff, and undertake awareness-raising activities for communities. We will establish a farmer-based &apos;experimentation network&apos; in the Mekong River Basin region for the testing of selected planting materials. This project provides the opportunity to set in motion sustainable agricultural practices for some of the Mekong River Basin&apos;s poorest people. The project team will explore local and international opportunities for funding to promote the further sustainability of the project following initial investment. The project will identify partners that offer expertise and support through in-kind contributions</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="ANON023" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anonymous 5</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="458092" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bioversity International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <sector code="31164" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="41030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">360000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
