<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-20410115</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">For With the funds, the Sahaja Samruda will work with farmers to promote food security through agricultural biodiversity, strengthen regional seed producer groups, develop technical support for farmer based conservation and use of local plant genetic diversity, strengthen farmer seed supply systems to reduce local dependence on public and private supply systems, and increase the income level of traditional tribal farmers with direct marketing and increasing the value of biodiversity. The tribal farmers of Araku Valley, Andhra Pradesh, and Attapadi in Kerala have traditionally produced biodiverse agriculture, however with the introduction of chemically dependence and genetically modifiedorganisms (GMOs) in the region, the environment is being degraded and production is inhibited. Local children are suffering malnutrition, and community livelihoods have been impacted. The group intends to introduce youth to traditional practices and preserve diversity with partner mother and women led groups in Attappady. Funds will be used to develop seed and diversity maps, form and support seed saver groups, develop seed collection and storage systems, link traditional farmers to the market, build capacity, organize a seed festival, establish a field gene bank, and organize large scale seed production of popular crop varieties.The project aims to work with 815 women, 685 men, 216 youth, and 150 indigenous people</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GLOB040" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Greengrants Fund, Inc.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="807955" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sahaja Samrudha</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="12240" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="52010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">6000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
