<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-20409616</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">For Centre for Environmental Education and Development (CEED) seeks to educate people living in the Gassol Local Government Area in Nigeria and the Lau Local Government Area about the consequences of possible rice project that would require 300,000 hectares of land. The Federal Government of Nigeria, the Taraba State Government, and Dominion Rice and Integrated Farms Limited USA are negotiating this project, which is in accordance with the G8 New Alliance for Food Security and Nutrition Cooperative Framework. The so called Staple Crop Processing Zones (SCPZs), 13 in total, will be created in different states of Nigeria, including the two local government areas in Taraba State. As Dominion Rice and Integrated Farms is known for its dominant land grabbing practices, the aforementioned communities&apos; fate is unclear. The organization plans to assess the consequences this project will have on livelihoods and will provide the communities of the area with enough information for them to make informed decisions about the efficacy of the project on their lives. Around 390 women, 672 men, 389 youth, and 450 indigenous people will be involved in the organization&apos;s activities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GLOB040" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Greengrants Fund, Inc.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="807607" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environmental Education and Development Nigeria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="12240" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="41081" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="52010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">4500</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
