<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-20409714</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GGF funds will be used to conduct field trips to evaluate the waste management (manure) system of the Oril Leader poultry farm. The public is deeply concerned about the risks associated with waste management at Oril Leader since there is little to no information available about the volumes of waste produced, existing waste management system, use and efficiency of the biogas power plant, and any risk mitigation measures. Since the construction of the farm, local residents complained about the large quantities of manure that was stored in the open lagoons; people were concerned about strong odours and potential contamination of soil and drinking water sources. In 2010, Myronivsky Hlibproduct (MHP), one the largest Ukrainian agro holdings, received a USD 65 million loan from the European Bank of Reconstruction and Development (EBRD) to build a biogas power plant at the Oril Leader poultry farm. The plant was built and put into operation, but recent field visit showed that manure is still stored in the open ditches, and local communities complain about strong odours. The group will invite experts to conduct several field trips to evaluate the waste management practices at Oril Leader and prepare a comprehensive report to be shared with the public, civic organizations, governmental .authorities and agricultural businesses</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GLOB040" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Greengrants Fund, Inc.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="807672" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voice of the Nature</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31163" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">4800</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
