<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-20676537</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s work provides the sole or significant source of income for many families in disadvantaged communities in Tanzania. The number of women micro entrepreneurs in Tanzania has increased dramatically in the last 20 years but most operate in the informal economy where they face a number of risks and challenges which make it difficult for them to start and grow their businesses. This project will provide a package of support to 1,000 women entrepreneurs from disadvantaged communities to improve their businesses and lift their families and communities out of poverty. This holistic package includes business and technical training combined with customized support and a programme of activities addressing the cultural and gender challenges facing women. As a result of this project women will be more confident and capable of running thriving sustainable enterprises; household incomes will increase, and women&#x2019;s rights will be understood by women themselves and their husbands/partners. Ultimately, women&#x2019;s role in household decision-making will be strengthened, there will be a more equal distribution and ownership of economic resources, and women will be confident to take leadership roles in their communities.The TVBI &#x2013; MKUBWA programme offers a comprehensive and tailored package of support for women entrepreneurs addressing both immediate and long term needs. Data from the pilot project indicates that the programme has the capacity to significantly increase sales in the poultry and food processing sectors. However the current application is very expensive and covers a wide range of sectors. Therefore, approval on a scaled down basis focused on one sector is recommended in principle to demonstrate the concept can work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="COMI416" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comic Relief</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="337546" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania Gatsby Trust</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="32120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="16015" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">414475</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
