<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-20409483</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centro Ecoceanos will utilize this grant to strengthen public monitoring of the salmon farming industry in Chile and to control the expansion of this industry in order to protect aquatic ecosystems and indigenous territories. The rapid growth of salmon farming and large scale aquaculture has drastically altered the livelihoods of coastal communities while deteriorating water quality, destroying aquatic biodiversity and threatening human health. The industry is seeking to expand its work into the areas of Bio Bio, Araucania, and Los Rios, which are all areas claimed by indigenous peoples. Centro Ecoceanos will conduct a public awareness campaign with the following goals: raise citizen awareness and strengthen public debate around the expansion of salmon farming; keep salmon production and exports under close scrutiny; establish a moratorium on the expansion of the salmon farming industry, organize a national campaign to stop the expansion of salmon farming in communities of the indigenous Mapuche, Lafkenche, Huilliche, and Kaweskar peoples; ban smolt (young salmon) production in freshwater sites in southern Chile, and research the impact of salmon farming on the environment, public health, human rights, and indigenous peoples in southern Chile.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GLOB040" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Greengrants Fund, Inc.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="364061" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centro Ecoceanos</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chile</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="313" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="12262" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">40000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
