<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-20410132</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the funds, ZIMSOFF/Shashe Agro Ecology School will promote conservation of biomass, gender equality, and ecologically sustainable activities among resettled farmers in the Shashe block. The ecological region (region IV) is arid and receives only 400mm of rainfall in normal seasons. Water availability is related to the biomass in the area; however, resettled farmers are cutting down forests and deforestation rates are increasing to a point where soil erosion is leading to gully formation. The resulting impacts are contributing to water table depletion, the silting of wetlands and streams, the drying up of boreholes, and the once perennial Shashe River becoming seasonal. Awareness of the importance of bio culture diversity and conservation is greatly needed to ensure that the remaining forests and the sacred but declining wetlands and springs are preserved. The group will raise awareness and develop integrated community based resource conservation action plan focused on sustainable bio culture conservation for Shashe farms; mainstream gender issues and integrate ecologically sustainable socio economic activities; facilitate sharing of good practices and innovation; and support documentation and dissemination of conservation good practices. Specifically, the group will map the historic timeline and gather baseline surveys; organize a 2 day workshop with stakeholders around planning and gender issues; facilitate the integration of gender related socio economic activities; organize farmer led resource conservation exchanges; and share information among local farmers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GLOB040" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Greengrants Fund, Inc.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="807968" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shashe Agro Ecology School</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="31164" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14031" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="41030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="41020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">5000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
