<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-20409175</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The network will identify activities and spheres where it can enact change to protect rural agricultural livelihoods, which particularly impacts women. Large international interests are focusing on the country&apos;s natural resources, which are gradually being degraded as the country develops. Currently the country is negotiating the signing of the Voluntary Partnership Agreement (VPA) of the Forest Law Enforcement, Governance, and Trade (FLEGT) within the European Union and REDD+ program, supported by larger donor entities. Forests and land are converted to large plantations by large monoculture agricultural and extractive companies, and rural lands are being captured. Many women in these areas depend on agricultural livelihoods, but they have little rights to the land or natural resources. With the funding, REFACOF Ivory Coast will analyze policy processes and investment and donor interests in the natural resource sector; document opportunities for the group to influence the processes; and search for spaces where the concerns of women can be introduced in policy and strategies around natural resources. Specifically, funds will help support a consultant on policy research; workshops to present research results, positioning, and strategy development; and communication and administration activities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GLOB040" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Greengrants Fund, Inc.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="807474" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Women&apos;s Network for Community Management of Forests</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CI" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="41020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="52010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="43040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">5000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
