<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-20669440</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Teso region in North Eastern Uganda has suffered from civil wars and instability, floods in 2007 and since 2009 begun to experience the negative consequences of climate variability manifested in unreliable and unpredictable weather patterns. These events resulted in the displacement of over 143,000 people, high poverty levels, and a negative impact on the delivery of social and development services such as health care, education and Agricultural Extension- food security to the people at the community and at the household levels. Serere district in Teso region has a population of 294,100 people (49.6% Male and 50.4% Female). Fishing is a major economic activity that has created a mobile population at the landing sites particularly in Kasilo county, Serere District. Serere has 20 health facilities that include: local government, NGO and privately owned. About 45% of the population is estimated to live within a distance of 5 KM from a health facility, thus far below the national average of 74%. Health Need Uganda (HNU) proposes to support the lower level health delivery system guided by the community participatory approach, and mainstream project interventions into local government services delivery structures. The project will aim at sustaining gains achieved in 2010-2012 in the 2 sub-counties of Serere and initiate pilot activities to additional 2 sub-counties in capacity-building and promotional exchange. The project activities will support and facilitate the functionality of Village Health Teams (VHT) in the 2 sub counties (and additional 2 sub counties of Serere district). The project will strengthen the function of public health facilities (HCIII/II) by establishing VHT working groups to support a platform where feedback on health services performance is shared with local leadership. To facilitate the process, training and supervision will be offered to VHTS and other community resource persons who will ensure that counselling and referrals are provided to families through home-to-home visits. Additionally, food demonstrations and support to establish kitchen gardens and improve sanitation (procedures to build pit latrines, tip taps, storage spaces, etc.) Will be offered through house model supported by VHTS.The project has four components:1) Scale up information, education and communication campaigns at public health facility and community on health, SRHR and HIV/AIDS;2) Strengthening community &#x2014; Public health facility service delivery;3) Promote community Safe Water and Sanitation education and promotion health environment;4) Promote food and nutrition practices at community.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="STOP422" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stop AIDS Now</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="554923" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Need Uganda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="52010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="12262" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="12250" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="13040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">46480</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
