<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-19040881</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over eight million people live a precarious existence in the overcrowded slums of Ethiopia&apos;s largest cities, and as many as one in three have no access to piped water or decent toilets. Many live in substandard accommodation, with limited opportunities to make a living, and many children, especially girls and orphans, cannot afford to go to school. SMCF works in the slums of five Ethiopian cities. They invest in local community organisations based in the slums that help to improve living conditions by upgrading housing, installing pit latrines and water kiosks. They run community schools for disadvantaged children, and promote urban agriculture so families can sell their produce in local markets. They invest in vocational and business training for local groups of women and young people who want to set up their own businesses. They also engage with local government to ensure that slum-upgrading programmes are responsive to local people&apos;s needs and aspirations. As a result of this project, tens of thousands of slum dwellers have better living conditions, which reduces the incidence of preventable diseases. Children receive a decent basic education and families have a more secure way of earning a living. Local governments are more accountable to local people, and systems are in place to ensure residents are consulted in slum development programmes</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="COMI416" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comic Relief</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="650497" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partners for Change Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="14032" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="52010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">4535120</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
