<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-19041274</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Workers and farmers involved in the fresh vegetable industry that exports to UK supermarkets are suffering from poor working conditions, unpredictable orders and low income. Farmers&#x2019; groups, workers&#x2019; representatives and management will receive training to understand workers&#x2019; rights and engage in more effective negotiations which lead to better working conditions. Through being better able to represent the interests of their members, workers and farmers&#x2019; representatives will improve the adoption and implementation of policies and laws by employers, reinforced by Kenya public authorities. A High Street Retailer will work in collaboration with a key supplier to influence change down the supply chain for the benefit of workers and farmers as well as improving efficiencies, lowering wastage and the costs of production and investing in the creation of better work-places. Improved worker-management relations will deliver higher wages and prices for workers and farmers and increased profits for business. The learning from the project will be shared to demonstrate a model where benefits and risks can be shared more fairly, the human rights of farmers and workers are respected and everybody has something to gain</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="COMI416" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comic Relief</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="650719" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Traidcraft or Traidcraft Exchange</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="311" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="331" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">758777</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
