<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-20409502</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GGF funding will be used to implement H.M. the King&apos;s New Theory which aims to maximize the land and water resource management for small scale agriculture. The Utokapat Foundation will be implementing this project in the Khlong Latmayom Floating Market Community, located in the Talinchan district of Bangkok and in the Ban Nong Ping Kai Community in Kamphaeng Phet Province. The Khlong Latmayom Floating Market is important source of water for agriculture in the area, as well as being a method or transportation and a destination for ecotourism. This project will focus on educating area residents and farmers on methods to control the quality of water and to conserve the canal for agricultural use. Kamphaeng Phet Province is area subject to harsh flood and drought problems on a yearly basis. In partnership with the Ban Nong Ping Kai Community Water Resource Management Committee, the Utokapat Foundation will work to mitigate these issues through creating a stronger irrigation system of water reservoirs and a distribution system for agricultural uses. Additionally, the group will work to increase the underground water volume to help alleviate water and soil problems caused by flooding. The Utokapat Foundation will be documenting their results and methods to use best practices in other communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GLOB040" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Greengrants Fund, Inc.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="697298" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Utokapat Foundation Under Royal Patronage of H M the King</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thailand</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="31140" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="41050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">20000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
