<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-20409608</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asamblea Permanente del Comahue por el Agua (Permanent Assembly of Comahue for Water) (APCA) aims to protect the environment of the Comahue region, especially its water resources, and the Mapuche community&apos;s rights to those lands. The area is one of the last agricultural production areas in Patagonia, producing fruit such as apples and pears for export and internal consumption. The indigenous people living in that biodiverse environment, which is dominated by glaciers and large rivers, are mainly migratory livestock herders. These people are increasingly being threatened by diminished and contaminated water sources, as well as serious health problems, due to extractive activities, and in particular fracking. The organization plans on equipping a local radio broadcast to inform local communities about the harmful effects of extractive activities. Furthermore, the group aims to edit their book Fracking NO ES NO, and to edit and release a short documentary about the issue titled Voces del agua, voces de la vida (Voices of water, voices of life). Finally, the organization will create 10 murals dedicated to Cristina Linkopan, and will host awareness building workshops about strategies to prevent water contamination. Around 150 women, 100 men, 200 youth, and 80 indigenous people will be involved in the projects.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GLOB040" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Greengrants Fund, Inc.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="807451" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asamblea Permanente del Comahue por el Agua</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="AR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Argentina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="14031" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31163" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="322" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">5000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
