<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-20408575</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">For The Centro Misionero para la Educacion Popular Asociacion para un Desarrollo Integral y Sustenable (CEMEP ADIS) will use the funds to strengthen the production and educational capacity of the Multigranja Integral Agroecologica (the Agro Ecological Comprehensive Multigranja or farming unit) to help member campesinos, particularly from Cinturon de Amortiguacion in the Misiones Province, produce healthy foods while protecting their water and soil. The Misiones Province is at the center of the Guarani Aquifer, which is the third most important fresh water reserve in the world. However, this region experiences massive deforestation (in the province over 20,000 hectares of native forests are lost each year) and the indiscriminant use of agro toxins. The Multigranja is made up of 14 member campesino, or rural farming, communities, some of which are the poorest in Cinturon de Amortiguacion. It promotes sustainable farming and polyculture to protect the surrounding jungle and produce marketable and healthy food. The group will develop the Multigranja&apos;s sustainable water management plan and promote it to neighboring farmers; strengthen its production of foods and seeds; develop commercialization of its and neighboring farmers&apos; agro ecologically produced goods in the Mercado de Posadas (Posadas City&apos;s market); and raise awareness between the families of the Multigranja of the importance of protecting the environment. In total, 50 campesino families will participate in workshops around water management, and the group will work with 10 families to convert their farms to more sustainable models and sell their produce in the Posadas market.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GLOB040" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Greengrants Fund, Inc.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="538960" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centro Misionero para la Educacion Popular (Asociacion para un Desarrollo Integral y Sustentable)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="AR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Argentina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="31164" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="312" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="43040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14015" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">17500</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
