<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-20408859</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support Gobi Soil&apos;s efforts to defend rights of local herders in the face of mining development in the Khanbogd Soum area. The International Financial Corporation and Multilateral Investment Guarantee Agency is providing financing and a political risk guarantee package to Oyu Tolgoi LLC for the implementation of the copper gold silver mining project in the Gobi Desert. Oyu Tolgoi LLC is expected to publicly disclose the operational management plans associated with the Environmental and Social Impact Assessment (ESIA) in the fall of 2013. In addition, the loan negotiation process has stalled due to conflicts between the Mongolian Government and Rio Tinto over the substantially increased project costs, making this a pivotal moment to act for Mongolian civil society organizations. The funds will be used to meet up with IFC management and decision makers at the World Bank Group&apos;s Annual Meetings in October 2013. Gobi Soil will organize at least three capacity building and strategy planning sessions in Khanbogd Soum with the assistance of national and international organizations. The sessions will include one experience sharing and alliance building training for local civil society organizations and one consensus building discussion meeting for all affected households in the Khanbogd Soum area.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GLOB040" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Greengrants Fund, Inc.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="807250" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gobi Soil</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mongolia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="410" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31163" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="43040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">5000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
