<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-18995885</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is based in Beed district in the rural Marathwada region of Maharashtra state in India. It addresses the extreme poverty and insecurity of Dalits, particularly women. It does this through a three-stage model: 1. Increasing security of land tenure; 2. Sustainable livelihoods through organic farming and women&apos;s self-help groups; 3. Increasing capacity to tackle caste-based violence. The promotion of gender equality is integrated throughout the project activities. Nature of the solution: 1. Increasing security of land tenure ... a central strategy to eliminate the poverty and vulnerability of women in developing countries. In the case of Dalit women, land rights helps to challenge their marginalisation due to caste and gender. In order to gain land rights, the RDC will focus on following up approximately 2,000 land rights claims made to the government by Dalits from 4 districts in Marathwada. 2. Sustainable livelihoods. 2A. Organic Farming: The value of possessing land will be maximised by enabling income-generation through organic farming; 2B Self-help groups: Through their participation in self-help groups, women have undertaken micro-economic activities; 2C Entitlements: The project will facilitate a bottom-up process to create a demand for the productive utilisation of government funds and schemes that have been ear-marked for Dalits. 3. Increasing capacity to tackle caste-based violence. Dalit communities will be empowered to fight discrimination by lobbying the government to improve the implementation of &apos;S.C./S.T Prevention of Atrocities Act&apos; on the one hand and attempt to build confidence measures with the dominant castes by engaging with opinion makers such as the village panchayat leaders , educational institutions, spiritual leaders</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="ANON023" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anonymous 5</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="579475" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Karuna Trust</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="1264418">
   <location-id code="1264418" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">State of Mah&#x101;r&#x101;shtra, India</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="31164" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">131286</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
