<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-20409036</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The group will create and strengthen community water management boards, through which members will be able to advocate for water rights in the SENAGUA (Secretaria Nacional del Agua) and strengthen the anti mining resistance movement defending water and community territories. The group is working to defend water resources and rights from mining projects within its territories. The group will organize campaigns to raise awareness about the distortion of information from the government about mining impacts and problems. It will denounce the current process of criminalization of resistance to these projects, which is a protected right guaranteed by Ecuador&apos;s Constitution. Specifically, the group will organize workshops for communities on constitutional rights and guarantees, environmental rights, the human right to water, and water laws presented to the National Assembly. It will develop organizational workshops with the community water boards on the consequences of mining and the loss of water, actions to advocate for water rights in SENAGUA, and the creation of a proposal for a new lifestyle that incorporates agroecology, food sovereignty, ecotourism, and alternative communication tools. The group will support organizational spaces in the south and at the national level. This will strengthen the organization and the Assembly of the Austro and Southern communities as a regional organization for the resistance against a model dependent on extractive industry. Additionally, it will initiate local governmental policies that defend the environment, water, and territories and stop the criminalization of social protests.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GLOB040" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Greengrants Fund, Inc.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="649454" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coordinadora Intercantonal del Jubones en Defensa de la Vida y la Naturaleza</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="EC" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecuador</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="14031" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="52010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="43040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">5000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
