<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-19040973</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Whilst poverty levels in Uganda are on the whole on the decline, in the north of the country over half the population still live in poverty. Two decades of civil war and a high prevalence of HIV/AIDS have left women in the region more vulnerable than ever before. After the civil war, women returned from camps to head families with an average of six dependents, including children orphaned by the war. Agriculture is the main source of income for rural households and 90% of employees are women. Trust for Africa&apos;s Orphans runs a project for the cultivation of sunflowers, a commercial crop experiencing increased demand and prices, which can be grown alongside traditional food crops. The project supports women to own land, enhance productivity of crops and access more profitable markets. As a result, women and their families gain increased income, better education, and improved nutrition for all, especially those living with HIV/AIDS. As part of this grant, Trust for Africa&apos;s Orphans have received a grant of 96,296 to enable them to reduce the impact of climate change on the people benefitting from the project</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="COMI416" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comic Relief</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="650550" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trust for Africa&apos;s Orphans</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <sector code="311" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="12240" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="410" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="43040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">624823</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
