<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-131837418-19041060</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-131837418" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation Center</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Extreme poverty in Ethiopia&#x2019;s cities has increased sharply in recent years, as vast numbers of people migrate from rural areas in the hope of finding work. Ethiopia&#x2019;s second largest city, Dire Dawa, is in one of the driest parts of the country and has been particularly affected by this rapid influx. Two thirds of the population live in slums where housing, safe water and decent sanitation are either inadequate or non-existent. The majority of households are headed by women, who are particularly vulnerable as they struggle daily for food, shelter and other basic necessities. Inevitably, these marginalised communities have little influence on government decisions regarding slum upgrading. This project will enable slum dwellers themselves to start to change this desperate situation. Some will be assisted to earn income from urban agriculture and small businesses. Loans for repairs and improvements to housing will help to improve living conditions, and new latrines and community kitchens will greatly improve sanitation and hygiene. These interventions will be managed and delivered by established grass-roots organisations, resulting in increased community confidence to participate in slum upgrading debates and decisions. The project will not only bring about positive change in the lives of some of the most vulnerable slum dwellers, but will also strengthen their capacity to lead future initiatives and improvements in their own communities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="COMI416" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comic Relief</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="832451" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Co-operation and Research in Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="14031" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14032" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="52010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="32120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">758578</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
