<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>CH-FDJP-CHE109994012-MoFA - 2018</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="CH-FDJP-CHE109994012" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interpeace</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dutch core grant</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs core grant 2018: The grant reported here was part of a 3-year core grant running from 01/2016 to 12/2018 with a total budget of 8,550,000USD. Interpeace started reporting in compliance with IATI as of 2018, which is why data for that year is presented seperately here. The data from the previous years of the grant were reported to the donor at the time.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="CH-FDJP-CHE109994012" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interpeace</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <telephone>00410224045900</telephone>
   <email>info@interpeace.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CH" percentage="71"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="29" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2850000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-02-02">800000</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Netherlands</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-04">2050000</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Netherlands</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-28">2850000</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Netherlands</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="NL">An organization-wide Change Framework is developed and appro</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Change Framework developed and approved by Governing Board</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">An organization-wide Change Framework is developed and approved by the Governing Board

The need for an organization-wide Change Framework was identified through Interpeace&#x2019;s institutional review process in 2017, which identified that while Interpeace&#x2019;s vision and mission were clearly articulated and understood by all of its stakeholders, the pathways to create the desired change and impact towards sustainable peace were less clear and explicit. 

Responding to this assessment and recommendation, Interpeace therefore undertook to develop a comprehensive organization-wide Change Framework in 2018 which clearly sets out the different ways in which the organization pursues its overall objectives and impact goals. This will help strengthen both programming and policy as well as communications efforts of the organization.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of Change Frameworks that exist</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">Number of Change Frameworks that exist</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of Change Frameworks that exist</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">Number of Change Frameworks that exist</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Greater agility/scope in prog. dev. and mgmt. is developed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Greater agility and scope in programme development and management is developed

Developing new programmes allows Interpeace to have a greater impact in fulfilling the first part of its mandate, namely to strengthen the capacities of societies to manage conflict in non-violent, non-coercive ways, by assisting national actors in their efforts to develop social and political cohesion. 

The core funding by the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs that Interpeace receives is an essential contribution to programme development, which is dependent upon the organization having the financial freedom to explore if its approach could add value in new contexts. This often leads to leveraging of further funds to support the newly developed programmes, thus multiplying the impact of the seed investment made possible through core funding. 

Developing new programme work also contributes to attaining the overall goal of the Dutch Security and Rule of Law Division (SRoL) Theory of Change to &#x201C;enhance &#x2018;legitimate&#x2019; stability and sustainable peace in fragile contexts in order to achieve sustainable development&#x201D;.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># countries in which program development has been conducted</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL"># countries in which program development has been conducted</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of countries in which programme development has been undertaken</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">Number of countries in which programme development has been undertaken</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expanding the scope and reach of Interpeace programmes allows the organization to have more impact in preventing violence and building peace, notably in new and emerging conflict situations. Developing programmes in fragile countries in an agile yet carefully calibrated manner enables Interpeace to contribute to reducing violence and enhancing security, as well as increasing inclusion and resilience. This can create the conditions for sustainable development at the heart of the Security and Rule of Law Division (SRoL) Theory of Change. In 2018, Interpeace undertook programme development  in the Democratic Republic of Congo, Burkina Faso, and Tunisia.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># new grants secured for programmes</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL"># new grants secured for programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of new grants secured for programmes</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">Number of new grants secured for programmes</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="26" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="26"></target>
     <actual value="26">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">To guarantee the sustainability of existing programmes and to create more impact through expansion and new programmes, securing new programme specific grants is essential for Interpeace.

The core funding helps initiate and maintain programmatic activities over the long-term, which is essential to effective peacebuilding and securing earmarked funding from other partners who want to build on and scale up existing activities. This multiplies the impact of the investments made in ongoing programmes from core funding. The volume of new programme specific grants demonstrates the leveraging effect of core funding.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># programmes that have undergone a strategic review process</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL"># programmes that have undergone a strategic review process</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of programmes that have undergone a strategic review process</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">Number of programmes that have undergone a strategic review process</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="3" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">One of the key strengths of Interpeace is its ability to continuously adapt to changing contexts and emerging crises. While sustainability lies at the heart of Interpeace programmes, it is essential to regularly conduct a strategic review of programmes and adapt them to changing contexts or needs, if necessary, to ensure their continued relevance and impact.

Core funding by the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs enables the organization to engage in this important exercise in a rigorous way that goes beyond what would be possible with earmarked funding alone. In 2018, programmes in Kenya, the Democratic Republic of Congo, Burundi, Rwanda, as well as the regional Great Lakes programme have undergone strategic reviews.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inst. systems refined to max. accountability and efficiency</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institutional systems are refined to maximize accountability, efficiency and reporting

Enhanced accountability, efficiency and reporting are key to create the transparency and trust required to engage in effective, long-term peacebuilding. We are committed to efficiency and transparency to ensure the best use of resources towards our institutional objectives and impact goals. Having modern, agile and efficient institutional systems in place, enhances Interpeace&#x2019;s ability to carry out its peacebuilding work.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># IT systems updated or newly introduced</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL"># IT systems updated or newly introduced</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of IT systems updated or newly introduced</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">Number of IT systems updated or newly introduced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6"></target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">As a leading peacebuilding organization, our IT systems need to fit our aspirations and professionalism in our programmatic and policy work. The new and updated systems ensure that our technological level is aligned with the quality of our work, with the ultimate objective of increasing our peacebuilding impact. The new IT systems allow Interpeace to communicate faster internally and externally and organize data in a more structured way, which is of crucial importance in an organization with a decentralized structure and a multitude of local partners in the field. The following IT systems have been updated or newly introduced:
1. Natural HR: A human resource management system that allows for the streamlining of HR operations in Interpeace globally, which facilitates and improves the HR management. 
2. Sun Systems upgrade: Upgrade of existing financial software for improved financial management and hence transparency and accountability across the decentralized structure of the organization. 
3. Internal Controls Checklist: Internally developed tool to monitor finance controls across the organization to ensure accountability.
4. Microsoft Teams: a collaboration tool that enables easier communication and tracking of internal work in the organization, particularly for teams who work across different locations.
5. ProjectConnect:  A project management tool which enables, among other things, the efficient collection of data and production of the IATI reporting that helps us more effectively capture and transparently report our results.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># updated or newly created institutional policies/manuals</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL"># updated or newly created institutional policies/manuals</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of updated or newly created institutional policies or manuals</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">Number of updated or newly created institutional policies or manuals</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6"></target>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institutional policy manuals provide guidance to our staff and streamline our approaches in line with the Change Framework and the strategic objectives of the organization. This enhances coherence and efficiency in our work on programme development and management, operations, policy and external engagement/communications, which ultimately allows us to have greater impact in building sustainable peace. This is all the more important in view of the decentralized structure of the organization. In 2018 the following policies were developed or updated: travel policy, whistle-blower policy, approval matrix, and gender policy.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% completion of a review of the institutional compensation</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">% completion of a review of the institutional compensation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of completion of a review of the institutional compensation model</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">Percentage of completion of a review of the institutional compensation model</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="20" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Having a transparent and unified compensation model in place, which  is aligned with each employee&#x2019;s duty station market and reflects the job size and contribution value of each position at Interpeace, is key to create equity, equal pay for equal value and underpins staff motivation and performance. A well-designed compensation model also ensures that the organization is able to attract and retain the talent it requires while spending its resources effectively and transparently. 

Interpeace&#x2019;s compensation model required a revision to ensure its ongoing competiveness and continued relevance in a sector where the talent pool is transforming.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% completion of an institutional review process</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">% completion of an institutional review process</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of completion of an institutional review process</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">Percentage of completion of an institutional review process</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="30" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following almost 25 years of operations and continuous adaptation of its structures, systems and processes, Interpeace&#x2019;s board decided that it would benefit the organization&#x2019;s health and ability to have the best possible impact to carry out an external review. 

This review was successfully completed in 2018 and informed institutional adaptations to key strategic developments in Interpeace&#x2019;s environment to ensure maximum efficiency and effectiveness.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% staff who have completed their annual performance review</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">% staff who have completed their annual performance review</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of staff who have completed their annual performance review</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">Percentage of staff who have completed their annual performance review</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="83" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="85"></target>
     <actual value="80">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The staff of Interpeace are the backbone of our organization and make our peacebuilding work possible. Having satisfied, motivated and effective staff that work towards commonly agreed objectives is key 
to achieving our overall objectives laid down in the Change Framework. At Interpeace, Performance management is the ongoing process of planning, measuring, monitoring, and developing employee performance. Performance management focuses on continuous constructive dialogue and feedback about past performance and future development. Effective performance management is always based on a two-way exchange between the staff member and the manager: 

Performance management and associated discussions are an ongoing and regular process, but once a year, the outcomes of these discussions are formally documented via the performance review process.  

The performance review process can contribute to personal growth, increased employee engagement and job satisfaction. In addition, performance reviews are an integral element of the staff members&#x2019; personnel files, capturing and ensuring that institutional records are kept for future reference.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policy lessons infused in hum. and sec. sector interventions</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peacebuilding policy lessons have been infused in humanitarian and security sector interventions, through interventions, accompaniment and collaboration

If actors delivering humanitarian and security sector interventions adopt conflict-sensitive approaches and develop capacity to strengthen resilience to violent conflict through their programs, then these interventions will more effectively contribute to achieving sustainable peace because they will avoid unintentional exacerbation of conflict and strengthen local capacities for conflict prevention and transformation.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># donor government political leaders engaged in dialogue</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL"># donor government political leaders engaged in dialogue</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of donor government political leaders engaged in political dialogue</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">Number of donor government political leaders engaged in political dialogue</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7"></target>
     <actual value="14">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Engaging political leaders of donor governments in political dialogue is equally important to fulfil the second part of Interpeace&#x2019;s mandate. It&#x2019;s moreover a key component of Interpeace&#x2019;s track 6 strategy, aiming to better align lessons learned at the field level with the political priorities and policies of governments and international organizations. When tracks 1, 2 and 3 achieve greater levels of coherence and complementarity, can our peacebuilding approaches be truly sustainable.

If the lessons shared by Interpeace are received and understood by political leaders, there is a greater chance that the policies and interventions they will shape will reflect peacebuilding principles and approaches.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># new partnerships with international humanitarian orgs</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL"># new partnerships with international humanitarian orgs</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of new partnerships with international humanitarian organisations concluded</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">Number of new partnerships with international humanitarian organisations concluded</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Working across institutional silos and together with humanitarian organizations is essential to ensuring that humanitarian interventions contribute longer term to reducing violence and sustaining peace, in addition to meeting short-term humanitarian needs.

Interpeace concludes partnerships with humanitarian organizations to guide them in adapting their programs in a way that includes conflict sensitive approaches and actions that increase capacities of local resilience and conflict prevention/transformation. In 2018 such a partnership was concluded with the International Federation of the Red Cross and Red Crescent (IFRC).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># donor governments engaged in political dialogue</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL"># donor governments engaged in political dialogue</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of donor governments engaged in political dialogue</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">Number of donor governments engaged in political dialogue</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="3" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6"></target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Engaging donor governments in political dialogues helps Interpeace to fulfil the second part of its mandate, namely to assist the international community (and in particular the United Nations) to play a more effective role in supporting peacebuilding&#x2019;s efforts around the world.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">An organization-wide Change Framework is mainstreamed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The articulation of an organization-wide Change Framework allows Interpeace to work more effectively towards its institutional objective of advancing sustainable peace. It enables staff to design and implement activities utilizing clearly defined effective pathways of change to attain this objective and the organization&#x2019;s three underlying impact goals: 1) Reduced Violence and Enhanced Security; 2) More Inclusion and Increased Resilience; 3) Systemic Progress in Peacebuilding Influence and Practice. 

The Change Framework also informs monitoring and evaluation efforts to enable Interpeace to more effectively track and report on the impacts it is collectively achieving as an organization. This comes at a time when the organization is also increasing its capacity to influence international policy with insights drawn from programming.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% staff who know the Change Framework</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">% staff who know the Change Framework</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of staff who know the Change Framework</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="NL">Percentage of staff who know the Change Framework</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interpeace developed an organization-wide change framework through a participatory process in 2018. As a first step towards ensuring all of the organization&#x2019;s programmes and initiatives are designed and implemented in pursuit of the identified institutional objectives and impact goals, a process was subsequently undertaken to closely familiarize all staff with the Change Framework and its implications for their work. 

The framework is reflected in the 2019 workplan for the organization. The framework in place now also allows Interpeace to speak with one voice and more effectively contribute to the shared goal of sustainable peace.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
