<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://data.mcc.gov/" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:mcc="https://data.mcc.gov/ns#" xmlns:usg="http://foreignassistance.gov/iati#">
  <iati-identifier>US-18-BE2-2750BXCOMD</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-18" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benin II-Compact</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benin Power Compact: This program targets poor electricity infrastructure, a binding constraint to economic growth in Benin, where the insufficient quantity and quality of electricity results in reduced productivity, output, and investment for businesses, less effective delivery of public and social services and diminished well-being and economic opportunity for households. This program will address these core problems through policy reforms and institutional strengthening, large-scale investments in energy generation and distribution infrastructure and off-grid electrification to expand access in a country where only one-third of the population has access to electricity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-8" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Account - Benin</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States of America</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-22" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administration &amp; Finance</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Open Data Team</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>202-521-3618</telephone>
   <email>opendata@mcc.gov</email>
   <website>data.mcc.gov</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1099 14th Street NW, Suite 700, Washington, DC 20005-3550</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="BJ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benin</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-12">34226401</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-12">54705786</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-12">57259771</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-12">61559754</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-12">67121766</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-12">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/where-we-work/err/benin-power-compact">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Rate of Return</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A03"></category>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/benin-power-compact-me-plan">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benin Power Compact Monitoring and Evaluation Plan</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A03"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.mcc.gov/content/uploads/2017/05/Benin_CA_withCover.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benin Power Compact Constraints Analysis</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.mcc.gov/content/uploads/compact-benin-power-amendment.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benin Power Compact Amendment</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <category code="A11"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.mcc.gov/content/uploads/2017/05/compact-benin-power.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benin Power Compact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <category code="A11"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.mcc.gov/where-we-work/program/benin-power-compact">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benin Power Compact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A06"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/benin-power-compact-kpi">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benin Power Compact Key Performance Indicators</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-BE2-2750BX69GD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-BE2-2750BXCOMD-ACCESSELEC" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-BE2-2750BXCOMD-ELEC DIST" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-BE2-2750BXCOMD-ELEC GEN" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-BE2-2750BXCOMD-MON &amp; EVAL" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-BE2-2750BXCOMD-NA" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-BE2-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-BE2-2750BXCOMD-PWR REFORM" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-BE2-2750BXDILD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-BEN-2750BX69GD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-BEN-2750BXCOMD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-BEN-2750BXDILD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-BJ" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCA-Benin II has developed the FAP (or an interim version), and the plan has been approved by MCC. FAP accepted by MCC on August 3, 2016.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCC has determined in its sole discretion that no material default or breach of any covenant, obligation or responsibility by the Government, MCA-Benin II or any Government entity has occurred and is continuing under the Compact, PIA or any other Supplemental Agreement, or under any systems, rules, policies, plans or guidance issued by MCA-Benin II or the Government (including CEB and SBEE) in fulfillment of any obligation set forth in the Compact or PIA  (including any condition set forth in PIA Annex III.  GoB is in compliance with the Tariff Plan.  GOB is in compliance with Government Arrears Payment Plan.  GOB annual budget provides sufficient resources for Selected Government Entities to pay their reasonably anticipated electricity bills.  Unpaid GOB electricity bills incurred since Compact signing will not be more than 60 days past due.  GOB will ensure that the annual budget provides sufficient resources for ARE.  GOB prepares a gas policy.  Continued compliance with installation of pre-paid meters covenant.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to Disbursement of Program Funding after first anniversary of EIF, MCC and the Gov?t must have revised Annex III of the Compact.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID for Program Funding, MCA-Benin II will have developed and adopted an environmental, social, health and safety management system (?ESHSMS?) (including a stakeholder engagement plan) in accordance with the MCC Environmental Guidelines (including the IFC Performance Standards that are incorporated by reference therein).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding MCC has determined that the Gov?t has satisfied all of its payment obligations, including any insurance, indemnification, tax payments or other obligations, and contributed all resources required from it, under the Compact, the PIA and any other Supplemental Agreement.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCA-Benin II must deliver to MCC, a certificate of MCA-Benin II, dated as of the date of such Disbursement Request, substantially in the form provided by MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCA-Benin II must deliver to MCC, a certificate of the Fiscal Agent, substantially in the form provided by MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCA-Benin II must deliver to MCC, a certificate of the Procurement Agent, substantially in the form provided by MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCA-Benin II must deliver to MCC, a completed Disbursement Request, together with the Periodic Reports covering the related Disbursement Period.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCA-Benin II must deliver to MCC, copies of any reports from any technical (including environmental) auditors engaged by MCA-Benin II for any Activity delivered since the previous Disbursement Request.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCC has determined that MCA-Benin II has complied in all material respects with its obligations set forth PIA ?2.3 with respect to the establishment of an M&amp;E Plan.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCC has determined that MCA-Benin II has complied in all material respects with its obligations set forth in PIA ?2.1(d) with respect to the establishment of a Bid Challenge System.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCC has determined that MCC does not have grounds for concluding that any matter certified to it in the related MCA Disbursement Certificate, Procurement Agent Disbursement Certificate or Fiscal Agent Disbursement Certificate is not as certified.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCC has determined that all Gov?t entities involved in the implementation of the Program, including the Implementing Entities, are coordinating successfully with MCA-Benin II and dedicating the necessary staff and other resources to ensure successful implementation of the Program.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCC has determined that any Implementing Entity Agreements appropriate or necessary for MCA-Benin II to implement the Activities contemplated during the Disbursement Period have been executed and delivered to MCC and are in full force and effect.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCC has determined that any Taxes paid with MCC Funding through the date 90 days prior to the start of the applicable Disbursement Period have been reimbursed by the Gov?t in full in accordance with ?2.8(c) of the Compact.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCC has determined that each of the Officers remains engaged, or if a position is vacant, MCA-Benin II is actively engaged, to MCC?s satisfaction, in recruiting a replacement.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCC has determined that no act, omission, condition, or event has occurred that would be the basis for MCC to suspend or terminate, in whole or in part, the Compact or MCC Funding in accordance with ?5.1 of the Compact.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCC has determined that the Gov?t (including CEB and SBEE) or MCA-Benin II, as applicable, has made sufficient progress on implementing any systems, rules, policies, plans or guidance issued by the Gov?t or MCA-Benin II, as the case may be, in fulfillment of any obligation set forth in the Compact or the PIA (including any condition set forth in Annex III of the PIA).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCC has determined that the Gov?t has complied in all material respects with its obligations set forth in PIA ?2.13 with respect to the making of its contributions in accordance with the projected timeline set forth in Annex IV of the PIA.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCC has determined that the Gov?t has obtained MCC?s written consent to any modification of any systems, rules, policies, plans or guidance issued by the Gov?t or MCA-Benin II, as the case may be, in fulfillment of any obligation set forth in the Compact or the PIA (including any condition set forth in Annex III).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCC has determined that the Implementation Plan Documents and FAP are current and updated and are in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, and there has been progress satisfactory to MCC on the components of the Implementation Plan for any relevant Projects or Activities related to such Disbursement.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCC has determined that the activities to be funded with such Disbursement will not violate any applicable law or regulation.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCC has determined that there has been no material negative finding in any financial audit report delivered in accordance with the Compact and Audit Plan, for the prior two quarters (or such other period as the Audit Plan may require).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCC has determined that there has been progress satisfactory to MCC on the Gov?t?s implementation of the Master Plan and the Additional Sector Documents.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding and each Disbursement of Program Funding, MCC has determined that there has been progress satisfactory to MCC on the M&amp;E Plan and Social and Gender Integration Plan for the Program, relevant Project or Activity and substantial compliance with the requirements of the M&amp;E Plan and Social and Gender Integration Plan (including the targets set forth therein and any applicable reporting requirements set forth therein for the relevant Disbursement Period).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding, MCA-Benin II has developed a complete Implementation Plan.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding, each of the Officers has been selected and engaged by MCA-Benin II and approved by MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to ID of Program Funding, the Compact must enter into force as provided in Article 7 of the Compact.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to any Disbursement of Program Funding on or after the commencement of year 5 of the Compact Term, the Gov?t must submit to MCC, an initial draft of the Compact Closure Plan in accordance with the MCC Program Closure Guidelines.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to second Disbursement of Program Funding, MCA-Benin II must develop and approve a comprehensive Social &amp; Gender Integration Plan.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to the initial Disbursement of Program Funding for payment under a particular works or construction contract for a given Project or Activity, MCA-Benin II must submit to MCC evidence that MCA-Benin II or the appropriate Gov?t entity has developed and adopted, or validated, as the case may be, an environmental and social impact assessment (?ESIA?), an environmental and social management plan (?ESMP?), or a resettlement action plan (?RAP?) (as appropriate) with respect to such Project or Activity.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Gov?t has adopted the Governing Documents necessary to ensure MCA-Benin II?s operation, and such Governing Documents are in full force and effect. Completed on Nov. 29, 2015.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benin II-2750BXCOMD Results</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Telecommunication system equipment installed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date Output of All telecommunication system equipment installed according to contractual specifications</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A - Date Indicator" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All telecommunication system equipment installed according to contractual specifications Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-22"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-06-22"></period-end>
     <target value="1/20/2021">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">All telecommunication system equipment installed according to contractual specifications Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A - Date Indicator">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">All telecommunication system equipment installed according to contractual specifications Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Validation and adoption of tariff study report</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date Process of Date of Tariff Policy and Tariff Plan approval by the government</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A - Date Indicator" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date of Tariff Policy and Tariff Plan approval by the government Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-22"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-06-22"></period-end>
     <target value="2/28/2018">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date of Tariff Policy and Tariff Plan approval by the government Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="10/26/2017">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date of Tariff Policy and Tariff Plan approval by the government Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Approval of IPP institutional framework</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date Process of Date of approval for IPP institutional framework</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A - Date Indicator" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date of approval for IPP institutional framework Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-22"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-06-22"></period-end>
     <target value="7/17/2018">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date of approval for IPP institutional framework Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7/31/2019">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date of approval for IPP institutional framework Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transactions advisor installed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date Output of Date of installation of the Transactions Advisor</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A - Date Indicator" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date of installation of the Transactions Advisor Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-22"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-06-22"></period-end>
     <target value="12/4/2017">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date of installation of the Transactions Advisor Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="12/5/2017">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date of installation of the Transactions Advisor Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">PTA adoption in accordance with Contract Plan</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date Output of Dates on which the PTA is adopted by SBEE management</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A - Date Indicator" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dates on which the PTA is adopted by SBEE management Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-22"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-06-22"></period-end>
     <target value="11/29/2017">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dates on which the PTA is adopted by SBEE management Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="11/29/2017">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dates on which the PTA is adopted by SBEE management Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Budget adoption in accordance with Contract Plan</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date Output of Dates on which the budget is adopted by SBEE management</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A - Date Indicator" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dates on which the budget is adopted by SBEE management Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-22"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-06-22"></period-end>
     <target value="11/29/2017">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dates on which the budget is adopted by SBEE management Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="11/29/2017">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dates on which the budget is adopted by SBEE management Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Dispatch Control Center constructed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date Output of Final acceptance of construction is received according to contractual specifications</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A - Date Indicator" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final acceptance of construction is received according to contractual specifications Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-22"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-06-22"></period-end>
     <target value="2/16/2021">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final acceptance of construction is received according to contractual specifications Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A - Date Indicator">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final acceptance of construction is received according to contractual specifications Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Approval of cost-reflective tariffs</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date Output of Indicator for Benin II-2750BXCOMD</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A - Date Indicator" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator for Benin II-2750BXCOMD Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-22"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-06-22"></period-end>
     <target value="8/24/2018">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator for Benin II-2750BXCOMD Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A - Date Indicator">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator for Benin II-2750BXCOMD Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Approval of Tariff Policy and Tariff Plan</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date Process of Indicator for Benin II-2750BXCOMD</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A - Date Indicator" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator for Benin II-2750BXCOMD Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-22"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-06-22"></period-end>
     <target value="7/27/2018">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator for Benin II-2750BXCOMD Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A - Date Indicator">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator for Benin II-2750BXCOMD Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Back-up National Dispatch Control Center constructed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date Output of Provisional acceptance of construction is received according to contractual specifications</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A - Date Indicator" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provisional acceptance of construction is received according to contractual specifications Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-22"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-06-22"></period-end>
     <target value="1/12/2021">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provisional acceptance of construction is received according to contractual specifications Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A - Date Indicator">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provisional acceptance of construction is received according to contractual specifications Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supervisory control data acquisition (SCADA) equipment installed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date Output of SCADA installed according to contractual specifications</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A - Date Indicator" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">SCADA installed according to contractual specifications Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-22"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-06-22"></period-end>
     <target value="2/16/2021">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">SCADA installed according to contractual specifications Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A - Date Indicator">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">SCADA installed according to contractual specifications Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kilometers of distribution lines upgraded or built</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of The sum of linear kilometers of new, reconstructed, rehabilitated, or upgraded distribution lines that have been energized, tested and commissioned with MCC support.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The sum of linear kilometers of new, reconstructed, rehabilitated, or upgraded distribution lines that have been energized, tested and commissioned with MCC support. Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-22"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-06-22"></period-end>
     <target value="979.58">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The sum of linear kilometers of new, reconstructed, rehabilitated, or upgraded distribution lines that have been energized, tested and commissioned with MCC support. Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The sum of linear kilometers of new, reconstructed, rehabilitated, or upgraded distribution lines that have been energized, tested and commissioned with MCC support. Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Distribution substation capacity added</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of The total added substation capacity, measured in megavolt amperes, that is energized, commissioned and accompanied by a test report and supervising engineer?s certification resulting from new construction or refurbishment of existing substations supported</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total added substation capacity, measured in megavolt amperes, that is energized, commissioned and accompanied by a test report and supervising engineer?s certification resulting from new construction or refurbishment of existing substations supported Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-22"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-06-22"></period-end>
     <target value="1088.5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total added substation capacity, measured in megavolt amperes, that is energized, commissioned and accompanied by a test report and supervising engineer?s certification resulting from new construction or refurbishment of existing substations supported Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total added substation capacity, measured in megavolt amperes, that is energized, commissioned and accompanied by a test report and supervising engineer?s certification resulting from new construction or refurbishment of existing substations supported Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
