<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Neet&apos;s net: Networked for inclusive and sustainable economic  growth. Decent work, entrepreneurship, skills acquisition and  participation of vulnerab</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In a context where the workforce skills are inadequate compared to the needs of the labour market, where 
employment opportunities are scarce and difficult to access and where youth employment is marked by 
precariousness and insecurity, the economic growth does not have a positive impact on the living conditions of 
young Cameroonians, especially the most vulnerable ones. The latter are increasingly exposed to 
unemployment, underemployment, vulnerable employment, impoverishment and are, consequently, victims of 
frustration, which can lead to political turmoil, radicalisation, crime, or illegal migration.
In response to the identified needs and considering the specific needs and different aspirations of boys and girls, 
including ex-detainees, at-risk youth, people with disabilities, migrants and internally displaced people, the 
project Neet&apos;s net: Networked for inclusive and sustainable economic growth. Decent work, entrepreneurship, 
skills acquisition and participation of vulnerable girls and boys promotes decent employment, entrepreneurship, 
skills acquisition, and participation in inclusive and sustainable economic growth of young people between 15 
and 24 years old, especially young women and young people in vulnerable situations, in the cities of Mbalmayo, 
Bafoussam and Garoua in Cameroon. 
The intervention, within 36 months, proposes: 
- solutions for skills mismatch, providing 800 boys and girls excluded from the school system with recognized 
technical, vocational, IT and entrepreneurial skills which are matched to existing job opportunities by 
strengthening and diversifying the training offer and the testing of a certification system for formal, informal 
and non-formal skills;
- strategies to promote employment, enabling 1,890 young men and women to obtain more employment 
opportunities, and more accessible ones, thanks to various services to promote orientation, the matching of job supply and demand, assisted employment tools and technical and financial support to start, formalize, optimize 
or manage a sustainable small enterprise;
- protection and social promotion, enabling 2,690 boys and girls to make their voices heard and be represented, 
to access the social protection system and to claim their right to decent work and the opportunity to participate 
in the economic and social development of the cities where they live.
COE (leading partner) is in a Temporary Scope Association with ARCS - Culture Solidali to maximise the impact of 
the intervention through the capitalization of best practices tested in the Cameroonian context. COE and ARCS 
interface with COE CAM, a Cameroonian association rooted in the areas of intervention and experienced in 
initiatives aimed at young and vulnerable people, and with international experts from Ingegneria Senza 
Frontiere - Milano, Universit&#xE0; Cattolica del Sacro Cuore and Comune di Milano, who will contribute to the 
intervention in their respective fields of expertise.
Beyond the immediate results for the beneficiaries, the impact is estimated according to the contribution of the 
intervention to lasting, inclusive and sustainable economic growth, full employment, and decent work for all. In 
addition to increasing the well-being of the boys and girls involved in the project and that of their families, the 
intervention proposes scalable and replicable processes, systems and services and promotes a more equitable 
and inclusive society in which all boys and girls, including the most vulnerable ones, are aware that they can 
aspire to decent work, fulfill their aspirations, and contribute to the sustainable development of their country.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">In un contesto in cui le competenze della forza lavoro risultano inadeguate rispetto alle esigenze del mercato del 
lavoro, in cui le opportunit&#xE0; d&#x2019;impiego, sono scarse e di difficile accesso e in cui il lavoro giovanile &#xE9; marcato da 
precariet&#xE0; e insicurezza, la crescita economica non impatta positivamente sulle condizioni di vita dei giovani 
camerunesi, e in particolare dei pi&#xF9; vulnerabili, che risultano sempre pi&#xF9; esposti a disoccupazione, 
sottoccupazione, occupazione vulnerabile e impoverimento e, di conseguenza, vittime di una frustrazione che 
pu&#xF2; tradursi in disordini politici, radicalizzazione, criminalit&#xE0; o migrazione illegale.
In risposta ai bisogni identificati e in considerazione delle specifiche necessit&#xE0; e delle differenti aspirazioni dei 
ragazzi e delle ragazze, compresi gli ex-detenuti, i giovani a rischio, i disabili, i migranti e gli sfollati interni, il 
progetto Neet&apos;s net: In rete per una crescita economica inclusiva e sostenibile. Occupazione dignitosa, 
imprenditoria, acquisizione di competenze e partecipazione di ragazze e ragazzi vulnerabili promuove 
l&apos;occupazione dignitosa, l&apos;imprenditorialit&#xE0;, l&#x2019;acquisizione di competenze e la partecipazione alla crescita 
economica inclusiva e sostenibile dei giovani tra i 15 e i 24 anni, in particolare giovani donne e giovani in 
situazioni di vulnerabilit&#xE0;, nelle citt&#xE0; di Mbalmayo, Bafoussam e Garoua, in Camerun. 
L&#x2019;intervento, nell&#x2019;arco di 36 mesi, propone:
- soluzioni per il disallineamento delle competenze, fornendo a 800 ragazzi e ragazze esclusi dal sistema 
scolastico competenze tecniche, professionali, informatiche e imprenditoriali riconosciute e adeguate alle 
opportunit&#xE0; di lavoro esistenti, grazie al rafforzamento e alla diversificazione dell&#x2019;offerta formativa e alla sperimentazione di un sistema di certificazione delle competenze formali, informali e non formali;
- strategie per la promozione dell&apos;occupazione, consentendo a 1.890 ragazzi e ragazze di ottenere maggiori 
opportunit&#xE0; di impiego, pi&#xF9; facilmente accessibili, grazie a diversi servizi per favorire l&#x2019;orientamento e l&#x2019;incontro 
tra offerta e domanda di lavoro, a strumenti di inserimento lavorativo assistito e a un accompagnamento 
tecnico e finanziario per avviare, formalizzare, ottimizzare o gestire una piccola attivit&#xE0; imprenditoriale 
sostenibile; 
- protezione e promozione sociale, permettendo a 2.690 ragazzi e ragazze di far sentire la propria voce ed essere 
rappresentati, di accedere al sistema di protezione sociale e di rivendicare il proprio diritto al lavoro dignitoso e 
la possibilit&#xE0; di partecipare allo sviluppo economico e sociale delle citt&#xE0; in cui vivono.
Il COE (capo-fila) &#xE9; in Associazione Temporanea di Scopo con ARCS &#x2013; Culture Solidali per massimizzare l&#x2019;impatto 
dell&#x2019;intervento attraverso la capitalizzazione di buone prassi sperimentate nel contesto camerunese. COE e 
ARCS si interfacciano con COE CAM, associazione camerunese radicata nelle zone d&#x2019;intervento e con esperienza 
in iniziative rivolte a giovani e soggetti vulnerabili e con gli esperti internazionali di Ingegneria Senza Frontiere -
Milano, Universit&#xE0; Cattolica del Sacro Cuore e Comune di Milano, che contribuiscono all&#x2019;intervento nei rispettivi 
ambiti di expertise.
L&#x2019;impatto &#xE8; stimato in base al contributo che l&#x2019;intervento offre, al di l&#xE0; dei risultati immediati per i beneficiari, 
alla crescita economica duratura, inclusiva e sostenibile, alla piena occupazione e al lavoro dignitoso per tutti. 
Oltre ad aumentare il benessere dei ragazzi e delle ragazze coinvolti nel progetto e quello delle loro famiglie, 
propone infatti processi, sistemi e servizi scalabili e replicabili e promuove una societ&#xE0; pi&#xF9; equa e inclusiva in cui 
si diffonde la consapevolezza che tutti i ragazzi e le ragazze, compresi i giovani pi&#xF9; vulnerabili, possono ambire a 
un lavoro dignitoso, alla realizzazione delle proprie aspirazioni e possono contribuire allo sviluppo sostenibile del 
proprio Paese.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASSOCIAZIONE CENTRO ORIENTAMENTO EDUCATIVO ONG/ON</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/04/3" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="46" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Employment creation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16070" percentage="21" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Labour rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="33" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vocational training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2020, substantially reduce the proportion of youth not in employment, education or training</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="10.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, empower and promote the social, economic and political inclusion of all, irrespective of age, sex, disability, race, ethnicity, origin, religion or economic or other status</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote development-oriented policies that support productive activities, decent job creation, entrepreneurship, creativity and innovation, and encourage the formalization and growth of micro-, small- and medium-sized enterprises, including through access to financial services</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote sustained, inclusive and sustainable economic growth, full and productive employment and decent work for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="10" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reduce inequality within and among countries</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-14">2747802</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASSOCIAZIONE CENTRO ORIENTAMENTO EDUCATIVO ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-30">1648681</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASSOCIAZIONE CENTRO ORIENTAMENTO EDUCATIVO ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
