<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-58183167-XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004259</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-58183167" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Healthy Entrepreneurs Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Healthy Entrepreneurs in Burundi - Replication: the next step to ultimate scale</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HE proposes to include in her existing replication project starting per 1st of January 2021 one replicator in Burundi next to three new replicators in Uganda. The project in Burundi starts with a market and feasibility study to validate the market opportunity and the legal operating framework and to design and adjust the franchise model to the Burundian context. In parallel, the replicator project designs and develops the materials &#x2013; conditions prerequisite for the replicators to start. All replicators start with a test of 200 new entrepreneurs in their geographic areas. In Burundi, HE proposes a go-no-go decision at the end of pilot where the Dutch Embassy and HE decide together to further expand the network or not. In case of further expansion, the project delivers 2,500 entrepreneurs in 3 years in 8 districts in Burundi.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-58183167" role="4" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Healthy Entrepreneurs Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BI" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="122" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-11-01">221445</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-01">286217</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-11-01">863289</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004259" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-11-20">150000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004259" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-25">5523</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004259" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-28">119277</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004259" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-04-05">111225</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004259" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="Expenditures for 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">11501</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="Expenditures for 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">185804</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="Expenditures for 2022 (Q1)">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-31">74739</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Replicator selected and fully operational</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">After the feasibility study, which took place from October 2020 till July 2021, the first two Provinces (Kayanza and Gitega) and two Districts Sanitaires (Gahombo and Mutaho) were selected for implementation of the pilot phase. A constructive relationship was built with the Ministry of Health (MoH), especially the DPS-DSCE department.

A complete team of four young people started by the end of September 2021. The team contained of the following roles: Operations &amp; Training Officer (also a department), Sales Officer (in same &#x201C;department&#x201D; as previous), Finance Officer (also a department), Procurement &amp; Supply Chain Officer (also a department). The team was led by a Country Coordinator (from the Netherlands), who had previous experience of establishing Healthy Entrepreneurs in Kenya. All team members (except the Country Coordinator) were men &lt;35 years. The recruitment process was done in a professional way, giving equal opportunities to men and women. 

HE did all the trainings of selected &#x201C;Agents de Sant&#xE9; Communautaire&#x201D; (ASCs) to become Community Health Entrepreneurs (CHEs) in collaboration with the DPS-DSCE. They were involved in both recruitment, selection of suitable ASCs, as well as the 4-days training. DPSCE got inspired by the social business model, and ensured encouragement among the trained ASCs and lower level officials from the MoH (TPS, MCD, MP). 

Each department/person in the team started by familiarizing with HE, through calls with their counterparts in Uganda and Kenya. All team members received very detailed job descriptions, which were discussed and adjusted (if needed) together with the Country Coordinator. This helped them to know what do to and which questions to ask during the familiarization. They all received a basic training for the ERP system (ODOO) that HE is using; details were learned on the job. 

After three months of working with the team, HE could see that the all the team members were very motivated, and took full ownership in executing the activities within their role successfully. Striking was that all team members were interested in the HE model as a whole and were always critical and creative towards implementing the social business idea in the Burundian context. HE realized again that having a motivated team, is the key to success. However, gender balance is very important, which was a focus area for the next recruit. Moreover, the Country Coordinator operated partly from Kenya during the first three months of operations, which was challenging when starting up and leading a local team. She moved to Burundi in January 2022, to coordinate and lead the team on a fulltime basis.

After five months of operating and finishing the trainings of ASCs for the pilot phase, HE ended the contract with the &#x201C;Business Development Officer&#x201D; (and later Operations and Training Officer). This was the person who started in March 2021 to execute the feasibility study (in collaboration with the Country Coordinator). The collaboration was successful and he supported in the set-up of the HE Burundi entity and first trainings of ASCs. 

In February 2022, the Sales Officer was promoted to the position of Operations and Training Officer, and HE started a recruitment process for a new (female) Sales Officer. Local partners in Burundi helped in the promotion of the job advert, and many applications were received. A young lady, Medical Doctor by profession, started on International Women&#x2019;s Day (which was a coincidence, but a great value to this important day). 

In March 2022, HE started the recruitment of a new Country Coordinator (or Country Manager), which is currently ongoing. The new Country Manager will start in April and will be trained by the current Country Coordinator, to ensure the operations is taken over properly, and can go to the next level in the coming years, executing our ambitions plans, sales targets, and social impact objectives.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Replicator selected and fully operational</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4. # of entrepreneurs offering SRH and HIV/AIDS services per year</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">All the 194 CHEs have access to the HE Health App, which offers a wide range of health education flows and 100+ videos, all in Kirundi. Due to network challenges up country, exact data on the number of flows/videos watched related to SRH and HIV/AIDS services is currently unknown. The information will be made available by the end of the year, whereby HE can support in the synchronization of all the CHE smartphones. More information in previous indicator narrative.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of entrepreneurs offering SRH and HIV/AIDS services per year</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">6. # of people receiving interventions against TB, malaria, hepatitis and NTDs</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Although HE does not (yet) offer products regarding TB, malaria, hepatitis and NTDs in the product basket, information is readily available in the Health App and CHEs are encouraged to use it, especially when they know someone in their community has one of the mentioned conditions.

In other countries where HE is active, people in the community have access to doctors, nurses, and nutrition experts for phone consultations, remote monitoring of conditions, and the provision of e-prescriptions. CHEs do screenings, monitoring tests, and deliver prescribed treatment, supported by the (to be developed) so-called &#x201C;e-dispensing&#x201D; solution which will ensure quality-assured pharmaceutical dispensing (supported by technology). People with the above conditions, together with non-communicable diseases (NCDs) and common infectious diseases (that can be treated without the need of physical assessment by a doctor) will benefit tremendously from this intervention. HE Burundi envision to implement the same over time. Also health promotion, healthy living, and prevention will be stimulated with this intervention, which in the end is the ultimate goal (and key role) of ASC in Burundi. To improve health promotion, people need to be informed, and to continuously feel motivated as ASC to provide information, someone need to earn an income with it. Someone without sufficient income, will never think creative, will never be innovative, will never be committed, will never feel motivated to do something for their community, but will only seek for the quickest opportunity to get income. The key question is: &#x201C;How can we sell a healthy life?&#x201D;.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of people receiving interventions against TB, malaria, hepatitis and NTDs</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5. % of young people reached with comprehensive, correct information on sexuality, HIV/AIDS, STIs, pregnancy and contraceptives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Currently, CHEs are not providing reports to HE regarding the number of (young) people they have reached. However, an estimation could be made based on sample surveys with CHEs and shared ASC reports through the MoH DHIS system.

HE is in discussions with BSF and PSI, in order to ensure CHEs know the near youth friendly centers and Tunza clinics for referral of youth for additional information (after they have used the HE Health App for initial sensitization). BSF&#x2019;s Carte KAJOU are explored to insert in the CHE smartphone for more readily available correct information on sexuality, HIV/AIDS, STIs, pregnancy and contraceptives.

Direct collaboration with other SRHR partners is explored in the coming months.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of young people reached with comprehensive, correct information on sexuality, HIV/AIDS, STIs, pregnancy and contraceptives</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3. # and type of (new) user-friendly SRHR products and services on the market</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the pilot, HE decided together with the MoH/DPS-DSCE to start with a product basket of personal care, hygiene, and nutrition products. To test the effectiveness of the concept of a social business model for ASCs in Burundi, and if it will provide them with a sustainable and decent income, hence improved motivation for the ASCs (health promotion) duties (e.g. through report submissions, #referrals, #households visited). SRHR products in the current basket are limited to disposable and washable (Burundian) sanitary pads. 
Based on an official evaluation with the DPS-DSCE that will take place in April 2022 (including a travel for two officials to HE Uganda), the social impact (i.e. first result indicators) will be assessed. The joint report will be shared with all stakeholders in the Health domain and used as one of the tools to commence conversations with the Cabinet (i.e. Minister of Health) to obtain formal authorization (i.e. MoU/agreement) for the roll-out of the HE social business model in Burundi. 

HE has already established initial contact with other relevant departments within the MoH (i.e. DG, PRONIANUT, PNSR, Paludisme, ICCM). Since the process with the Cabinet requires time, inspirational discussions and field visits will be organized with the other relevant MoH departments in parallel. The final objective of HE is to inspire the MoH and let them see the importance of adding SRHR products (i.e. anti-conception pill, condoms, emergency pill, Sayana press), pharmaceuticals (allowed at ASC level e.g. malarial and diarrhea treatment), and other medical tests (e.g. malaria test, pregnancy test, HIV self-test, blood pressure and blood sugar test). Therefore, assessing the need in the community to indicate the value of paid products is required and will be performed.

In the Burundian healthcare system, all pharmaceuticals and some other products (condoms, bed nets), provided at community level, are aimed to be offered for free through the ASCs. The commodities are coming from the national supply chain (CAMEBU), which supplies the national hospitals, who in turn supply the lower level CDS. HE believes that free (public) and paid (private) supplies from different distribution channels can exist together at community level. Rather, they are complementing each other. The training program for the CHEs is designed in a way that they get a holistic training on community (public) health. Hereby, the focus is on health information/education, health products and services (supplied through different channels, i.e., MoH, HE, or other partner) which are all linked to prevention, health promotion, improved health-seeking behavior, and customer satisfaction (which in turn increases their product sales).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># and type of (new) user-friendly SRHR products and services on the market</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Number of entrepreneurs recruited and onboarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HE has recruited 266 ASCs during the period of November 2021 and February 2022 in the two selected District Sanitaires. The recruitment was done per commune, whereby all the GASCs (Groupement d&#x2019;ASCs) were invited. Six trainings (in three communes) with between 30-40 selected ASCs were done. At the end of the training, an exam was done, after which a few ASCs were eliminated (in some trainings). ASCs were selected based on a set of questions to assess their understanding and motivation for the HE social business model. The ASCs were always free to leave (during recruitment) or drop out (during training) when they did not feel motivated or willing to start the business. 194 CHEs started their business, either in November, December, January, or February. 

All the ASCs who became CHEs, joined the HE social business model program together with their GASC. This means that the contracts were all signed per GASC, by the president, with all the trained CHEs co-signing. The GASC as a whole has signed for the responsibility to repay for the health products and smartphone on credit for all the trained CHEs. An agreement was also made with the ASCs in the GASC who were not trained. 

A short overview of the business opportunity to the CHEs is presented below. 

HE offers: 
&#x2022;	4-days training on business (entrepreneurship, marketing, bookkeeping, savings) and community health (information, health promotion, prevention and cure, HE and government supplied health products)
&#x2022;	Provision of 120,000 BIF worth starterkit of health products (personal care, hygiene, and nutrition products)
&#x2022;	Provision of smartphone 50% on credit (value 60,000 BIF)
&#x2022;	Monthly (or twice a month) product delivery and entrepreneurship/business coaching
&#x2022;	Continuous product basket development based on feedback and recommendations from community, CHEs, HE staff, government (and other stakeholders) &#x2013; potential expansion of product basket to basic pharmaceuticals and SRHR commodities
&#x2022;	Business plan with growth projections (for 2 years) to improve business and sell health products supplied by HE worth 400,000 BIF, with an estimated 120,000 BIF monthly profit
&#x2022;	Provision of additional credit if initial credit successfully repaid (within the payment terms)

CHEs:
&#x2022;	Invests 40,000 BIF
&#x2022;	Active participation in 4-days training
&#x2022;	Sign contract (with GASC), including agreements between HE and CHEs, especially regarding supporting products and credit repayment
&#x2022;	Good care and responsible usage of smartphone (which is received 50% on credit)
&#x2022;	Minimum sales orders of 80,000 BIF (as a guidance, also lower amounts are accepted)
&#x2022;	Growth of monthly sales with 10,000 BIF in year 1, and 20,000 BIF in year 2
&#x2022;	Active participations in cluster (delivery) meetings, provide feedback on progress on business and sales performance, do suggestions on prices and products</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of entrepreneurs recruited and onboarded</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="200"></target>
     <actual value="194"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
