<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:usg="http://www.foreignassistance.gov" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-GOV-2-CL-2824</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comite Regional de Sanidad Vegetal del Cono Sur Regional (COSAVE) Workshop</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support the science and practice of food, feed, and fiber production (including forestry, wildlife, fisheries, aquaculture and floriculture) and its relationships to natural resources, processing, marketing, distribution, utilization (including nutrition), and trade.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This award strives to support the science and practice of food, feed, and fiber production (including forestry, wildlife, fisheries, aquaculture and floriculture) and its relationships to natural resources, processing, marketing, distribution, utilization (including nutrition), and trade. In addition, this award APHIS supported a two part training for representatives from COSAVE member states in Chile. 1: Visit to Los R&#xED;os and Los Lagos regions to observe and learn about the surveillance and official control programs of forest pests in Chile, with special emphasis of Sirex noctilio (Hymenoptera: Siricidae) and Pissodes castaneus (Coleoptera: Curculionidae). This included field and laboratory visits to observe the production of biological control agents of Sirex noctilio. Part 2: APHIS worked with COSAVE (Brazil, Argentina, Chile, Uruguay, Paraguay, Bolivia, Peru) and counterparts in Chile and Canada to participate in a joint workshop to present and analyze the risk and phytosanitary measures of surveillance, regulatory measures and control of forest pest outbreaks of high interest for the participating organizations, with special relevance of the Asian gypsy moth Lymantria dispar (AGM) and pests detected in wood packages coming from abroad after the implementation of the ISPM 15. This activity was a follow on from the November 2016 tripartite visit of Canada and the United States to Chile to discuss the mitigation and exclusion programs for Asian gypsy moth and other Lymantria species, which are carried out in the United States, Canada and Chile; and to analyze opportunities for harmonization of criteria and standards of work and explore ways of cooperation and exchange of information..</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service</narrative>
   <usg:duns-number>929332450</usg:duns-number>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-USAGOV" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-2" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of Agriculture</narrative>
   <usg:office-name>Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service</usg:office-name>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-2" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of Agriculture</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="US-GOV" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="US-USAGOV">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-09" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using transaction date.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-09" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using transaction date.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-12" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-12" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of Agriculture</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tyson Whitney</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+1 202-720-8978</telephone>
   <email>Tyson.whitney@cfo.usda.gov</email>
   <website>http://www.usda.gov</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1400 Independence Ave SW, Washington, DC 20250</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="CL">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chile</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chile is a regional strategic partner in peacekeeping activities, training both civilian and military personnel from Latin America at its peacekeeping training center and attaching peacekeeping platoons from other countries to its own large and professional force. U.S. assistance will support Chile&apos;s efforts to modernize and enhance its military&apos;s capacity to participate in regional security and peacekeeping operations, and increase interoperability with U.S. forces. U.S. assistance will also help to combat the spread of weapons of mass destruction and the transfer of dangerous contraband as Chile develops a comprehensive export control system that meets international standards. Additionally, U.S. assistance will support technical exchanges and training relevant to the establishment and enforcement of export control laws.</narrative>
   </description>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="4"></location-class>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-09">60000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Salaries &amp; Benefits; Travel &amp; Transportation; Accomodations</narrative>
   </description>
   <sector code="31181" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural education/training</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="5005" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2017" end="2017"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="5161">Agricultural Quarantine Inspection User Fee Account, Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="12"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <usg:mechanism-signing-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></usg:mechanism-signing-date>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
