<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-294329-Yemen2014-16</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-294329" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progressio</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen 2014-2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.) HONOR, POWER AND EXPECTATION (HOPE) FOR WOMEN IN HODEIDA. Start: 01/14 - 06/16 (project was suspended for 6 months due to the escalation of the conflict, but restarted in 01/16) This two year project aims to contribute to promotion of human rights and strengthening of the rule of law particularly in relation to Gender Based Violence in the districts of Bait Al Faqee, Azaidia, Alkhoha &amp; Zabid in Hodeida governorate. Specific objectives are; to increase awareness on the impact of domestic violence in Hodeida governorate, and to increase awareness on female genital mutilation. Expected results: 1. Key Stakeholders including Community health workers and paramedics including midwives, traditional birth attendants and clinical staff and other influential leaders in the society gain improved knowledge and skills on side effects of FGM on the health of women. 2. Increased multi-stakeholder engagement in the campaigns to end the practice of FGM in Hodeida governorate. Final beneficiaries are expected to be 500 households. Activities: &#x2022; Conduct study on the extent of domestic violence and FGM in the target areas. &#x2022; Mobilise stakeholders for dialogue on solutions to the challenges of Domestic Violence and FGM. &#x2022; Training of traditional birth attendants and midwives on the dangers of FGM. &#x2022; Conducting media campaigns and advocacy against GBV and FGM. &#x2022; Capacity building of different stakeholders to campaign for an end to GBV and FGM. &#x2022; Production of a documentary on GBV and FGM &#x2022; Lobbying and advocacy for change of policy and implementation of the rule of law to stop GBV and FGM. Donor: EuropeAid/EIDHR Partner led: Reach Out Foundation for Human Development (ROFHD) 2.) YEMEN AT A CROSSROADS: PROMOTING GOOD GOVERNANCE AND CITIZENS&#x2019; PARTICIPATION IN A FRAGILE CONTEXT (This project was terminated by donor in 10/15 because the situation in Yemen) This OXFAM-led, 40 months (3yrs and 4 months) long project aims to contribute to good governance processes in which vulnerable women and men in Yemen influence decisions affecting their lives and benefit from pro-poor and gender aware development policies and programmes at the local and national level. At the local level, the project will be implemented in the four governorates of Hadramout, Al Hodeidah, Taiz and Aden. The estimated direct beneficiaries are 516,173 people, which include leaders of VCCs (Village Cooperation Councils), SDDC (Sub-District Development Committees), and DDCs (District Development Committees), Members of Local NGOs/CBOs/Associations, District and Governorate Council Members, District and governorate Executive Offices staff, Members of National Level Civil Society Networks/Coalitions and relevant government ministries&#x2019; staff. Progressio will be responsible for continuous capacity building of civil society organisations and networks both at the local and national level through placement and management of the experienced DW in targeted civil society organisations. Main activities: &#x2022; Capacity building of SDDCs and District Committees in rights based and gender sensitive development planning, prioritisation of needs, advocacy with authorities and resource mobilisation. &#x2022; Designing appropriate IEC materials on good governance, gender sensitive participatory development processes informed by analysis of traditional, cultural and religious practices that reinforce these principles. &#x2022; Awareness raising sessions/events by SDDCs and District Committees and LCSO Networks among communities (VCCs and community members) on their right to high quality service provision, and on their civil responsibilities. &#x2022; Facilitating participatory rights based development analysis and planning at the community level by VCCs, SDDCs and other Local CSO and networks. &#x2022; Participatory design and implementation of local advocacy plans on issues arising from the rights based participatory planning process, especially around women specific issues, and establishment of budget monitoring mechanisms by Local CSO Network/members and community structures. &#x2022; Capacity development of 2 National civil society Networks to enable them to engage in policy analysis, advocacy and lobbying, as well as budget monitoring -40 members, 20 from each network (estimated number). Donor: SIDA 3.) - THE PROTECTION OF THE RIGHTS OF FEMALE INMATES AND JUVENILE OFFENDERS PROJECT (The project the start date is 1/13 &#x2013; 11/15, but the project was suspended for 6 months that&#x2019;s why the end of date was changed to 9/16) The Protection of the Rights of Female Inmates and Juvenile Offenders project The Protection of the Rights of Female Inmates and Juvenile Offenders project in Hodeida, is under European Instrument for Democracy and Human Rights has been implemented by Abo Mousa Social Charitable Association with 6 partners including : 1.Tamkeen for Society Development NGO, 2 Child Right Association,3 Al Atif Development Charitable Foundation, 4 . Yemeni Association for Fighting Illiteracy and Women Education, 5 Qotof Foundation for Social Development, 6 Grassroots Anti - poverty Empowerment Sustainability (GRAPES), with technical support of Progressio, UK based charitable organization and funded by EU. The project is implemented in Hodeidah Yemen during March2014-September2016. EU Contribution : EUR 237,500 , 95% as a percentage of total budget of the action The 7 NGOs involved in this project strengthened capacity, skills and knowledge of individual female inmates, juveniles, prison staff, judiciary, civil society organizations, religious leaders, Local Authorities, the media and the the traditional leaders in order to promote the defence and respect of human rights for female inmates and juveniles Offenders. The Action sought support (140) female prisoners and (60)Juveniles offenders in Hodeida governorate to have access to fair judicial process, enjoy their fundamental rights and prepare them to reintegrate in society. Background The prison population rate in Yemen stands at 55 per 100,000 of national population (ICPS, 2013). Out of this pre - trial detainees/remand prisoners account for 70.1%. Similarly, female and juvenile prisoners account 1.5% and 2.1% respectively. Women prisoners in Yemen have borne the brunt of brutality including torture, rape, inhuman treatment, and other forms of deprivation such as isolation and psychological torture. In addition, they suffer double punishment by being stigmatised by the society and rejected by their families apparently for bringing shame to the family. The result of this is continuous suffering both in prison and outside prisons since the ex - prisoners find it hard to fully re - integrate in the society after completing their prison sentences. In addition, juvenile prisoners have also been subjected to inhuman treatment including denial of access to education, healthcare and psychosocial support. In a number of cases, juveniles have been subjected to capital punishment including death sentences. This also indicates gross violation of human rights against the requirements of the Declaration on the Rights of the Child to which Yemen is a State party. In Hodeida juveniles have a centre where they are held, while girls are taken to Taiz and Sana&apos;a where such centres exist. Abo Mousa Association has been implementing a two year project: the Female Inmates Capacity Enhancement (FICE) with the support of the EU funding during2011-2013. Therefore this action emanates from the lessons learnt and further needs identified in the previous project. Overall objective; to contribute to promotion of human rights and strengthening of the rule of law particularly in relation to Female inmates and juvenile offenders. Key Results ; Increased awareness of the rights of female prisoners&amp; juveniles offenders and their re-integration. Improved conditions of female prisoners &amp;juvenile offenders inside prison &amp; juveniles custodies. Created local NGOs coalition supporting female prisoners and juvenile offenders Target Group ; prison Staff; Police Officers; Judicial Staff, Religious Leaders; Traditional Leaders, Journalists; Civil Society Organisations, Decision makers Abo Mousa Association and partners continues monitoring visits to places of deprivation of liberty for psycho-social support and legal support. It is noticed monthly increased of female inmates from 30-40 female inmates cases to 130 cases in central prisons during the ongoing crisis lack basic services including water, electricity , personal hygiene and health care. The increased number of female inmates coming from African origin asylum seekers. The demand is beyond NGOs capacities with less response from public institutions. Juveniles are not held at juvenile&#x2019;s house and are sent to orphanage center as the government can&#x2019;t afford operational costs for running juvenile&#x2019;s house. Humanitarian support to female inmates prison and orphanage center is provided by Abo Mousa including cool water, and food items but not sufficient. 4.) YOUTH SUSTAINABLE SKILLS AND EMPOWERMENT PROGRAMME: Funded by the EC Shakara Shabab, this two year project aims to empower young men and women, in the districts of Al Hali, Al Hawak, Bayt Al Fakeeh, Asuleef, Kamaran Island in the Hodeida governorate, to actively participate in peaceful, transparent and democratic processes that will strengthen local governance in Hodeidah governorate. Specific objectives of the project are; to build capacity of young men and women to act as catalyst for change at the grassroots level, and to strengthen youth groups and organizations for effective advocacy and social accountability at the grassroots level. The project aims to achieve: increased participation of youths and women in decision making processes at the community level, and strengthened CSOs and Youth Network: Strong networks at the grassroots will enhance advocacy leading to improved governance. The target population is estimated to be 20,000 youth, women and men. In addition, this project will build capacity of the applicant and co-applicants through skills share, mentoring and exchange visits. The technical support that will be provided by Progressio will ensure that the local partner organisations benefit from the knowledge, skills and experience of a highly qualified and experienced Development Worker who will be placed in the project to coordinate and provide technical support to the implementing partners. Main activities &#x2022; Training of youth in participatory community development and advocacy. &#x2022; Formation of Youth Councils &#x2022; Supporting advocacy initiatives of the Youth Councils &#x2022; Capacity Development of Youth Organisations &#x2022; Facilitating networking of Youth Organisations &#x2022; Support to Multi-stakeholder Dialogue Forums &#x2022; Support to Media Advocacy This project is led by Progressio&#x2019;s partner, Abo Musa Alashary Social Charitable Association. Start date: 01/02/2015 End date: 31/01/2017 (please note that the suspension period was 9 months and the project resumed from 1/2/2016)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abo Musa Alashary Social Charitable Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Hodeida network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EC Shakara Shabab</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europeaid/EIDHR/2013/134-085/L/ACT/YE (partner led)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hadramout network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National networks Sana&apos;a</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ROFHD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SIDA (Oxfam led)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taiz network 15/02/2014 31/12/2016</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tamkeen for Society Development NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tamkeen for Society Development NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">518170</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">101306</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">135449</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">188770</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">92645</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">692442</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">104880</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">126760</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">130323</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">330479</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">179257</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">48533</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">82219</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">12636</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">35869</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
