<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-294329-Zimbabwe</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org>Progressio</reporting-org>
  <title>Zimbabwe</title>
  <description>Action for better governance: Realising the common good(1)
The project seeks to empower poor and marginalised people especially women to have a greater influence on decisions and policies that affect their lives. This aim is to be achieved through building the capacity of faith groups, leaders and communities to promote democratic participation and influence local and national government plans and policies. Activities include: training of trainers, training of CCJP diocesan and parish members and volunteers, training of Bishops and other church leaders to advocate effectively on key governance issues, undertaking awareness raising and capacity building activities for church members within the diocesan parishes and small Christian community structures, and supporting the establishment of faith/secular partnerships.
Hear our voice! Speaking for HIV services and care support(2)
he project aims to reduce stigma and discrimination and increase access to HIV care, support and prevention among poor and at-risk groups, specifically employees, truck drivers, prisoners and children vulnerable to HIV and AIDS. The specific objectives include:
&#x2022;	To increase HIV knowledge, reduce stigma and discrimination and provide care and support to groups vulnerable to HIV, including inmates, prison officers and long-distance truck drivers; 
&#x2022;	To increase the voice, influence and capacity of people living with HIV, vulnerable groups and their representative organisations to represent their rights and improve service delivery and policies that affect their lives; 
&#x2022;	To increase access to prevention and care services, and reduce levels of stigma and discrimination by promoting the development and implementation of workplace policies and programmes in small/informal companies and in the transport sector; and 
&#x2022;	To increase the capacity of local implementing partners to improve their response to the needs of PLHIV and those most vulnerable to HIV. 
11,520 people are going to benefit directly and 30, 000 people are to benefit indirectly.
 Mitigating Sexual and Gender-Based Violence (SGBV) and HIV and AIDS(3)
The project aims to strengthen the capacity of faith-based organizations and their leadership to engage more proactively in the fight against sexual and gender-based violence and HIV and AIDS in Zimbabwe. Activities include capacity building of NFBCZ as an organisation undertaking HIV&amp;AIDS-related interventions among faith communities; production of documents and training manuals; training of local church leaders and congregants at the community level on both SGBV and HIV/AIDS; psychosocial and counselling support programmes for victims of gender violence; documentation and information dissemination on gender-based violence from a faith perspective. The project is directly benefiting 160 church leaders and 320 provincial coordinators. Indirect beneficiaries include approximately 1,000,000 church goers as a result of their leadership becoming  clearer and more committed in dealing with SGBV and HIV in church.
Enhancing livelihoods and food security among rural communities in Zimbabwe(4)
he project seeks to improve the quality of life of poor and marginalised people in Zimbabwe through more equitable and more sustainable management of natural resources especially in the light of climate change and resource scarcity. The main project activities include: 
&#x2022;	Promoting the adoption of soil and water conservation farming techniques by communal farmers 
&#x2022;	Promoting the use of alternative energy sources amongst communities 
&#x2022;	Setting up Environment Action Groups and  training the groups on the management of natural resources
&#x2022;	Training Environment Africa field officers on agro-ecology, marketing and business development, and lobbying and advocacy
&#x2022;	Advocacy - producing policy briefs, agro-ecology manuals and publications on agro-ecology and product development
Supporting visual and hearing impaired persons in Zimbabwe(5)
The aim of this project is to contribute towards the reduction of new HIV infections among disabled people in Zimbabwe by providing support to The HIV and AIDS Management Service Organisation (THAMASO) and the Disability HIV and AIDS Trust (DHAT) in the production and distribution of HIV and AIDS information for visual and hearing impaired persons. The main activities include production and distribution of HIV and AIDS information in Braille and sign language; and production of training manuals, policy monographs and briefs. The project will also strengthen the capacity of THAMASO and DHAT to advocate for the rights of disabled persons among duty bearers that include relevant government departments, village heads, chiefs and traditional healers with regard to HIV and AIDS information, prevention, treatment and care. This project is expected to benefit directly 650 visual and hearing impaired persons and approximately 4,000 family members from Hwange and Harare districts in Zimbabwe</description>
  <participating-org>Catholic Commission for Justice and Peace</participating-org>
  <participating-org>DFID</participating-org>
  <participating-org>Disability HIV and AIDS Trust (DHAT)</participating-org>
  <participating-org>Environment Africa</participating-org>
  <participating-org>National Employment Council for the Transport Operating Industry (NECTOI)</participating-org>
  <participating-org>National Faith Based Council of Zimbabwe</participating-org>
  <participating-org>Progressio</participating-org>
  <participating-org>The HIV and AIDS Management Service Organisation (THAMASO)</participating-org>
  <participating-org>Zimbabwe AIDS Prevention and Support Organisation (ZAPSO)</participating-org>
  <participating-org>Zimbabwe Association of Crime Prevention and Rehabilitation of the Offender (ZACRO)</participating-org>
  <participating-org>Zimbabwe National Council for the Welfare of Children (ZNCWC)</participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-07-01" type="START-ACTUAL"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="END-PLANNED"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>Progressio</organisation>
   <person-name>Belisario Nieto</person-name>
   <telephone>+44(0)20 77331195</telephone>
   <email>belisario@progressio.org.uk</email>
   <mailing-address>Units 9-12, The Stableyard
Broomgrove Road
London SW9 9TL, UK</mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31140" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31165" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31281" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP">605193</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="D"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP">150083</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="D"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP">169714</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP">219632</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP">65764</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link url="http://www.progressio.org.uk/sites/progressio.org.uk/files/theIDLgroup-Progressio-PPA-Independent-Progress-Review.pdf">
   <title>Progressio PPA Independent Progress Review</title>
   <category code="A07"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link url="http://www.progressio.org.uk/sites/progressio.org.uk/files/Progressio-PPA-performance-assessment-2013.pdf">
   <title>Progressio PPA Performance Assessment</title>
   <category code="A07"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link url="http://www.progressio.org.uk/sites/progressio.org.uk/files/Progressio-PPA-logframe.pdf">
   <title>Progressio PPA logframe</title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link url="http://www.progressio.org.uk/sites/progressio.org.uk/files/Progressio-PPA-Additionality-Report-2011-12.pdf">
   <title>Progressio PPA Additionality Report</title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link url="http://www.progressio.org.uk/sites/progressio.org.uk/files/Progressio-PPA-Annual-Review-2011-12-final.doc">
   <title>Progressio PPA Annual Review 2011-12</title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
