<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-294329-Zimbabwe-2014-16</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-294329" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progressio</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZIMBABWE-2014-16</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.) AMPLIFYING THE VOICES OF PEOPLE AFFECTED BY HIV IN ZIMBABWE - Amplifying the voices of people affected by HIV in Zimbabwe This three year project aims to A) increase uptake of HIV services among truck drivers, sex workers, SME and informal sector employees and prisoners; B) improve advocacy for HIV policy and practice that benefits truck drivers, sex workers, SME and informal sector employees, prisoners and children; C) enhance and sustain livelihoods for prisoners and ex-offenders living with HIV; D) increase capacity of partner organisations and ZNCWC members to effectively design, deliver and evaluate HIV interventions. This project will directly reach approximately 27,000 people. Main activities: &#x2022; Train peer educators to new target prisons, companies and truck stops. Peer educators will train peers on HIV issues, prevention and care services. &#x2022; Mobile VCT services will be piloted for informal sector workers with limited/no access to HIV services. &#x2022; Distribute male/female condoms to new target workers, truck drivers and sex workers. &#x2022; Pilot 14 distribution machines in toilets at 2 new and 5 existing sites to provide 24 hour access. &#x2022; Workplace wellness days conducted in order to increase information and access to HIV prevention and care services for employees, using discrete branding to address stigma as a barrier to attendance. As a new initiative, employees will be encouraged to bring their spouses. &#x2022; Support 170 new organisations to establish workplace HIV policies and committees in response to continuing high demand. &#x2022; Undertake research and advocacy to address root causes of truck drivers engaging in risky sexual behaviour and low availability/access to ART for children. &#x2022; Support junior parliamentarians to hold publicised debates on this issue and train journalists on appropriate advocacy messaging in media reporting. &#x2022; Establish support groups and livelihoods training for 360 prisoners and replicate the successful pilot of livelihoods inputs for 15 new released prisoners. &#x2022; 1 DW specialising in advocacy to support will be placed with all partners throughout the project. &#x2022; 1 DW expert in M&amp;E will also support all partners in Years 1 and 2 of the project, working towards facilitating partners&#x2019; independent management of M&amp;E in Year 3. &#x2022; Update and distribute handbook on child friendly HIV programming to relevant organisations, networks and ministries, especially targeting those with limited internet access. Partner organisations: Zimbabwe Aids and Prevention Support Organisation (ZAPSO), Zimbabwe National Council for the Welfare of children (ZNCWC), Zimbabwe Association for Crime Prevention and Rehabilitation of the Offender (ZACRO), National Employment Council for the Transport Operating Industry (NECTOI) This is a follow-on project from the earlier initiative &#x2018;Hear Our Voice! Speaking Out For HIV Services &amp; Care Support&#x2019; (2011-2014), also funded by Comic Relief. Location: Zimbabwe, nationwide. Start date: 01/08/2015 End date: 30/06/2018 Donor: Comic Relief 2.) PROMOTING ACCESS TO HIV VISUAL INFOMRATION AMONGST VISUAL AND HEARING IMPAIRED PERSONS IN ZIMBABWE -This one-year project aims to improve access to HIV and Sexual and Reproductive health information, care and support services for people with visual and hearing impairments (PVHI) through distribution of accessible relevant materials; outreach and awareness raising on services; training and support to beneficiaries, caregivers and service providers; and strengthening the capacity of partners and target communities to support and champion issues of disability, HIV and SRH, particularly among health professionals and policy makers. This project is going to directly benefit approximately 150 hearing impaired and 200 visually impaired people in Harare. Main activities: &#x2022; Refinement and distribution of the IEC Material that was produced during the pilot phase &#x2022; Training and awareness-raising of identified service providers, community leaders and community members &#x2022; Peer Education training and support &#x2022; Training of PVHI on their HIV and SRHR and life skills (leadership, negotiation, management, communication, problem solving and goal setting, advocacy) &#x2022; Facilitating engagements and dialogue meeting of PWDs with their community and national leaders &#x2022; DW Placement for capacity building of the two partner organisations in knowledge management, advocacy, monitoring and evaluation Partner organisations: Disability and AIDS Trust (DHAT) in Harare and Deaf Zimbabwe Trust (DZT) in Harare. Location: Harare, Zimbabwe Start date: 01/09/2012 End date: 31/08/2013 Donor: Porticus This is a follow-on project from the earlier initiative &#x2018;HIV/AIDS Disability Information&#x2019; Project (2012-2013), also funded by Porticus. 3.) ACTION FOR BETTER GOVERNANCE project will enable ordinary Zimbabweans to make concrete advances in their livelihoods, not through aid handouts, but by influencing local and provincial government. Progressio&#x2019;s advocacy specialist will train local partner staff at the Zimbabwe Catholic Commission for Justice and Peace (CCJPZ) who in turn will train women and men from the local community in setting up and running Parish Advocacy committees. The aim is to tackle one of the root causes of poverty &#x2013; a lack of power over decisions that affect citizens&#x2019; lives &#x2013; and improve local governance so that it is: informed about and more responsive to the greatest needs of its citizens, like access to clean water for drinking and for growing food to improve diet and livelihoods; held accountable to the people for its local budget decisions and actions; participatory - listens to the voices of women as well as men and takes account of the priority needs of the whole community regardless of faith and gender. In short, our aim is to help ordinary Zimbabweans create more democratic structures that address poverty and injustice. The pilot was externally independently evaluated and recommended the successful approach is replicated in other areas. Initial improvements included local government decisions that made a real lasting difference to poor communities. Start date 01/10/2015 End date 30/09/2016 4.) CAPACITY BUILDING ON GENDER AND POLICY, Development Worker placement: Gender, Economic Development and Policy Adviser Partner ZELA Start date 06/10/2015 End date 05/10/2016</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCJP</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comic Relief</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DFID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DHAT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DZT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NECTOI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZACRO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZAPSO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZELA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="50"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">642630</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">134546</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">169465</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">246460</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">92159</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">386181</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">131834</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">77057</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">111640</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">65650</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">582109</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">129218</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">50629</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">107318</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">294944</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
