<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5217004301-BGD-43060</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Designst&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r Nationellt Resilience Program</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme development support for National        Resilience Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen &#xE4;r ett st&#xF6;d till designen av ett nationellt resiliensprogramme f&#xF6;r gemensamt implementering av FN-systemet (UNDP, UNWOMEN, UNOPS) och nationella myndigheter (MoDMR, MoP, MoCWA, etc.). Ing&#xE5;ngsv&#xE4;rdena f&#xF6;r designprocesses &#xE4;r att bygga p&#xE5; resultaten fr&#xE5;n CDMP, prioritera samarbete mellan olika myndigheter och sektorer, inkludera ett tydligt genusfokus, koordinera med andra program och initativ inom DRR/CCA/resiliens och fokusera programmet p&#xE5; omr&#xE5;den d&#xE4;r implementerade organisationer har tydliga komperativa f&#xF6;rdelar. Givargruppens(SE, UK, EU) ing&#xE5;ngsv&#xE4;rden finns mer utf&#xF6;rligt beskrivna i bilagan &quot;Guiding priciples for design&quot;. 

Designprocessen f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntas ta sex m&#xE5;nader och ambitionen &#xE4;r att d&#xE5; ha tagit fram ett projektf&#xF6;rslag som &#xE4;r godk&#xE4;nt av GoB. Programmedesignen leds av ett &quot;task team&quot; med representanter fr&#xE5;n UNDP, UNWOMEN och UNOPS men ambassaden skriver avtal och finansierar processen genom UNWOMEN.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention is a support to the design process of new National Resilience Progamme that will be implemented jointly by the UN-system (UNDP, UNWOMEN, UNOPS) and government ministries  (MoDMR, MoP, MoCWA, etc.). Guiding principles from the donor group (SE, UK, EU) for the design are to build on achievements of CDMP, prioritize intra-ministerial programming, focus on gender integration, coordinate with planned and on-going project and initiatives in the DRR/CCD/resilience sector and to limit the scope of the programme to areas with definite comparative advantages of the implementing agencies.

The desing process is planned for six months and the ambition is to deliver a programme document that has been approved by national authorities for implementation. The processes is lead by a task team with representatives from the UNDP, UNWOMEN and UNOPS by the Embassy&apos;s agreement will be signed with UNWOMEN.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the design support to UN-Women was to develop a full project proposal for the National Resilience Programme. Sweden decided in Decemebr 2017 to sign the agreement with UNOPS for further support to thje full project of NRP.
In 2015-2016 Sweden, together with EU and DFID, invited the UN to develop aconcept note on how the UN would work with the Government of Bangladesh, thedeveloping partner&apos;s and others to develop a &quot;focused&quot; programme to support the furtherstrengthening of the approach to disaster management in Bangladesh. The invitationletter included specific guiding principles on which issues should be addressed in theconcept note.
As a response to the invitation at hand, Sweden recieved a concept note from the threeUN-agencies (UN-Women/UNDP/UNOPS). The Embassy agreed in April 2016 to provide a 6 month (April-October) design support of initially 2,75 MSEK to UN-WOMEN (together with UNOPS and UNDP) for theproduction of a proposal based on the concept note, The National Resilience Programme.
The agreement between Sweden and UN-Women was further amended to a totalamount of 4,5 MSEK and with an extension of duration to April 2017.
The overall goal of the NRP is &quot;to sustain resilience of human and economicdevelopment in Bangladesh through inclusive, gender responsive disaster managementand risk informed management&quot;, which in turn is foreseen to generate the followingoutcome:
&quot;Substantial increase in resilience to disaster and reduction in disaster risk, loss of livesand livelihoods of men, women, Girls and boys; and protection of the health of persons,businesses and communities in Bangladesh&quot;.
The Swedish results strategy for international development cooperation with Bangladesh2014-2020 is aligned with the NRP mainly within sub-objective 3: A betterEnvironment, limited climate impact and greater resilience to environmental impact,climate change and natural disasters.
In the Swedish results strategy it is a guiding principle that both individuals andinstitutions need support to increase their resilience to climate change and environmentalrisks. It is also foreseen that contributions in this area are important, as strengtheneddisaster management systems and resilience lower the risk of existing investments beinglost to natural disasters.
The following outputs have been set up for NRP:Output 1: Improved capacities for gender-responsive risk-informed development planning;Output 2: Strengthened disability inclusive, gender-responsive national capacities toaddress recurrent and mega disasters;Output 3: Improved capacity of selected public institutions to achieve resilienceoutcomes through designing and constructing risk-informed and gender-responsiveinfrastructure system;Output 4: Enhanced women leadership capacities for gender-responsive disastermanagement decisions, investments and policies at national and local levels;Output 5: Strengthened disability inclusive, gender responsive community preparedness,response and recovery capacities for recurrent and mega disasters.
The outputs of the NRP is planned to be achieved by adopting the following principles:- National ownership;- Building understanding of disaster risk to promote investment in disaster risk reductionand resilience;- Strategic multi-ministerial engagement;- Acountability and empowerment of partners;- Gender-responsive programming and management;- Complementarity and coordination.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41146" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNWOMEN/United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41146" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="43060" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">525915.9703149652</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">525915.9703149652</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">525915.970314</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-28">321393.0929702565</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">204522.8773447087</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project successfully achieved its primary objective which was to collaboratively develop a fully gender-responsive, risk-informed NRP ProDoc. The NRP ProDoc is fully owned by the four ministries (the Ministry of Disaster Management and Relief (MoDMR), the Ministry of Women and Children Affairs (MoWCA), the Ministry of Planning (MoP) and the Ministry of Local Government and Rural Development and Cooperatives (MoLGRDC)), which are ready for coordinated implementation of the joint&#xA0;programme. The partnership between UN Women, as the cross-cutting gender expert and the lead in the project; UNDP as the technical lead in DRR; and UNOPS, with its administrative expertise, effectively convened the required key stakeholders, allowing for the successful completion of the project. A number of objectives were set up in the initial phase of the design supported project, which have resulted in concrete achievements as presented below: 1.&#xA0;Define and agree on the objectives and expected broad impacts of the Programme with development partners (DPs) and the Government of Bangladesh A Task Team was established consisting of focal points from the three United Nations agencies and the four ministries to drive the NRP formulation process. The Task Team developed the detail roadmap of the formulation process, which was discussed and agreed to by the Reference Group, consisting of heads of agencies of the three United Nations agencies and representatives from the development partners (DFID and SIDA). 2.&#xA0;Identify and/or confirm the potential government and non-government stakeholders who will be involved in the formulation and possibly in the execution of the programme July to August 2016 a series of consultations took place at national and local levels with various officials (mostly from MoWCA and MoDMR). A total of 43 officials from Dhaka and 117 from six districts were consulted to identify the capacity gaps of the officials to mainstream gender in DRR and humanitarian actions. Findings from the consultations informed the ProDoc formulation, taking into account the required capacity development interventions and the relevant strategies to ensure gender-responsive resilience building. At a two-day brainstorming and team-building workshop in August 2016, United Nations agencies and the four ministries/departments formulated a theory of change for a gender-responsive, risk-informed NRP and agreed on the key results to be achieved by the programme. The noted gender and disaster management expert, Dr. Maureen Fordham from University College London, facilitated the parties towards a well-debated, discussed and unanimously agreed and endorsed theory of change and results framework.&#xA0;Many discussions took place over several months in order to come up with the management structure of this multi-ministry project, with a particular focus on keeping intact individual ministries&#x2019; and departments&#x2019; accountability structures while making sure that all parties worked closely together under one umbrella. The ministry focal points and the Task Team undertook extensive deliberations and agreed to a workable management structure, one of which was the option of having multiple TAPPs, one per ministry and considering them as a &#x201C;bundle TAPP&#x201D; against the single ProDoc; thus each ministry being accountable to deliver their own targets as defined in their TAPPs. Further, having a steering committee comprised of all ministry Project Directors and chaired by the Secretary of the lead Ministry (MoDMR) ensured top-level coordination among the implementing ministries. 3.&#xA0;Engage with stakeholders to assess and formulate their roles in the overall programme and their progress, capacities and willingness to participate and contribute; determine which incentives to be put in place Consider how other large programmes should be used/leveraged. UN Women, UNDP and UNOPS fielded a programme document formulation mission comprised of national and international experts between July and December 2016. UN Women engaged Dr. Fordham and a national gender and DRM expert. UNDP brought in the team leader of the ProDoc formulation mission, including the team leader and then institutional and a theory of change experts from another UNDP country office. UNOPS engaged their regional experts in the process (also see point 3 below for information on consultations with various stakeholders representing NGOs, academia and the private sector). 4.&#xA0;Define tentative budget requirements for the initial multi-year programme. In addition to consultations with officials of the four implementing ministries and departments at the local and national levels, consultations were held with 155 women vulnerable to disasters, including women Disaster Management Committee members from the six targeted districts. The women discussed first-hand disaster preparedness challenges, risks and experiences. The women offered valuable recommendations to make DRR actions gender-responsive and to address the specific needs of women and girls. The programme formulation mission met with various stakeholders, including those from NGOs (Action Aid, Bangladesh Centre for Advanced Studies, BRAC and Oxfam), from academia (Professor Ainun Nishat, BRAC University; Professor Mahbuba Nasrin and Professor Mokaddem Hossain from the Institute of Disaster Management and Vulnerability Studies), and from the private sector (Dialogue initiated with Business Initiative Leading Development; Chittagong Chamber of Commerce and Industry; Dhaka Chamber of Commerce and Industry; Metropolitan Chamber of Commerce and Industry; and The Swedish Civil Contingency Agency.)LGED held series of consultations with its gender network (consisting of gender focal points from among their own officials), to share ideas and discuss the challenges of gender integration in infrastructure development projects. A draft &#x201C;Capacity Building Needs Assessment for Gender Mainstreaming in&#xA0;DRR/Resilience Action&#x201D; was developed. There were extensive consultations through seven separate events7 on the capacity gaps of MoDMR and MoWCA officials for gender mainstreaming in DRR at the national and local levels. 5.&#xA0;Consult with the Government of Bangladesh and development partners and refine the approach to produce the final ProDoc. Starting with tempered expectations, the four ministries were unsure how the joint working modality would work out. Upon finalization of the ProDoc the four ministries expressed their commitment and sense of ownership of the NRP project strategy. The ministries made at least two presentations on the content of the NRP and its management strategies to the DPs. The four ministries agreed to contribute 10 per cent of NRP project costs through cash and in-kind transfers. 6.&#xA0;Build the government&#x2019;s technical capacities to prepare for the implementation of a gender-responsive programme. The MoWCA Joint Secretary and the DWA Director were sponsored and received technical support to actively participate in the November 2016 Asian Ministerial Conference on DRR in Delhi and the November 2016 South Asian Peer Learning Regional Consultation on Disaster Preparedness for an Effective Response for Gender Equality and Women&#x2019;s Empowerment in Kathmandu. They made joint presentations at a special event and a pre-conference event on gender and DRR, with MoDMR at the AMCDRR (Asian Ministerial Conference on Disaster Risk Reduction) on behalf of the Government of Bangladesh. UN Women and UNDP provided technical support for their presentations.The Deputy Secretary of MoDMR attended the May 2016 Asia and the Pacific Conference on Gender and DRR in Hanoi, Vietnam. 7.&#xA0;Finalize and approve the programme. Draft ProDoc was submitted to the Government of Bangladesh on 25 November 2016 for their feedback. On 18 December, the draft was submitted to DFID and SIDA for their comments. It was then finalized, taking into account the DPs comments and the UNDP Local Project Appraisal Committee meeting (held February 2017). On 22 February, the ProDoc was submitted to the Economic Relations Division.&#xA0;The Economic Relations Division held an inter-ministerial meeting in April 2017, which produced some observations that required addressing in the ProDoc. The relevant United Nations agencies and ministries addressed them and resubmitted the final ProDoc to the Economic Relations Division in June 2017. The Economic Relations Division and the three United Nations agencies signed the ProDoc in July 2017. Thus a fundable project document is ready to begin implementation with a clear theory of change and ownership of the government, DPs and United Nations agencies. Agreement between DFID, one of the DPs and the Administrative Agent for the NRP (UNOPS) was signed in November 2016. The process of TAPP production began after the February submission of the draft ProDoc to the Economic Relations Division. All drafts were ready by the end of April 2017. The ministries are going through their internal approval processes. The first set of inter-ministerial scrutiny took place. It produced several observations, which were addressed by the United Nations agencies and the respective ministries. Follow-up meetings resulted in final approvals (signatures) from the respective Secretaries. The TAPPs are now waiting to be collected at MoDMR for submission to the Planning Ministry for final government approval.&#xA0;The final TAPP approval process within the government system is taking longer than expected due to the Rohingya refugee crisis&#xA0;which is placing unusual pressure on the entire government machinery (particularly MoDMR). 8.&#xA0;Implementation plans and strategies in place. United Nations agencies, jointly with government representatives, have developed detailed TAPPs, which include a clear theory of change, an agreed governance structure for NRP, identifying of key partners, project areas, detailed results and resources framework, a joint monitoring framework and&#xA0;implementation plans (trailing plan, procurement plan, recruitment plan, and implementation schedule for example).&#xA0;On 20-21 March 2017, a two-day planning workshop was held by UN Women with DWA (Department of Women Affairs) and DDM (Department of Disaster Management) field-level officials (32 participants) from the project areas and national-level officials to explore field-level challenges that might be encountered during implementation and prepare an implementation plan in advance for smooth operations in the field. A workshop on &#x201C;Social and Gender Inclusiveness in the NRP was organized jointly by LGED, MoLGRDC and UNOPS on 1 March 2017. The main objective of the workshop was to Identify existing gender and social inclusiveness practices within LGED, share such practices with representatives from MOWCA (Ministry of Women and Children Affairs), UNOPS, UN Women and UNDP, and agree on ways forward for developing a comprehensive, gender informed strategy for resilient infrastructure. Disability inclusiveness and protection of people with disabilities emerged as a major priority for the government in the course of the NRP design process. As disability issues and disabled people&#x2019;s rights fall outside the expertise of all three involved United Nations agencies, successful mainstreaming of this issue will require a common strategy and reference document for the project partners. A National Resilience Programme Disability Inclusion Strategy was therefore drafted. UNDP initiated &#x201C;Resilience Dialogues&#x201D; with the private sector, including members of Chittagong Chamber of Commerce and Industry; Dhaka Chamber of Commerce and Industry; Metropolitan Chamber of Commerce and Industry as a platform for private sector dialogues.&#xA0;A comprehensive mapping was carried out to collect information on previous and ongoing interventions related to resilience by LGED (Local Government Engineering Department) to identify current practices on resilient infrastructure and identify gaps at subnational level, including the scope enhancing government capacities. A total of 32 Key Informant Interviews, Focus Group Discussions and field consultations at national and subnational level were conducted under the mapping exercise. The mapping exercise captured the important baseline information on approaches and gaps related to resilient infrastructure in LGED and the potential impact of disasters for next programme phase. A ToR requesting proposals from qualified consultants was first advertised in August 2016 and again in February 2017. However, the proposals received in response to the advertisement were found to be inadequate. Consequently, UNDP attempted a desk review process where consultants with proven previous experience, the appropriate experience and CVs were enquired about their availability and interest. Again, none of the consultants contacted were available to take on the assignment. And therefore, the activity was cancelled. 9.&#xA0;Technical assistance supports Government of Bangladesh policy development and participation in Sendai processes. MoDMR, with support from UNDP, led the planning and review process of the National Plan for Disaster Management (NPDM) and the Standing Orders on Disaster. UN Women facilitated bringing women&#x2019;s voices into the process. Support was extended for national and local-level consultations involving women&#x2019;s organizations and DWA officials in relation to the discussion on the second NPDM. Technical support has been provided for&#xA0;shaping the NPDM as a member of drafting committee. The MoWCA, DWA and MoDMR received support to participate in the Asia and the Pacific Conference on Gender and DRR in Hanoi, Vietnam in May 2016, the AMCDRR in Delhi, India, in November 2016 and South Asian Peer Learning Regional Consultation on Disaster Preparedness for an Effective Response for Gender Equality and Women&#x2019;s Empowerment at Kathmandu, Nepal in November 2016. The presentations made by MoWCA and MoDMR both in pre-conference meetings and in technical sessions at the AMCDRR received recognition for their strong focus on gender-responsive resilience and disaster management. UN Women supported the participation of Mr. Golam Rabbani, Fellow, BCAS to present on Gender and DRR in the climate change context in Bangladesh, as well as Ms. Naila Ahmed, Deputy Secretary from MoDMR at Hanoi Conference. Ms Dilruba Haider, UN Women Bangladesh moderated a group discussion on &#x201C;Understanding Disaster Risk - Gender and Disaster Data Collection, Analysis, Use and Management&#x201D; while Mr. Shakeb Nabi, Country Director, Christian Aid Bangladesh moderated a group discussion on &#x201C;Gender and Risk Governance&#x201D; at the conference.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="52170043" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1040102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1900000000.0" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <title>Bangladesh 2014-2020</title>
    <titleSV>Bangladesh 2014-2020</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
