<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5405015301-BGD-16020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre of Excellence for the RMG industry in Bangladesh (H&amp;M-ILO)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Centre of Excellence f&#xF6;r teko-industrin i Bangladesh (H&amp;M-ILO)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">H&amp;M, Sida and ILO aims to set up a Center for Excellence for skills   training in the Ready Made Garments (RMG) industry in Bangladesh.     With an industry based training focus, the project will serve as a    replicable model for meeting the skilled labour force need in the     sector as well as increase employability and higher incomes for the   working poor and therefore contribute to poverty alleviation.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">H&amp;M, Sida och ILO &#xE4;mnar s&#xE4;tta upp ett s&#xE5; kallat Center of Excellence  f&#xF6;r yrkesutbildning inom teko-industrin i Bangladesh. Med ett         industribaserat tr&#xE4;nigsfokus, ska projektet s&#xE4;tta upp en replikerbar  modell f&#xF6;r att m&#xF6;ta industrins behov av mer yrkeskunnig arbetskraft   samtidigt som anst&#xE4;llningsbarheten och l&#xF6;nerna f&#xF6;r de arbetande       fattiga kan h&#xF6;jas och d&#xE4;rmed leda till fattigdomsbek&#xE4;mpning.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="41144" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ILO/International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41144" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ILO/International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Employment creation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">460603.0829699687</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">145774.7197481013</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">117000.117000117</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">460603.0829699686</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">145774.7197481013</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">117000.117000117</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">-28798.6743993372</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-11-01">767671.804949</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">460603.0829699687</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-28">145774.7197481013</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-28">117000.117000117</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">-28798.7480438185</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The immediate objective 1 (An industry driven training and support service Centre of Excellence (COE), to meet the skilled labour force needs of the export oriented RGM industry in Ashulia and surrounding areas is established) was supported by four outputs, such as establishment and making COE functional with self financing, RMG factories have capacity to implement enterprise based training as an effective model, delivery of consistent, pre-employment and industry-oriented training with national certification by training providers, and strengthening the assessment and certification capacities of CoE and Bangladesh Technical Education Board (BTEB).
The main achievement under this objective was the Centre of Excellence known as Centre of Excellence of Bangladesh Apparel Industry (CEBAI) has been recognized as Registered Training Organization (RTO) for Sewing Machine Operation national skill certificate level-1 &amp; 2 as well as RTO to run competency based training and assessment (CBT&amp;A) national certificate level-4 by allowing TOT and assessments on CBT&amp;A for trainers &amp; assessors both from industry and institutes.
CEBAI launched training programmes for workers, mid-level management and trainers and assessors, initially from March 2015, but more actively in planned manner after September 2016 and achieved following results:
* Trained about 1,309 workers in the Competency Based Training (CBT) program in Ashulia, of these, 893 workers assessed and provided with certification on sewing machine operation NTVQF Level-1 by BTEB
* Trained 103 mid-level managers and 66 factory supervisors on key leadership skills including occupational safety and health, disability inclusion and workers&#x2019; rights.
* Trained 262 EBT Competency Based Training and Assessment Level-4 trainers and assessors (36% female) and 137 of them achieved certification from BTEB.
CEBAI prepared 3 researches in collaboration with the academic and research institutions, reviewed its business plan and prepared a new one for 2018-2022, developed financial and accounting manual, conducted 2 seminars (Sustainable CEBAI and efficiency through EBT model, Inclusive Business Policy) and 1 roundtable ($50bln RMG Export and the role of CEBAI), developed 1 documentary and more than 80 articles, news supplements, activity related news covered by Daily Bangla, English Newspapers, online news portal, monthly-bi-monthly newspapers and launched the website https://cebai.org/.
CEBAI has also developed Competency Skills Log Books (CSLBs) of Sewing Machine Operation 4 RMG sub-sectors, and Competency Based Learning Materials (CBLMs) of Sewing Machine Operation 4 RMG sub-sectors which are fully in-line with the national TVET-programmes. Total of 453 skilled workers were assessed by BTEB in the RPL model at CEBAI on sewing machine operation NTVQF Level 1 and 2. Project has collaborated with existing training providers, in particular 3 NGOs (UCEP Bangladesh, Dhaka Ahsania Mission and Muslim Aid) and 1 Technical Training Center (TTC) for being able to reach the set training targets. There are two more results achieved by the COE Project under IO1, namely Accreditation of CEBAI for the assessment of NTVQF Level 2 on SMO and preparing Competency Standards of RMG sub sectors knit, woven, lingerie and denim as per industry demands.
&#xA0;In addition, all targeted 10 RMG factories have joined the Enterprise Based Training (EBT) program and got registered as training organization accreditation from BTEB. They have started competency based training on sewing machine operation national skill certificate level-1 &amp; 2 with the technical guidance of the project. During end of project period in 2017, 3 more RMG factories have joined the Enterprise Based Training program.
&#xA0;During the project period, both EBT companies and CEBAI have enrolled total 11,702 fresh workers and 10,383 have completed job and got job placement in different factories, out of it 90% female workers.
&#xA0;Under the Immediate Objective 2 (To improve the situation of vulnerable and poor people who are or who become garment workers by enhancing their skills, income opportunities and working conditions, while providing the RMG sector with a more skilled workforce), the project had one output which focused on improved training and employment outcomes for women and disadvantaged groups. The result achieved by the project was the development of the inclusion policy for RMG sector which advised selected RMG enterprises to train and employ people with disabilities. In addition, assisted selected three enterprises with the development of operational plans for ensuring the implementation of the adopted inclusion policies at selected enterprises, prepared a small audio-visual documentary to showcase the policy and to demonstrate benefit of adopting inclusive business approach. Further project has organized a National Seminar on &#x201C;Inclusive Business: Could it Lead to Higher Productivity and Better Working Condition&#x201D;, and provided 300 (85% female) extreme poor or marginalized people with pre-vocational course at machine operator by partner 2 NGOs.
&#xA0;In summary, project has been able to achieve most of it&#x2019;s targeted results excepting establishing CEBAI as a fully functional and self-sustainable centre of coordinator of services and key actors in the garment sector.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="54050153" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1900000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Bangladesh 2014-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Bangladesh 2014-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
