<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5106004401-BGD-13020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RHSTEP 2014-2016</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">RHSTEP 2014-2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">RHSTEP har ans&#xF6;kt till Sveriges ambassad f&#xF6;r finansiering av 45,5 miljoner kronor f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra projektet med titeln &#x201D;Fr&#xE4;mjande av sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och r&#xE4;ttigheter: Spridning SRH-tj&#xE4;nster med fokus p&#xE5; s&#xE4;kra aborter och minskning av os&#xE4;kra aborter i Bangladesh&#x201D;. Med h&#xE4;nvisning till slutsatserna av ovanst&#xE5;ende bed&#xF6;mningar  belsutar Sida  att finansiera insatsen f&#xF6;r perioden juli 2014 till december 2016 med 45,5 miljoner kronor. Insatsen syftar till att bidra till minskning av m&#xF6;drad&#xF6;dlighet, sjukdom fr&#xE5;n os&#xE4;kra aborter och f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra SRHR situationen f&#xF6;r kvinnor och ungdomar i projektomr&#xE5;dena. 
Insatsens totala budget uppg&#xE5;r till 48,25 MSEK, varav Sida kommer att bidra med 45,5 MSEK, resterande 2,75 MSEK kommer SRHR-konsortiet att bidra med fr&#xE5;n de samlade anv&#xE4;ndaravgifter fr&#xE5;n den sista fasen.

RHSTEP has applied to Embassy of Sweden for funding of MSEK 45.5 to carry out the project titled Promotion of Sexual and Reproductive Health and Rights: Provisioning of SRH services focusing on Safe MR and Reduction of Unsafe abortion in Bangladesh. Given the evidence from the assessments above Sweden decides to fund the project for the period of July 2014 to December 2016 with MSEK 45.5 for the proposal.  The intervention aims at contributing in reduction of Maternal Mortality, morbidity from unsafe abortion and improve the SRHR situation of women and adolescents in the project areas. 

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is MSEK 48.25 , out of which the Embassy of Sweden will contribute 45 MSEK remaining MSEK 2,75 will be contributed by the SRHR consortium from the accumulated user fees from the last phase.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The purpose of the project is to contribute in reduction of Maternal Mortality, morbidity from unsafe abortion and improve the Sexual Reproductive Health and Rights (SRHR) situation of women and adolescents in the project areas. 

This project targets to achieve 150500 MR conducted , 12250 patient managed for Complications of unsafe abortion , 322,550 FP methods distributed during Post MR counseling, 80500 individual received Reproductive Health service at school, community and garments,  Institutionalized and sustainable attention at the national level to ensure access to safe abortion and family planning. 

This will be achieved by ensuring that poor and marginalized women and adolescents have access to unsafe abortion and can access modern Family Planning (FP) methods;  Providing comprehensive MR and PAC training to  health service providers, Raising Awareness and Creation of Demand on SRHR issues and Supporting changes to the regulatory and/ or policy environments for abortion services.

SRHR project will help Bangladesh to achieve MDG 5 by increasing family planning use and reducing maternal mortality in Bangladesh.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the project is to contribute in reduction of Maternal Mortality, morbidity from unsafe abortion and improve the SRHR situation of women and adolescents in the project areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RHSTEP/Reproductive Health Services Training and Education Program</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RHSTEP/Reproductive Health Services Training and Education Program</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="130" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population Policies/Programmes &amp; Reproductive Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">2623944.9554658234</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1067704.3170844554</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">2162098.989072635</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">2623944.9554658234</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1067704.3170844554</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">2162098.989072635</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-07-01">6632749.748538</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-09-28">2623944.9554658234</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-09-28">1067704.3170844554</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-04-28">1051831.9406299305</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-28">1051831.9406299305</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">As the overall goal of the project is to improve Sexual and Reproductive Health Rights (SRHR) and wellbeing of women and adolescents in Bangladesh, the report mentioned that at the beginning of the project the overall situation of the country was supportive to the project implementation i.e. political, social and economic. Though there is no change in legislative or policies in the health arena the Reproductive Health issues especially Menstrual Regulation is also a priority issue for achievingMDG-5 in the country. The project implemented different activities including Training on Menstrual Regulation for Doctors, Paramedics, and Family Welfare Visitors, SACMOS from Government; non-government and private sectors across the country.&#xA0; The consortium members also provided training to service providers on clinical and non-clinical services as well as SRHR and life skills education support in the project areas. In this project period 1,055doctors, paramedic, FWVs, SACMOs received basic and refresher MR and PAC training; 583 service providers included peer educator, community volunteer received SRHR and life skill training. During the project period 595 staff of the consortium received training on different programmatic and management issue. The SRHR Consortium (RHSTEP and BAPSA) served 2021,569 women, men and adolescents on MR and SRH services from the consortium clinics as needed. Total of 384,283 MR related services offered to clients in the form of MR Counseling, MR performance, Follow-up of MR Clients; PAC services, and providing Anti-D support. A total MR performed during this project period was 137,663. The consortium also delivered 321,526 family planning methods which includes&#xA0; post MR Contraceptive, non MR contraceptive, and follow-up of contraceptive methods. Total of 108,244 maternal health care services provided that includes ANC, Delivery, PNC and TT immunization. Within this reporting period 119,912 OBS/GYN services rendered to clients. For this reporting period 192,569 clients were screened for the cervical cancer and breast cancer through Pap&#x2019;s Smear, VIA test, bi-manual breast examination and counseling. Limited curative care provided 281,058clients which include health care at clinics, school, community, garments, services through mobile phone and also male involvement in SRHR services.&#xA0; 613,248 clients received diagnostic (Pathology and USG) services in this project period. 
Through BCC activities 2135,769 people were informed on SRHR issues through door to door visit, school, community and garments visit. These activities done by190,788 SRHR educational session, awareness session, orientation meeting, BCC materials distribution, door to visit etc. also Health and Rights based newsletter on SRHR.
The above performance achieved by 32 centers in the project areas. Out of those RHSTEP has 22 centers situated in public medical college hospitals with the direct involvement of the hospital authority in project and technical advisory positions. Only the maternity clinic of RHSTEP (MCD) is situated in Dhaka outside the public hospitals. BAPSA has 10 centers (See Annex-2) under this project. Few centers of BAPSA&#x2019;s are located in district towns and few are at Upazila level.
The SRHR consortium (RHSTEP and BAPSA) has been successfully contributing as development partners of the Government of Bangladesh in achieving its sexual and reproductive health related progress of the country.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51060044" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1900000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Bangladesh 2014-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Bangladesh 2014-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
