<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5106000103-BGD-12220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Sector Programme Bangladesh 2011-2016</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">H&#xE4;lsosektorprogrammet Bangladesh 2011-2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3:e H&#xE4;lsosektorst&#xF6;det t. Bangladesh 201107-201606 med SEK 515         miljoner, 1%av den tot budg p&#xE5; SEK 50 miljarder. H&#xE4;lsomin &#xE4;ger och    genomf&#xF6;r progmt. M&#xE5;let &#xE4;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;tta tillg&#xE5;ng till och utnyttjande  av n&#xF6;dv&#xE4;ndiga h&#xE4;lsotj&#xE4;nster, speciellt bland de fattiga, gen          f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad h&#xE4;lsoservice och st&#xE4;rkt h&#xE4;lsosystem. Sida fiansierar gnmn  VB MDTF m andra giv: USAID, AUSaid, DFID, JIVA, CIDA, UNFPA, Kfw, mfl</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3rd Healthsectorprgm to Badesh 201106-201607 with SEK 515 million, 1% of tot budg SEK 50 billion. Ministry of Health owner and implementer  of prgrm. Goal is to improve access to and utilization of essential   health, population and nutrition services, partc by the poor, through impr health services add strengthening health systems. Sida is        financing through a WB MDTF, w USAID,AUSaid,DFID,CIDA,UNFPA,KfW ao.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-06-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-06-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="122" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">20449.2605888697</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">35100.0351000351</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">20449.2605888697</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">35100.0351000351</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-06-30">67561.332675</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-09-28">20449.2605888697</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">32127.1451971452</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GoB and DPs investments in the health sector program with focus on service delivery and health system strengthening has contributed to increase equity in access to health care, especially for women and children. Substantial achievements in key health indicators for maternal and child health can be observed. The health MDGs were achieved, except for MDG 5, including reduction in children mortality, increased rates of birth delivery by skilled birth attendance, children immunization coverage expanded and increased coverage of ante-natal care.&#xA0;
The public health system is improving its performance and efficiency, e.g. through the introduction of the asset management system that has reduced misuse of equipment&#x2019;s, improved Health Information System that has contributed to better follow-up and surveillance of overall health situation. According to the WB, the use of Government treasury system has also reduced transaction costs. Large numbers of doctors and nurses has been recruited and the since 2015, midwifes has been introduced as a new profession. Investments in human resources has shown to have positive impact on health outcomes, especially in rural areas. 
The agreement between the MDTF and the GoB was extended with six month until 30th of June 2018 with the aim to provide support to the MoHFW to respond to the Rohingya-crisis. This grant has facilitated MOHFW to have a coordination team on the ground in Cox&#x2019;s Bazar. The team facilitated the coordination with Dhaka officials from MOHFW, DHGS as well as different line ministries to inform decision-makers and improve liaison between field and capital.
The coordination team contributed to strengthen the hands of Civil Surgeon (Health Manger) in Cox&#x2019;s bazaar district amidst the fluidity and scale of the crisis in Cox&#x2019;s Bazar. The coordination team working closely with the Civil Surgeon, strengthened the government&#x2019;s stewardship role by providing information for planning and coordination of activities required for provision of HNP services to the displaced population. The cell also provided support to contract in some key health professionals where the facilities were overstretched due to the rapid influx of the Rohingya population (who had very with little access to services in Myanmar). This assistance also supported the contracting out the cleaning services in the Sadar hospitals and Upazilla health complexes (Ukhia and Teknaf) which were running at a bed occupancy rate of 150%.
The coordination team supported the agreement of standards among 120 health partners (UN, INGOs and national NGOs) on the aspect of number of population to be served by each health unit/center as well as the range of services that should be provided. The coordination team composed of senior health official and managers has also been leading efforts, with support from WHO, to prepare for the monsoon season with measures such as the relocation of health facilities that face a high risk of flooding and landslide. Through the pre-monsoon risk assessment led by the government, 53 facilities were identified for relocation/decommissioning.
Concurrently, the coordination cell is working with humanitarian health partner towards a more sustainable and equitable solution for the provision of health care services by the government. DGHS, through this coordination cell on the ground, is coordinating the setup of 19 PHC and 3 multipurpose PHC centers. Through negotiation of the coordination team lead, land allocation has been approved by RRRC. The partners have started the work in Kutupalong (in camps 1, 7, 10-14, and 20), Kenotoli, and Shalbon. These are centers which were earlier made of plastic sheets and bamboo materials have been replaced by prefabricated material.&#xA0; The first centre has been built and is in operation in Jamtoli since March 2018, operationalized by the Swiss Red Cross. Land for another 6 PHCs and the three Multi- purpose Health centers has been identified and is pending approval by RRRC.
Support to outbreak and vaccination related activities: On the technical level, several coordination teams were deployed to support control of outbreak and vaccination related activities. The field coordinators in the coordination cell managed the organization of contact tracing, outbreak investigation and control and were crucial for thee smooth implementation of half a dozen vaccination campaigns. The Immunization expert in coordination cell oversaw development of the micro-plans for the different campaigns, organized the mobilization of communities to increase coverage rates, and helped to mobilize several thousand volunteers from different stakeholders for immunization campaigns. Because of the planning and coordination provided through the coordination cell was it possible to implement the various campaigns so quickly and avert communicable disease outbreaks such as measles or cholera.
Apart from the timely implementation of the campaigns, the team from coordination cell was also instrumental in monitoring those campaigns and guiding the response to quality concerns with a few volunteers. During the first 2 rounds of OCV in the 4th quarter of 2017, more than 840 000 people (refugees and host communities) were vaccinated against cholera. The 3rd round of OCV that just concluded on 13 May 2018 reached more than 900 000 persons, which equals a 94% coverage rate. Together with other vaccination campaigns targeting measles/rubella, polio and diphtheria (3 rounds of pentavalent/ tetanus&#x2013;diphtheria vaccine), close to 4 million vaccinations have been administered since the onset of the crisis. 
Meanwhile, the MOHFW coordination team and WHO have established 25 fixed sites where the routine Expanded Programme on Immunization (EPI) is being provided. Fifty-six vaccination teams, of two members each, are providing routine EPI through the 672 outreach sessions (576 in Ukhia and 96 in Teknaf). Going forward, each team will conduct 12 vaccination sessions per month in the camps. Entry-point vaccination continues to be provided to all new arrivals in Cox&#x2019;s Bazar from Rakhine state of Myanmar. The field coordinators are supporting the planning and monitoring of these vaccination sessions.
The main tool for outbreak detection and control is the early warning and response system (EWARS), that was set up by MOHFW and WHO early on in the crisis. The field workers from the coordination cell were instrumental in picking up any suspected outbreaks early on, guide the investigation of alerts and support the management of &#xA0;the response with the concerned stakeholders. From January 1st to 31 March 2018, a total of 1 127 outbreak alerts were raised, were verified and assessed; 90% of alerts have been investigated within 72 hours of their notification. This equals an average of 80 alerts every week or eleven every day. The outbreak team and the coordination cell financed through the grant is leading and managing the coordination of the investigation teams, gathering results and deciding on further action.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51060001" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1900000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Bangladesh 2014-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Bangladesh 2014-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
