<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5217004005-BGD-14031</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Water Safety for the wellbeing of Women and Children in Bangladesh</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Water Safety for the wellbeing of Women and Children in Bangladesh</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Det f&#xF6;reslagna programmet kommer att st&#xF6;dja Bangladesh regerings arbete med att leda, samordna och fr&#xE4;mja genomf&#xF6;randet och f&#xF6;rvaltningen av ramverk och metoder f&#xF6;r skydd av vatten. Det l&#xE5;ngsiktiga utvecklingsm&#xE5;let &#xE4;r allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till s&#xE4;kert och h&#xE5;llbart dricksvatten. De f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade resultaten av projektet &#xE4;r:

1. &#xC5;r 2020 ska roller och ansvar f&#xF6;r reglering, kapacitetsuppbyggnad, tillhandah&#xE5;llande av tj&#xE4;nster och provning av vattenkvalitet vara tilldelade.
2. &#xC5;r 2020 &#xE4;r harmoniserade system och metoder utplacerade av ansvariga akt&#xF6;rer f&#xF6;r leverans av arseniks&#xE4;kert och bakteriologiskt s&#xE4;kert dricksvatten.
3. &#xC5;r 2020 anv&#xE4;nds evidensbaserade system av ansvariga akt&#xF6;rer inom delsektorerna h&#xE4;lsa och dricksvatten.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
The intervention is considered to deliver sustainable results that contributes to the Results strategy for Bangladesh has made significant progress in increasing access to improved drinking water in both urban and rural areas, and to all segments of the population. As a result of this, Bangladesh achieved the Millennium Development Goal 7c related to drinking water well before the end date in 2015 and currently 98% of the population enjoys access to a protected drinking water source (JMP, 2015). However, looking past the quality proxy of &#x201C;improved water source&#x201D; reveals that the water supply is undermined by quality issues and unreliable service provision (MICS 2009). According to the most recent Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey, MICS, only 35 % of households consume water which meets the Bangladesh standard for both arsenic and bacteriological contamination. WHO estimate that chronic arsenic exposure leads to 43 000 deaths annually having a significant economic impact on the country. Despite improvements in prevention and treatment of waterborne disease, 15% of post-neonatal deaths all 6% of all U5 deaths are currently due to diarrhea. 

Arsenic contamination of shallow wells has been a recognized problem since the 1990s but, despite large investments by donors and government, the result has only been a decrease in exposure of 1%, which actually translates into an increased number of affected people given the population growth during the same period. Several factors contribute to this limited success and water quality issues in general, but at the core lay weak regulation and accountability, poor information management, and a lack of capacity of government to coordinate and engage with small scale entrepreneurs in the water sector. 

The proposed programme will support the government of Bangladesh to lead, coordinate and facilitate the implementation and management of water safety frameworks and protocols. The long term development goal is universal access to safe and sustainable drinking water and the expected outcomes of the project are:
1. By 2020, roles and responsibilities for regulation, capacity building, service provision and water quality testing are assigned. 
2. By 2020, harmonized systems and procedures are deployed by stakeholders for the delivery of arsenic and bacteriologically safe drinking water.
3. By 2020, evidence-based systems are used by accountable stakeholders in the health and drinking water sub-sectors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The key outcomes and outputs of the project are:

1. By 2021, roles and responsibilities for regulation, capacity building, service provision and water quality testing are assigned

1.1 A government-led platform for adaptation and adoption of sub-sector wide scalable water safety models and protocols is established and functional

1.2 Drinking water safety policies and regulations are complied with and capacity of public/ private personnel developed to deliver safe water at-scale &apos;

2. By 2021, harmonized systems and procedures are deployed by stakeholders for the delivery of arsenic and bacteriologically safe drinking water

2.1 A government-led national performance-based monitoring and surveillance system for urban and rural drinking water safety is established and functional &apos;

2.2 A harmonized National Arsenic Mitigation Protocol and evidence-based model is adopted and implemented securing safe water rights

3. By 2021, evidence-based systems are used by accountable stakeholders in the health and drinking water sub-sectors

3.1 Arsenicosis case detection and management protocol is operationalized &amp; evidence and database of arsenicosis patients established and strengthened

3.2 The integrated WASH National Monitoring and Evaluation System is established, populated and functional

4. By 2021, Rohingya and Host Communities in Ukhiya and Teknaf Upazilas under Coxs Bazar District have sustainable WASH services

4.1 The Behaviour of both host and Rohingya communities have been changed through safe sanitation and hygiene intervention change and safe sanitation

4.2 Rohingya and Host communities are trained on Water Safety Plan (WSP) and able to ensure their own access to safe water

4.3 GoB departments and stakeholders are strengthened to ensure sustainable WASH services for the target communities.

Following the projects successes, the Government of Bangladesh decided to upscale this approach in a $240 million worth programme directed at rural water supply and has requested technical support from UNICEF to expand the well-developed arsenic safe union model to the new programme locations. Consequently, the Swedish Embassy in Bangladesh and UNICEF discussed and agreed to continue support in this area, with a shift of UNICEFs role to solely render technical assistance while leveraging huge GoB resources. This revised role will allow focus on quality assurance of the larger Government programme, capacity building and targeting the poorest and most vulnerable, ensuring a strong equity lens to the intervention. The current contribution will thus be further extended to allow the continuation of support to DPHE while building on previous achievements.

In September 2021, Embassy of Sweden and UNICEF decided that the support of the Swedish Embassy to UNICEF would be provided under the thematic funding modality (pooled funds received against the programmes approved by the Executive Board, i.e the UNICEF Country Programme) instead of a dedicated proposal. Therefore, this bridging phase will cover the first year of UNICEFs Country Programme 2022-26 (January  December 2022) with a special focus on water safety, while the larger 3-year broader thematic proposal based on the UNICEF Bangladesh WASH Programme Strategy Note 2022-26, is being drafted.

Objectives 5 and 6 for the extended period. These objectives are from the technical support to the government initiative.  

5. By 2022, the National Water Quality Monitoring &amp; Surveillance System is strengthened with a mechanism for water quality monitoring and management and adapted/used for informed decision-making with quality compliance regulated through the development/ revision, and implementation of the standardized water safety and arsenic mitigation guidelines and protocols.

5.1 Access to quality water resources by communities through water service is regulated through the enforcement of quality guidelines and protocols. 

5.2 Management information system for water quality for informed decision making is established and regularly updated and expanded.

6. By 2022, the poorest and most vulnerable communities in arsenic-affected unions have access to safe, sustainable and climate resilient water services and contribute to sustainably clean and safe environment.

6.1 An informed and all-inclusive consultative process is followed in defining an action plan for safe/arsenic-free water services in selected priority unions.

6.2 Safe/arsenic free water systems that are climate resilient and sustainable are in place to serve targeted population.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF/United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF/United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="14031" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic drinking water supply</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="6.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">6.1 - By 2030, achieve universal and equitable access to safe and affordable drinking water for all.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">6.1 - Senast 2030 uppn&#xE5; allm&#xE4;n och r&#xE4;ttvis tillg&#xE5;ng till s&#xE4;kert och ekonomiskt &#xF6;verkomligt dricksvatten f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">6.2 - By 2030, achieve access to adequate and equitable sanitation and hygiene for all and end open defecation, paying special attention to the needs of women and girls and those in vulnerable situations.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">6.2 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla har tillg&#xE5;ng till fullgod och r&#xE4;ttvis sanitet och hygien och att ingen beh&#xF6;ver utr&#xE4;tta sina behov utomhus. S&#xE4;rskild uppm&#xE4;rksamhet b&#xF6;r &#xE4;gnas &#xE5;t behoven hos kvinnor och flickor samt m&#xE4;nniskor i utsatta situationer.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2448437.0809966302</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2448437.0809966307</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-01">2457002.457002</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-28">349776.7258566615</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-28">2098660.355139969</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bangladesh/52170040_UM2017_23389_DHAK-44Secondamendmentofagreementonwatersafetyforthewellbeingofwomen7204353_1_1.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement amendment- Water safety for the wellbeing of women and children in Bangladesh</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bangladesh/52170040-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bangladesh/52170040-amendment.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bangladesh/decision1617.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Safety for the wellbeing of Women and Children in Bangladesh</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This conclusion on performance prepared for the period of October 2020 to September 2021 of the contribution with UNICEF.

The Embassy of Sweden signed an agreement with UNICEF to implement non-thematic support to Systems Strengthening and Scaling up Drinking Water Safety in Bangladesh programme in September 2017. The agreement was amended in July 2018 to include emergency support to the Rohingya crisis response and the title of the project was changed to non-thematic support to Water Safety for the Wellbeing of Women and Children in Bangladesh. This project is based on the realization that an important root cause of the gap between access to improved drinking water sources (97.8 per cent) and access to safe drinking water sources (35 per cent) is the lack of coordination and functional sector-wide platforms for sharing, adapting, adopting and utilizing successful approaches in a harmonized manner.

Due to the COVID-19 pandemic, field movements were restricted as the Government imposed country-wide lockdown and mobility restrictions for almost six months. This resulted in delays in the project implementation, and hence, a four months extension from September to December 2021 was requested and approved by the Embassy to complete the project as per plan. The new end date of the contribution activity is 31 December 2021.

This project aims to support the Government of Bangladesh to strengthen systems for scaling up safe drinking water in Bangladesh. Key project outcomes to be achieved by 2021 are : (1) roles and responsibilities for regulation, capacity building, service provision and water quality testing are assigned; (2) harmonized systems and procedures are deployed by stakeholders for the delivery of arsenic and bacteriologically safe drinking water; (3) evidence-based systems are used by accountable stakeholders in the health and drinking water sub-sectors. (4) Rohingya and host communities in Ukhiya and Teknaf Upazilas under Coxs Bazar District have sustainable WASH services. This Annual report covers the project period from September 2020 to August 2021.

The key achievements during the reporting period are:

During the reporting period, four strategies and guidelines namely National Operations &amp; Maintenance (O&amp;M) Guidelines for WASH, Response to COVID-19 Outbreak through WASH Interventions Bangladesh Strategy Paper 2020-2023, and National Strategy for Menstrual Hygiene Management (MHM) were finalized and submitted to the Ministry of Local Government, Rural Development and Cooperatives (MoLGRD &amp; C) for approval. The project organised three sub-national workshops in all three targeted Upazilas on Policy &amp; Protocols Review and Capacity Building of Private Sector for Arsenic Safe Water for 119 key local government institutes (LGI) representatives, non-governmental organisations (NGO) officials, local technocrats and local drillers. The workshop provided a platform for the participants to share their valuable experience regarding Arsenic Mitigation at Source (ASMITAS), drillers capacity enhancement programme and harmonized plans and protocols 25 master trainers, 88 private and public drillers and 81 local technocrats were trained on arsenic issues, technologies and safe drilling in all three targeted Upazilas. As a result of these trainings, at least 85 per cent of the drillers reported an improved understanding of standard limits of arsenic in the water and the provision of arsenic-free water points.

The project, in collaboration with the Non-Communicable Disease Center (NCDC) of the Ministry of Health and Family Welfare (MoH &amp; FW), trained more than 220 health workers, medical officers and Government and NGO representatives (90 per cent women) on arsenicosis detection and management protocol. It is expected that the training will lead to strengthening the capacity of the participants for identification and referral of suspected cases of arsenicosis for proper diagnosis on time and support to conduct health camps in arsenic affected areas.

The project established a groundwater level monitoring system through piezometer drilling in 16 unions in the targeted three Upazilas. ASMITAS was extensively used for data capturing during the interventions.

A total of 30 climate-resilient double platform deep tubewells were constructed in flood-prone areas of Sylhet districts, benefitting 3,100 people including 1,519 women.

During this reporting period, 65,898 women, men and children gained access to arsenic-safe drinking water from 731 new and rehabilitation of water supply facilities. Cumulatively, 169,262 women, men and children gained access to arsenic-safe drinking water from a total of 1,460 newly installed or rehabilitated or switching to, safe water points. This represents 92 per cent of the total target beneficiaries of 183,000 people.

In Coxs Bazar, 105,375 people benefitted from access to safe water and 160,000 people from WASH supplies and hygiene education. This represents 100 per cent of targeted beneficiaries.

Success of this contribution, innovations and quality of work convinced Bangladesh government to continually get the technical support from UNICEF in their big initiative for country wide Arsenic mitigation. The Chief Engineer of DPHE has formally requested UNICEF for their technical support and quality assurance role. Now UNICEF proposed Embassy for funding this technical support part. The Embassy planned to provide this support to UNICEF through extending this contribution for one more year.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52170040" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1750000000" strategy-end-date="2025-12-31" strategy-start-date="2021-01-01">
    <sida:title>Bangladesh 2021-2025</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Bangladesh 2021-2025</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
