<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-29-2011-7370-666-43082</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Att utveckla en modell av patientens s&#xE4;kerhetssystem f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra kvaliteten p&#xE5; v&#xE5;rden vid sjukhusen i Bangladesh</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To develop a model of patient safety system to improve the safety and quality of patient care at the Intensive Care Units at the hospitals in Ban</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intensive Care Units (ICU), equipped with life support devices is prone to patient safety problems. Human and financial toll due to adverse events is high specially in developing countries like Bangladesh, due to failure in the design, organization and operation of the system. This proposal plans to develop a support system to reduce hazards and errors and improve the quality of care and safety. ICUs organizational structure, process and the occurrence of adverse outcomes will be studied. A multidisciplinary team from Sweden and Bangladesh will work together to study the factors related to Patient safety. Hazards related to medical device use will be addressed during device development as part of the risk management. Guidelines will be developed to detect failures and complications, spread patient safety principles. This work will provide a template to improve the safety aspects at the ICU employing ICT tools, to develop capabilities specifically in the areas of electronic medical records, medical equipment management and maintenance routine, medical and health education to prevent a person from being placed at risk of injury due to dangerous or defective devices or procedures. After the finalisation of this proposed project, we anticipate a continuation and replication of the project at other hospitals and clinics in Bangladesh, and other developing countries.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">To develop a model of patient safety system to improve the quality of patient care at the Intensive Care Units at the hospitals in Bangladesh The Intensive Care Unit (ICU) equipped with modern life support devices is particularly prone to problems related to patient safety. WHO noted with concern that there is a high human and financial toll due to adverse events and most of the harm to the patients is due to failure in the design, organization and operation of the system. The conditions are more acute in the developing countries like Bangladesh where there is a serious lack of risk management system. This proposal aims to provide a better understanding for the errors, risks and accidents related to the use of medical devices at the ICU, and to develop a support system using ICT tools in order to reduce hazards and errors and thus improve the quality of performance, care and cost effectiveness at the ICU. A multidisciplinary team from Sweden and Bangladesh will work together to study Patient factors, Task factors, Provider factors, Team factors and Institutional environment factors. The team will develop guidelines to detect failures and complications, spread patient safety principles and set the stage for further work to ensure safe and effective use of medical devices and thus improve patient safety and care. Potential use-related hazards will be identified using human factors engineering. The work will also describe how hazards related to medical device use should be addressed during device development as part of the risk management process guidance. Engineering and organisational skills will be developed to provide increased risk management activities to improve patient safety. A reporting system that allows clinicians and others to understand the problem will be created. This work will provide a template for future clinicians, researchers, and policy makers to improve the safety aspects at the ICU to bring benefit to all patients, poor and female in particular, who are dependent on the government hospitals. ICT tools will be employed to start developing electronic medical records, medical equipment management and maintenance routine, medical and health education to prevent a person from being placed at risk of injury due to dangerous or defective devices or procedures. The project will increase visibility of the ICT related activities for better safety at the hospitals in the developing countries. The project?s impact would be; effective intensive care with reduced risk, fewer people in accident, enhanced efficiencies in the health sector, provide better health, increase ability for higher income and thus reduce poverty. Therefore, the project will make significant contribution to achieve to support developing countries for better access to health information, delivery of safe medical knowledge and communication for the benefit of the patients After the finalisation of this proposed project, we anticipate a continuation and replication of the project at other hospitals and clinics in Bangladesh, and other developing countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-29" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Swedish Research Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University, college or other teaching institution, research institute or think-tank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Swedish Research Council</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 546 44 000</telephone>
   <email>vetenskapsradet@vr.se</email>
   <website>www.vr.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Box 1035, 101 38 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">38383.5902474974</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">36443.6799370253</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-11-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-11-15">115576.6504345682</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-28">36443.6799370253</value>
  </transaction>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
