<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41152786-1800-4</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41152786" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voice for Change Partnership-Indonesia-Food and nutrition security</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia-Food and nutrition security</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the &#x2018;Voice for Change Partnership&#x2019; (V4CP) programme, SNV works to strengthen civil society organisations (CSOs) in their role as advocates and lobbyists. We work together with IFPRI and over 50 CSOs to foster collaboration among relevant stakeholders, and influence decision-makers with solid and contextualized evidence to get the interests of communities embedded into government and business policies and practices. For this specific project in Indonesia, our advocacy activities focus on Food &amp; Nutrition Security (FNS).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim to motivate and encourage provincial and district governments to implement policies and programmes targeting chronic malnutrition, in order to improve the nutritional condition of children below the age of 5 and to decrease stunting among the same age group.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Indonesia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Indonesia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41152786-3552" ref="NL-KVK-41152786" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The International Food Policy Research Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="4004" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>maritonang@snv.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jl. Kemang Timur Raya No. 66
Jakarta Selatan 12730
Indonesia</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="6"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-6.208763 106.845599</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">253925</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-01-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">562521</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">562521</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41152786-3552" ref="NL-KVK-41152786" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Indonesia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">253925</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41152786-3552" ref="NL-KVK-41152786" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/4004/Project_4004_current_image_2016-03-07_16.37.48.PNG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41152786-3552" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evidence on Food Availability (Dietary Diversity, Increase Production and Land Optimization), Access to Food (Crop Diversification); Food Utilization (Nutrition Education) Available</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evidence made available by SNV, IFPRI and/or other research/knowledge institutes</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of policy briefs and/or evidence based knowledge products made available to CSO that are supportive to its advocacy plan</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">FNS study data collection will be conducted in August 2017.  There are some roles  between SNV, IFPRI and CSO for the study.                                                                                                         
Roles of SNV Indonesia: SNV is main lead of the study. SNV will prepare TOR, budget and financing for the study. SNV will review, revise questionnaire drafter by IFPRI and translate it in to bahasa Indonesia version. SNV will mobilize CSOs and team and provide training for the enumerators and supervisors. SNV will share questionnaire, manual, and V4CP program brief, survey CTO structure on device pretesting survey form during training. SNV will supervise CSOs; communicating findings with team during data collection process. SNV will prepare sampling frame for selection of household respondents using systematic sampling.                                                                                                         
Roles of CSO: CSO will  coordinate the FNS study with provincial, district and subdistrict and village government including legal letter; provides list of villages and sub-district for each respective area. CSO will collect household data for selected villages. CSO will also recruit enumerators and supervisors, direct supervision data collection. In collaboration with SNV ensuring quality of data submitted to the server. 
Roles of IFPRI : IFPRI will adjust the TOR, draft questionnaire and manual; sampling of villages. IFPRI will  create and revise survey form based on pretesting. IFPRI will be involved in first training. IFPRI will review data submitted to be followed up by SNV and perform data cleaning. IFPRI will analyze data and prepare general findings in learning workshop. IFPRI will prepare preliminary report , full report and policy brief.      
It will be expected to share general findings in September and preliminary study report in October 2017. The final report will be available on December 2017.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">in half year There will be 1  one study report on current situation/reality of practices of FNS condition of household, Food security mapping policy/program, review on FNS secondary data</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: Result of Analysis of secondary data on food an nutrition provided to CSOs. The final document will be presented in September</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">in half year There will be 2 two study report on current situation/reality of practices of FNS condition of household; and review on FNS secondary data</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: There were two research reports from IFPRI made available to CSOs. These were Food and Nutrition Security Indicators from DHS (demographic and health surveys) and Susenas (The National Socioeconomic Survey) data. However, the analysis process took longer time than it was expected to be. It was finished by the end of December 2017. It caused the CSOs lost the opportunity to disseminate the research in 2017. Another research was FAO&#x2019;s (The&#xA0;Food and Agriculture Organization&#xA0;of the United Nations) research about integrating food security, nutrition, and good governance in district development planning through advocacy, social mobilization, and capacity strengthening.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There will be at least 5 new knowledge products related to budget tracking research for each area</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="8.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: there were 8 evidence made available to CSOs which are 5 studies of budget tracking from Lombok Timur, Lombok Utara, Manggarai, Flores Timur, and Kupang, 1 desk research by IFPRI related to adolescent nutrition in Indonesia, 1 research in Kupang about adolescent nutrition and food consumption pattern, and 1 GESI (Gender and Social Inclusion) and climate on FNS in NTB Province that used to advocate the FNS provincial action plan (RADPG)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the 2018, there will be 5 research reports which are; 1) Budget tracking study 2) Mapping of FNS policy study 3) Stunting and the yearly trends 4) Interconnected approach to food, climate, and sustainability study 5) Private sector scoping study</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: There were 4 evidence made available to CSOs which are 1) FNS policy review 2)Lesson learned from Oelnasi village that conducted by Bengkel Appek with FNS forum to advocate the district government and 3) East Lombok Stunting Survey by IFPRI. However, Konsepsi just disseminated the pre-elimanary results from the stunting survey because the final report is still in the finalisastion process by IFPRI 4) Riskesdas 2018 (Health national survey) conducted by Health Ministry in the national government. it was effective to use data from national government to advocate the provincial and district government

For the budget tracking study, the time allocated for Budget Tracking  was extended to early 2019 due to several challenges faced in the field which had contributted to the delayed of analysis process. The CSOs experienced difficulties in obtaining data from local authorities, some for budget planning, and others experienced diffculties in obtaining Budget report (Spent/Expenditures)

For the other 2 studies in the previous target (private sector scoping study &amp; interconnected approach for food, climate, and sustainability) was cancelled due to the availibility of the time and priority for advocacy focus on 2018</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There will be additional of 4 research that will be finalised in the beginning of 2020 (before April) which are 1) correlation of worm infection with stunting, 2) budget gap research by IFPRI, 3) GESI assessment on FNS national action plan (RANPG), 4) V4CP lesson learned research</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: there were 2 evidence made available to CSOs which are 1)  Prevalence deworming and nutritional status on under two years children in East Flores and 2) GESI assessment on FNS national action plan (RANPG) by IFPRI. For budget gap research and V4CP lesson learned book are still in the finalisation process</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of portals and websites made accessible for CSOs that generate evidence for advocacy issues</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">there are no portals and websites made accessible for CSOs that generate evidence for advocacy issues</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Website: Ministry of Health (Basic Health Research, RDA)  Statistic Agency (Socio Economic Sensus, Pronvincial and District Statistic Data) Ministry of Agricultures (FSVA)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: There are 4 websites made accessible for CSOs for advocacy issues: Ministry of Health (Basic Health Research, RDA);  Statistic Agency (Socio Economic Sensus, Pronvincial and District Statistic Data) Ministry of Agricultures (FSVA), Health office at Provincial and district level website)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO continue to access FNS Websites: Ministry of Health (Basic Health Research, RDA)  Statistic Agency (Socio Economic Census, Provincial and District Statistic Data) Ministry of Agriculture (FSVA)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="6.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: There are 6 portals/website made accessible for CSOs in 2017. CSOs continue to access FNS Websites: Ministry of Health (Basic Health Research, DRA - gizi.depkes.go.id), Statistic Agency (Socio Economic Census, Provincial and District Statistic Data - e.g., https://lombokutarakab.bps.go.id/), Ministry of Agriculture (FSVA - bkp.pertanian.go.id). In addition, there were several portals and websites made accessible for CSOs by the SNV staff or CSOs which were used together as an evidence. These were, for instance, video that explains the risk of stunting for children in Indonesia (By Katadata - https://katadata.co.id/video/2018/01/06/balita-indonesia-dihantui-stunting), TNP2K website (tnp2k.go.id) which sometimes discuss about FNS and stunting issues and www.gizitinggi.org which contains about stunting issue.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Besides the existing portals and websites that already made accessible for CSOs, it is already enough to support their advocacy process. They will use more on the evidence of the lesson learned evaluation from stunting intervention</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: There are no additional website/portals that regularly used by CSOs to advocate the government. CSOs continue to access website related to FNS such as Ministry of Health website, statistic agency (socio-economic census, provincial and district statistic data)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Besides the existing portals and websites that already made accessible for CSOs, it is expected that at least 4 additional portals and websites (in global and national level) are available to generate evidence such as FNS (Food and Nutrition Security) Forum (https://www.fsnnetwork.org/) and Jejaring informasi pangan dan gizi (Food and Nutrition information network)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: There are no additional website/portals that regularly used by CSOs to advocate the government. CSOs continue to access FNS Websites: Ministry of Health (Basic Health Research, DRA - gizi.depkes.go.id), Statistic Agency (Socio Economic Census, Provincial and District Statistic Data - e.g., https://lombokutarakab.bps.go.id/), Ministry of Agriculture (FSVA - bkp.pertanian.go.id). In addition, there were several portals and websites made accessible for CSOs by the SNV staff or CSOs which were used together as an evidence. These were, for instance, video that explains the risk of stunting for children in Indonesia (By Katadata - https://katadata.co.id/video/2018/01/06/balita-indonesia-dihantui-stunting), TNP2K website (tnp2k.go.id) which sometimes discuss about FNS and stunting issues and www.gizitinggi.org which contains about stunting issue.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Besides the existing portals and websites that already made accessible for CSOs, it is already enough to support their advocacy process. They will use more on the evidence of the lesson learned evaluation from stunting intervention</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: There are no additional website/portals that regularly used by CSOs to advocate the government. CSOs continue to access website related to FNS such as Ministry of Health website, statistic agency (socio-economic census, provincial and district statistic data)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Appropriate budget to improve Crop Diversification and Production; and Dietary Diversification allocated by related SKPD)* in District</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase/decrease (in %) of annual budget allocation for Crop Diversification and Production; and Dietary Diversification allocated by related SKPD* in Province/District</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage is based on absolute increase in budget allocation</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">(The annual budget allocation ranging from EUR 517052 to EUR 27131373). The budget data from 2016 indicated that FSN budget allocation are available  from different institution for FNS specific issues. The annual budget allocation ranging from EUR 517052 to EUR 27131373. Budget allocation for specific issues are still needed to breakdown for some institution. The percentage of of annual budget allocation for Crop Diversification and Production Dietary Diversification allocated by related SKPD in Province/District increase/decrease vary from 27% to 190% (Please see annex). The average of increase is 134.55</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="+1%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">in 2017 CSO will not directly touch budget issue, This will be promoted in medium and longterm outcome. However budget issue will be still promoted during the year through some activities under outcome D, E, F</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: The data from 2016 and 2017 for the whole budget allocation sector is not available. It was quite a challenge since the food and nutrition budget is divided in various line of agencies. Currently, CSOs and SNV with the support of IFPRI (International Food Policy Research) are conducting food and nutrition budget tracking research. The research will give CSOs and SNV some insights to track the budget for food and nutrition sector. It expected to be finished in the end of July 2018 which could be used as the baseline to monitor the budget and set the target for the next period.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Currently, the target is set at 2% increase in budget allocation for pillar 1 and 2 on food and nutrition sector. CSOs will more advocate the government to use the budget efficiently rather than for increasing the budget.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: It was range from -17 to 360%. Those data was based on the previous report and collected under budget tracking research by IFPRI, Pattiro, and CSOs. The increase budget allocation could be attributed as one of the results of CSOs&apos; work which advocated for stunting issue since 2016. In addition, stunting issue is a current top priority issue in the national. Therefore, it might influence the increase in the budget allocation also. In 2019, we are still not able to collect the allocation data and track it, but most of the villages allocated the village fund for stunting prevention and reduction. For instance, three villages in Kupang District who joined the workshop facilitated by Bengkel APPek allocated 30% (average) of their village fund for stunting reduction and prevention activity.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="+2%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target will be reviewed at a later stage after CSOs and SNV get the budget report or calculate the baseline based on the results of budget tracking research which targeted to be finished in the end of July 2018. Currently, the target is set at 2% increase in budget allocation for food and nutrition sector. There will be only one activity dedicated to budget allocation (participation in public hearings for budget allocations in parliament and Bappeda (Regional Planning and Development Agency))</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="150.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: For the crop diversification, production and dietary diversification are under pillar 1 and 2 in the FNS district action plan, therefore the total amount of those pillars are:
Manggarai &gt; 2016 : 9.166.461.221 , 2018 : 42.141.466.674
Kupang &gt; 2016 : 49.630.000.000 , 2018 : 41.410.000.000
Lombok Utara &gt; 2016 : 26.155.226.950 , 2018 : 67.204.716.803
Lombok Timur &gt; 2016 : 77.981.512.778 , 2017 : 158.210.070.363

Therefore, the details for increased percentage of the budget are:
Manggarai 2016 to 2018 &gt; 360%
Kupang 2016 to 2017 &gt; -17%
Lombok Utara 2016 to 2018 &gt; 157%
Lombok Timur 2016 to 2017 &gt; 103%
Flores Timur : there is no data for pillar 1 and 2

Those data was collected under budget tracking research by IFPRI, Pattiro, and CSOs. The report has not finalised yet because CSOs faced some challenges to collect the data especially for expenditure data in the beginning which made the delay in the report. The increase budget allocation could be attributed as one of the results of CSOs&apos; work which advocated for stunting issue since 2016. In addition, stunting issue is a current top priority issue in the national. Therefore, it might influence the increase in the budget allocation also.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Currently, the target is set at 2% increase in budget allocation for pillar 1 and 2 on food and nutrition sector. CSOs will more advocate the government to use the budget efficiently rather than for increasing the budget. Also, CSOs will advocate for the utilisation of village fund for the targeted programme in stunting reduction and prevention</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: Due to COVID-19 situation, there is a major budget re-allocation in this period. Therefore, it is hard for us to get the information about the 2021 budget allocation of FNS for all four areas. Also, FNS budget is separated in several agencies. Then, CSOs did not conduct the budget tracking research this year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase/decrease (in %) of relative annual budget allocation for Crop Diversification and Production; and Dietary Diversification by related SKPD* in Province/District level (budget for Crop Diversification and Production; and Dietary Diversification X as percentage of total Food Security Nutrition sector budget)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage is based on increase of budget for issue X as percentage of total sector budget</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relative annual budget allocation for Crop Diversification, Production, and Dietary Diversification by related SKPD in Province/District level X as percentage of total Food Security Nutrition sector budget vary from 1.7% to 100%. (Please see annex). The average is 22,5%</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="+1%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">in 2017 CSO will not directly touch budget issue, This will be promoted in medium and longterm outcome. However budget issue will be still promoted during the year through some activities under outcome D, E, F</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: The data from 2016 and 2017 for the whole budget allocation sector is not available. It was quite a challenge since the food and nutrition budget is divided in various line of agencies. Currently, CSOs and SNV with the support of IFPRI (International Food Policy Research) are conducting food and nutrition budget tracking research. The research will give CSOs and SNV some insights to track the budget for food and nutrition sector. It expected to be finished in the end of July 2018 which could be used as the baseline to monitor the budget and set the target for the next period.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="+2%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Currently, the target is set at 2% increase in budget allocation for pillar 1 and 2 on food and nutrition sector. CSOs will more advocate the government to use the budget efficiently rather than for increasing the budget.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: It was range from -19.95% to 43.2%. Those data was based on the previous report and collected under budget tracking research by IFPRI, Pattiro, and CSOs. The increase budget allocation could be attributed as one of the results of CSOs&apos; work which advocated for stunting issue since 2016. In addition, stunting issue is a current top priority issue in the national. Therefore, it might influence the increase in the budget allocation also.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="+2%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target will be reviewed at a later stage after CSOs and SNV get the budget report or calculate the baseline based on the results of budget tracking research which targeted to be finished in the end of July 2018. Currently, the target is set at 2% increase in budget allocation for food and nutrition sector. There will be only one activity dedicated to budget allocation (participation in public hearings for budget allocations in parliament and Bappeda (Regional Planning and Development Agency))</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="13.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: Based on budget tracking research, here it is the details of FNS related budget allocation
Manggarai &gt; 2016 : 21.421.963.131, 2017 : 18.323.689.321, 2018 : 49.007.070.702 (2016 to 2018 &gt; 128.7%)
Kupang &gt; 2016 : 85.701.926.863, 2018 : 109.094.765.219 (2016 to 2018 &gt; 27.3%)
Lombok Utara &gt; 2016 : 76.684.956.570, 2017 : 100.130.970.397, 2018 : 99.336.015.263 (2016 to 2018 &gt; 29.5%)
Lombok Timur &gt;  2016 : 87.001.687.712, 2017 : 167.882.528.027 (2016 to 2017 &gt; 92.9%)
Flores Timur &gt; 2016 : 54.657.113.766, 2017 : 54.656.934.822 (2016 to 2017 &gt; 0%)

For the crop diversification, production and dietary diversification are under pillar 1 and 2 in the FNS district action plan, therefore the proportion of those pillars compare to whole FNS budget are:
Manggarai &gt; 2016 : 42.7 % , 2018 : 85.99%
Kupang &gt; 2016 : 57.9%, 2017 : 37.95%
Lombok Utara &gt; 2016 : 34.1% , 2018 : 61.6%
Lombok Timur &gt; 2016 : 89.6% , 2017 : 94.2%
Flores Timur : we still did not get the complete data per pillar, therefore we could not calculate this

Therefore, these are the details for increased percentage for relative annual budget:
Manggarai : 2016 to 2018 &gt; 43.2%
Kupang : 2016 to 2017 &gt; -19.95%
Lombok Utara : 2016 to 2018 &gt; 27.5%
Lombok Timur : 4.6%

Those data was collected under budget tracking research by IFPRI, Pattiro, and CSOs. The report has not finalised yet because CSOs faced some challenges to collect the data especially for expenditure data in the beginning which made the delay in the report. The increase budget allocation could be attributed as one of the results of CSOs&apos; work which advocated for stunting issue since 2016. In addition, stunting issue is a current top priority issue in the national. Therefore, it might influence the increase in the budget allocation also.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Currently, the target is set at 2% increase in budget allocation for food and nutrition sector. CSOs will more advocate the government to use the budget efficiently rather than for increasing the budget. Also, CSOs will advocate for the utilisation of village fund for the targeted programme in stunting reduction and prevention</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: Due to COVID-19 situation, there is a major budget re-allocation in this period. Therefore, it is hard for us to get the information about the 2021 budget allocation of FNS for all four areas. Also, FNS budget is separated in several agencies. Then, CSOs did not conduct the budget tracking research this year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased Active Participation of NGO/CSO, working unit (Satuan Kerja Perangkat Daerah -SKPD*), Media and CBO in Advocacy Work through Food and Nutrition Forum, Platform, and Networking at Province and District Level</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of formal and informal meeting with related Government Working Unit (Satuan Kerja Perangkat Daerah-SKPD) and CBO at province and district level</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of encounters is total number of encounters</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="7" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">7 total meeting divided per 5 CSO, with working unit members (SKPD), key stakeholder represented meeting is from Regional Office (Bapeda), Agriculture Office, Regional Office, Health Office, Food Security Agency (at Province and District level) in the last one year</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Based on the annual plan of 2018, it is expected to have 4 encounters in the next 6 month per CSO. It will decrease from previous status because usually in the beginning of the year, the CSOs and district government offices will put more focus on the planning process.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="48.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">13-09-2018: The encounters amount are beyond our target because stunting issue gets the significant momentum this year. President of Indonesia instructed the reduction of stunting as the priority program. Also, all of our programme areas are belong to 160 city/district as the priority for stunting intervention. Therefore, the government also eager to involved in this issue and ask our CSOs for the collaboration. Ayo Indonesia had in total 11 encounters.  4 encounters to conduct the study in the village as the pilot project to gather stunting data. They also had 7 meetings with the government especially with the reduction stunting team task force to develop the district action plan for FNS. Konsepsi had 10 encounters where most of the interaction related to village level research for stunting, raising the issue of FNS in the village, assisting their budgeting and planning to allocate FNS program. Also, most of the encounters were related to FNS district action plan discussion. Transform had 10 encounters which ranging from the discussion with village and sub-district for FNS issue, assisting village for FNS program planning, FNS research in the village, discussion with other NGOs and stakeholders such as PAMSIMAS (community water team) about collaboration for stunting issue. YPPS had 7 meeting which covered the meeting with FNS forum, discussion with the health agency related to intervention focus, discussion about Bupati&apos;s regulation for local food diversification, collecting FNS data from village level, and preparation for FNS district action planning. Bengkel APPeK had 10 encounters. Since it was their first year for this programme work in Kabupaten Kupang, most of the meeting discussed the FNS issue first. Also, some of the activity was about the establishment of FNS forum in village Oelnasi as the pilot project. They also collected some initial data related FNS from this village</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="42">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on the trend for the last 6 month in 2018, it is expected that CSOs will have at least the same amount of encounters to support and advocate the government to develop inclusive FNS district action plan and make proper intervention strategy since this issue has already been a priority in the national, province, and district. Therefore, the focus for the next 6 month is to oversee the development of regulation and implementation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="44.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">18-10-2019: Stunting issue still a priority of the national programme. Also, all of our programme areas are to 160 city/district as the priority for stunting intervention. Therefore, the government is eager to be involved in this issue and ask our CSOs for the collaboration. 

Ayo Indonesia had in total 8 encounters. It included several meetings to finalise FNS action plan and scaled up to neighboring district which is Manggarai Timur and had several meeting to influence Bupati and facilitate the gathering to discuss stunting in the district and village level.  

Konsepsi had 11 encounters where most of the interaction related to advocating the village head on the stunting issue, facilitated the convergence planning from various stakeholder in the government for stunting reduction effort, supported for stunting situation analysis based on the survey result, and facilitated the voice of women in the development planning meeting to discuss FNS issue. 

Transform had 9 encounters where it was related to facilitation of FNS action plan (RADPG) establishment, monitor the planning process from a different agency in the government for stunting reduction effort, and scaling up the initiative in the Mataram city which tried to connect sanitation and FNS issue. 

YPPS had 9 meetings which covered the meeting with FNS forum, development of FNS action plan, implementation of &quot;Gempur stunting&quot; movement including supported convergence actions at districts, advocate regulaton on village fund allocation for FNS activities, establishment of Monev tools for stunting management at village level, and advocated the church organisation to raise the stunting issue.

Bengkel APPeK had 7 encounters. Together with the district government, they raised the commitment from village leader to address FNS issue through planning and budget allocation from village fund. Also, they facilitated the development of FNS action plan (RADPG) in the district level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In half year there will be 2 formal and informal meeting with related Government Working Unit (Satuan Kerja Perangkat Daerah-SKPD) and CBO at province and district level per CSO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="20.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: &apos;For this reporting period at provincial level in average there were 4  encounters (formal &amp; informal) have been made by 5 CSOs. Formal encounters are made based acitvity under annual advocacy plan. At the district level in average there were  7 encounters (formal and informal)   have been made by 4 CSOs. One CSO in NTT-Bengkel APk is only working in provincial level). At the provincial level encounters with relevant actors were mainly made by 2 CSOs (Bengkel Apek, Transform).  General formal encounters inluded formal discussion with Goverment and stakeholder at the district level through dissemination of program, workshop, discussion and consultation on food and nutrition.  Informal encounters including preparation for the for all activity (preparation, coordination and communication, participating in Government events related to FNS issues)  Encounters were done with Government and Provincial level ( Bappeda, Health Office, Agriculture Office, Food Security Agencies, Ministry of Village, Provincial/District Secretary, legislative, Forestry and Environment Office, District of population control and family planning, Child protection and women empowerment);  Local NGOs/CSOs (i.e Yaspensel, Pikul); University , media  (Flores Pos, Bali News, Pos Kupang, Jurnal Timur).  Intention of those encounters included to discuss the implementation of FNS policy from national level and the implementation in the provincial and district level; FNS issues especially to food availability, access and utilization with more concern to stunting, policy on food and nutrition including local food  development/revision  of local action plan FNS document);  establishment/revitalization of FNS multistakeholder forum  including establishment of informal forum to discuss FNS group (social media. i.e whats up group, facebook); coordination, cooperation and colaboration among Government offices/agencies in implementing in related to FNS; engagement, involvement and networking wit ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In half year there will be 3 formal and informal meeting with related Government Working Unit (Satuan Kerja Perangkat Daerah-SKPD) and CBO at province and district level per CSO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="38.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: In total, there were 38 meetings and encounters with the government and relevant-community/stakeholder by all CSOs (8 meetings per CSO in average). Previously, the targeted amount of meetings was 3 per CSO. However, as the relationship between CSOs and related OPD (Regional Government Offices) was getting closer in the last 6 months of 2017, the number of encounters was increased.  Another factor was that government was focus on its planning processes in the first half of the year. On the second half of the year (July-December) government has more flexible time. Therefore, CSOs have bigger opportunity to encounter with government. Most of the activities were part of the coordination meeting with Food Security Agency, Health Agency, Bappeda (Regional Development and Planning Agency, BPBD (Regional Disaster Management Agency), other CSOs and community. All CSOs were involved in the establishment of food nutrition security forum and World Food Day celebration in each districts. For instance, YPPS involved in the establishment and selection of the board of Food Nutrition Security Forum, conducted thematic discussion about stunting and dietary habit with the multi-stakeholder forum, as well as spreading stunting issue at the community level. YAI also had a workshop in the World Food Day, as well as creating an exhibition booth to spread stunting issue to stakeholders. Beside conducted similar event and meetings, Konsepsi involved in the RPJMD (Regional Development Plan) and budget allocation discussion at the district level. Additionally, Konsepsi also socialized food insecurity map. Bengkel Appek had some meetings that focused more on CSOs forum which concerned about food and nutrition security issues. It also had several meetings with media and district government to spread stunting issue.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="44">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on the trend for the first 6 months in 2019, it is expected that CSOs will have at least the same amount of encounters to support and advocate the government to develop inclusive FNS district action plan and make proper intervention strategy since this issue has already been a priority in the national, province, and district. Therefore, the focus for the next 6 month is to scale up towards neighboring district and oversee the development of regulation and implementation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="31.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: Stunting issue is part of top priority for our national medium term planning (2019 - 2024) , the government is eager to be involved in this issue and ask our CSOs for the collaboration. 

Ayo Indonesia had in total 8 encounters. It included several meetings to push FNS action plan as the Bupati (head of district)&apos;s regulation and scaled up to neighboring district which is Manggarai Timur and had several meeting to advocate PKK and Darmawanita (women group in the district) for their involvement against stunting and also advocated for the establishment of stunting prevention and reduction team

Konsepsi had 6 encounters where most of the interaction related to advocating the incorporation of GESI aspect based on their research results in the Province FNS action plan, review process of Bupati&apos;s regulation related to stunting for sharpening the role of responsibility until the village level, the invovement of PKK (women group) for stunting reduction effort, realisation of budge allocation for stunting, and performance assessment of cities/districts on convergence action for stunting reduction and prevention on the NTB-province level

Transform had 6 encoutners where most of the interaction about the development of NTB Province FNS action plan (RADPG), RADPG Lombok Utara, research about GESI and climate aspect on FNS in NTB province, facilitated the convergence action for stunting reduction and prevention programme, and facilitated the involvement of youth for FNS issue through business competition to address FNS problems namely SEMETHON

YPPS had 6 meetings which covered the meeting to advocate village government for utilisation of their budget for stunting prevention and reduction through workshop and multi-stakeholder monitoring and evaluation for the priority villages for stunting effort and continued advocacy to District Government to establish and launched District Regulation on Stunting prevention and reduction using Village Fund. Also, they advoc ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="48">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on the trend for the first 6 months in 2018, it is expected that CSOs will have at least the same amount of encounters to support and advocate the government to develop inclusive FNS district action plan and make proper intervention strategy since this issue has already been a priority in the national, province, and district. Therefore, the focus for the next 6 month not advocating this issue to be a priority for the government, but to oversee the development of regulation and implementation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="42.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: Stunting issue still a priority of national programme. Also, all of our programme areas are belong to 160 city/district as the priority for stunting intervention. Therefore, the government also eager to involved in this issue and ask our CSOs for the collaboration. Ayo Indonesia had in total 8 encounters. It involved several meetings to develop FNS action plan and collaboration with food security agency and health agency to increase the capacity of local champion for stunting issue.  Also, they had public hearing with legislative to discuss the stunting intervention in Manggarai.  Konsepsi had 9 encounters where most of the interaction related to develop FNS local action plan, conduct the stunting survey research in 10 priority villages, do data verfication and discuss the results of the survey, develop the integrated stunting management system and stunting reduction roadmap based on the research finding. Also, most of the encounters were related to preparation for FNS seminar invited various stakeholders from all over Indonesia. Transform had 8 encounters after the earthquake. their focus after earthquake was more advocating the government to assist the village for capacity building related to food nutrition security after earthquake. They also have several meeting with village government to dissuss those issues. Then, they prepared for the discussion of Lombok Utara&apos; resilience and FNS nationa seminar. YPPS had 8 meeting which covered the meeting with FNS forum, development of FNS action plan, workshop with village government to plan and allocate budget for FNS issue from village fund, development of &quot;Flores Timur Gempur Stunting / stunting reduction movement&quot; strategy and intervention. Bengkel APPeK had 9 encounters. Since it was their first year for this programme work in Kabupaten Kupang, most of the meeting related to advocacy in the village level. Together with district government, they raised the commitment from village leader to address FNS ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on the trend for the last 6 month in 2019, it is expected that CSOs will have less amount of encounters to support and advocate the government to develop inclusive FNS district action plan and make proper intervention strategy because it will be the last year implementation of the programme, and they will not arrange the activities until the end of the year. Also, they will focus more on the establishment of regulation that still pending and monitor the implementation of the regulation/strategy, and advocate more group such as women group, youth group, potential disadvantaged people for joining the effort.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="58.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: Stunting issue is part of the top priority for our national medium-term planning (2019 - 2024), the government is eager to be involved in this issue and ask our CSOs for the collaboration. 
 
 Ayo Indonesia had in total 10 encounters. It included several meetings to advocate PKK and Darmawanita (women group in the district) for their involvement against stunting (in 76 villages), training for health cadre related to stunting, media visit to raise the awareness about stunting, the documentary film about the effort of stunting prevention and reduction in Manggarai, dissemination of Bupati&apos;s regulation related to District FNS action plan (RADPG), and supported the stunting prevetion and reduction convergence action of the government.
 
 Konsepsi had 12 encounters where most of the interaction related to advocating the incorporation of GESI aspect based on their research results in the NTB Province FNS action plan (RADPG), budget gap research, facilitated the convergence action for stunting prevention and reduction programme, and raised the involvement of youth through MISSION (Millenials scientist for nutrition) which is research competition and social media campaign for FNS issue. It was attended by key stakeholder in province, national, and even international level. It was beneficial to raise the visibility of FNS topic during the pandemic situation, and CSO and SNV profiling. 
 
 Transform had 11 encoutners where most of the interaction about the development of NTB Province FNS action plan (RADPG) and incorporated the GESI aspect based on the research findings, RADPG/FNS action plan for North Lombok, and facilitated the involvement of youth for FNS issue through a business competition to address FNS problems namely SEMETHON. It was attended by key stakeholder in province, national, and even international level. It was beneficial to raise the visibility of FNS topic during the pandemic situation, and CSO and SNV profiling. 
 
 YPPS had 11 meetings wh ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of knowledge/research products on food and nutrition security shared with relevant SKPD* and CBO at province and district Level</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of evidence based knowledge/research products shared is total number of unique evidence based knowledge/research products shared</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">there is no evidence based knowledge/research products shared with relevant stakeholders per CSO so far</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In half year There will be 1  knowledge/research products on FNS shared with relevant SKPD* and CBO at province and district Level per CSO     (1 study report (quantitative on current situation/reality of practices of FNS condition of household, Food security mapping policy/program, review on FNS secondary data</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018:  There was different between expected result and target due to delay of FNS study training and data collection during August 2017. During last 6 months were focusing on FNS study preparation. It will be expected to share general findings in September 2017 and preliminary study report in October 2017. The final report will be available on December 2017. IFPRI will present the results of the survey to the SNV and CSOs at a learning workshop. IFPRI will analyse the data on food security, diet diversity, access to government services, crop production, and livelihood strategies.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;In mid-year of 2018, it is expected to have at least 4 food and nutrition security research products that shared to relevant government stakeholder. These are: 1) FNS indicator based on Susenas (The National Socioeconomic Survey), 2) Food and nutrition security indicator based on DHS (Demographic Health Survey), 3) Budget tracking and mechanism study, 4) FNS policy study</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">16-09-2018: here are 2 studies has already shared with relevant stakeholder. These are: 1) FNS indicator based on Susenas (The National Socioeconomic Survey), 2) Food and nutrition security indicator based on DHS (Demographic Health Survey). The FNS policy study has finished, and will be distributed to the relevant stakeholder (e.g., district action plan task force, FNS multi-stakeholder forum, health agency, food security agency, agriculture agency, etc) upon the completion of policy brief.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There will be at least 2 new knowledge products related to budget tracking research. It is expected that it will finish on mid May</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">18-10-2019: There is one study has already shared with relevant stakeholder: Budget tracking research in East Lombok. It was used by the government to give the input for their budget allocation for stunting reduction initiative</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In half year There will be 2 knowledge/research products on FNS shared with relevant SKPD* and CBO at province and district Level per CSO     (1 study report (quantitative on current situation/reality of practices of FNS condition of household, review on FNS secondary data</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: There was a delay on food and nutrition security indicator research results. The results was finished in the end of December 2017. Therefore, CSOs did not fully utilize it for advocacy in 2017. However, CSOs were regularly used food nutrition and security data from government, for instance: Basic Health Research (Riskesdas) as one of the evidences for advocacy. CSOs also used success stories from other areas as the evidence in its presentation when having meetings with government. CSOs believe that the real case from the pilot project or other areas could be a strong evidence for relevant stakeholders. As an example, YPPS used success story from Kawalelu Village which has improved its nutritional status using local food such as Sorghum.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There will be at least 7 new knowledge products that produced by each CSO and their government counterpart which are SIMANTRI (integrated agricultural management) research, FNS and stunting census, and influence of non-food aspect for stunting research, GESI aspects on Government Programs, and two additional research by IFPRI which are GESI review within FNS action plan and Indonesian adolescent nutrition program : IFA Supplementation desk review</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="8.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: There are 8 studies has already shared with relevant stakeholder. These are 5 studies of budget tracking from Lombok Timur, Lombok Utara, Manggarai, Flores Timur, and Kupang, 1 desk research by IFPRI related to adolescent nutrition in Indonesia, 1 research in Kupang about adolescent nutrition and food consumption pattern, and 1 GESI (Gender and Social Inclusion) and climate on FNS in NTB Province that used to advocate the FNS provincial action plan (RADPG)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the end of 2018, it is expected to have at least 3 food and nutrition security research products that shared to relevant government stakeholder (e.g., district action plan task force, FNS multi-stakeholder forum, health agency, food security agency, agriculture agency, etc). These are 1) FNS policy research 2) Budget tracking research and 3) Stunting baseline research for Lombok Timur</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: There are 5 studies has already shared with relevant stakeholder. These are:
1) FNS survey in NTB 
2) FNS survey in NTT
3) FNS policy review
4) East Lombok Stunting Survey
5) Lesson Learned from Oelnasi Village (Kupang District)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There will be at least 4 new knowledge products that will be dissemianted before the end of the programme which are 1) correlation of worm infection with stunting, 2) budget gap research by IFPRI, 3) GESI assessment on FNS national action plan (RANPG), 4) V4CP lesson learned research</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: Besides the previous research from 2019 which still be disseminated until now (1 desk research by IFPRI related to adolescent nutrition in Indonesia, 1 research in Kupang about adolescent nutrition and food consumption pattern), there is one additional study has already shared with relevant stakeholder which is Deworming Prevalence and Nutritional Status on under two years old children in East Flores. The GESI assessment on FNS action plan research will be disseminated in the national level on September 2020, and budget gap research by IFPRI is still in the finalisation process</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of verbal interventions of CSO at relevant encounters on  Food Security with related and CBO at province and district level</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of interventions is total number of interventions</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="2" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">there were two types of intervention per CSO ; presentations, comments on presentation/asking for clarifications</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected to have verbal interventions from CSOs such as presentation, comments and recommendations in every encounters.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="48.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">16-09-2018: There was verbal intervention in each of the meetings conducted and participated by CSOs. Some of the example of their verbal interventions were raising the stunting issue based on community health data, bringing success stories of improved nutrition status due to increase of accessibility to food, availability and utilization of the food or dietary habit, the importance of holistic planning through RAD-PG, and stunting reduction intervention type. This verbal interventions made the government aware and know more detail about this issue and motivated them to develop the district action plan and intervention strategy. It also enhanced the necessity for collaboration to tackle stunting issue, and lead to the establishment of task force or multi-stakeholder forum for stunting reduction efforts</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="42">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected to have verbal interventions from CSOs such as presentation, comments and recommendations in every encounters. The focus for the next 6 month are finalisation of district action plan and facilitating the making of intervention strategy especially in the priority village for stunting reduction programme and scaling up to other areas</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="44.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">18-10-2019: There was a verbal intervention in each of the meetings conducted and participated by CSOs. Some of the example of their verbal interventions were raising the stunting issue based on community health data, bringing success stories of improved nutrition status due to increase of accessibility to food, availability and utilization of the food or dietary habit, the importance of convergence planning and actions for stunting reduction effort, the role of religious community for tackling stunting issue, and the importance of village fund utilisation for FNS issue. This verbal interventions made the government aware and know more detail about this issue and motivated them to develop the district action plan and intervention strategy. It also enhanced the necessity for collaboration to tackle stunting issue and lead to the establishment of the task force or multi-stakeholder forum for stunting reduction efforts</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In half year there will be 3 types of  intervention of CSO at relevant encounters (presentations, comments on presentation/asking for clarifications) on  Food Security encounters with related and CBO at province and district level per CSO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="15.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: In the last 6 months CSOs have encounters with relevant actors. Below are some example of intevention made by CSOs. It showed that all 5 CSOs were actively involved in the discussion related to budgeting FNS issues and  annual budget plan workshop in NTB and NTT provincial level. Three CSOs were actively involved in Local plan of FSN for the revision of document (Bengkel APPeK, Konsepsi and Transform).  One CSO (Konsepsi)  as part of core team was involved in the evaluation of SDG&apos;s implementation at the provincial level. All five CSOs and Government organized  a multi stakeholder workshop in building awareness on FNS forum. All five CSOs made coordination and consultation on FNS policy with related Government offices (SKPD)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">n half year there will be 3 types of  intervention of CSO at relevant encounters (presentations, comments on presentation/asking for clarifications) on  Food Security encounters with related and CBO at province and district level per CSO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="38.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: There was verbal intervention in each of the meetings conducted and participated by CSOs. Some of the example of their verbal interventions were raising the stunting issue based on community health data, bringing success stories of improved nutrition status due to increase of accessibility to food, availability and utilization of the food or dietary habit.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="44">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected to have verbal interventions from CSOs such as presentation, comments, and recommendations in every encounter. The focus for the next 6 month is the finalisation of district action plan and facilitating the making of intervention strategy especially in the priority village for stunting reduction programme and scaling up to other areas</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="31.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: There was verbal intervention in each of the meetings conducted and participated by CSOs. Some of the example of their verbal interventions were raising the importance of comvergence action for the stunting reduction and prevention effort, establishment of FNS action plan (RADPG), involvement of women group and religious leader for this issue, and the huge opportunity of village fund money to be mobilised for stunting reduction programme. Also, CSOs shared their research results such as GESI and climate change aspect for FNS in NTB province, adolescent nutrition and food consumption pattern in Kupang, and the correlation between worm infection and nutrition status particularly stunting. This verbal interventions made the government aware and know more detail about this issue and motivated them to develop the district action plan, stunting related regulation, and intervention strategy or flagship programme. It also enhanced the necessity for collaboration to tackle stunting issue, and lead to the establishment of task force or multi-stakeholder forum for stunting reduction efforts</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="48">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected to have verbal interventions from CSOs such as presentation, comments, and recommendations in every encounters. The focus for the next 6 month are leading and advocating the development of district action plan and facilitating the making of intervention strategy especially in the priority village for stunting reduction programme</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="42.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: There was verbal intervention in each of the meetings conducted and participated by CSOs. Some of the example of their verbal interventions were raising the stunting issue based on community health data, bringing success stories of improved nutrition status due to increase of accessibility to food, availability and utilization of the food or dietary habit, the importance of holistic planning through RAD-PG, and stunting reduction intervention type. Also, the importance of village fund utilisation for FNS issue. This verbal interventions made the government aware and know more detail about this issue and motivated them to develop the district action plan and intervention strategy. It also enhanced the necessity for collaboration to tackle stunting issue, and lead to the establishment of task force or multi-stakeholder forum for stunting reduction efforts</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected to have verbal interventions from CSOs such as presentation, comments and recommendations in every encounters. The focus for the next 6 month are finalisation of district action plan and monitor the implementation of the regulation/strategy, and advocate more group such as women group, youth group, potential disadvantaged people for joining the effort.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="58.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: There was verbal intervention in each of the meetings conducted and participated by CSOs. Some of the examples of their verbal interventions were raising the importance of convergence action for the stunting prevention and reduction effort, establishment of FNS action plan (RADPG), involvement of women group, difabled people organisation, and religious leader for this issue, and the huge opportunity of village fund money to be mobilised for stunting prevention and reduction programme. Also, CSOs shared their research results such as GESI and climate change aspect for FNS in NTB province, adolescent food consumption and health pattern in Kupang, and the Deworming prevalence and nutritional status on under two years old children, particularly stunting. This verbal interventions made the government aware and know more detail about this issue and motivated them to develop the district action plan, stunting related regulation, and intervention strategy or flagship programme. It also enhanced the necessity for collaboration to tackle stunting issue, and lead to the establishment of a task force or multi-stakeholder forum for stunting prevention and reduction efforts</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved Cooperation &amp; Collaboration of Multi-Stakeholder (NGO/CSO, working unit (SKPD) and CBO) in Advocacy Work through Food and Nutrition Forum, Platform, and Networking at Province and District Level</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree of collaboration between CSOs, working unit (SKPD) and CBO in advocacy work</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. no or only occasional formal or informal encounters between CSOs, government and private sector take place that are related to the issue
1. regular meetings and communications take place between CSOs, government and/or the private sector which are related to the issue
2. relevant theme related information / data are sought, shared and discussed among CSOs, government and/or the private sector.
3. plans that include CSOs interests are (jointly) made by CSOs, government and/or the private sector.
4. follow up actions are taken that includes CSOs interests</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO has no occasional formal encounters with Government related to FNS at Province level so far. However CSO has encounters with Government related to different issues of their program</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">in half year (CSO and Government and multistakeholder have regular meeting and communication  on Food Security Nutrition in 2017-2018 to discuss related Food security and nutrition)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: In general CSOs with Government and multistakeholder have regular meeting and communication on FNS issues. It is also due to establishment/revitalization of FNS multistakeholder forum  including establishment of informal communication forum to discuss FNS group through social media i.e whats up group, facebook. They used it for discussing FNS issues and following up in relevant meeting.  Here are major stakeholders that joined in communication group from different level, provincial and district level and sectors. Here are mainstakeholders: Bappeda, Health Office, Agriculture Office, Food Security Agencies, Ministry of Village, Provincial/District Secretary, legislative, Forestry and Environment Office, District of population control and family planning, Child protection and women empowerment);  Local NGOs/CSOs University , media  (Flores Pos, Bali News, Pos Kupang, Jurnal Timur).  Some FNS issues were discussed included food availability, access and utilization with more concern to stunting, policy, budget, regulation on food and nutrition including local food , sustainability of FNS forum, the utilization of government service on food availability, access and utilization</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that in the mid-2018, CSOs could jointly made planning for the relevant issue through this multi-stakeholder forum. It is a big opportunity as currently the forum has already established/revitalized.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">16-09-2018: In the district level, all of the CSOs got 4 as the score. CSOs had regular meetings and communication with district and provincial level government. In 2017, CSOs focused on revitalizing and encouraging the establishment of the multi-stakeholder forum to share and discuss relevant information related to food and nutrition security, including stunting issues. This year, CSOs were focused on collaboration to assist the implementation of follow-up actions with the government. For example, Ayo Indonesia monitored and facilitated the FNS District Action Plan. This was as one of the follow-up action plan after Ayo Indonesia advocating the importance of stunting issue to the stakeholder. Konsepsi collaborated with the district government to conduct stunting baseline survey as the input for establishing the regulation. YPPS and Bengkel APPek collaborated with the government to raise the issue of stunting and FNS towards the stakeholder in the village and sub-district. Then, Transform collaborated with the government and other NGOs to plan the intervention for 10 priority village. Actually, the follow-up actions were taken by the government which include CSO&apos;s interest. However, the level of commitment was still different in each government agency and stakeholder

The degree of collaboration between CSOs and provincial government got 2 as the average score. Bengkel Appek got 4 because follow up actions were taken related to stunting issue such as FNS provincial action plan and increasing budget for stunting issue. Konsepsi together with Transform got 2 because they were still focus on the district level and advocate more provincial government in 2019. Therefore the average score for district and provincial level is 3</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that in the mid-2019, CSOs will still have 4 as the score because Transform and Konsespi will scale their advocacy effort at provincial level especially to facilitate the FNS action plan in the provincial level. Therefore, both the score for province and district will be 4.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">18-10-2019: In the district level, all of the CSOs scored 4. CSOs had regular meetings and communication with the district and provincial-level government. At early 2018, CSOs focused on revitalizing and encouraging the establishment of the multi-stakeholder forum to share and discuss relevant information related to food and nutrition security, including stunting issues. At the mid-2018, CSOs were focused on collaboration to assist the implementation of follow-up actions with the government. In 2019, CSOs continue to help the government to change the system through the establishment of regulation and support the multi-stakeholder and convergence approach for stunting reduction. Also, CSOs started to scale up their experience in the neighboring district. For example, Ayo Indonesia monitored the finalisation of FNS District Action Plan and scaled up their intervention in Manggarati Timur to conduct the big gathering to discuss stunting issue. Konsepsi collaborated with the district government of East Lombok to develop convergence planning, especially for 20 villages as the focus based on the results of stunting survey and situation analysis. This year, Konsepsi scales up to provincial level while starting to approach and scale up to Central Lombok District. Transform collaborated with the government to finalise FNS action plan (RADPG) and tried to scale up the intervention in Mataram City and to link the stunting with sanitation issue. YPPS facilitated the government for FNS action plan and assisted the monitoring of 10 villages in making sure the allocation of village fund for FNS issue. Also, YPPS collaborated with the church community and made sure stunting reduction is one of the programmes for church organisation which covered Flores Timur and Lembata). Bengkel APPek collaborated with the government to raise the issue of stunting and FNS towards the stakeholder in the village and sub-district. Also, they assisted the village government to make the planning a ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">in half year (CSO and Government and multistakeholder have regular meeting and communication on Food and Nutrition Security to discuss related issue)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: CSOs had regular meetings and communication with district and provincial level government. In 2017, CSOs focused to revitalize and encourage the establishment of the multi-stakeholder forum to share and discuss relevant information related to food and nutrition security, including stunting issues. For example, there was food and nutrition forum which members are government, CSOs, universities, media, community leaders and parliament member in Lombok Utara (Transform), Kupang (Bengkel APPek), Manggarai (Ayo Indonesia), and Flores Timur (YPPS). CSOs also managed to establish informal communication forum to discuss relevant issue through social media i.e WhatsApp Group and Facebook. Some of the government agencies that actively collaborates for this issue were Bappeda (Regional Development and Planning Agency), Health Agency, Food Security Agency, Agriculture Agency and Village Empowerment Agency.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that in the end-2019, CSOs will still have 4 as the score because they will continue to collaborate with the government for FNS issue</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: All of the CSOs scored 4. CSOs had regular meetings and communication with the district and provincial-level government. At early 2018, CSOs focused on revitalizing and encouraging the establishment of the multi-stakeholder forum to share and discuss relevant information related to food and nutrition security, including stunting issues. At the mid-2018, CSOs were focused on collaboration to assist the implementation of follow-up actions with the government. In 2019, CSOs continue to support the government to change the system through the establishment of regulation and support the multi-stakeholder and convergence approach for stunting reduction and prevention based on the evidence. Also, CSOs started to scale up their experience in the neighboring district. For example, Ayo Indonesia collaborated with government for integrated agriculture system research and monitored the finalisation of FNS District Action Plan and scaled up their intervention in Manggarai Timur. Konsepsi collaborated with the district government of East Lombok to develop convergence planning, especially for 20 villages as the focus based on the results of stunting survey and situation analysis. However, the government followed up this initiative and add additional villages up to 32 as the village intervention for stunting reduction and prevention. Also, Konsepsi facilitated assessment for districts&apos; performance in NTB province to tackling stunting, Konsepsi was the only CSO who trusted by the province government as the judging pannel in this provincial assessment. Transform advocacy work was followed up by the government with the establishment of regulation about utilisation of village fund money for stunting reduction and prevention in Lombok Utara. They also scaled to provincial level and advocated for establishment of Province FNS action plan (RADPG). YPPS and Bengkel APPeK facilitated the government for stunting convergence action including discussion and action about data, r ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that in the end-2018, CSOs will still have the same score because they will still focus on the district level. Next year, CSOs will scale their advocacy effort at provincial level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: In the district level, all of the CSOs scored 4. CSOs had regular meetings and communication with district and provincial level government. At the early 2018, CSOs focused on revitalizing and encouraging the establishment of the multi-stakeholder forum to share and discuss relevant information related to food and nutrition security, including stunting issues. At the mid 2018, CSOs were focused on collaboration to assist the implementation of follow-up actions with the government. For example, Ayo Indonesia monitored and facilitated the FNS District Action Plan. This was as one of the follow-up action plan after Ayo Indonesia advocating the importance of stunting issue to the stakeholder. Konsepsi collaborated with the district government to conduct stunting baseline survey as the input for establishing the regulation and facilitated the stunting reduction team to plan the roadmap. YPPS facilitated the government for FNS action plan and assisted the two villages for budget planning which incorporated stunting issue. Bengkel APPek collaborated with the government to raise the issue of stunting and FNS towards the stakeholder in the village and sub-district. They assisted the village government to make the planning and budget and incorporate FNS issue. Transform collaborated with the government and other NGOs to plan the intervention for 10 priority village. Actually, the follow-up actions were taken by the government which include CSO&apos;s interest. However, the level of commitment was still different in each government agency and stakeholder</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that in the half beginning of 2020, CSOs will still have 4 as the score because they will continue to collaborate with the government for FNS issue towards the end of the programme</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: All of the CSOs scored 4. CSOs had regular meetings and communication with the district and provincial-level government. At early 2018, CSOs focused on revitalizing and encouraging the establishment of the multi-stakeholder forum to share and discuss relevant information related to food and nutrition security, including stunting issues. At the mid-2018, CSOs were focused on collaboration to assist the implementation of follow-up actions with the government. In 2019, CSOs continue to support the government to change the system through the establishment of regulation and support the multi-stakeholder and convergence approach for stunting prevention and reduction efforts based on the evidence. In 2020, CSOs continued collaborated with government which follwed up by the establishment of FNS action plan. They also initiated the collaboration with youth and millennials. For instance, Konsepsi had MISSION which is the research competition and social media campaign, Transform had SEMETHON which is the social business competiton for FNS issue, Bengkel APPeK had AMUNISI which is the radio roadshow invovled the key champion from millennials and youth to promote the FNS issue. It was involved the various key stakeholders from national level also. Therefore, it increased the visibility of FNS topic, CSO, and SNV. Also, In 2020, all CSOs collaborated with media through media visit and involved them in CSOs&apos; activity and webinar. Collaboration with media is effective to strengthen the advocacy activity for influencing the policy and enabling environment. Media has the power to raise the issue in the community and as the reminder for better implementation for the government. Also, CSOs&apos; profiles were elevated through media coverage related to FNS. Also, CSOs tried to involved as much as possible difabled people&apos;s organisation. For instance, Bengkel APPeK involved difabled people&apos;s organisation as the key speaker for their various activites. Also, CSOs as much as po ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased CSO influence on agenda setting for food and nutrition security related to food availability, access, and utilization in different forum at province, district, and village level.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree of CSO influence on agenda setting related to Food Availability, Access, and Utilization in Different Forum at District</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. CSO has no or only occasional interaction with key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector 
1. CSO has regular interactions with key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector
2. CSO gets opportunity to explain its interests towards key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector
3. CSO&#x2019;s interests are &#x2018;put on the agenda&#x2019; and are discussed among stakeholders in government and/or the private sector</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO has no occasional interaction related to FNS with key stakeholders in government at District so far. However CSO has interaction with Government related to different issues of their program</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">in half year (CSO has regular interactions with key stakeholders in government at district level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: in the last 6 months compared to baseline status there were more and become regular CSO interaction with key stakeholders in NTB and NTT at the district level to discuss Food security issues. District government were involved in the provincial and village level meeting where previously rarely happened.  During the interactions here are some issues discussed: Commitment and support from Government and other stakeholders in the implementation of FNS-V4CP;  the implementation of FNS policy from national and provincial level and the implementation in the district level; food availability, access and utilization with more concern to stunting,  policy on food and nutrition including local food  development/revision  of local action plan FNS document);  establishment/revitalization of FNS multi-stakeholder forum  including establishment of informal forum to discuss FNS group (social media. i.e whats up group, facebook); coordination, cooperation and colaboration among Government offices/agencies in implementing in related to FNS; engagement, involvement and networking with local NGOs/CSO/media/Universities and religious leaders</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the next half year, CSOs will have regular interactions with key stakeholders in government at district level and be able to put CSO&apos;s interest about food and nutrition security on the agenda and make it discussed among stakeholders in the government. Therefore, the CSOs will not just be able to explain its interest, but also be able to encourage government to prioritize the issue. Thus, CSOs could discuss the issue together and lead to several follow up action plan especially to decrease stunting rate and increase food security management at district level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.80">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">16-09-2018: The score is the average from 5 CSOs. Transform, Konsepsi, Ayo Indonesia, and YPPS got 3 as the score. Bengkel APPeK&apos;s score is 2 because they have just started to work at district since this year. CSOs has increased its regular interaction with key stakeholders in NTB and NTT at the district level to discuss food and nutrition security issues. CSOs had opportunities to explain its interests about the relevant issues towards district government and CSO&apos;s intereset were put on the agenda. CSOs also involved in meetings that conducted by other CSO or Food and Nutrition multi-stakeholder forum. For instance, Ayo Indonesia facilitated the district action plan for FNS with the government. YPPS encouraged district government, especially Distrcit Health Office to issue sozialitation program on stunting and local food diversification through premarital courses, as well as facilitating the FNS District Action Plan. Konsepsi facilitated the FNS District Action Plan with the government and also the stunting baseline survey to get the real existing data in their area. Transform encouraged the government to have one doctor for one village which capable to monitor the stunting situation in the community. Those acitivies are proof that CSO&apos;s interest were discussed and put on the agenda by government</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the next half year, all of the CSOs will have regular interactions with key stakeholders in government at district level and be able to put CSO&apos;s interest about food and nutrition security on the agenda and make it discussed among stakeholders in the government. Therefore, the CSOs will not just be able to explain its interest, but also be able to encourage government to prioritize the issue. Thus, CSOs could discuss the issue together and lead to several follow up action plan especially to decrease stunting rate and increase food security management at district level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">18-10-2019: In the district level, all of the CSOs scored 3. CSOs had regular meetings and communication with the district and provincial-level government. Also, the government discussed and inserted FNS issue to be on their agenda. In 2019, CSOs facilitated the development and finalisation of FNS district action plan and advocated for FNS and stunting issue to inserted in the regional development planning (RPJMD) 2020 - 2024. All of the 5 focus areas acknowledged the importance of this issue and put that in RPJMD. Specifically, Ayo Indonesia monitored the finalisation of FNS District Action Plan and tried to scale up to the neighboring district and influence the Bupati (head of district) Manggarai Timur, District Health Office and Village Empowerment Office. This followed up by the establishment of a big meeting by the government to discuss stunting reduction and joint capacity building activity at village level in Manggarai Timur. Konsepsi and Transform advocated for more involvement of women group and potentially disadvantaged group such as elderly and disabled people to participate in development planning meeting (Musrenbang) primarily to discuss stunting issue. YPPS advocated the district government to influence all of the village leaders to allocate village fund for FNS issue, especially stunting reduction. After the monitoring process, all of the villages have already made the budget for that. YPPS also actively advocated the religious community through church network for stunting reduction issue. Bengkel Appek was successful in influencing the district government to start the process of RADPG development and supported the village head to allocate the budget for FNS. Also, the sub-district level government responded to the voice of CSO to establish the task force for tackling FNS issue</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">in half year (CSO has regular interactions with key stakeholders in government at district level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: CSO has increased its regular interaction with key stakeholders in NTB and NTT at the district level to discuss food and nutrition security issues. CSOs had opportunities to explain its interests about the relevant issues towards district government. CSOs also involved in meetings that conducted by other CSO or Food and Nutrition multi-stakeholder forum. In those meetings, some issues discussed were: strategic action plan for food and nutrition security issues, utilization of village fund to accelerate the development of relevant activities, optimization of yard in order to fulfill the food and nutrition needs to decrease stunting rate and other thematic knowledge related to food and stunting issues. For instance, Yayasan Ayo Indonesia advocated district government to add and made stunting issue as the topic for World Food Day 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the next half year, all of the CSOs will have regular interactions with key stakeholders in government at the district level and be able to put CSO&apos;s interest about food and nutrition security on the agenda and make it discussed among stakeholders in the government. Therefore, the CSOs will not just be able to explain its interest, but also be able to encourage the government to prioritize the issue. Thus, CSOs could discuss the problem together and lead to several follow up action plan mainly to decrease stunting rate and increase food security management at the district level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: In the district level, all of the CSOs scored 3. CSOs had regular meetings and communication with the district and provincial-level government. Also, the government discussed and inserted FNS issue to be on their agenda. In 2019, CSOs facilitated the development and finalisation of FNS district action plan and advocated for FNS and stunting issue to inserted in the regional development planning (RPJMD) 2020 - 2024. All of the 5 focus areas acknowledged the importance of this issue and put that in RPJMD. Specifically, Ayo Indonesia monitored the finalisation of FNS District Action Plan and tried to scale up to the neighboring district and influence the Bupati (head of district) Manggarai Timur, District Health Office and Village Empowerment Office. Also, they collaborated with Manggarai Timur government to conduct workshop about village fund utlisation for stunting reduction and prevention. Transform focused on to advocate the stunting issue to be part of RPJMD and also be part of RKP (government work planning) of the each agency in Lombok Utara.  Konsepsi facilitated the Lombok Timur government for the involvement of PKK (women group) in monitoring system for stunting (SISTARI). YPPS advocated the district government to influence all of the village leaders to allocate village fund for FNS issue, especially stunting prevention and reduction. After the monitoring process, all of the villages have already made the budget for that. YPPS also actively advocated the religious community through church networks for stunting prevention and reduction issue. Bengkel Appek was successful in influencing the district government to start the process of RADPG development and the vice of Bupati (Head of District) has already started to discuss the stunting issue in the forum</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the next half year, all of the CSOs will have regular interactions with key stakeholders in government at district level and be able to put CSO&apos;s interest about food and nutrition security on the agenda and make it discussed among stakeholders in the government. Therefore, the CSOs will not just be able to explain its interest, but also be able to encourage government to prioritize the issue. Thus, CSOs could discuss the issue together and lead to several follow up action plan especially to decrease stunting rate and increase food security management at district level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: In the district level, all of the CSOs scored 4. CSOs had regular meetings and communication with district and provincial level government. Also, the government discussed and inserted this issue to be in their agenda. In 2018, CSOs facilitated the development of FNS district action plan and intervention planning for several priority villages. For example, Ayo Indonesia monitored and facilitated the FNS District Action Plan and facilitated and advocated the lesson learned from 3 pilot village. This was as one of the follow-up action plan after Ayo Indonesia advocating the importance of stunting issue to the stakeholder. Konsepsi collaborated with the district government to conduct stunting baseline survey as the input for establishing the regulation. The district government used those survey results as the basis for stunting reduction roadmap planning and integrated monitoring evaluation system. YPPS, Ayo Indonesia and Bengkel APPek collaborated with the government to raise the issue of stunting and FNS towards the stakeholder in the village and sub-district especially related to budget allocation and planning for village fund utilization. Transform collaborated with the government and other NGOs to plan the intervention for 10 priority village. The follow-up actions were taken by the government which include CSO&apos;s interest. However, the level of commitment was still different in each government agency and stakeholder</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the next half year, all of the CSOs will have regular interactions with key stakeholders in government at the district level and be able to put CSO&apos;s interest about food and nutrition security on the agenda and make it discussed among stakeholders in the government. Therefore, the CSOs will not just be able to explain its interest, but also be able to encourage the government to prioritize the issue. Thus, CSOs could discuss the problem together and lead to several follow up action plan mainly to decrease stunting rate and increase food security management at the district level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: In the district level, all of the CSOs scored 3. CSOs had regular meetings and communication with the district and provincial-level government. Also, the government discussed and inserted FNS issue to be on their agenda. In 2020, CSOs facilitated the development and finalisation of FNS district action plan and advocated for the importance of FNS issue in the pandemic COVID-19 situation. Ayo Indonesia monitored the finalisation of FNS District Action Plan and tried to push the involvement of PKK (women group) for stunting prevention and reductin effort. Transform focused on the finalisation of NTB province FNS action plan (RADPG) and North Lombok&apos;s RADPG.  Konsepsi facilitated stunting reduction convergence action and budget gap research. YPPS advocated the finalisation and launching of FNS action plan in East Flores (RADPG) . YPPS also actively advocated the religious community through church networks for stunting prevention and reduction issue. Bengkel Appek supported the stunting prevention and reduction convergence action in Kupang District.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree of CSO influence on agenda setting related to Food Availability, Access, and Utilization in Different Forum at Province Level</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. CSO has no or only occasional interaction with key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector 
1. CSO has regular interactions with key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector
2. CSO gets opportunity to explain its interests towards key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector
3. CSO&#x2019;s interests are &#x2018;put on the agenda&#x2019; and are discussed among stakeholders in government and/or the private sector</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO has no occasional interaction related to FNS with key stakeholders in government at Province so far. However CSO has interaction with Government related to different issues of their program</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the next 6 months, CSOs will have regular interactions with key stakeholders in government at provincial level. It will enable CSOs to put its interest on food and nutrition issue, specially stunting, on government agenda and make it discussed among government and stakeholders. Therefore, CSOs will not just able to explain its interest, but also be able to encourage government to prioritize the issue. Thus, CSOs could discuss the issue together with government and lead it to several follow up action plan, especially on decreasing stunting rate and increasing food security management at the province level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2018: This score is the average for the degree of CSO influence in the Province. Bengkel Appek, Transform and Konsepsi have started the advocacy work with provincial government. CSOs had regular interactions with the key stakeholder for food and nutrition security issue such as Food Security Agency, Health Agency, Agriculture Agency and District Development Planning Agency (has coordinator role for government agencies). CSOs also had the opportunity to explain its interest in food and nutrition issue, especially stunting, towards stakeholders. For instance, Bengkel APPek got score 3 because they involved and advocated the FNS Provincial Action Plan. Bengkel Appek also encouraged the increase of budget allocation for FNS in 2019. Konsepsi together with Transform&apos;s score are 2 because they have just started the advocacy process at the province level. These two CSOs were able to present and discuss the FNS issue with the government. However, it is still a challenge to influence the follow-up action from the provincial government for making FNS issue as the priority and their agenda. It did not meet the target for score 3 because Konsepsi and Transform are focusing on the district level for this year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">in half year (CSO will have regular interactions regular interactions with key stakeholders in government at province level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: in the last 6 months compared to baseline status  there were more and become regular CSO interaction with key stakeholders in NTB and NTT provincial level to discuss Food security issues.  Provincial government have been involved in the district level meeting where previously rarely happened. The discussions include  commitment and support from Government and other stakeholders in the implementation of FNS-V4CP;  the implementation of FNS policy from national level and the implementation in the provincial level; food availability, access and utilization with more concern to stunting,  policy on food and nutrition including local food  development/revision  of local action plan FNS document);  establishment/revitalization of FNS multi-stakeholder forum  including establishment of informal forum to discuss FNS group (social media. i.e whats up group, facebook); coordination, cooperation and colaboration among Government offices/agencies in implementing in related to FNS; engagement, involvement and networking with local NGOs/CSO/media/Universities and religious leaders.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the next 6 months, the score will increase because Transform and Konsepsi will focus more on the provincial level this year. Therefore, they could advocate for followed up action regarding the FNS issue. In the annual plan, they will plan to facilitate the developent of provincial FNS action plan</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">18-10-2019: This score is the average for the degree of CSO influence in the Province. NTB province advocated by Transform and Konsepsi. Then, NTT province advocated by Bengkel Appek. CSOs had regular interactions with the key stakeholder of food and nutrition security issue such as Food Security Agency, Health Agency, Agriculture Agency and Province Development Planning Agency (has coordinator role for government agencies). CSOs also had the opportunity to explain its interest in food and nutrition issue, especially related to the acceleration of stunting reduction. In 2018, Konsepsi and trasform focused on the awareness raising for stunting issue and advocated the imporatnce of FNS action plan (RADPG) for the provincial level. NTB province has already followed up this effort through the development of local action plan for food nutrition security (RADPG) which facilitated by CSOs. The CSOs are listed in the Provincial Decree as the technical teams of the RADPG. The provincial government and the CSOs have a regular meeting to develop and finalize the RADPG, especially to integrate GESI and climate change adaptation aspects from the on-going GESI and climate change adaptation research in NTB Province that is led and conducted by the CSOs. For 2019, CSOs will focus on the finalisation of RADPG and advocated the establishment of team to monitor and evaluate the stunting reduction progress in the cities/districts. Therefore, the score is three. Bengkel APPek scored three because the Provincial government followed up this issue with several actions such as the development of FNS local action plan (RADPG) and incorporated FNS issue into regional medium-term planning (RPJMD 2019-2024). Bengkel APPeK will focus on the finalisation of RADPG for 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">in half year (CSO will have regular interactions regular interactions with key stakeholders in government at province level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: CSOs had regular interactions with key stakeholder for food and nutrition security issue such as Food Security Agency, Health Agency and Agriculture Agency. CSOs also had the opportunity to explain its interest about food and nutrition issue, specially stunting, towards stakeholders. For instance, Bengkel APPek encouraged the Nusa Tenggara Timur government to collaborate with NGOs and raised the issue of diverse, safe and healthy food consumption in the World Food Day. Additionally, Bengkel Appek gave recommendations related to good and nutrition government program and budget for the next period.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the next 6 months, the score will be the same. CSOs will maintain their relationship with provincial government especially to finalise RADPG. It is expected those policy will be signed in the end of this year</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: This score is the average for the degree of CSO influence in the Province. NTB province advocated by Transform and Konsepsi. Then, NTT province advocated by Bengkel Appek. CSOs had regular interactions with the key stakeholder of food and nutrition security issue such as Food Security Agency, Health Agency, Agriculture Agency and Province Development Planning Agency (has coordinator role for government agencies). CSOs also had the opportunity to explain its interest in food and nutrition issue, especially related to the acceleration of stunting reduction. In 2019, Transform focused on influencing the FNS provincial action plan (RADPG) and incorporated gender and social inclusion aspect as the results of their research. NTB province has already followed up this effort through the development of provincial action plan for food nutrition security (RADPG) which facilitated by Transform and conducted the performance assessment for cities and districts related to stunting prevention and reduction effort facilitated by Konsepsi . For 2020, CSOs will focus on the finalisation of RADPG. Therefore, the score is three. Bengkel APPek scored three because the Provincial government followed up this issue with several actions such as supported the development of FNS local action plan (RADPG) for example in Manggarai and East Flores District and incorporated FNS issue into regional medium-term planning (RPJMD 2019-2024). In 2020, Bengkel APPeK will focus on the finalisation of RADPG and continune to advocate the importance of adolescent nutrition for stunting prevention</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2.5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the next 6 months, the score will be the same since the CSOs will focus more in district level. However, CSOs will have regular interactions with key stakeholders in government at the provincial level. It will enable CSOs to put its interest in food and nutrition issue, especially stunting, on government agenda and make it discussed among government and stakeholders.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: This score is the average for the degree of CSO influence in the Province. NTB province advocated by Transform and Konsepsi. CSOs had regular interactions with the key stakeholder of food and nutrition security issue such as Food Security Agency, Health Agency, Agriculture Agency and Province Development Planning Agency (has coordinator role for government agencies). CSOs also had the opportunity to explain its interest on food and nutrition issue, especially related to acceleration of stunting reduction. However, CSOs need to push the government to have the followed up action regarding this issue. In 2019, both CSOs will focus more on province level and facilitate them to update the Provincial action plan for Food and Nutrition Security. Bengkel APPek scored three because Provincial government followed up this issue with several action such as the requested Bengkel Appek to take substantial role in re-establishment of FNS action plan, set up a Declaration of Commitment of all stakeholder to accelerate the reduction of  stunting to gain political will and commitment of head regions, green movement to eat the healthy food, etc. Bengkel Appek also encouraged the increase of budget allocation for FNS in 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the next 6 months, the score will be the same. CSOs will maintain their relationship with provincial government especially to finalise RADPG and governor regulation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: This score is the average for the degree of CSO influence in the Province. NTB province advocated by Transform and Konsepsi. Then, NTT province advocated by Bengkel Appek. CSOs had regular interactions with the key stakeholder of food and nutrition security issue such as Food Security Agency, Health Agency, Agriculture Agency and Province Development Planning Agency (has coordinator role for government agencies). CSOs also had the opportunity to explain its interest in food and nutrition issue, especially related to the acceleration of stunting reduction. In 2020, Transform and Konsepsi focused on influencing the FNS provincial action plan (RADPG) and incorporated gender and social inclusion aspect as the results of their research. NTB province has already followed up this effort through the establishment and launching of provincial action plan for food nutrition security (RADPG). Therefore, the score is three. Bengkel APPek scored three because the Provincial government followed up this issue with several actions such as supported the development of FNS local action plan (RADPG) for NTT province that followed up by public consultation for this. Also, Bengkel APPek involved and gave feedback for stunting prevention and reduction strategy though stunting task force in NTT province. The contribution of the CSOs for RADPG developmet is big because eventough there is a guideline from national level for RADPG development, but they were the one who pushed for the development in their area. Currently, many other areas in Indonesia who still do not have the RADPG.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree of CSO influence on agenda setting related to Food Availability, Access, and Utilization in Different Forum at village</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. CSO has no or only occasional interaction with key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector 
1. CSO has regular interactions with key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector
2. CSO gets opportunity to explain its interests towards key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector
3. CSO&#x2019;s interests are &#x2018;put on the agenda&#x2019; and are discussed among stakeholders in government and/or the private sector</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO has no occasional interaction related to FNS with key stakeholders in government at village so far. However CSO has interaction with Government related to different issues of their program</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">in half year (CSO has regular interactions with key stakeholders in government at village level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: in the last 6 months compared to baseline status CSOs started to establish regular interaction with key stakeholders in NTB and NTT at village level to discuss Food security issues. The stakeholder at village level were involved in the district level meeting. During the interactions here are some topics discussed: commitment and support from village government, including women empower group, health cadre, women and youth group, religious leaders and other stakeholders in the implementation of FNS-V4CP;  building awareness of local government and community related to  food availability, access and utilization with more concern to stunting; campaign on local food through women group and posyandu - a community based health post activity, campaign on home gardening to improve nutrition status</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the next half year, CSOs will have regular interactions with key stakeholders in government at village level. It will enable CSOs to put its interest on food and nutrition issues, specially stunting, on government agenda and make it discussed among government and stakeholders. Therefore, CSOs will not just be able to explain its interest, but also to encourage government to prioritize the issue. Thus, CSOs could discuss the issue together with government and lead it to several follow up action plan, especially on decreasing stunting rate and increasing food security management at the village level. It could be seen whether food and nutrition issues discussed in the village Musrenbang (Multi Stakeholder Consultation Forum for Development Planning), and followed by integration in the village program planning and budget.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">16-09-2018: The score is still the same with the previous six months because the first six months of the year, CSOs focused on government engagement at district level. However, YPPS and Bengkel APPek have already engaged with the village level and make FNS issues especially stunting were put on the government agenda. YPPS advocated Mokantarak Village Government to promote local food cultivation at community&apos;s garden. Bengkel APPeK assisted the Oelnasi village in incorporating baby food supply in their planning and budgeting. Also, the other CSOs had regular interactions with government and stakeholders at the village level. There were some meetings conducted in the village, or in some occasions, village stakeholders joined the meetings at the district level or in FNS multi-stakeholder forum. Some of the topics discussed were village fund utilization for the improvement of food and nutrition security and stunting reduction, sustainable agriculture and optimization of local food usage</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the next six months, CSOs will focus more to gather the evidence and lesson learned from village level as the input for district government to monitor their progress for stunting reduction effort. They will have regular interactions with key stakeholders in government at the village level. It will enable CSOs to put its interest in food and nutrition issues, especially stunting, on government agenda and make it discussed among government and stakeholders. Therefore, CSOs will not just be able to explain its interest, but also to encourage the government to prioritize the issue. Thus, CSOs could discuss the problem together with the government and lead it to several follow up action plan</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">18-10-2019: All of the CSOs scored 3. They have already engaged with the village level and make FNS issues especially stunting, were put on the government agenda. Last year, YPPS advocated the 10 villages to allocate budget for stunting reduction and FNS issue. In 2019, they monitored the implementation, and all of the villages have allocated it, they also developed a monitoring and evaluation tool  that can be used by the district government to monitor stunting management through village fund at village level. Bengkel APPeK assisted the Oelnasi village and 9 other villages in putting the activity related to food nutrition security in their village planning and budget ; they also providing continued support to FNS Forum at Oelnasi level to be more capable in managing and advocating FNS related issues. Transform, and Konsepsi assisted the government in rolling out the intervention in the 10 priority villages and assisted the village in implementing their planning.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">in half year (CSO has regular interactions with key stakeholders in government at village level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: CSOs had regular interactions with government and stakeholders at village level. There were some meetings conducted in the village, or in some occasions, village stakeholders joined the meetings at district level or in FNS multi-stakeholder forum. Some of the topics discussed were village fund utilization for the improvement of food and nutrition security and reduce of stunting, optimization of local food usage and woman empowerment for food and nutrition security at household level. For instance, YPPS did some discussions with people in Kolaka Village and representative of village government about local food and stunting issue. In the meeting, YPPS brought success story from Kawalelo Village about the optimization of sorghum as the local food. In addition, Bengkel Appek also facilitated discussion about food, nutrition and stunting issue for women farmers group and vulnerable people. This was conducted to identify these group&#x2019;s needs in related to food and nutrition issue.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the next six months, CSOs will continue to monitor the implementation of village fund and gather the evidence and lesson learned from village level as the input for district government to monitor their progress for stunting reduction effort. They will have regular interactions with key stakeholders in the government at the village level. It will enable CSOs to put its interest in food and nutrition issues, especially stunting, on government agenda and make it discussed among government and stakeholders. Therefore, CSOs will not just be able to explain its interest, but also to encourage the government to prioritize the issue. Thus, CSOs could discuss the problem together with the government and lead it to several follow up action plan</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: All of the CSOs scored 3. They have already engaged with the village level and make FNS issues especially stunting, were put on the government agenda. All of the CSOs focused on to advocate the village government to allocate village fund for stunting reduction and prevention and part of their medium-term planning. Currently, most of the village in our 5 areas have already allocated various amount of budget for this effort.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the next six months, CSOs will focus more to assist and advocate the pilot village for stunting reduction. They will have regular interactions with key stakeholders in government at the village level. It will enable CSOs to put its interest in food and nutrition issues, especially stunting, on government agenda and make it discussed among government and stakeholders. Therefore, CSOs will not just be able to explain its interest, but also to encourage the government to prioritize the issue. Thus, CSOs could discuss the problem together with the government and lead it to several follow up action plan, especially on decreasing stunting rate and increasing food security management at the village level. It could be done through the integration of FNS issue within village program planning and budget.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.75">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: Transform, Konsepsi, YPPS, and Bengkel Appek scored 3. They have already engaged with the village level and make FNS issues especially stunting were put on the government agenda. YPPS advocated Mokantarak and Kimikamak Village Government to promote local food cultivation at community&apos;s garden and advocated the village planning to conduct children feeding training and additional feeding for children . Bengkel APPeK assisted the Oelnasi village and 9 other villages to put the activity related to food nutrition security in their village planning and budget. Transform and Konsepsi assisted the government to roll out the intervention in the 10 priority villages and assisted the village to develop planning that incorporate FNS aspect. However, Ayo Indonesia&apos;s score is 2 because even-though they had regular meeting and got opportunity to share their interest on FNS issue in the 3 villages, they could not check until now whether the village government has already taken followed up action
The degree of collaboration between CSOs and provincial government got 2 as the average score. Bengkel Appek got 4 because follow up actions were taken related to stunting issue such as FNS provincial action plan and increasing budget for stunting issue. Konsepsi together with Transform got 2 because they were still focus on the district level and advocate more provincial government in 2019. Therefore the average score for district and provincial level is 3</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the next six months, CSOs will continue to monitor the implementation of village fund and gather the evidence and lesson learned from village level as the input for district government to monitor their progress for stunting reduction effort. They will have regular interactions with key stakeholders in the government at the village level. It will enable CSOs to put its interest in food and nutrition issues, especially stunting, on government agenda and make it discussed among government and stakeholders. Therefore, CSOs will not just be able to explain its interest, but also to encourage the government to prioritize the issue. Thus, CSOs could discuss the problem together with the government and lead it to several follow up action plan</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="6.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: All of the CSOs scored 3. They have already engaged with the village level and make FNS issues especially stunting, were put on the government agenda. All of the CSOs focused on to advocate the village government to allocate village fund for stunting prevention and reduction efforts as part of their medium-term planning. Also, they facilitated the innovation and best practice in the village level through competition of health centre by YPPS and health cadre training by Ayo Indonesia | 30-11-2020: All of the CSOs scored 3. They have already engaged with the village level and make FNS issues especially stunting, were put on the government agenda. All of the CSOs focused on to advocate the village government to allocate village fund for stunting prevention and reduction efforts as part of their medium-term planning. Also, they facilitated the innovation and best practice in the village level through competition of health centre by YPPS and health cadre training by Ayo Indonesia</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved Accountability Mechanism of Province/District Level Government on Access to Information, Policy Agenda and Decision Making Process related to Local Plan of Action on Food and Nutrition</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree to which accountability mechanisms are functioning at district level government on access to information, Policy Agenda and Decision Making Process related to Local Plan of Action on Food and Nutrition</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. CSOs are not provided with information - about decisions, decision making processes, policies - by government / companies
1. CSOs are provided with information - about decisions, decision making processes, policies - by government / companies
2. Existence of ad-hoc fora for consultation with CSOs.  CSOs are given the opportunity to provide information to decision makers
3. Government /companies are transparent in their decisions and actions. Government / companies provide feedback on demands of CSOs
4. Formal structures / procedures for feedback/consultations with CSOs are established
5. Government/ companies act on the demands of CSOs through changes in rhetoric and changes in policies and practices
6. Government / companies pro-actively engage with CSOs in determining the policy agenda, in seeking information and possible options</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are not provided with information about policy and budged plan of Food &amp; Nutrition District Action Plan (RAK-PG) by government at the District level due to the policy is not developed yet</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are provided with information about policy and budged plan of Food &amp; Nutrition District Action Plan (RAK-PG) by government at the District level which is being developed</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: &quot;CSOs were provided with information and involved as part of working group for Food &amp; Nutrition District Action Plan (RAD-PG) at the district level which was being developed. For instance, Bengkel APPek involved in 3 working groups to develop the RAD-PG, 1) Improvement of community nutrition 2) Improvement of food access 3) Food quality and safety. In addition, Lombok Timur District Government asked Konsepsi for consultation and to review RPJMD (Mid-term development planning) to strengthen food and nutrition strategy.  Another example was came from Lombok Utara. Transform also involved in the consultation process of RPJMDes (Mid-term village development planning) to include gender aspect in the food and nutrition planning. Lastly, YPPS and Ayo Indonesia had agreement with Health Agency and other government officials to collaborate on food and nutrition security issues.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are provided with information and engaged in the consultation process about policy and budget plan of Food &amp; Nutrition Regional Action Plan (RAD-PG) and other government regulations and programs at province level. It is also expected that government will be more transparent on its decisions and actions and provide feedback on CSOs interests. After 2 year implementation, it is expected that there will be formal platform for consultation process and the government will follow up the feedback from CSOs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.80">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: Lombok Timur and Konsepsi&apos;s score is 5 because there are formal platfoms collaboration to develop the FNS local action plan. Konsepsi is part of the comittee and actively giving the input. Also, government act on the demands through changes in the regulation and practice such as the establishment of monitoring system (SISTARI). 

Flores Timur and YPPS&apos;s also Manggarai and Ayo Indonesia&apos;s score is also 5 because they have the formal structure for consultation through FNS forum in Flores Timur or through the activation of food security council which involved multi stakeholder from government, CSOs, religious and cultural leaders, etc to discuss FNS issue especially stunting. Then, government established the movement for stunting reduction called &quot;gempur stunting&quot; in Flores Timur and developed Bupati&apos;s regulation for FNS action plan in Manggarai . 

Lombok utara and Transform got 3 as the score because the government was transparant regarding this issue. They always involved CSOs, religious leader, and academia to make the planning together and collaborated for stunting issue such as the development of FNS action plan. 

Kupang District got 3 as the score because Bengkel Appek just started the advocacy work in 2018. The government has already transparant and involved the CSO to discuss the FNS issue. However, there is no formal mechanism for consultation yet.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are provided with information and engaged in the consultation process about policy and budget plan of Food &amp; Nutrition Regional Action Plan (RAD-PG) and other government regulations and programs at the district level. It is also expected that the government will be more transparent on its decisions and actions and provide feedback on CSOs interests. After one year of implementing activities, the relationship between district government and CSOs is expected to be more fluid.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.20">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: Lombok Timur and Konsepsi&apos;s score is 4 because there are formal platfoms collaboration to develop the FNS local action plan. Konsepsi is part of the comittee and actively giving the input. For instance, they gave the input regarding the survey results, and government used those data for their basis to develop integrated stunting monitoring system. Lombok utara and Transform also Manggarai and Ayo Indonesia got 3 as the score because the government was transparant regarding this issue. They always involved CSOs, religious leader, and academia to make the planning together. However, the head of Manggarai district has not supported the FNS local action plan yet. Kupang District got 3 as the score because Bengkel Appek just started the advocacy work in 2018. The government has already transparant and involved the CSO to discuss the FNS issue. However, there is no formal mechanism for consultation yet. YPPS and Flores Timur&apos;s score is 3 because the government asked the CSO to give the input related stunting reduction intervention, utilisation of local food, and food security and CSO facilitated the process. However, YPPS was not involved in the formal FNS local action plan development team.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4.8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Because it is the last year of implementation and we are expected to focus on other outcome achievement such as the establishment/ finalisation of some regulation, the improved implementation, and will be collecting the lesson learned for the closing programme, we will expected that the score will remain the same</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.80">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: East Lombok and Konsepsi&apos;s score is 5 because there are formal platfoms collaboration to develop the FNS local action plan. Konsepsi is part of the comittee and actively giving the input. Also, government act on the demands through changes in the regulation and practice such as the establishment of monitoring system (SISTARI). 

East Flores and YPPS&apos;s also Manggarai and Ayo Indonesia&apos;s score is also 5 because they have the formal structure for consultation through FNS forum in East Flores or through the activation of food security council which involved multi stakeholder from government, CSOs, religious and cultural leaders, etc to discuss FNS action plan (RADPG). It was followed up by the legalisation of FNS district action plan (RADPG) both for Manggarai and East Flores in 2020

North Lombok and Transform got 5 as the score because the government was transparant regarding this issue. They always involved CSOs, religious leader, and academia to make the planning together and collaborated for stunting issue such as the development of FNS action plan. It was followed up by the legalisation of FNS district action plan (RADPG) for North Lombok

Kupang District got 4 as the score because Bengkel Appek just started the advocacy work for district level in 2018. The government has already transparant and consulted CSO to discuss the FNS issue and FNS action plan. However, in 2020, Bengkel APPek decided to focus more on the development of FNS action plan in NTT province level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree to which accountability mechanisms are functioning at province level government on access to information, Policy Agenda and Decision Making Processrelated to Local Plan of Action on Food and Nutrition</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. CSOs are not provided with information - about decisions, decision making processes, policies - by government / companies
1. CSOs are provided with information - about decisions, decision making processes, policies - by government / companies
2. Existence of ad-hoc fora for consultation with CSOs.  CSOs are given the opportunity to provide information to decision makers
3. Government /companies are transparent in their decisions and actions. Government / companies provide feedback on demands of CSOs
4. Formal structures / procedures for feedback/consultations with CSOs are established
5. Government/ companies act on the demands of CSOs through changes in rhetoric and changes in policies and practices
6. Government / companies pro-actively engage with CSOs in determining the policy agenda, in seeking information and possible options</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are provided with information about policy and budged plan of Food &amp; Nutrition Regional Action Plan (RAD-PG) by government at the province level which is being developed by Regional Development Planning Agency Plan (BAPEDA).</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are provided with information and engaged in consultation process about policy and budged plan of Food &amp; Nutrition Regional Action Plan (RAD-PG) by government at the province level which is being developed</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: CSOs were provided with information and engaged in the consultation process about policy and budget plan of Food &amp; Nutrition Regional Action Plan (RAD-PG) by the government at the province level which was being reviewed. However, sometimes CSOs still have limited access to the government budget allocation and expenditure data on food and nutrition.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are provided with information and engaged in the consultation process about policy and budget plan of Food &amp; Nutrition Regional Action Plan (RAD-PG) and other government regulations and programs at province level. It is also expected that government will be more transparent on its decisions and actions and provide feedback on CSOs interests. After 2 year implementation, it is expected that there will be formal platform for consultation process and the government will follow up the feedback from CSOs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: The average score is 4.5 because CSOs were provided with information and engaged in the consultation process about policy and budget plan of Food &amp; Nutrition Regional Action Plan (RAD-PG). There is also already formal consultation process between Bengkel Appek and NTT province also Transform &amp; Konsepsi with NTB province. Even, Transform and Konsepsi is part of the RADPG development team. Transform facilitated and led the process of Provincial RADPG in NTB. Also, Konsepsi is part of the formal team (technical team and judging pannel) in the province for the assessment performance of cities/districts for their effort towards stunting reduction and prevention. Therefore, NTB province&apos;s score is 5. For Bengkel APPeK, the were always provided with the information and engaged in the consultation process related to stunting issue such as on province medium term planning and FNS local action plan (RADPG), but there is still no formal structures for consultations with CSOs are established. Therefore, the score is 4</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are provided with information and engaged in the consultation process about policy and budget plan of Food &amp; Nutrition Regional Action Plan (RAD-PG) and other government regulations and programs at province level. It is also expected that government will be more transparent on its decisions and actions and provide feedback on CSOs interests. After one year of implementing activities, the relationship between provincial government and CSOs is expected to be more fluid.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: CSOs were provided with information and engaged in the consultation process about policy and budget plan of Food &amp; Nutrition Regional Action Plan (RAD-PG). There is also already formal consultation process between Bengkel Appek and NTT province. Then, government followed up the input from CSOs. Konsepsi and Transform just started the advocacy process in the province level since the end of 2018. Therefore, NTB province&apos;s score is 3 and NTT province&apos;s is 4.However, sometimes CSOs still have limited access to the government budget allocation and expenditure data on food and nutrition.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4.5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Because it is the last year of implementation and we are expected to focus on other outcome achievement such as the establishment/ finalisation of some regulation, the improved implementation, and will be collecting the lesson learned for the closing programme, we will expected that the score will remain the same</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: The average score is 5 because CSOs were provided with information and engaged in the consultation process about policy and budget plan of Food &amp; Nutrition Regional Action Plan (RAD-PG). There is also already formal consultation process between Bengkel Appek and NTT province also Transform &amp; Konsepsi with NTB province. Even, they are part of the RADPG development team. Then, it was followed up by the launching and finalisation of the RADPG draft. Therefore, the score is 5. For Bengkel APPeK, the were always provided with the information and engaged in the consultation process related to FNS local action plan (RADPG). Also, it was followed up by the public consultation for RADPG NTT. Therefore, the score is 5</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Knowledge and capacity CSO in advocacy work improved</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs with increased advocacy (incl. use of evidence) capacities per FNS</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their advocacy capacities guided by a list of advocacy criteria. The score is the average of individual CSO&apos;s scores.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="4.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs with increased leadership capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their leadership capacities guided by a list of leadership criteria. The score is the average of individual CSO members&apos; scores.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="3.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs with increased thematic knowledge</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their thematic knowledge guided by a list of knowledge related criteria. The score is the average of individual CSOs&apos; scores.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="3.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs with increased capacity in organisational sustainability</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their advocacy capacities guided by a list of advocacy criteria. The score is the average of individual CSO&apos;s scores.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Score over 2017. Confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">condiential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regulation on Local Plan of Action on Food and Nutrition Related to Crop Diversification as derivative from National Regulation Enacted and Implemented by Head of Province/District and Implemented by Related SKPD*</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of new/adjusted inclusive policies, regulations or frameworks developed, adopted and implemented on local plan of action on food and nutrition related to crop diversification as derivative from national regulation</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policy is available, RAD is being at province level, at the district level is still not available.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Nutritional Regional Budget Plan (RADPG) and Renja will be considered as Food and nutrition issue and priority program</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: There is one regulation that could enhance the implementation of local action plan on food and nutrition security and stunting issues which is Regent Regulation in Lombok Timur District. This regulation focuses on reducing stunting which have been adopted and enforced. However, its implementation has not equally applied yet and still needs to be improved. CSOs were involved in the discussion to encourage this regulation and will also support and give contribution for its implementation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">it will be expected that previous 4 draft of regulation will be finalised and at least there will be two additional draft local action plan from NTB province and Kupang Distict</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: There five new policies/FNS action plan in Flores Timur, Lombok Timur, Manggarai, Lombok Utara, Kab. Kupang,  and 2 for NTT Province and NTB Province. One of them which is Manggarai FNS action plan has already been established by the Bupati&apos;s regulation. The others are still in the development and finalisation process</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target is to have two RAD-PG at provincial level adopted and available in 2018. Currently, those two RAD-PG for provincial level is still in development and review process.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: There are four new policies developed related to FNS issue which are FNS local action plan in Flores Timur, Lombok Timur, and Manggarai. The draft just need to be finalised as regulation in 2019. Also, there is draft of stunting reduction roadmap in Lombok Timur. It will operationalise the target which put in local action plan</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">After all of the RADPG in 5 district area and 2 province finalised, there will be no other RADPG will be advocated</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: Theare five new policies/FNS action plan in East Lombok, East Lombok, Manggarai, North Lombok, Kab. Kupang,  and 2 for NTT Province and NTB Province. The status of each regulation progress could be seen in the indicator above</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting, implementing new/adjusted inclusive RAD-PG at district level in Flores Timur (Food and Nutrition Local Action Plan) related to Crop Diversification as derivative from National Regulation</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policy is available, RAD is being at province level, at the district level is still not available.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It will be expected that RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at Flores Timur will be scored as 3. YPPS will facilitated the finalisation and public consultation of the document in the beginning of 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) in Flores Timur is still in the finalisation process. In 2019, it has already been discussed with national development planning agency for the revision process and currently in the process to launch Bupati&apos;s regulation as the umbrela for this RAD-PG</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="na">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;in 2017 at Province Food and Nutritional Regional Budget Plan (RADPG) is available at the district level and has start discussing planning of RADPG formulation (drafted).                                             
in 2018 will be formulation and public consultation about Regional Action Plan at the district level
In 2019 at province and district  Food and Nutritional Regional Budget Plan  (RADPG) is available &quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">23-04-2018: Currently, there is one regulation related to planning for food and nutrition security issue, especially stunting. It is Regent Regulation on reducing stunting in Lombok Timur District (3). The regulation is scored as 4 because it has been adopted and enforced, but without appropriate means which have not reached all of the groups equally. The implementation of this regulation still needs to be improved. Additionally, RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) is still reviewed in the two provincial levels of Nusa Tenggara Barat and Nusa Tenggara Timur. These documents cover five years long planning. Provincial government already have the draft, but it still needs to be reviewed (2). Moreover, RAD-PG at district level is still under discussion (1). The government set the goal to have the final draft and roadmap to be operationalized in 2018, in which CSOs will support the process. Therefore, the average score for this indicator is 2.3 ((4+2+1)/3) = 2.3). CSOs were involved in the discussion to encourage this regulation and also will assist and give contribution for its implementation. For RAD-PG, CSOs were involved in the working group and consultation meetings regarding the regulation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establishment and adoption of RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at provincial level which will be scored as 3. Then, there will be formulation and public consultation about Regional Action Plan at the district level for 2018 which government already set the target to have the final draft in the end of 2018. This particular target is scored as 2. In 2019, Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan (RAD-PG) at province and district level are expected to be available. The target for 2018 also include the enforcement of two Regent Regulations on food and nutrition security, including stunting (4).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) in Flores Timur is still in the development process. In 2018, the government and CSOs had series of meeting for the development process. However, they have not finalised it yet</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It will be expected that RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at Flores Timur will be finalised and adopted. YPPS will push for the establishment of Bupati&apos;s regulation for this RAD-PG within 2020 

&#x200B;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: RAD-PG (The Local Food and Nutrition Action Plan) in East Flores has already adopted by the government. However, we still need to monitor and oversee the implementation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting, implementing new/adjusted inclusive RAD-PG at district level in Manggarai (Food and Nutrition Local Action Plan) related to Crop Diversification as derivative from National Regulation</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policy is available, RAD is being reviewed  in 2 provincies. RAD still not exist at the district level.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It will be expected that RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at Manggarai will be scored as 3. Ayo Indonesia will facilitated the finalisation and public consultation of the document in the beginning of 2019. 

&#x200B;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) in Manggarai has already adopted and signed by the Bupati and be Bupati&apos;s regulation No.48 year 2019. It will be enforced in 2020</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="na">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;in 2017 at Province Food and Nutritional Regional Budget Plan (RADPG) is available at the district level and has start discussing planning of RADPG formulation (drafted).                                             
in 2018 will be formulation and public consultation about Regional Action Plan at the district level
In 2019 at province and district  Food and Nutritional Regional Budget Plan  (RADPG) is available &quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">23-04-2018: Currently, there is one regulation related to planning for food and nutrition security issue, especially stunting. It is Regent Regulation on reducing stunting in Lombok Timur District (3). The regulation is scored as 4 because it has been adopted and enforced, but without appropriate means which have not reached all of the groups equally. The implementation of this regulation still needs to be improved. Additionally, RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) is still reviewed in the two provincial levels of Nusa Tenggara Barat and Nusa Tenggara Timur. These documents cover five years long planning. Provincial government already have the draft, but it still needs to be reviewed (2). Moreover, RAD-PG at district level is still under discussion (1). The government set the goal to have the final draft and roadmap to be operationalized in 2018, in which CSOs will support the process. Therefore, the average score for this indicator is 2.3 ((4+2+1)/3) = 2.3). CSOs were involved in the discussion to encourage this regulation and also will assist and give contribution for its implementation. For RAD-PG, CSOs were involved in the working group and consultation meetings regarding the regulation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establishment and adoption of RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at provincial level which will be scored as 3. Then, there will be formulation and public consultation about Regional Action Plan at the district level for 2018 which government already set the target to have the final draft in the end of 2018. This particular target is scored as 2. In 2019, Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan (RAD-PG) at province and district level are expected to be available. The target for 2018 also include the enforcement of two Regent Regulations on food and nutrition security, including stunting (4).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) in Manggarai is still in the development process. In 2018, the government and CSOs had series of meeting for the development process. However, they have not finalised it yet</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It will be expected that RAD-PG that has already signed and adopted will implemented in Manggarai. Ayo Indonesia will monitor the implementation in 2020</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: RAD-PG (The Local Food and Nutrition Action Plan) in Manggarai has already adopted and signed by the Bupati and be Bupati&apos;s regulation No.48 year 2019. However, we need to monitor and oversee the implementation to make sure it will be equally implemented</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting, implementing new/adjusted inclusive RAD-PG at district level in Lombok Utara (Food and Nutrition Local Action Plan) related to Crop Diversification as derivative from National Regulation</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policy is available, RAD is being reviewed  in 2 provincies. RAD still not exist at the district level.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO   will try to facilitate the development of RAD-PG in Lombok Utara after the   development process in NTB province</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: RAD-PG (The local action plan for food and nutrition) in Lombok Utara is in the finalisation process. They need to wait the Provincial RADPG to be launched first before finalize and launch RAD-PG in Lombok Utara. They used the results of their GESI research to produce more inclusive RAD-PG.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="na">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;in 2017 at Province Food and Nutritional Regional Budget Plan (RADPG) is available at the district level and has start discussing planning of RADPG formulation (drafted).                                             
in 2018 will be formulation and public consultation about Regional Action Plan at the district level
In 2019 at province and district  Food and Nutritional Regional Budget Plan  (RADPG) is available &quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">23-04-2018: Currently, there is one regulation related to planning for food and nutrition security issue, especially stunting. It is Regent Regulation on reducing stunting in Lombok Timur District (3). The regulation is scored as 4 because it has been adopted and enforced, but without appropriate means which have not reached all of the groups equally. The implementation of this regulation still needs to be improved. Additionally, RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) is still reviewed in the two provincial levels of Nusa Tenggara Barat and Nusa Tenggara Timur. These documents cover five years long planning. Provincial government already have the draft, but it still needs to be reviewed (2). Moreover, RAD-PG at district level is still under discussion (1). The government set the goal to have the final draft and roadmap to be operationalized in 2018, in which CSOs will support the process. Therefore, the average score for this indicator is 2.3 ((4+2+1)/3) = 2.3). CSOs were involved in the discussion to encourage this regulation and also will assist and give contribution for its implementation. For RAD-PG, CSOs were involved in the working group and consultation meetings regarding the regulation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establishment and adoption of RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at provincial level which will be scored as 3. Then, there will be formulation and public consultation about Regional Action Plan at the district level for 2018 which government already set the target to have the final draft in the end of 2018. This particular target is scored as 2. In 2019, Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan (RAD-PG) at province and district level are expected to be available. The target for 2018 also include the enforcement of two Regent Regulations on food and nutrition security, including stunting (4).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: RAD-PG (The local action plan for food and nutrition)in Lombok Utara is still in the consideration process. Previously, the government and CSO planned to develop it in 2018, but there was the big earthquake. Therefore, it is still in the consideration process</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It will be expected that RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at Lombok Utara will be finalised and adopted. Transform will push for the establishment of Bupati&apos;s regulation for this RAD-PG within 2020 

&#x200B;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) in North Lombok has already been adopted and applied. However, we need to monitor and oversee the implementation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting, implementing new/adjusted inclusive RAD-PG at district level in Kupang (Food and Nutrition Local Action Plan) related to Crop Diversification as derivative from National Regulation</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policy is available, RAD is being reviewed  in 2 provincies. RAD still not exist at the district level.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO will try to have a draft of RAD-PG for Kupang District in 2019. Therefore, the public consultation could be conducted in the end of 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) in Kupang is still in the development process. For Kupang District, in 2019, we were focusing on medium-term district planning, so we need to wait this document to be finalised because District RAD-PG should follow the guidance of this document.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="na">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;in 2017 at Province Food and Nutritional Regional Budget Plan (RADPG) is available at the district level and has start discussing planning of RADPG formulation (drafted).                                             
in 2018 will be formulation and public consultation about Regional Action Plan at the district level
In 2019 at province and district  Food and Nutritional Regional Budget Plan  (RADPG) is available &quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">23-04-2018: Currently, there is one regulation related to planning for food and nutrition security issue, especially stunting. It is Regent Regulation on reducing stunting in Lombok Timur District (3). The regulation is scored as 4 because it has been adopted and enforced, but without appropriate means which have not reached all of the groups equally. The implementation of this regulation still needs to be improved. Additionally, RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) is still reviewed in the two provincial levels of Nusa Tenggara Barat and Nusa Tenggara Timur. These documents cover five years long planning. Provincial government already have the draft, but it still needs to be reviewed (2). Moreover, RAD-PG at district level is still under discussion (1). The government set the goal to have the final draft and roadmap to be operationalized in 2018, in which CSOs will support the process. Therefore, the average score for this indicator is 2.3 ((4+2+1)/3) = 2.3). CSOs were involved in the discussion to encourage this regulation and also will assist and give contribution for its implementation. For RAD-PG, CSOs were involved in the working group and consultation meetings regarding the regulation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establishment and adoption of RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at provincial level which will be scored as 3. Then, there will be formulation and public consultation about Regional Action Plan at the district level for 2018 which government already set the target to have the final draft in the end of 2018. This particular target is scored as 2. In 2019, Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan (RAD-PG) at province and district level are expected to be available. The target for 2018 also include the enforcement of two Regent Regulations on food and nutrition security, including stunting (4).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: RAD-PG (The local action plan for food and nutrition)in Kupang is still in the consideration process. 2018 is the first year for Bengkel Appek work in Kupang District. However, they have already planning with government to start the development process in the mid of 2019. In addition, for new Provincial RAD-PG, Bengkel Appek will support the government in develop it</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2.5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It will be expected that RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at Kupang District will have a draft and ready for the finalsiation. Bengkel APPek will push for the development process in 2020 and aligning it with province medium-term planning</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: RAD-PG (The Local Food and Nutrition Action Plan) in Kupang is still in the development process. For Kupang District, in 2019, we were focusing on medium-term district planning, so we need to wait this document to be finalised because District RAD-PG should follow the guidance of this document. Also, the process has been delayed due to COVID-19 situation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting, implementing new/adjusted inclusive regent regulation on reducing stunting related to Food and Nutrition Local Action Plan related to Crop Diversification as derivative from National Regulation in Lombok Timur</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. No legislative framework in the form of policies, laws, standards, regulations and/or guidelines exists, or existing/new suggested legislative framework is detrimental to issue
1. A new/adjusted legislative framework is considered 
2. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been drafted
3. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR framework detrimental to issue has been prevented
4. New/adjusted legislative framework is applied and/or enforced, but without appropriate means and/or not equally applied (across geographical areas, socio-economic groups, men/women &#x2026;.)
5. New/adjusted legislative framework is effectively and equally applied and/or enforced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policy is available, RAD is being reviewed  in 2 provincies. RAD still not exist at the district level.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;in 2017 at Province Food and Nutritional Regional Budget Plan (RADPG) is available at the district level and has start discussing planning of RADPG formulation (drafted).                                             
in 2018 will be formulation and public consultation about Regional Action Plan at the district level
In 2019 at province and district  Food and Nutritional Regional Budget Plan  (RADPG) is available &quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">06-11-2018: Currently, there is one regulation related to planning for food and nutrition security issue, especially stunting. It is Regent Regulation on reducing stunting in Lombok Timur District. The regulation is scored as 4 because it has been adopted and enforced, but without appropriate means which have not reached all of the groups equally. The implementation of this regulation still needs to be improved.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4.5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It will be expected that the stunting reduction regulation will be implemented more equally in 2019 based on the lesson learned in several pilot project villages.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) in Lombok timur is still in the finalisation process with GESI perspective based on the research results. In 2019, it has already been discussed with national development planning agency for the revision process, and currently in the process to launch Bupati&apos;s regulation as the umbrela for this RAD-PG and wait for NTB province RAD-PG to make it allign with province action plan

However, there is also one regulation related to planning for food and nutrition security issue in East Lombok that used as the guidance for implementation. It is Regent Regulation number 30 year 2017 on reducing stunting in Lombok Timur District. The regulation is scored as 4 because it has been adopted and enforced, but without appropriate means which have not reached all of the groups equally. However, the implementation has improved because the pilot project for the stunting reduction and prevention effort was established in 32 villages (out of 239 villages). In 2017, Konsepsi raised the awareness of the key stakeholders in the government about the importance of stunting issue and the necessity for the regulation. They also gave the input for this regulation. Then, in 2019, the government of Lombok Timur and Konsepsi also reviewed this regulation for sharpering the roles and responsibility of each actor until the village level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Establishment and adoption of RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at provincial level which will be scored as 3. Then, there will be formulation and public consultation about Regional Action Plan at the district level for 2018 which government already set the target to have the final draft in the end of 2018. This particular target is scored as 2. In 2019, Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan (RAD-PG) at province and district level are expected to be available. The target for 2018 also include the enforcement of two Regent Regulations on food and nutrition security, including stunting (4). 

&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: Currently, there is one regulation related to planning for food and nutrition security issue in East Lombok. It is Regent Regulation number 30 on reducing stunting in Lombok Timur District. The regulation is scored as 4 because it has been adopted and enforced, but without appropriate means which have not reached all of the groups equally. The implementation of this regulation still needs to be improved. The implementation of this regulation will be strengthened by district action plan and stunting reduction roadmap as the planning document.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It will be expected that RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at district level will be finalised and adopted. Konsepsi will push for the establishment of Bupati&apos;s regulation for this RAD-PG within 2020</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) in East Lombok has already been adopted and implemented. However, it has not been equally applied. There is still a need to monitor and oversee the implementation especially for the inclusive development and programme approach</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting, implementing new/adjusted inclusive RAD-PG at provincial level in West Nusa Tenggara (NTB) ( Food and Nutrition Local Action Plan) related to Crop Diversification as derivative from National Regulation</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policy is available, RAD is being reviewed  in 2 provincies. RAD still not exist at the district level.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It will be expected that RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at provincial level will be scored as 3. Konsepsi and Transform will facilitated the development and public consultation of the document in the beginning of 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) in NTB is still in the finalisation process with GESI and climate change perspective based on the research results. In 2019, it has already been discussed with national development planning agency for the revision process, and currently in the process to launch Bupati&apos;s regulation as the umbrela for this RAD-PG</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="na">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;in 2017 at Province Food and Nutritional Regional Budget Plan (RADPG) is available at the district level and has start discussing planning of RADPG formulation (drafted).                                             
in 2018 will be formulation and public consultation about Regional Action Plan at the district level
In 2019 at province and district  Food and Nutritional Regional Budget Plan  (RADPG) is available &quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">23-04-2018: Currently, there is one regulation related to planning for food and nutrition security issue, especially stunting. It is Regent Regulation on reducing stunting in Lombok Timur District (3). The regulation is scored as 4 because it has been adopted and enforced, but without appropriate means which have not reached all of the groups equally. The implementation of this regulation still needs to be improved. Additionally, RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) is still reviewed in the two provincial levels of Nusa Tenggara Barat and Nusa Tenggara Timur. These documents cover five years long planning. Provincial government already have the draft, but it still needs to be reviewed (2). Moreover, RAD-PG at district level is still under discussion (1). The government set the goal to have the final draft and roadmap to be operationalized in 2018, in which CSOs will support the process. Therefore, the average score for this indicator is 2.3 ((4+2+1)/3) = 2.3). CSOs were involved in the discussion to encourage this regulation and also will assist and give contribution for its implementation. For RAD-PG, CSOs were involved in the working group and consultation meetings regarding the regulation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establishment and adoption of RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at provincial level which will be scored as 3. Then, there will be formulation and public consultation about Regional Action Plan at the district level for 2018 which government already set the target to have the final draft in the end of 2018. This particular target is scored as 2. In 2019, Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan (RAD-PG) at province and district level are expected to be available. The target for 2018 also include the enforcement of two Regent Regulations on food and nutrition security, including stunting (4).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) in NTB is still in the development process. In 2018, the government and CSOs focused on the collection of secondary data for the development.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It will be expected that RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at provincial level will be finalised and adopted. Konsepsi and Transform will push for the establishment of Bupati&apos;s regulation for this RAD-PG within 2020</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) in NTB has already been adopted and applied, with GESI and climate change perspective based on the research results. However, we need to monitor and oversee the implementation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting, implementing new/adjusted inclusive RAD-PG at provincial level in East Nusa Tenggara (NTT) ( Food and Nutrition Local Action Plan) related to Crop Diversification as derivative from National Regulation</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policy is available, RAD is being reviewed  in 2 provincies. RAD still not exist at the district level.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It will be expected that RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at provincial level will be scored as 3. Bengkel Appek will facilitated the development and public consultation of the document in the beginning of 2019. 

&#x200B;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) in NTT is still in the development process. As 2020 was the latest year of the latest 2016-2020 RADPG, so Bappeda and Bengkel APPek agreed to start the process of new 2021--2025 Provincial RADPG on early 2020.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="na">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;in 2017 at Province Food and Nutritional Regional Budget Plan (RADPG) is available at the district level and has start discussing planning of RADPG formulation (drafted).                                             
in 2018 will be formulation and public consultation about Regional Action Plan at the district level
In 2019 at province and district  Food and Nutritional Regional Budget Plan  (RADPG) is available &quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">23-04-2018: Currently, there is one regulation related to planning for food and nutrition security issue, especially stunting. It is Regent Regulation on reducing stunting in Lombok Timur District (3). The regulation is scored as 4 because it has been adopted and enforced, but without appropriate means which have not reached all of the groups equally. The implementation of this regulation still needs to be improved. Additionally, RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) is still reviewed in the two provincial levels of Nusa Tenggara Barat and Nusa Tenggara Timur. These documents cover five years long planning. Provincial government already have the draft, but it still needs to be reviewed (2). Moreover, RAD-PG at district level is still under discussion (1). The government set the goal to have the final draft and roadmap to be operationalized in 2018, in which CSOs will support the process. Therefore, the average score for this indicator is 2.3 ((4+2+1)/3) = 2.3). CSOs were involved in the discussion to encourage this regulation and also will assist and give contribution for its implementation. For RAD-PG, CSOs were involved in the working group and consultation meetings regarding the regulation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establishment and adoption of RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at provincial level which will be scored as 3. Then, there will be formulation and public consultation about Regional Action Plan at the district level for 2018 which government already set the target to have the final draft in the end of 2018. This particular target is scored as 2. In 2019, Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan (RAD-PG) at province and district level are expected to be available. The target for 2018 also include the enforcement of two Regent Regulations on food and nutrition security, including stunting (4).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) in NTT is still in the development process. In 2018, the government and CSOs focused on the collection of secondary data for the development because there is new governor in 2018. Therefore, they need to wait for the establishment of medium term planning from NTT based on the vision of the new governor to make the relevant RAD-PG.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2.5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It will be expected that RAD-PG (Regional Food and Nutrition Action Plan) at provincial level of NTT will have a draft and ready for the finalisation. Bengkel APPek will push for the development process in 2020 and aligning it with province medium-term planning</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: The draft of RAD-PG (The Local Action Plan for Food and Nutrition) in NTT has been developed. Bengkel APPeK has already facilitated the public consultation, and it is still need a finalisation process</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># new/adjusted inclusive policies, regulations or frameworks detrimental to interest of CSO have been prevented from developing, adoption and implementation on food and nutrition related to crop diversification as derivative from national regulation</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">there is no policies, regulations or frameworks detrimental to interest of CSO so far</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">(during the implementation will be identified from existing policies, regulations or frameworks which detrimental to interest of CSO, new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR new suggested framework detrimental to issue has been prevented</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: There was no detrimental regulation to the interest of CSOs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the implementation of the advocacy activities, it will be identified from existing policies, regulations or frameworks which detrimental to interest of CSO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: There was no detrimental regulation to the interest of CSOs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the implementation of the advocacy activities, it will be identified from existing policies, regulations or frameworks which detrimental to interest of CSO, new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR new suggested framework detrimental to issue has been prevented.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: There was no detrimental regulation to the interest of CSOs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the implementation of the advocacy activities, it will be identified from existing policies, regulations or frameworks which detrimental to interest of CSO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: There was no detrimental regulation to the interest of CSOs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased Service Provision of Government on Food Availability, Access and Utilization in Province &amp; District Level</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree to level of government service provision on food utilisation in province and district level</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Service provision are available on education and food utilization such as assistance to women farmer group, training post harvesting, nutrition education through women empower group, posyandu. However the service are not adequate on food utilization. The service is mostlly available on education and food utilization. It meets criteria on service availability, budget and gender inclusion in strategy&#xA0;. However it doesnot not met criteria on improving community awareness, attitude and practice/behavior, addressing relevant target group , improve community nutritional  status, inclusion on climate change, contribution to nutritional  status .&#xA0;&#xA0; There is still lack of awareness and practice to utilize food particularly by most poor families. Some prefer buying food not   preparing at home. Community Interest to access education session are also still lacking although nutrition education is available in the area. The community still prioritize money instead of nutrition  See Annex FNS outcomes for detail score</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;target is to impove service provision to improve nutrition education and food diversity, particularly on: 
1. Improve budget policy
2. Improve Gender and climate change sensitive strategies in program implementation
3.  Effectiveness in addressing relevant target group
4. Improve community awareness
5. contribution to nutritional  status  improvement.&#xA0;&#xA0; &quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The average score for all of the area is 1.8. The rubric score was used to determine the score where the maximum score is 3 which service provision on food availibility meets 5 criteria. The criteria includes regulation, gender and climate change sensitive strategies, accesible from any different area, effectively addresing relevant target group, able to improve community awareness and behavior, and improving community nutritional status. Service provision are available on education and food utilization such as local food utilisation training, post harvesting training, nutrition and parenting training and campaign through media communication, posyandu, health cadre and PKK mobilisation. There is also some ceremonial events to gain commitment from district government and community to use local food and reduce stunting movement. Most service met criteria on the availibility of regulation and budget for the programme, addressing the FNS issue in the area, addresing relevant target group especially women and children, and effectively improved the nutrition status of community. Based on the Riskesdas 2018 (Health national survey), Stunting rate for Lombok Timur, Kupang, and Manggarai are decreased expect for Lombok Utara that might be affected by earthquake and Flores Timur. However, the service is still not sufficient to meet criteria on improving community awareness, attitude and practice/behavior, gender and climate change inclusion on strategy, and reach all of the community in all of area.&#xA0;There is still lack of awareness and practice to utilize food, feeding pattern, and parenting pattern particularly by low income families. Some prefer buying instant food or just carbohydrate without vegetable, fruit, etc. Most of the feedback said that it is still challenging to change the behaviour of community eventhough there are various programme existed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target is to improve service provision to improve food access, particularly on: 

1. Improve Gender and climate change sensitive strategies in program implementation

2. Improve community awareness

3. Reach all of the area

&#x200B;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: The average score for all of the area is 2.5. The rubric score was used to determine the score where the maximum score is 3 which service provision on food availability meets 5 criteria. The criteria include regulation, gender and climate change sensitive strategies, accessible from any different area, effectively addressing relevant target group, able to improve community awareness and behaviour, and improving community nutritional status. Service provision are available on education and food utilisation such as local food utilisation training, post-harvesting training, training for youth about adolescent nutrition, nutrition and parenting training and campaign through media communication, posyandu, health cadre and PKK mobilisation. Most services met criteria on the availability of regulation and budget for the programme, addressing the FNS issue in the area, addressing relevant target group especially women and children, and effectively improved the nutrition status of the community. Based on the Riskesdas 2018 (Health national survey), Stunting rate for East Lombok, Kupang, and, North Lombok, and Manggarai are decreased. Also, based on the data of health agency in East Flores, the stunting rate decreased to 26% by 2019. However, the service is still not sufficient to meet criteria on improving community awareness, attitude and practice/behavior, gender and climate change inclusion on strategy, and reach all of the community in all of the area.&#xA0;Even though all of the health centre and Posyandu have the nutrition programme, but the degree of implementation quality is still vary. Also, there is still a lack of awareness and practice to utilise food, feeding pattern, and parenting pattern, particularly by low-income families. Some prefer buying instant food or just carbohydrate without vegetable, fruit, etc. The practice was improved since the beginning of the programme, but the there are still some challenges to change the behavior all of the targe ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quality level of government service provision on food availability in province and district level</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Service provision are available such as land extensification, strengthen farmer capacity through  training and assitance, subsidized fertilizer for farmer, food self reliance, support for good seeds for farmer group). However the service are not adequate. Most service met criteria on: availability of service and budget and gender inclusion in strategy&#xA0;. It is available on increase production but still not sufficient for service on crop diversification. However the service is still not sufficient to meet criteria on improving community awareness, attitude and practice/behavior, addressing relevant target group , improving community nutritional  status, climate change inclusion on strategy, contribution to nutritional  status. Support such as fertilizer, seeds distributed to community are considered still not effective by community. It is mostly considered driven by project. Mostly community dont know  how to apply crop diversification. Its only practiced and driven by community innisiative, common practice   and experience. It is applied mosly for coffee, roots, and planting space. Farmer group usually has access to Government service but mostly  farmer as labour dont have access to such services. See Annex FNS outcomes for detailed score</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">it is expected to improve service provision to level of increase production and food diversification, particularly on:
1. Improve budget policy
2. Improve Gender and climate change sensitive strategies in program implementation
3.  Effectiveness in addressing relevant target group
4. Improve community awareness</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.80">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The average score for all of the area is 1.8. The rubric score was used to determine the score where the maximum score is 3 which service provision on food availibility meets 5 criteria. The criteria includes regulation, gender and climate change sensitive strategies, accesible from any different area, effectively addresing relevant target group, able to improve community awareness and behavior, and improving community nutritional status. Service provision for food availibility are available such as capacity building for farmer related to climate smart agriculture and agriculture good practice, subsidy or support for seed and fertilizer, and assisting from the extension. Most service met criteria on the availibility of regulation and budget for the programme, addressing the FNS issue in the area, and effectively improved the nutrition status of community. Based on the Riskesdas 2018 (Health national survey), Stunting rate for Lombok Timur, Kupang, and Manggarai are decreased expect for Lombok Utara that might be affected by earthquake and Flores Timur. However, the service is still not sufficient to meet criteria on improving community awareness, attitude and practice/behavior, addressing relevant target group, gender inclusion on strategy, and reach all of the community in all of area. Support such as fertilizer, seeds distributed to community are considered still not effective by community. It is mostly considered driven by project and just reach the certain farmer group. It will the same for all of the programme because they have limited budget, they need to choose or select the most relevant farmer/community group. Therefore, not all of the people could access the programme. Therefore the score for Lombok timur is 2, Manggarai is 2, Kupang district is 2, Flores Timur is 1, and Lombok Utara is 1.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target is to improve service provision to improve food availibility, particularly on: 

1. Improve Gender and climate change sensitive strategies in program implementation

2. Effectiveness in addressing relevant target group

3. Improve community awareness

4. Reach all of the area</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: The average score for all of the area is 2.5. The rubric score was used to determine the score where the maximum rating is 3, which service provision on food availibility meets 5 criteria. The criteria include regulation, gender and climate change sensitive strategies, accessible from any different area, effectively addressing relevant target group, able to improve community awareness and behaviour, and improving community nutritional status. Service provision for food availability is available such as capacity building for farmer related to climate-smart agriculture and agriculture good practice, the improvement of agriculture extension quality, subsidy or support for seed and fertilizer, and assisting from the extension. Most services met criteria on the availability of regulation and budget for the programme, addressing the FNS issue in the area, addressing the relevant target group, and effectively improved the nutrition status of the community. For instance, in Kupang and East Flores, the food availability such as land optamilisation and the utilisation of local food are one of the targets in their district medium-term planning document. Also, based on the Riskesdas 2018 (Health national survey), Stunting rate for East Lombok, Kupang, and, North Lombok, and Manggarai are decreased. Also, based on the data of health agency in East Flores, the stunting rate fell to 26% by 2019.  However, the service is still not sufficient to meet criteria on improving community awareness, attitude and practice/behavior, gender inclusion on strategy, and reach all of the community in all of the area. Support such as fertilizer, seeds distributed to the community are considered still not effective by the community. It is mostly considered driven by project and just reach a certain farmer group. It will the same for all of the programmes because they have a limited budget, they need to choose or select the most relevant farmer/community group. Therefore, not all of ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree to level of government service provision on access to food in province and district level</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Service provision on land optimization and better access market are available such as provide support for farmer group  establish new holticulture market, market network,  farm-to-market road and production,  distribution link i.e hotel for maize. However the service is not adequate. Service mets some criteria on availability of service, budget and gender inclusion in strategy stated by Government but not by community. The service is still less available. It does not meet criteria on improving community awareness, attitude and practice/behavior, addressing relevant target group , improving  community nutritional  status, inclusion on climate change, contribution to nutritional  status. There are many land still not productive. Mostly farmer dont have capital. There is no bargain position in determining price for their commodity. Mostly they are still dependent on middleman (tengkulak). The market location in some area are not available and not accesible There is See Annex FNS outcomes for detail score</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;target is to impove service provision to improve nutrition education and food diversity, particularly on: 
1. Improve budget policy
2. Improve Gender and climate change sensitive strategies in program implementation
3.  Effectiveness in addressing relevant target group
4. Improve community awareness
5. contribution to nutritional  status  improvement.&#xA0;&#xA0; &quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.80">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The average score for all of the area is 1.8. The rubric score was used to determine the score where the maximum score is 3 which service provision on food availibility meets 5 criteria. The criteria includes regulation, gender and climate change sensitive strategies, accesible from any different area, effectively addresing relevant target group, able to improve community awareness and behavior, and improving community nutritional status. Service provision on land optimization and better access market are available such as provide support for farmer group  establish new holticulture market, market network,  farm-to-market road and production,  distribution link i.e hotel for maize. Also, there is rice for poor programme called RASKIN. Most service met criteria on the availibility of regulation and budget for the programme, addressing the FNS issue in the area, and effectively improved the nutrition status of community. Based on the Riskesdas 2018 (Health national survey), Stunting rate for Lombok Timur, Kupang, and Manggarai are decreased expect for Lombok Utara that might be affected by earthquake and Flores Timur. However, the service is still not sufficient to meet criteria on improving community awareness, attitude and practice/behavior, addressing relevant target group, gender and climate change inclusion on strategy, and reach all of the community in all of area. There are many land still not productive or sold to the other people and property agent. Also, There is limited bargain position in determining price for their commodity except through the cooperative. Mostly they are still dependent on middleman (tengkulak). The market location in some area are not available and not accesible.  Therefore the score for Lombok timur is 2, Manggarai is 2, Kupang district is 2, Flores Timur is 1, and Lombok Utara is 1.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target is to improve service provision to improve food access, particularly on: 

1. Improve Gender and climate change sensitive strategies in program implementation

2. Effectiveness in addressing relevant target group

3. Improve community awareness

4. Reach all of the area

&#x200B;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: The average score for all of the area is 2.5. The rubric score was used to determine the score where the maximum score is 3 which service provision on food availability meets 5 criteria. The criteria include regulation, gender and climate change sensitive strategies, accessible from any different area, effectively addressing relevant target group, able to improve community awareness and behaviour, and improving community nutritional status. Service provision on better access market is available such as provide support for farmer group establish new horticulture market, market network,  farm-to-market road and production,  distribution link i.e hotel for maize, utilisation of social media, improving the road infrastructure, and increasing the information system for trading especially for the price. Most services met criteria on the availability of regulation and budget for the programme, addressing the FNS issue in the area, addressing the relevant target group such as the farmer group, and effectively improved the nutrition status of the community. Stunting rate for 5 districts are decreased. However, the service is still not sufficient to meet criteria on improving community awareness, attitude and practice/behavior, gender and climate change inclusion on strategy, and reach all of the community in all of the area. There are many lands still not productive or sold to the other people and property agent. Also, There is limited bargain position in determining the price for their commodity except through the cooperative. Mostly they are still dependent on middleman (tengkulak). The market location in some area are not available and not accessible from the remote area.  Therefore the score for all CSOs is 2.5</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advocacy strategies and plans available per theme</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual advocacy plan developed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thematic annual advocacy plan developed</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Yes" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The FNS Annual advocacy plan has been  developed in 2016  for 2017</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual advocacy plan will be develop in 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: Annual advocacy plan has been developed</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual advocacy plan will be develop next year</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: Annual advocacy plan has been developed. In 2019, we tried to incorporate some GESI aspects in our ToC and advocacy plan. For instance, there were some activities to include women voices in the big planning meeting to set the agenda for FNS issue. Also, some activities advocated the women group (PKK) and youth group (business competition programme and research on adolescent) to be part of stunting movement. Then, we conducted the research related to GESI aspect for FNS issue in NTB province and desk assessment of GESI aspect on national FNS action plan. Also, we revised our outcome K related to inclusive regulation to be more GESI and climate change sensitive</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: Annual advocacy plan has been developed</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual advocacy plan will be develop next year</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: Annual advocacy plan has been developed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of CSO activity plans developed versus number of CSOs involved (in %</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="100" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">the 5 CSOs from FNS have developed their annual activity plans</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">5  CSOs have developed activity plan</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: There were 5 CSOs activity plans developed and total of 5 CSOs were involved in FNS sector</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There will be 5 CSO activity plan developed (total 5 CSOs involved in FNS sector)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: There were 5 CSOs activity plans developed and total of 5 CSOs were involved in FNS sector</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: There were 5 CSOs activity plans developed and total of 5 CSOs were involved in FNS sector</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There will be 5 CSO activity plan developed (total 5 CSOs involved in FNS sector)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: There were 5 CSOs activity plans developed and total of 5 CSOs were involved in FNS sector</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased Commitment &amp; Political will from Governor/ Reagent, and related SKPD* on Local Plan of Action on Food and Nutrition</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of policy makers/decision makers that demonstrate increased support for local plan of action on food and nutrition</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The data on this indicator will be collected using the policymaker rating tool. For each individual policy or decision maker the score for support will be determined.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="10.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Next year, the target is set at 12, where at least 2 until 3 policy makers/decision makers per district and province demonstrates increased of support for FNS issue and local plan of action on food and nutrition security. The number will not as much as the previous year because most of the important people have already supported this issue, but there are still some people that need more extra advocacy process. Usually, the last mile will be the hardest one. It is expected that the rating support increase to extremely supportive (4) and rating influence still the same (3) and confidence level will stay the same (3).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="26.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: In 2019, stunting is part of the top priority agenda on the national level. Therefore, most of the policy makers/decision makers demonstrated increase support for the stunting issue. However, this support was not ultimately lead to the increased support also for FNS action plan (RADPG). This is because in 2018, the national government established national strategy for stunting reduction and prevention which including several action for convergence. Therefore, most of the policy makers/decision makers put more the attention to conduct this convergence action in 2019 than to RADPG. However, CSOs still focused on several activities that could support the achievement of outcome H, K, J, L, M of the ToC which covered the increased commitment and political will and including RADPG development. As the results, in 5 district areas and 2 provinces levels, RADPG are in the development  process and finalization

In this section, the number is calculated for the person that demonstrated increase support for stunting issue and RADPG development. There are 26 key stakeholders demonstrated increased support based on the policy maker rating tool for stunting issue. Those people extremely support the FNS issue, the establishment of local action plan, and other programs to support stunting reduction. They verbally expressed their support in the public space, encouraged others to support the issue, and known as the champion for FNS issue. Those stakeholders were varying from the governor, vice governor, the head of district, health agency especially from environmental health division, district and provincial planning agency as the leading for local action plan development, food security agency, and village empowerment agency. For instance, in December 2018, all of the Bupati (head of district) and governor (head of province) supported this issue through verbal expression and instructed the formation of stunting reduction and prevention team and pushed several flagship ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="21.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: In 2018, CSOs focused on several activities that could support the achievement of outcome H, K, J, L, M of the ToC which covered the increased commitment and political will. There are 21 people from stakeholders demonstrated increased support based on the policy maker rating tool. Those people extremely support the FNS issue, the establishment of local action plan, and other programs to support stunting reduction. They verbally expressed their support in the public space, encouraged others to support the issue, and known as the champion for FNS issue. Those stakeholders were varying from the governor, vice governor, the head of district, health agency especially from environmental health division, district and provincial planning agency as the leading for local action plan development, food security agency, and village empowerment agency. For instance, village empowerment agency in East Flores and religious leader scored 4 as they raise and campaign the importance of FNS issue and stunting reduction to the community and advocated the village government to put the attention and allocate budget for that. Also, governor of NTT put the special attention and be the champion for utilization of local food for stunting reduction. It is one of his main programs. Also, Vice Governor of NTB supported this issue through the revitalization of Posyandu (Community Health Post) and strengthen the collaboration from various sectors. Then, child protection and women empowerment agency in East Lombok also really supported the stunting reduction program and raise this issue in various event.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Most of the key decision makers in the district and province has already been supported the issue. It will be expected that the additional key leaders is from legislative that will be support this issue</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="12.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: In this section, the number is calculated for the person that demonstrated increase support for stunting issue and RADPG development. Due to COVID-19 situation, most of the government leaders and staffs concern to address that challenges. However, there are some people that demonstrated the increased support for FNS local action plan development and stunting issue during this pandemic situation. Most of them are the stakeholders who have shown their support from 2019. Therefore, the number in here is only for the new stakeholders or the one who demonstrated increased support based on the policy maker rating tool for stunting issue. There are 12 people that demonstrated their support. Those people extremely support the FNS issue, the establishment of local action plan, and other programs to support stunting reduction. They verbally expressed their support in the public space, encouraged others to support the issue, and known as the champion for FNS issue. Those stakeholders were varying from national stakeholders from development planning ministry, parliament member (vice head of commision), BKKBN, district and provincial planning agency as the leading for local action plan development, food security agency, health agency, agency of Drug and Food Control, and researcher from local university.

For instance, Bupati of Manggarai expressed his support for the RADPG legalisation. While in East Flores, district planning agency involved and supported the finalisation of RADPG as well as the province planning agency of NTT for RADPG development. Also, the special staff of Governor NTB, Food Security Agency, health agency, and  agency of drug and food control supported this issue through the development of NTB&apos;s RADPG and their commitment for the importance of adolescent nutrition Then, in the national level, the director of national development ministry, BKKBN, and parliament member also supported the importance of FNS issue especially the involvement of yo ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender and Climate Change Sensitive Food and Nutrition Flagship Program to Improve Crop Diversification and Production; and Dietary Diversification Adopted and Implemented by Related SKPD* in Province/District</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># new/adjusted inclusive policies, regulations or frameworks detrimental to interest of CSO on gender and climate change sensitive food and nutrition flagship program to improve crop diversification and production; and dietary diversification have been prevented from developing, adoption and implementation</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: There was no detrimental regulation to the interest of CSOs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the implementation of the advocacy activities, it will be identified from existing policies, regulations or frameworks which detrimental to interest of CSO.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: There was no detrimental regulation to the interest of CSOs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the implementation of the advocacy activities, it will be identified from existing policies, regulations or frameworks which detrimental to interest of CSO, new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR new suggested framework detrimental to issue has been prevented.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: There was no detrimental regulation to the interest of CSOs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the implementation of the advocacy activities, it will be identified from existing policies, regulations or frameworks which detrimental to interest of CSO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: There was no detrimental regulation to the interest of CSOs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting, implementing new/adjusted inclusive policies, regulations or frameworks on gender and climate change sensitive food and nutrition flagship program to improve crop diversification and production; and dietary diversification by related skpd* in province/district</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. No legislative framework in the form of policies, laws, standards, regulations and/or guidelines exists, or existing/new suggested legislative framework is detrimental to issue
1. A new/adjusted legislative framework is considered 
2. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been drafted
3. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR framework detrimental to issue has been prevented
4. New/adjusted legislative framework is applied and/or enforced, but without appropriate means and/or not equally applied (across geographical areas, socio-economic groups, men/women &#x2026;.)
5. New/adjusted legislative framework is effectively and equally applied and/or enforced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: The CSOs have encouraged the establishment of regulation and framework as the formal base to support food and nutrition flag-ship program and forum. However, this framework has been adopted, but not yet applied or enforced optimally. It is expected to be applied in 2018. For instance, Konsepi encouraged the government to have flag-ship program plan on poverty reduction (Program Pengentasan Kemiskinan) with one focus on food and nutrition that will be implemented in 2018. It was already adopted, but not applied and enforced optimally (score : 3). Transform also had an effort to advocate the Mid-Term Village Development Planning (RPJMDes). It was made available and incorporated the gender issue as well as planning for food and nutrition security such as improving capacity of community, food diversification at household level, and monitoring visit to Posyandu (community health clinic)). It was already adopted and available in the planning, but not enforced yet (score : 3). Therefore the average score is 3.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">it is expected that average score is 4 for all of the flagship programme in the next year. The lesson learned from several pilot project area could be replicate to other areas in the districts.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: The CSOs have encouraged the establishment of regulation and framework as the formal base to support food and nutrition flag-ship program and forum. The framework has been applied and enforced, but still not yet equally applied. For instance, Konsepi assisted a flag-ship program on stunting reduction and poverty  reduction (Program Pengentasan Kemiskinan) with one focus on food and nutrition piloted in 10 priority villages and with the additional villages from government up to 32 villages. Next, they will use lesson learned from the intervention to scale up to another village (score : 4). Transform also had an effort to advocate the stunting reduction movement in Lombok Utara which followed up by the several flag-ship programme including moringa plantation movement, agriculture product revitalisation, and village fund optimalisation for stunting reduction and prevention (score: 4). Also, Flores timur and part as the results of YPPS&apos;s advocacy work has the flag-ship programme called &quot;Gempur Stunting&quot; (Fighting Together Against Stunting - stunting reduction program) and &quot;Gerobak Cinta&quot; which is the community-based supplementary feeding programme . The budget has already allocated for all of the sub-district. Also, &quot;Gerobak Cinta&quot; targeted all of the under 2 children who are stunted(short, very short) and wasted (thin, very thin) based on the by name by address data in EPPGBM (nutrition data management) and pregnant women who suffers from Chronic Energy Deficiency (CED), However, the intervention is not yet target other group in community that plays significant roles for community nutrition status such as adolescent and school age children (score : 4.5). Then, for Manggarai, they have the programme namely &quot;lonto leok&quot; which is the socialisation programme for stunting through the cultural house and the capacity building for health cadre in the villages. However, it is still not equally applied (score : 4). In Kupang, several villages authorities who hav ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The implementation of poverty reduction flag-ship program on food and nutrition security issue in Lombok Timur will be implemented in 2018 and supported by Konsepsi (score : 4). Transform will support government in enforcing and implementing RPJMDes (village plan) in Lombok Utara, which incorporated food and nutrition security issues including its gender aspect (score : 4). Therefore, it is expected that the average score is 4.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: The CSOs have encouraged the establishment of regulation and framework as the formal base to support food and nutrition flag-ship program and forum. The framework has been applied and enforced, but still not yet equally applied. For instance, Konsepi assisted a flag-ship program on stunting reduction and poverty  reduction (Program Pengentasan Kemiskinan) with one focus on food and nutrition piloted in 10 priority villages. Next, they will use lesson learned from the intervention to scale up to another village (score : 4). Transform also had an effort to advocate the Mid-Term Village Development Planning (RPJMDes). It was made available and incorporated the gender issue as well as planning for food and nutrition security such as improving capacity of community, food diversification at household level, and monitoring visit to Posyandu (community health clinic). It was already adopted and available in the planning, but not enforced yet because the earthquake (score : 3). Also, Flores timur has the flag-ship programme called &quot;Gempur Stunting&quot; (stunting reduction program). The budget has already allocated for all of the sub-district. However, the implementation still could not be evaluated whether it will be equally applied. It will be evaluated once the government starts the implementation (score : 3)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4.1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">it is expected that average score is still 4.1 for all of the regulations or flagship programmes in the next year. CSOs will try to collect the lesson learned from several pilot project area could be replicate to other areas and influence the others</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: The CSOs have encouraged the establishment of regulation and framework as the formal base to support food and nutrition flag-ship program and forum. The framework has been applied and enforced, but still not yet equally applied. For instance, Konsepsi and East Lombok District continued to monitor the implementation of stunting prevention and reduction movement programme through annual stunting meeting (Rembug stunting) which led directly by the head of district. (score : 4). Transform also had an effort to advocate the stunting reduction movement in North Lombok which followed up by the several flag-ship programme including moringa plantation movement, agriculture product revitalisation, honey trigona development and village fund optimalisation for stunting prevention and reduction programme (score: 4). Also, East Flores and part as the results of YPPS&apos;s advocacy work has the flag-ship programme called &quot;Gempur Stunting&quot; (Fighting Together Against Stunting - stunting reduction program) and &quot;Gerobak Cinta&quot; which is the community-based supplementary feeding programme . The budget has already allocated for all of the sub-district. Also, &quot;Gerobak Cinta&quot; targeted all of the under 2 children who are stunted(short, very short) and wasted (thin, very thin) based on the by name by address data in EPPGBM (nutrition data management) and pregnant women who suffers from Chronic Energy Deficiency (CED). However, the implementation is still not equally applied due to cultural barrier. Then, the intervention is not yet target other group in community that plays significant roles for community nutrition status such as adolescent and school age children (score : 4.5). In Kupang, the current framework of district-medium term planning document is very related to food nutrition security. It could be seen from their target for land optimalisation and nutrious food consumption behaviour. It is implemented through 2 programmes which are the increased food security and empow ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of new/adjusted inclusive policies, regulations or frameworks developed, adopted and implemented on gender and climate change sensitive food and nutrition flagship program to improve crop diversification and production; and dietary diversification by related skpd* in province/district</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19-03-2018: &quot;There were three new/adjusted regulations and framework developed to support the implementation of gender and climate change sensitive food and nutrition flag-ship program. It includes the RPJMDes (sensitive gender) with planning on food and nutrition security in Lombok Utara District, framework for the establishment of flag-ship program with the focus on food and nutrition issues in Lombok Timur District, and Framework to revitalize the food forum into food and nutrition forum that will dealt with climate change issues in Flores Timur. Those frameworks have already been adopted, but not enforced yet. CSOs were engaged in the discussion and consultation meetings to draft these frameworks and advocated the regulation to be adopted and implemented.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected to have two more policies, regulations or framework (e.g., for Kupang and Manggarai District) adopted and enforced to support climate change and GESI sensitive food and nutrition flag-ship program on improving crop diversification and production, as well as dietary diversification, and stunting reduction.

&#x200B;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-04-2020: There were five new/adjusted regulations and framework adopted and developed to support the implementation of gender and climate change sensitive food and nutrition flag-ship program. It includes: 
1. Bupati&apos;s regulation for village&apos;s role on stunting reduction and prevention (No.27 year 2019) in Flores Timur
2. Decision Letter (SK) on task force of Gender Mainstreaming in Lombok Timur
3. Bupati&apos;s regulation on integrated stunting reduction efforts in Lombok Utara (No. 16 year 2019)
4. Village regulation (Oelnasi) in Kupang District about cattle management to support food security
5. Bupati&apos;s regulation on stunting reduction and prevention in Manggarai (No. 24 year 2019)

However, the climate change sensitive aspect is not equally applied in the regulation/framework because CSOs have determined that while they have some capacity in gender and social inclusion and are working to incorpoate those two issues on their advocacy works, their capacity to incorporate climate change aspects is far too limited. Consequently, CSOs will not be focusing on climate change aspects. Only some of CSOs which are Transform and Konsepsi conducted the research in NTB Province about FNS including climate change aspect and still trying to incoporate that in the province FNS action plan (RAD-PG) - see above KL.1.2 indicator</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;It is expected to have two more policies, regulations or framework (e.g., for Kupang and Manggarai District) adopted and enforced to support climate change sensitive food and nutrition flag-ship program on improving crop diversification and production, as well as dietary diversification.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2019: There were three new/adjusted regulations and framework developed to support the implementation of gender and climate change sensitive food and nutrition flag-ship program. It includes the RPJMDes (sensitive gender) with planning on food and nutrition security in Lombok Utara District, framework for the establishment of flag-ship program with the focus stunting reduction and FNS issue in Lombok Timur District, and Framework to revitalize the food forum into food and nutrition forum that will dealt with climate change issues in Flores Timur. In addition, there was the framework for &quot;gempur stunting&quot;programme in Flores Timur which gave attention to local food, revitalisation of Posyandu to reduce stunting prevalence.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs will not focus on to advocate the new regulation in the last year of the programme, but the will try to push for the finalisation of FNS action plan (RADPG), monitor the programme that has been running, and collect the evidence for the lesson learned</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-11-2020: There are no new/adjusted regulations and framework adopted and developed this year (except RADPG/FNS action plan - see indicator K.L.1 above) because CSOs focused on the finalisation of the FNS action plan (RADPG)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
