<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41152786-1796-1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41152786" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voice for Change Partnership-Kenya-WASH-Sanitation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya-WASH-Sanitation</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the &#x2018;Voice for Change Partnership&#x2019; (V4CP) programme, SNV works to strengthen civil society organisations (CSOs) in their role as advocates and lobbyists. We work together with IFPRI and over 50 CSOs to foster collaboration among relevant stakeholders, and influence decision-makers with solid and contextualized evidence to get the interests of communities embedded into government and business policies and practices. For this specific project in Kenya, our advocacy activities focus on Water, Sanitation &amp; Hygiene (WASH), in particular sanitation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim to contribute to an increase in budgetary allocations to sanitation by the county and national government. This will be achieved through equipping CSOs with the capacity to undertake budget tracking at county level so as to increase their participation at county and national level in advocating for increased budgetary allocation for sanitation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41152786" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="3978" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>kenya@snv.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ngong Lane, off Ngong Road
P.O. Box 30776, 00100 Nairobi
Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="5"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-1.292066 36.821946</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">104653</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">267017</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">267017</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41152786-3552" ref="NL-KVK-41152786" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">104653</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41152786-3552" ref="NL-KVK-41152786" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/3978/update/18551/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA Paper on Water and Sanitation as an Agenda for Elections 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/3978/Project_3978_current_image_2016-03-07_13.21.56.PNG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41152786-3552" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved Collaboration between CSOs and National and County Government Officials</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree of collaboration between CSO and national government officials</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. no or only occasional formal or informal encounters between CSOs, government and private sector take place that are related to the issue
1. regular meetings and communications take place between CSOs, government and/or the private sector which are related to the issue
2. relevant theme related information / data are sought, shared and discussed among CSOs, government and/or the private sector.
3. plans that include CSOs interests are (jointly) made by CSOs, government and/or the private sector.
4. follow up actions are taken that includes CSOs interests</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO and other stakeholders have only occasionally met with national level officials.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">With evidence available from the Study on Social effects of poor sanitation,IEA will organise more meetings with National government officials to push for incresed investment to sanitation and better service delivery in the sanitation sector.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2018: Delay in completion of the research and publication together with the budget analysis has pushed meaningful engagement with National Government to the second half of the year. With evidence available from the Study on effects of poor sanitation, IEA will organise more meetings with National Government officials to push for increased investment to sanitation and better service delivery in the sanitation sector. This will happen in the second half of the year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Develop a questionnaire to be used for national FGDs and consequently produce a report of the results after conducting an assessment to gauge the degree of coordination between CSOs and the government at the two levels. This can be done during the planned national level breakfast meetings (see topics in reflection of first meeting explained in this report). The IEA will also attend TWGs and the ICC and conferences like the WASPA Conference to increase its participation in national sanitation meetings. This will enable us create more raport and influence with the stakeholders at the National level. A range of informal encounters will also contribute to this.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: The IEA attended the Annual WASPA conference organised by the Ministry of Water and Sanitation as well as the AFRICASAN conference held in Cape Town, South Africa.The IEA continues to work closely with the National Treasury who willingly provide information on budgetary allocations and receive IEA alternative budgets.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: The IEA held a national roundtable meeting in Dec 2019 with Ministry of Water and Sanitation and Ministry of Health (MoH) and participated in the Sanitation conference organised by the Ministry of Water and Sanitation  in October 2019. Resulting from these meetings, IEA together with the ministries agreed to hold more frequent stakeholder meetings to advance the sanitation agenda. IEA was also invited to participate in the national public sector hearings as discussants for various issues including  Health, water and sanitation  and Environment.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO will engage with ministry officials during round table meetings and Technical Working Groups.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-11-2018: On the dates of 7th to 9th February 2017, Institute of Economic Affairs attended a Sanitation Conference in Nairobi that was organised by the Ministry of Health. The objective of the 2nd sanitation conference was to review the country commitments made on sanitation during the first sanitation conference held in 2014. The conference provided an opportunity to learn about sanitation context and outlook from a countrywide perspective, the bottlenecks that the sector is confronted with and opportunities to address them. | 25-11-2018: Though round table meetings have been held, the CSO cannot yet establish the degree of collaboration with the national  government officials.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO will engage with ministry officials during round table meetings and TWGs/ICC</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-11-2018: On the dates of 7th to 9th February 2017, Institute of Economic Affairs attended a Sanitation Conference in Nairobi that was organised by the Ministry of Health. The objective of the 2nd sanitation conference was to review the country commitments made on sanitation during the first sanitation conference held in 2014. The conference provided an opportunity to learn about sanitation context and outlook from a countrywide perspective, the bottlenecks that the sector is confronted with and opportunities to address them.There were however minimal interactions with the National government officials during the last half of the year as most of the Ministry officials we reached out to were not available to attend our public forums during the last quarter.Although there hasnt been any major collaboration with the national government,IEA will build on the interactions with the national government to influence sanitation policy and legislations. IEA was involved in the launch and riding on other projects where engaged with, conduct trainings on water and sanitation to political parties, to voters and to CSOs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IEA intends to participate in the Sanitation conference organised by the Ministry of Water and Sanitation and scheduled to take place in October 2019.The IEA intends to continue advocating for increased investment in sanitation and the need to prioritise the sanitation sector by showcasing updated statistics on the small investment in the sanitation sector.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: The ministry concerned with sanitation previously believed that sanitation matters are well handled at the county level.The initial discussions on why the national should share and advocacte for creation of sanitation budget lines has now gotten the attention of ministries permanent secretaries through the engagement during the public hearings and sanitation conference held IN THE YEAR 2019.
The IEA held a national roudtable meeting in Dec 2019 with Ministry of Water and Sanitation and Ministry of Health (MoH) and participated in the Sanitation conference organised by the Ministry of Water and Sanitation  in October 2019. Resulting from these meetings, IEA together with the ministries agreed to hold more frequent stakeholder meetings to advance the sanitation agenda. IEA was also invited to participate in the national public sector hearings as discussants for various issues including  Health,water and sanitation  and Environment.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will engage with ministry officials during round table meetings and TWGs and a roundtable meeting in the second half of the year with evidence from the Study on Social effects of poor sanitation and budget analysis available. This is expected to lead to increased prioritisation and budget allocation at the county level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA and other stakeholders have only occasionally met with national level officials but haven&apos;t had collaborative activities towards access to improved sanitation. Outcome of the meeting (see elaborated above) was identified list of priorities and follow up meetings planned for 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Develop a questionnaire to be used for national FGDs and consequently produce a report of the results after conducting an assessment to gauge the degree of coordination between CSOs and the government at the two levels. This can be done during the planned national level breakfast meetings (see topics in reflection of first meeting explained in this report). The IEA will also attend TWGs and the ICC and conferences like the WASPA Conference to increase its participation in national sanitation meetings. This will enable us create more raport and influence with the stakeholders at the National level. A range of informal encounters will also contribute to this.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree of collaboration between CSOs and county government officials</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. no or only occasional formal or informal encounters between CSOs, government and private sector take place that are related to the issue
1. regular meetings and communications take place between CSOs, government and/or the private sector which are related to the issue
2. relevant theme related information / data are sought, shared and discussed among CSOs, government and/or the private sector.
3. plans that include CSOs interests are (jointly) made by CSOs, government and/or the private sector.
4. follow up actions are taken that includes CSOs interests</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO has on one occasion met the county govt officials in the four counties and have egaged and shared information on current sanitation information in counties as well as budget allocation - where available</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">With evidence available from the Study on Social effects of poor sanitation,IEA will organise more meetings with County government officials to push for incresed investment to sanitation and better service de4livery in the sanitation sector.
IEA will Increase stakeholder engagement in County Budget processes by involving more Sanitation experts and County government officials as well as the private sector in the TWGs,Public Forums and Pre-budget hearing meetings.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2018: IEA held two forums in the month of march 2018 and May 2018 inviting CSOs and County Public Health officials for validation of county study on poor effects of sanitation and public hearings.The discussions and the interactions with both stakeholders was mutual and reflected a state of improvement from  interractions in the previous year. With evidence available from the Study on Social effects of poor sanitation, IEA will organise more meetings with County government officials to push for increased investment to sanitation and better service delivery in the sanitation sector.
IEA will also increase stakeholder engagement in County Budget processes by involving more Sanitation experts and County Government officials as well as the private sector in the TWGs, Public Forums and Pre-budget hearing meetings.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Develop a questionnaire to be used for county FGDs and consequently produce a report of the results after Conducting an  assessment to gauge the degree of coordination between CSOs and the government at the two levels. IEA will also keep constant communication and information sharing with the local CSO networks and county government officials to ensure the county government officials are aware of and are involved in all our activities. IEA will stimulate the local CSO networks to engage in all relevant forums and build personal relationships with decision makers.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: The IEA is in constant communication with the county governments of Kericho , Homabay and Elgeyo Marakwet counties and updates them on the social audits of the sanitation projects ongoing in the counties.The county officials have  cooperated and provided the necessary information whenever called upon.The County officials will also participate in the validation of the social audit findings where they will be held to account by the CSOs who conducted the social audits</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: Overall, the collaboration between IEA, CSO networks and county government officials across the three counties  ((Kericho, Elgeyo Marakwet and Homa Bay) has greatly improved. IEA collaborated with the county officials and local CSOs on the following;
1. The social audit process and the validation - changes are being seen as a result e.g. Department of Trade in Kericho county committed to allocate resources towards building toilets in Kericho public markets and in Homa Bay there is allocation of resources for additional toilets in Shauri Yako slums
2. The generation of budget memos - CSO advocacy during pre-budget hearings is yielding results e.g. Kericho County has made public, county annual budgets on its website. 
3. Generation of case studies  - helped in highlighting the sanitation issues that needed to be prioritised by the county governments of Kericho, Elgeyo Marakwet and  Homa Bay counties to improve access to sanitation. The case studies have been used to strengthen the social audit recommendations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through interaction with county government offcials and stakeholders in the 4 counties, CSO intents to ensure that data on sanitation is easily available and accessible as well as discussed by stakeholders. Civil society actors and government officials will be encouraged to engage through the WASH Forums, public hearings and other encounters</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-11-2018: The Institute held meetings with officials from Homa bay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet Counties. The officials included the County Executive Committee, Member for Health, County Public Health Officers Budget director among other representatives. The purpose of the meeting was to pick up from the initial visits towards end of 2016 and reiterate the purpose and objective of the Voice For Change Project on sanitation in their areas. The meetings were used to solicit participant&#x2019;s contribution and cooperation in providing sanitation data and information to facilitate budget analysis and advocacy.The IEA aloso trained the MCAs on budget analysis and tracking to equip them with knowledge on how to track investment in sanitation . Engagement with CPHOs is more enhanced. CPHOs have called for benchmarking visits; public forum also invited other CPHOs, more exchange, catching up, even between counties</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IEA will continously update the county officials on the progress of the social audits and create awareness about the need for prioritization of the sanitation sector.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Overall, the collaboration between IEA, CSO networks and county government officials across the three counties  ((Kericho, Elgeyo Marakwet and Homa Bay) has greatly improved. IEA collaborated with the county officials and local CSOs on the following;
1. The social audit process and the validation - changes are being seen as a result e.g. Department of Trade in Kericho county committed to allocate resources towards building toilets in Kericho public markets and in Homa Bay there is allocation of resources for additional toilets in Shauri Yako slums
2. The generation of budget memos - CSO advocacy during pre-budget hearings is yielding results e.g. Kericho County has made public, county annual budgets on its website. 
3. Generation of case studies  - helped in highlighting the sanitation issues that needed to be priotised by the county governments of Kericho, Elgeyo Marakwet and  Homa Bay counties to improve access to sanitation. The case studies have been used to strenghten the social audit recomendations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will increase stakeholder engagements at the county level based on the research finding to ensure that even community led total sanitation coordinators and county based based County public Health officer are more informed on the basis of advocating for more resource allocation at their respective sub counties.
Sub county based CSOs with strong advocacy in sanitation will be tasked to share sub county based saitation issues in the Third quarter. IEA will then sythesize these submission from the sun county and prepare an alternative budget memo for engaging with the county executive and the budget and appropriation committee of the county assembly.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA held two forums in the month of March 2018 and May 2018 inviting CSOs and County public health officials for validation of county study on poor effects of sanitation and public hearings.The discussions and the interractions with both stakeholders was mutual  and reflected a state of improvement from last years forums interractions. With evidence available from the Study on Social effects of poor sanitation, IEA organised more meetings with County government officials to push for increased investment to sanitation and better service delivery in the sanitation sector.
IEA increased stakeholder engagement in County Budget processes by involving more Sanitation experts and County government officials as well as the private sector in the WASH/Public Forums and Pre-budget hearing meetings. This activity was conducted the last week of November 2018 with Local based CSOs in the counties of Homa Bay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet focusing on the social audit of sanitation projects. Each of the counties developed a report on the social audit and shared the outcome of the audit with CSO and government representation of the other counties as well as CSO&#x2019;s from Indonesia and Ghana who participated as part of the V4CP exchange visit in Kericho county on 5th December 2018. Government representatives presented the counties sanitation advocacy efforts and the increased participation with civil society actors in their counties. The interaction between CSOs and government officials has evolved over time to one of sharing and defining actions together. Another indicator of this is that the local CSOs interact with their decision makers beyond V4CP meetings.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through interaction with county govt officials and stakeholders in the  counties, IEA intends to ensure that data on sanitation is easily available and accessible as well as  discussed by stakeholders</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Develop a questionnaire to be used for county FGDs and consequently produce a report of the results after Conducting an  assessment to gauge the degree of coordination between CSOs and the government at the two levels. IEA will also keep constant communication and information sharing with the local CSO networks and county government officials to ensure the county government officials are aware of and are involved in all our activities. IEA will stimulate the local CSO networks to engage in all relevant forums and build personal relationships with decision makers.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased CSOs influence in agenda setting with national ministries (MoH, MoENR, MoWI)  and county governments (CEC for Health) on horizontal and vertical collaboration, investment case for sanitation and transparency</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The degree of influence on agenda setting by CSOs related to sanitation at the national level</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. CSO has no or only occasional interaction with key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector 
1. CSO has regular interactions with key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector
2. CSO gets opportunity to explain its interests towards key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector
3. CSO&#x2019;s interests are &#x2018;put on the agenda&#x2019; and are discussed among stakeholders in government and/or the private sector</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO has had no interaction with the national level ministries yet</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will organise a meeting with ministry officials to discuss institutional fragmentation and role overlap among the 3 sanitation related ministries. This will be done through a roundtabl to discuss the need for better coordination towards improved service provision in sanitation. IEA use evidence to support its advocacy agenda. IEA will focus on encouragement of information shared and expect that it will require time for this to happen at a satisfactory level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2018: IEA has only had occasional interaction with key stakeholders in government at the stakeholders in sanitation conference in Nairobi and during the learning event organised by the Sanitation Technical Working Group at the Panafric Hotel in Nairobi. More formal and informal encounters will be planned to influence policy and decision making on sanitation at the national level. Interactions are expected to become more regular in the second half year 2018 through  regular technical working groups and breakfast meetings. The national level sanitation meeting was a first good step towards national engagement and it was decided therefore that a  meeting would be planned after the event, in the second half of the year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA is expected to organise 3 breakfast meetings at the national level to follow up on the breakfast meeting held in December 2018. It is expected that concrete action will be defined.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: The IEA attended the Annual WASPA conference organised by the Ministry of Water and made a presenation on the state of play and investment in the sanitation sector advocating for the need to prioritize the sanitation sector by increasing budgetary allocations in the sector and creating budget codes for sanitation to enable tracking of investment in the sector.The IEA has been advocating for a creation of budget codes for sanitation to be created but this has not happened yet. However,there is a committee in place working towards the creation of sanitation chart of accounts and this is work in progress</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2017, CSO will engage with ministry officials during round table meetings and TWGs/ICC. CSO will share budget memo&apos;s and other knowledge products. Focus will be creation of a budget code for sanitation and clear instruction and delegation (incl. funds) to the county level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: As expected the CSO has only occasional interaction with key government stakeholders. Through regular technical working groups and other interactions, these interactions are planned to be regular towards the end of 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: &gt;IEA has joined forces with other National level CSOs i.e. WASHFIN to push for increased investment in sanitation and creation of budget codes for sanitation during the sanitation conference in 2019. The budget codes are yet to be created but there is a committee in place overseeing this process
&gt;IEA&apos;s agenda in sanitation has been recognised, in December 2019, IEA was invited by the National Treasury to be a discussant in the Environmental Protection and National Resources  public hearing to be held in 2020.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute of Economic Affairs will engage with ministry officials during round table meetings and Technical Working Groups</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-11-2018: The CSO has had occasional interaction with key government stakeholders. A key engagement was during the V4CP Launch where the Ministry of Public Health was well presented and engaged with IEA staff on budget code issues. More formal and informal encounters will be required to influence policy and decision making on sanitation at the national level. These interactions are expected to become more regular in 2018 through public hearings, regular technical working groups and the ICC Forums.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IEA plans to hold a national level sanitation stakeholders forum in the last quarter of 2019, with the Treasury, Ministry of Health, Ministry of Water and Sanitation as well as the Ministry of Environment and Natural Resources to share updated statistics on the investment and prioritisation of the sanitation sector. IEA has also joined forces with other National level CSOs i.e WASHFIN to push for increased investment in sanitation and creation of budget codes for sanitation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: &gt;IEA has joined forces with other National level CSOs i.e WASHFIN to push for increased investment in sanitation and creation of budget codes for sanitation during the sanitation conference in 2019. The budget codes are yet to be created but there is a committee in place overseeing this process
&gt;IEA&apos;s agenda in sanitation has been recognised, in December 2019, IEA was invited by the National Treasury to be a discussant in the Environmental Protection and National Resources  public hearing to be held in 2020.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA is  organising a roundtable meeting with  a the ministry officials to discuss institutional fragmentation and role overlap among the 3 sanitation related ministries. The discussions will centre around better coordination towards improved service provision in sanitation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The IEA held a roundtable meeting with three ministries to discuss role overlaps and institutional fragmentation and how this is impacting on access to improved sanitation on Thursday, December 6th, 2018 at the Panafric Hotel. The invited participants were from the National Treasury and the three sanitation sensitive Ministries of Health, Water and Sanitation and Environment and Natural Resources. The following are the key messages split between general and national level based on the sanitation budget analysis report that was shared with the participants:                                               General level
&#x2022; Budget transparency and comprehensive budget information and code for sanitation.
&#x2022; More disaggregated information on sanitation but explicit sanitation budget codes to facilitate budget analysis and tracking. 
&#x2022; Revise Chart of accounts for standardization in order to facilitate comparative analysis. This is critical to facilitate meaningful public participation as provided for in the Constitution. 
&#x2022; Rural focused policy and budgetary interventions as well as addressing poverty since there is a positive correlation between poverty and poor sanitation
National Level 
&#x2022; Progressively scale up investment in sanitation to adhere to sanitation policy commitments towards realizing sanitation targets of ODF and improved sanitation access by 2030.
&#x2022; Increase utilization of sanitation related budgets for the Ministries of Water and Sanitation, the Ministry of Environment and Natural resources as well as the Ministry of Health. Poor utilization of funds is the major cause of low absorption rates.
This meeting was preceded by information encounters and as a result of this meeting regular meetings were agreed upon for 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The degree of influence on agenda setting by CSOs related to sanitation at the county level</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. CSO has no or only occasional interaction with key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector 
1. CSO has regular interactions with key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector
2. CSO gets opportunity to explain its interests towards key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector
3. CSO&#x2019;s interests are &#x2018;put on the agenda&#x2019; and are discussed among stakeholders in government and/or the private sector</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO has on one occasion interacted with the county officials in the four selected counties</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will influence sanitation planning agenda by participating and providing verbal and written input in the formulation of county development plans for Elgeyo Marakwet,Kericho and Homabay Counties through budget guides and budget memo&apos;s as well as evidence based advocacy products.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2018: So far, IEA has engaged a number of CSOs at the county level in the three counties mandated to ensure sanitation agenda is at the forefront of discussion. On this, IEA developed a data base of county based CSOs whom we shall work hand in hand with in ensuring that water and sanitation programme are given priority in the three counties. Success of any budget proposal on allocation to sanitation for the fiscal year 2018/19 at the county level will be reflected once the counties make approved estimates of expenditure, publicise and make the estimates readily available in the third quarter of the year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will organise several meetings in 2019 which will ensure the continued interaction and ability of CSOs to set the agenda. This will include social audit training and from their conducting the social audits and sharing these with decision makers, participating in public hearings, and other forums. IEA will also organise the yearly roundtable meetings with the county executives and CSOs on the need for inclusion of sanitation investment plans in planning and budgeting. With the knowledge products on the effects of poor sanitation and budget analysis shared with the county executive and CSOs, there is bound to be increased prioritization of sanitation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: The IEA continues to work closely with sanitation CSO networks formed in the counties of Homabay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet in advancing the sanitation agenda and advocating for better service delivery. CSOs in Kericho County are working with their local government and have been able to influence better sharing of budget information, unlike before, budget documents are now uploaded on the County Government website; in Homa Bay County CSOs have advanced advocacy on sanitation through media, a feature story in which they share effects poor sanitation in the County will be aired on local TV in the second half of the year; In Elgeyo Marakwet County, CSOs are collaborating with County Public Health Officer (CPHO) in conducting social audit of local sanitation projects. The IEA also continues the dissemination of the water testing results to influence the allocation of funds for water testing of the major water sources in the three counties and the allocation of funds for awareness creation on the need to increase latrine coverage in order to achieve ODF at the county level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: Overall the level of influence is high in all the three counties (Kericho, Elgeyo Marakwet and Homa Bay). Together with local CSOs at the counties IEA organised  validation meetings for the social audit report and held roundtable meetings with MCAs and senior officers (from the Department of Public Health and Budget and Planning Departments) where evidence was shared .  In Elgeyo Marakwet the Sanitation bill has been taken up for debate by the committee on Health; In Homa Bay there is now allocation of resources for additional toilets in Shauri Yako slums highlighted in the social audit reports while in Kericho, the Dept. of Trade committed to repair toilets in public markets.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2017, through interaction with county government offcials and stakeholders in the three focus counties, CSO intends to ensure that data on sanitation is available and accessible as well as discussed by stakeholders</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-11-2018: The IEA Influenced sanitation planning agenda by participating and providing verbal and written input in the formulation of the new county development plans as well as doing an analysis of the prevoius period CIDPs to see whether project implementation actualy took place over the reported period of time. | 25-11-2018: As expected the CSO has only occasional interaction with key government stakeholders. Through WASH Forums, budget hearings and other interactions, these interactions are planned to be regular towards the end of 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2017, through interaction with county government offcials and stakeholders in the three focus counties, CSO intends to ensure that data on sanitation is available and accessible as well as discussed by stakeholders</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-11-2018: The IEA influenced sanitation planning agenda by participating and providing verbal and written input in the formulation of the new county development plans as well as doing an analysis of the previous period CIDPs to see whether project implementation actualy took place over the reported period of time. Through collecting views of civil society actors, IEA developed budget memo&apos;s for input in new CIDPs and budget documents.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will organise several meetings in 2019 which will ensure the continued interaction and agenda  setting of CSOs at the county level. This will include social audit training from which social audits will be conducted and translated into social audit reports.The reports will be shared with decision makers, participating in public hearings, and other stakeholders to increase prioritization of the sanitation sector. IEA will also organise the yearly roundtable meetings with the county executives and CSOs on the need for inclusion of sanitation investment plans in planning and budgeting. With the knowledge products on the effects of poor sanitation and budget analysis shared with the county executive and CSOs, increased prioritization of sanitation is anticipated.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Overall the level of influence is high in all the three counties (Kericho, Elgeyo Marakwet and Homa Bay). Together with local CSOs at the counties IEA organised  validation meetings for the social audit report and held roundtable meetings with MCAs and senior officers (from the Department of Public Health and Budget and Planning Departments) where evidence was shared .  In Elgeyo Marakwet the Sanitation bill has been taken up for debate by the committee on Health; In Homabay there is now allocation of resources for additional toilets in Shauri Yako slums highlighted in the social audit reports while in Kericho, the Dept. of Trade committed to repair toilets in public markets.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sub county based CSOs with strong advocacy in sanitation will be tasked to share sub county based saitation issues in the Third quarter. IEA will then sythesize these submission from the sun county and prepare an alternative budget memo for engaging with the county executive and the budget and appropriation committee of the county assembly.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: So far, IEA has engaged a number of CSOs at the county level mandated on ensuring the sanitation agenda is on the forefront of discussion. IEA developed a data base of county based CSOs whom we work hand in hand in ensuring that water and sanitation programmes are given priority in the three counties. Tracking of any budget proposals shared for the fiscal year 2018/19 at the county level will be reflected once the counties make approved estimated of expenditure publicise and make the estimates readily available. During the year a local CSO capacity building need in advocacy skills was identified. The IEA together with Centre for Population Health Research and Management (CPHRM) conducted a two day training on advocacy with CSOs in each of the counties. The advocacy training focused on the following key areas:
&#x2022; A walk through the county budget cycle; participants identified the different stages and the challenges CSOs face in engaging at each stage of the budget process.
&#x2022; Key concepts and best practices; advocacy as a communication skill
o Advocacy 101 (the must know about Advocacy)
o Understanding the advocacy process/ Advocacy as a process
o Understanding the change process; Force field analysis
&#x2022; Identifying issues, audiences and key messages
o Stakeholder analysis (opponents, allies and their influence)
o Communicating your message
This training has resulted in CSOs actively advocating for sanitation in relevant forums.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced accountability mechanisms in sanitation service delivery chain (analysis of sanitation budget implementation, platforms for voicing issues/queries)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree to which accountability mechanism are functioning at the national level</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. CSOs are not provided with information - about decisions, decision making processes, policies - by government / companies
1. CSOs are provided with information - about decisions, decision making processes, policies - by government / companies
2. Existence of ad-hoc fora for consultation with CSOs.  CSOs are given the opportunity to provide information to decision makers
3. Government /companies are transparent in their decisions and actions. Government / companies provide feedback on demands of CSOs
4. Formal structures / procedures for feedback/consultations with CSOs are established
5. Government/ companies act on the demands of CSOs through changes in rhetoric and changes in policies and practices
6. Government / companies pro-actively engage with CSOs in determining the policy agenda, in seeking information and possible options</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO has limited information available on sanitation and how decisions and budget alocations are arrived at</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that increased information will be available to CSO and more engagement will take place on the same</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: IEA was provided with information about when the national pre-budget hearing meetings were to be held to enable us give submissions and participate in the budget making process. However,due to the fact that 2017 was an election year, the dates for submissions was pushed foward hence we did not have enough time to prepare and share our submissions. However, IEA plans to hold pre-budget hearings in the first quarter of 2018.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: In Dec 2019, the IEA -Kenya participated in the National Public Hearings for the FY 2020/2021 and raised concerns on the outcomes of sanitation conference  particularly on budget codes and chart of account on sanitation.
The platform provided an opportunity for IEA to interrogate the proposed budget 2020/2021 and suggest the need for increased investment in sanitation.  
The IEA also convened  a breakfast  meeting with the three sanitation friendly ministries to discuss the need for coming up with sanitation budget codes. There is a committee in place to help drive this process but more needs to be done to speed up the process</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will address accountability issues during the planned breakfast meetings at the national level. This is also closely related to the issues of budget codes and charts of accounts. Other forums will be explored as well.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: In Dec 2019, the IEA -Kenya participated in the National Public Hearings for the FY 2020/2021 and raised concerns on the outcomes of sanitation conference  particularly on budget codes and chart of account on sanitation.
The platform provided an opportunity for IEA to interrogate the proposed budget 2020/2021 and suggest the need for increased investment in sanitation.  
The IEA also convened  a breakfast  meeting with the three sanitation friendly ministries to discuss the need for coming up with sanitation budget codes. There is a commitee in place to help drive this process but more needs to be done to speed up the process</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA plans to conduct pre-budget hearing and will prepare a alternative budget memo which wil lbe shared with the National Treasury in the first quarter of 2018. There will be a follow-up with a launch of the alternative budget to the general public and media to ensure awareness and public participation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA was provided with information about when the national pre-budget hearing meetings were to be held to enable us give submissions and participate in the budget making process. The pre-budget hearings were held in the month February 2018 and involved the corporate and the social sector sharing budgetary proposal for the fiscal year 2018/2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree to which accountability mechanism are functioning at the county level</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. CSOs are not provided with information - about decisions, decision making processes, policies - by government / companies
1. CSOs are provided with information - about decisions, decision making processes, policies - by government / companies
2. Existence of ad-hoc fora for consultation with CSOs.  CSOs are given the opportunity to provide information to decision makers
3. Government /companies are transparent in their decisions and actions. Government / companies provide feedback on demands of CSOs
4. Formal structures / procedures for feedback/consultations with CSOs are established
5. Government/ companies act on the demands of CSOs through changes in rhetoric and changes in policies and practices
6. Government / companies pro-actively engage with CSOs in determining the policy agenda, in seeking information and possible options</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO has requested information on sanitation and how decisions on sanitation service provision and budget allocations are made. Only one county (Elgeyo Marakwet) supplied the requested documents</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that counties will provide information and engage on its content. The WASH Forums as well as Sanitation Bill and County Sanitation Investment Plans will encourage this</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: &quot;IEA organised for the pre-budget hearings in the three counties and the CSOs shared budget proposals with respect to sanitation. Thereafter IEA consolidated the budget proposals into budget memo&apos;s which were shared with the members of the county assembly and Health Department in a round-table meeting in the month of September 2017. This is expected to be repeated in 2018. 
&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: IEA  held training workshops for local CSOS  on how utilize various accountability mechanisms/tools to hold government officers to account on  implementation of sanitation budget. Together with IEA the local CSOs attended the MCA roundtable meetings where the alternative budget memos and social audit findings were presented and specific demands made by CSOs that have received response from government e.g. construction of toilets in Kericho market and repair of toilets in health facilities in Elgeyo Marakwet  county. The decision made by the county government were more transparent after CSOs demand through public health department requesting the CSOs to participate during the public hearing and point out the economic and planning on issues of allocation and utilization in three counties.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold a follow up training workshop on how CSOs/WASH Forums can utilize various accountability mechanisms/tools to hold government officers to account on  implementation of sanitation budget and on efficient utilization of sanitation funds for better service delivery. Through the training on Social Audits, the IEA together with CSOs in the counties will conduct a social audit on the Sanitation Projects and Programs to ensure accountability at the county level. This is in addition to input during public hearings.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: IEA  held training workshops for local CSOS  on how utilize various accountability mechanisms/tools to hold government officers to account on  implementation of sanitation budget. Together with IEA the local CSOs attended the MCA roundtable meetings where the alternative budget memos and social audit findings were presented and specific demands made by CSOs that have received resonse from government e.g. construction of toilets in Kericho market and repair of toilets in health facilities in Elgeyo Marakwet  county. The decision made by the county government were more transparent after CSOs demand through public health department requesting the CSOs to participate during the public hearing and point out the economic and planning on issues of allocation and utilization in three counties.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will prepare budget guides and budget memos for the three counties in consultation with local civil society actors and share this with government officers. IEA will focus on ensuring CSOs are provided with inforrmation on decisions, policies and budgets and that they will be increasingly consulted in the decision making processes and formulation of county documents. CSOs are also encouraged to monitor implementation of agreed plans and budgets.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA prepared budget memos for the three counties in consultation with local civil society actors and shared this with government officers. IEA focused on ensuring CSOs are provided with information on decisions, policies and budgets and that they will be increasingly consulted in the decision making processes and formulation of county documents. CSOs were also encouraged to monitor implementation of agreed plans and budgets. IEA also trained WASH CSOs from the 3 Counties to monitor implementation of sanitation budget and undertake social audits of sanitation projects which they did in the month of November.  IEA together with CPHRM trained county based CSOs in the counties of Homabay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet Counties. This was to familiarise CSOs on the advocacy product developed for the study into poor effects of sanitation in Kenya and budgeting at the county level and in turn be able to package the study products for their advocacy efforts targeted to the county government officers.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased CSOs participation in sanitation multi stakeholder engagements through Technical Working Groups (MoH, MoW, MoENR, Donors &amp; CSOs), stakeholder forums and public hearings</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of formal encounters of civil society actors with government officials through WASH Forums at the county level</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="6" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">A number of WASH Forums were organised in 2016: 1 in Kericho, 0 in Elgeyo Marakwet, 1 in Homa Bay and 4 in Kilifi</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In collaboration with the SSH4A WASH advisors and the county governments, IEA plans to hold a WASH forum in Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homabay counties to create awareness around investment and accountability in sanitation service delivery through evidence based advocacy. This is to ensure WASH stakeholders meet and this type of forums are encouraged. In addition we expect the counties themselves will also organise their own WASH Forums. This is expected to take off towards the second quarter or second half of the year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2018: WASH forums were organised by IEA in March 2018. The counties also organised their own WASH forums and updated IEA on the outcomes. Participation diversity and discussions are indicating increased inter-ministerial coordination and prioritisation of sanitation at the county level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will participate, share and input to discussions towards enhancing delivery of sanitation services in the county TWG and WASH forums in each of the three counties.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: Homabay County CSOs continously hold county WASH forums to discuss sanitation issues, 5 Forums were organised in this county. In Elgeyo Marakwet County, CSOs held 2 WASH forums. However, due to the short notice before the meetings, the IEA has not been able to attend any of the WASH forums held so far in 2019 at the county level. However, in Homa Bay County there has been improved community sensitization and awareness on WASH after a forum held in the month of March 2019 through the SSH4A programme; this is expected to raise the standard of hygiene and reduction of occurence of cases of diarrhoea especially for children below  5 years</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that WASH Forums will become more regular and better attended. Input for County WASH Forums will be provided  by CSO and where possible CSO represented</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: WASH Forums were postponed in the selected counties to the third quarter of 2017. Institute of Economic Affairs will attend upcoming forums and organise other forms of encounters with WASH stakeholders would WASH Forums not take place.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: The WASH forums are designed to be driven by the county government but have not been active in the second half of 2019 . However IEA convened 3 MCA roundtable meetings in the 3 counties and requested the county to sustainably effect the establishment of the county WASH forums in the three counties. In Homa Bay county , for example, through these meetings WASH issues form part of engagements in the county prioritisation of resources.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that WASH Forums will become more regular and better attended. Input for County WASH Forums will be provided  by CSO and where possible CSO represented</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-11-2018: WASH forums were postponed due to political uncertainity at the county level by Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet counties to 2018. Homabay County did attempt to start their WASH Forums and had 4 meetings. Physical presense of IEA was not possible due to short notice and clashing dates with other activities. IEA has however been updated on the progress and supported other civil society actors in their contributions. IEA also organised a forum in Kericho in December 2017 where they were able to meet civil society actors who will be key in the WASH Forum in Kericho county.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IEA has expresses the need for WASH advisors in Homabay,Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet counties to give timely information on when the county WASH forums are happening to enable IEA attend at least one WASH forum in each of the three counties</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: The WASH forums are designed to be driven by the county government but have not been active in the second half of 2019 . However IEA convened 3 MCA roundtable meetings in the 3 counties and requested the county to sustainably effect the establishment of the county WASH forums in the three counties. In Homa Bay county , for example, through these meetings WASH issues form part of engagements in the county prioritazation of resources.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We expect that in each county at least one WASH Forum will be organised by the counties themselves.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Towards the end of 2018,  IEA did not participate in county organised WASH forums since no forums were organised at the county level. IEA did however organise, as planned, their forums during which they engaged with the county government officials and other key stakeholders. This was the executive round table meeting as well as the roundtable CSO/Government official meeting in December 2019 where all three counties came together and during which social audit reports and sanitation progress per county were presented.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of verbal interventions at relevant encounters for CSO in the selected counties</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of interventions is total number of interventions, divided by number of CSOs</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="4" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO had formal interactions with Public Health Officers and other government officials from each of the four counties during the county visits</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold public at least two public forums in each of the three counties (Elgeyo Marakwet,Homabay and Kericho) to discuss and share information on coordination, investment and accountability in delivery of sanitation services at the county level as well as the results of the sanitation study and advocacy products.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="10.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2018: In each of the three counties, IEA has convened two forums (to validate research report for the study into poor effects of sanitation  and create knowledge and awareness on public budget hearings). In addition and during this forums, participants were taken through the budget cycle and the existing entry points for participation in te budget process and county Public hearings. IEA also shared research products out of the research on effects of poor sanitation in kenya at additional forums.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold public forums to discuss and share information on coordination, investment and accountability in delivery of sanitation services in the three counties. IEA will also conduct a training and carry out social audits in the three counties. In addition it is expected that the local CSO networks participate in relevant meetings and contribute to those meetings. If possible, IEA and SNV will co-facilitate and coordinate days for private sector to share options for water testing.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: IEA prepared a social audit toolkit and used it to train the Homabay,Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet county CSO network members on how to conduct social audits, its importance and need.This was carried out on the 12th,13th and 14th March 2019 in Homabay,Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet counties respectively. Social audits begun in the month of May in each of the three counties and has been finalised.The IEA will participate in the validation of the audit report findings.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2017, CSO plans to at least meet stakeholders from the three focus counties (Homabay, Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho; Kilifi will be included at a later date) at three crucial times (public hearings, round table meeting with members of the county assemble; share and discuss budget guides) as well as during a baseline visit during which documents and strategies were discussed</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: The Institute held meetings with officials from Homa bay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet Counties. The officials included the County Executive Committee, Member for Health, County Public Health Officers Budget director among other representatives. The purpose of the meeting was to pick up from the initial visits towards end of 2016 and reiterate the purpose and objective of the Voice For Change Project on sanitation in their areas. The meetings were used to solicit participant&#x2019;s contribution and cooperation in providing sanitation data and information to facilitate budget analysis and advocacy. SNV facilitated a Sanitation Benchmarking visit for Institute of Economic Affairs to Nakuru County as a learning and mentorship initiative to share and exchange experience on best practices to use in advocating for improved access to sanitation. Lessons learnt from the County Public Health Officer will be incorporated in the study for evidence generation and a benchmarking visit of other counties to Nakuru has been proposed. IEA organised a public forum on 23rd June 2017 in Nairobi, Kenya to share with members of the public and the media on situational analysis of water and sanitation. Other areas shared included the opportunity cost associated with lack of investment in sanitation. The forum was expected to debate on issues of sanitation particularly increasing resources so that access level on sanitation can increase country wide. Other members targeted included representative of political parties and marginalized groups. Due to the change in the budget calendar because of the 2017 elections, the next county visits will be done in the quarter.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="9.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: The IEA made inputs in the following engagements: 
1. Validation meetings of social audit reports in the three counties of Homa Bay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet - the validation was to verify the findings of the social audits and ascertain the findings with county government. IEA gave inputs on how to improve the social audit reports, and checking accurateness of the information reported 
2. MCA roundtable meetings in the 3 counties - IEA presented on alternative budget memo and case studies
3. Pre-budget hearings in the 3 counties - Collected views from sub-counties on what they would like to see from the budget 2020/21 (with a focus on sanitation)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute of Economic Affairs will hold trainings for Civil Society Organizations at the focus counties of Homabay, Elgeyo Marakwet and Kericho</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-11-2018: In the first half of the year, IEA held meetings with officials from Homa bay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet Counties. The officials included the County Executive Committee, Member for Health, County Public Health Officers Budget director among other representatives. The purpose of the meeting was to pick up from the initial visits towards end of 2016 to ensure participant&#x2019;s contribution and cooperation in providing sanitation data and information to facilitate budget analysis and advocacy. SNV facilitated a Sanitation Benchmarking visit for IEA to Nakuru County as a learning and mentorship initiative to share and exchange experience on best practices to use in advocating for improved access to sanitation. In the second half of the year, IEA held a training for CSOs and CPHOs on budget analysis and trackingin July 2017 in the three counties. The purpose for this was to equip the various stakeholders with knowledge on budget analysis to enable them track financing in the sanitation sector and demand for increased investment. In September 2017 IEA conducted a round-table meeting with members of the county assembly and county department officials. In addition there was the December public forum in Kericho as described above.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IEA plans to hold validation meetings for social audits in Elgeyo Marakwet,Homabay and Kericho counties in the month of July 2019.This is meant to verify the findings of the social audits and ascertain the finding with county governemnt officers as well ownership by all the parties involved in the Social Audit work.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="9.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: The IEA made inputs in the following engagements: 
1. Validation meetings of social audit reports in the three counties of Homa Bay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet - the validation was to verify the findings of the social audits and ascertain the findings with county government. IEA gave inputs on how to improve the social audit reports, and checking accurateness of the information reported 
2. MCA roundtable meetings in the 3 counties - IEA presented on alternative budget memo and case studies
3. Pre-budget hearings in the 3 counties - Collected views from sub-counties on what they would like to see from the budget 2020/21 (with a focus on sanitation)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We plan to organize two more forums in each of the counties.The forums are expected to debate on issues of sanitation particularly increasing resources so that access level on sanitation can increase country wide. Other members targeted include representatives of political parties and marginalized groups.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA held a roundtable meeting on 19th to 23rd November 2018 with MCAs and County Executive county governments in the three counties of Homa Bay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet and shared the state of public investment in sanitation. This was to enhance awareness on the level of investment at the county government&#x2019;s level. Other issues shared with the county government officers from the budget and planning department, Health department and the members of the health committee in the county assembly were the advocacy products for the study into poor effects of sanitation in Kenya with a focus on the shit flow diagram, geospatial maps, the F-diagram as well as specific county report on understanding the effects of poor sanitation on public health, the environment and well-being of Homa Bay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet counties. Other information shared during the forum included published specific county alternative budget memos containing budget proposals from the sub county levels. CSO/Government official meeting in December 2019 during which social audit reports and sanitation progress per county were presented. Other encounters in the second half of the year were between IEA and the local level CSOs (e.g. training)                                                           
In the first half of the year IEA also shared and created awareness around investment and accountability in sanitation during the validation and dissemination of the study into poor effects of sanitation in Kenya as well as during the MCAs and Executive roundtable meeting in the counties of Homa Bay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet. IEA has so far convened two forums to validate research report for the study into poor effects of sanitation and create knowledge and awareness on public budget hearings) in each of the three counties. In addition and during this forums, participants were taken through the budget cycle and the existing entry points for participation in te budget process and co ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of formal encounters of CSO with government officials and donors through technical working groups, public hearings and/or stakeholder forums at the national level</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of encounters is total number of encounters, divided by number of CSOs</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO has not attended TWG/ICC meetings. At the national level CSO interacted with the World Bank consultant on sanitation</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will participate, share and input to discussions towards enhancing delivery of sanitation services. This includes participation in national public hearings, sanitation Technical Working groups, participation during one of the Interagency Coordinating Committee meetings organised by Public Health and participation in the WEDC Conference among other upcoming forums. At least two forums will be attended in the first half of the year with more expected in the second half of the year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2018: IEA attended the National Sanitation Workshop at Safari Park Hotel, Nairobi, on February 12 and 13, 2018. This conference was organised by The World Bank Group, in collaboration with the National Government&#x2019;s Ministry of Health and Ministry of Water and Irrigation, and increased IEA&apos;s capacity on sanitation including the latest trends. IEA also participated during the sanitation learning event which took place at the Panafric Hotel. The sanitation technical working group learning event was held between 19th to 20th June 2018 with the theme &#x201C;Results with quality at Scale: from Policy to Practice&#x201D;. IEA participated during the event as a panelist discussing budgeting for sanitation in the Kenya context. The learnings of this event are yet to be taken forward.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will participate, share and input to discussions towards enhancing delivery of sanitation services in the national TWG/ICC or relevant national WASH related Conference. In addition a follow up roundtable meetings with representatives from the ministry  will be held to discuss the need for increased investment in the sanitation sector in the second half of the year and sanitation budget codes. An additional two meetings are expected in the second half of the year. Focus in the first quarter will be on information encounters and follow-up.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: &gt;The IEA participated in the AFRICASAN Conference held in South Africa  and shared the social audit concept as well hard copies of the research on effects of poor sanitation in Kenya. Key issue from the conference covered on data revolution, important of citizen on data ownership and use of inforgraphic while communicating research findings. During the AFRICASAN conference, the IEA interacted with a Ministry of Health official who shared how Government is coordinating various stakeholders through technical working group for stronger sector coordination.Through the WASH hub in the Ministry of Health, there are planned meetings in the month of July to follow up on the development of urban sanitation guidelines and IEA plans to attend. 
&gt;The IEA also registered and participated in the 3rd WASPA conference held in Nairobi from 8th-10th  May 2019 where the team made a presentation on the state of play and budget trends on sanitation programs at the national level as well as in Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homabay counties. The IEA got connected with water, sanitation and hygiene finance (WASHFIN) who conduct analysis on WASH expenditure at the national and county level. An initial meeting on how to collaborate better was agreed during the WASPA conference, settling for a date in the month of July 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: The IEA participated in:
1. The Ministry of Water and Sanitation of the Republic of Kenya organised the Kenya Sanitation Conference from the 28th to 31st October, 2019, at KICC, Nairobi. IEA with KEWASNET, WASHFIN, WATER.ORG and KIWASH facilitated the session on the state and future of sanitation financing in Kenya. IEA made a presentation on highlights of V4CP evidence based advocacy during the session on the status and the future of sanitation financing in Kenya. 
2. Roundtable meeting in December 2019 with the Ministry of Water and Sanitation, Ministry of Health as well as the Ministry of Environment and Natural Resources was held to discuss the Investment in the sanitation sector and assess progress in improving inter-ministerial coordination. The forum was co-facilitated with KEWASNET                                                                                                                     3. WASPA Conference 8-10th of May 2019 at KICC, Nairobi. The National Water Service Providers Association invited partners to exchange knowledge on emerging leading practices. The IEA made a presentation during the last day of the workshop on the analysis of budgetary allocation to the sanitation sector at the national level and for Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homa Bay counties.                                                                         4. IEA attended urban sanitation technical working group (TWG) meeting on 8th July at the Panafric hotel. The objective of the meeting was for the stakeholders to share ideas on the revival and updating of urban sanitation guidelines that would form a basis for engagement and investment towards improvement of access to sanitation in Kenya.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will work with WASH Advisors to ensure attendance in all WASH forums and Technocal Working Group meetings held at the county level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-11-2018: In the first half of the year, on 7th to 9th February 2017, IEA attended the 2nd Sanitation Conference in Nairobi. The conference was organised by the Ministry of Health with the objective of reviewing the country commitments made on sanitation during the first sanitation conference held in 2014. The conference provided an opportunity to learn about sanitation context and outlook from a countrywide perspective, the bottlenecks that the sector is confronted with and opportunities to address them. Various county initiatives to promote improved sanitation and means to enhance networks were discussed. In the second half of 2017 IEA engaged with both key national and county Ministry of Health officials during the V4CP Project Launch. The planned attendence of the national Interagency Coordinating Committee was postponed by the Ministry of Public Health to 2018 due to budget constraints.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2017, a CSO staff member will attend the Technical Working Group for sanitation. Encounters are also expected during public hearings and conferences like the Sanitation Conference.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-11-2018: Institute of Economic Affairs had engagements with World Bank consultants, United Nations Children Education Fund and other NGO&#x2019;s in a training workshop in Machakos in the month of December 2016. Institute of Economic Affairs shared and exchanged experiences with donors and stakeholders on sanitation and sanitation investment issues. On the dates of 7th to 9th February 2017, Institute of Economic Affairs attended a Sanitation Conference in Nairobi that was organised by the Ministry of Health. The objective of the 2nd sanitation conference was to review the country commitments made on sanitation during the first sanitation conference held in 2014. The conference provided an opportunity to learn about sanitation context and outlook from a countrywide perspective, the bottlenecks that the sector is confronted with and opportunities to address them. Various county initiatives to promote improved sanitation and means to enhance networks were discussed. The Institute will be attending the Technical Working Groups and Inter Agency Coordinating Committee meetings in the second half of the year. Budget hearings that were to be held in the first quarter of 2017 of which Institute of Economic Affairs was to participate were not held due the elections to be held in August 2017. The budget hearings has been planned for September 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IEA intends to attend and participate in the Sanitation conference scheduled in October 2019 and also hold a national roundtable meeting with the Ministry of Water and Sanitation, Ministry of Health as well as the Ministry of Environment and Natural Resources to discuss the Investment in the sanitation sector and assess progress in improving inter-ministerial coordination</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: The IEA participated in:
1. The Ministry of Water and Sanitation of the Republic of Kenya organised the Kenya Sanitation Conference from the 28th to 31st October, 2019, at KICC, Nairobi. IEA with KEWASNET, WASHFIN, WATER.ORG and KIWASH facilitated the session on the state and future of sanitation financing in Kenya. IEA made a presentation on highlights of V4CP evidence based advocacy during the session on the status and the future of sanitation financing in Kenya. 
2. Roundtable meeting in December 2019 with the Ministry of Water and Sanitation, Ministry of Health as well as the Ministry of Environment and Natural Resources was held to discuss the Investment in the sanitation sector and assesss progress in improving inter-ministerial coordination. The forum was co-facilitated with KEWASNET                                                                                                                     3. WASPA Conference 8-10th of May 2019 at KICC, Nairobi. The National Water Service Providers Association invited partners to exchange knowledge on emerging leading practices. The IEA made a presentation during the last day of the workshop on the analysis of budgetary allocation to the sanitation sector at the national level and for Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homa Bay counties.                                                                         4. IEA attended urban sanitation technical working group (TWG) meeting on 8th July at the Panafric hotel. The objective of the meeting was for the stakeholders to share ideas on the revival and updating of urban sanitation guidelines that would form a basis for engagement and investment towards improvement of access to sanitation in Kenya.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IEA plan to organize a breakfast meeting with the Ministry of Health officials before December 2018 to discuss sector coordination and sanitation budget codes. IEA will also attend TWG or ICC meeting for the Health sector to share about sanitation budget analysis and research. IEA will intend to increase the visibility of sanitation in the public hearing at the national level at the end of the year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA held a national sanitation stakeholder&apos;s roundtable meeting to discuss the need for creation of sanitation budget codes and better inter-ministerial coordination in December 2019. In the first half of the year IEA had convened the national level pre-budget hearings and  participated and interacted with government officials and other stakeholders during the sanitation technical working group learning event.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of knowledge/research products shared with relevant stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of evidence based knowledge/research products shared is total number of evidence based knowledge/research products shared, divided by number of CSOs</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Knowledge products have not been shared to date</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will share the final advocacy products resulting from the sanitation study during a public forum in the first half of the year. In the second half of the year the advocacy package generated by IEA&apos;s budget research will be shared.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2018: Validation and dissemination meetings at the three counties for the intial products (County reports on poor effects of sanitation, GIS Maps, F-Diagram, County policy briefs, posters and Shit flow diagrams) from a study on effects of poor sanitation were held so that the counties could verify data of the research and take ownership. In the month of february 2018, the IEA held a pre budget forum inviting private and social sector players to make budget proposals for submission to the National Treasury as a requirement in Public Finance Management Act.The IEA  synthesized the proposals and  prepared a memorandum dubbed &quot; Citizen&apos;s Alternative Budget&quot; which was shared with the National Treasury for  consideration on 28th February 2018.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA has reviewed national and county level budget documents to create up to date statistics on the budgetary allocations towards sanitation. The resulting budget analysis reports will be shared. A budget guide will also be shared. In the second half of the year it is expected that social audit reports for each of the counties will be developed and shared with government officials. In addition two case study documents will be shared with relevant decision makers (as listed under B.).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="6.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: The reports on the state of play on sanitation  budget trends  in the National level as well as the Homabay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet counties were shared during the 3rd WASPA conference to create awareness on the need for increased investment in sanitation.This was not planned for but it was an opportunity which presented and The IEA used it to advocate increased investment in sanitation.The IEA also shared the National alternative budget with the National Treasury advocating for increased investment and the need for creating budget codes for the sanitation sector to help track budgetary allocations to the sanitation sector.The Alternative budget memo contained a range of proposals on WASH as well as proposal on food security and enegy all drawn for the Voice for Change Project.The IEA aslo shared social audit toolkits for Elgeyo Marakwet,Homabay and Kericho counties to be used for social audit of sanitation projects in the three counties</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO intends to develop a budget memo for sharing with stakeholders in the three focus counties and at the national level (period 1); a budget guide will be developed and shared (period 2); in addition IEA will share the Report on Budgetary allocations on sanitation and levels of access to improved sanitation at the county and national level (Period 2)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: Institute of Economic Affairs shared a Policy Brief labelled: Water and Sanitation as an Agenda for Elections 2017. The policy brief is not a replacement of the budget analysis memo but provides supporting information on intervention to support Water and Sanitation Agenda. The paper was used as training material for candidates aspiring to be political parties&#x2019; representatives. Shared as a knowledge and research product, the policy is paper will be used for advocacy at the county and national levels. The organisation is also working on the analysis of sanitation budget information which will result in three county briefs that might be ready in the third quarter of the year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="13.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: The following knowledge products were developed and shared:
&gt;3 social audit reports for Elgeyo Marakwet, Homa Bay and Kericho developed and  shared during MCA roundtable meetings where the Director Public Health  was represented
&gt;The IEA also updated statistics on the budgetary allocations for sanitation at the national level and shared a sanitation brief during the national roundtable with the Ministry of Health,Ministry of Water and Sanitation as well as the Ministry of Environment and Natural Reasources.
&gt;3 alternative budgets reports developed for the counties and shared during MCA roundtable meetings where the economic and planning departments were represented 
&gt;2 case studies developed for each of the 3 counties (Elgeyo Marakwet, Homabay and Kericho) and shared during MCA roundtable meetings</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are ongoing social audits in Elgeyo Marakwet,Homabay and Kericho counties.This will culminate into three social audit reports which will be shared with the members of the public and other county officials to show how well the sanitation projects have been implemented.The IEA will also update statistics on the budgetary allocations for sanitation at the national level and share this during the national roundtable with the Ministry of Health, Ministry of Water and Sanitation as well as the Ministry of Environment and Natural Reasources.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="13.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: The following knowledge products were developed and shared:
&gt;3 social audit reports for Elgeyo Marakwet, Homa Bay and Kericho developed and  shared during MCA roundtable meetings where the Director Public Health  was represented
&gt;The IEA also updated statistics on the budgetary allocations for sanitation at the national level and shared a sanitation brief during the national roundtable with the Ministry of Health,Ministry of Water and Sanitation as well as the Ministry of Environment and Natural Reasources.
&gt;3 alternative budgets reports developed for the counties and shared during MCA roundtable meetings where the economic and planning departments were represented 
&gt;2 case studies developed for each of the 3 counties (Elgeyo Marakwet, Homabay and Kericho) and shared during MCA roundtable meetings</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will conduct budget analysis for the three counties and share the trends on water and sanitation and package this information for sharing with county officials and CSOs in these counties.
IEA will also share the final advocacy products resulting from the sanitation study during CSO pre budget hearing and training as well as during the international WEDC Conference and roundtable meeting with county officials  in the second half of the year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA collated the budget and policy documents at the national and the county level to help conduct analysis of investment in sanitation for the three counties of Homa Bay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet Counties. This culminated into budget analysis reports of which the first findings were shared with Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homa Bay county stakeholders. The publication of this document will be done in the year 2019. Printing and dissemination of the county based alternative budget memo&#x2019;s was done and shared with the respective counties (3). During the first half of the year, IEA shared the synthesis report, county reports and advocacy ready products (policy briefs,  posters, F-diagram, GIS booklets) and Shit Flow Diagram Reports with county officials, CSOs and other stakeholders during several county encounters. The finalised SFD reports and diagrams were shared during the fourth quarter.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA intends to develop a budget memo for sharing with stakeholders in the three focus counties and at the national level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advocacy strategies and plans on sanitation available</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual advocacy plan developed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thematic annual advocacy plan developed</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Yes" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO prepared and submitted annual plan</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="yes">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO will develop their advocacy plan for 2018</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: 0=no
1=yes
The Annual Advocacy Plan was developed by IEA.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: Annual advocacy plan developed for the year 2020</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual advocacy plan to be developed for the year 2020</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Annual advocacy plan developed for the year 2020</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="yes">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The advocacy plan will be updated for 2019 by IEA with support from SNV</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Annual advocacy plan has been developed</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of CSO activity plans developed versus number of CSOs involved in the advocacy process</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="100%" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The participating CSO submitted the plan</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that the 2018 plan will be developed by the end of 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: One Activity plan and gantt chart was developed by IEA.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: CSO activity plan developed for the year 2020</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO activity plan to be developed for the year 2020</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: CSO activity plan developed for the year 2020</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV will support IEA developing activity plan for 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: CSO activity plan developed . In addition each of the three counties also develop their own advocacy action plan.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO capacities improved</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs with increased advocacy capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their advocacy capacities guided by a list of advocacy criteria. The score is the average of individual CSO&apos;s scores.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs with improved leadership capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their leadership capacities guided by a list of leadership criteria. The score is the average of individual CSO members&apos; scores.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="62.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">01-05-2019: The ODF status as at the reporting time was 62%. IEA continously advocates for behaviour change and better hygiene practices which contribute towards ODF.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs with increased thematic knowledge</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their thematic knowledge guided by a list of knowledge related criteria. The score is the average of individual CSOs&apos; scores.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs with increased capacity in organisational sustainability</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their capacities guided by a list of criteria.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved Commitment and political will to adopt county sanitation investment plans and better coordination among National &amp; County Government Ministries</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of policy / decision makers that demonstrate increased support for sanitation at the national level</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The data on this indicator will be collected using the policymaker rating tool. For each individual policy or decision maker the score will be determined. For reporting purposes the scores of all policy or decision makers will be aggregated; then the average score (the total score / number of assessed policy or decision makers) on the indicator will be determined and reported on.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: 0= -
At the national level, the key individuals to be rated have been changed after the results of the 2017 general elections. Therefore IEA will repeat the baseline rating exercise to establish the current and subsequently increase in support for new office bearers. This exercise has been planned for the first quarter of 2018.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: IEA convened a National Sanitation stakeholder&apos;s meeting with representatives from the ministry of Water ,Sanitation and Irrigation, Ministry of Environment and Natural resources . The representatives indicated that the various ministries are working together to ensure improved sanitation service delivery. Among the issues they are working towards is the  creation of sanitation budget codes for ease in budget analysis. The policy marker rating was however not done at the national level in 2019 due to the continuous cabinet shuffles and changes in office. However, we are basing the judgement on the commitments towards improved access to Sanitation by the Deputy President during the National Sanitation Conference held at the ICC as well as the Commitment by the CAS Ms Winnie Guchu to ensure increased investment to sanitation during the same forum.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IEA will ride on other activities under the project to share with government official on coordination of programmes on the sanitation sector. The IEA is intending to work with the PSs of the three ministries and the PS Treasury. It is expected that out of the 5 at least 4 will show increased support.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: IEA convened a National Sanitation stakeholder&apos;s meeting with representatives from the ministry of Water ,Sanitation and Irrigation, Ministry of Environment and Natural resources . The representatives indicated that the various ministries are working together to ensure improved sanitation service delivery.Among the issues they are working towards is the  creation of sanitation budget codes for ease in budget analysis. The policy marker rating was however not done at the national level in 2019 due to the continous cabinet shuffles and changes in office. However,we are basing the judgement on the commitments towards improved access to Sanitation by the Deputy President during the National Sanitation Conference held at the ICC as well as the Commitment by the CAS Ms Winnie Guchu to ensure increased investment to sanitation during the same forum.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold a public forum/roundtable meeting engaging on the need for improved coordination between the different ministries and increased priority for saniation. Out of the six key officers expected to be rated, it is intended that half will increase their support.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA held one National Sanitation stakeholder&apos;s meeting with representatives from the ministry of Water and Sanitation, Ministry of Environment and Natural resources as well as the national treasury. The representatives indicated that the various ministries have increased their interest and commitment to improve sanitation service delivery and creating sanitation budget codes for ease in budget tracking. The policy marker rating was however not done at the national level in 2018 but we can do a national level policy marker rating in 2019 if agreed. It was not done as we did not have a crucial group of people who were well informed enough to do the rating for key people identified (who did change as well). The stakeholders have not declared publicly their interest for sanitation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of policy / decision makers that demonstrate increased support for sanitation at the county level</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The data on this indicator will be collected using the policymaker rating tool. For each individual policy or decision maker the score will be determined. For reporting purposes the scores of all policy or decision makers will be aggregated; then the average score (the total score / number of assessed policy or decision makers) on the indicator will be determined and reported on.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: 0= -
The rating of officers will be conducted in May 2018. During this time IEA will evaluate how many ratings can be compared to the baseline rating performed early 2017 for 28 positions. As at the national level, new officers have assumed office in key county positions and therefore a new baseline rating might need to be done in order to track these specific officer positions over the coming years. Some officers like the CPHO have remained stable and will be rated. The previous MCAs, CECs, CPHOs, Members of the Health Committee and Budget Officers for Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homabay Counties showed increased  participation in Sanitation forums and increasingly associated themselves and advocate for increased prioritisation of investment in sanitation. Especially the CPHOs have continually provided us with information about any sanitation activities as well as sought support in the analysis of budget documents in order to get a better understanding of the budgetary allocations towards sanitation at the county level. The MCAs also expressed interest and participated in a training by IEA to take them through the budget analysis process. The Budget Directors also started providing budget information more easily to the public.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="20.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: IEA held the county MCA roundtable meetings with County Officials for Elgeyo Marakwet, Homa Bay and Kericho counties  to advocate for better partnership and improvement of resource allocation toward sanitation and adoption of investment plans in the three counties. The policy maker ratings were also conducted during this period for 28 individuals. In summary, we have seen increased support and influence from the policy makers. There has been improved commitment and political will from the Governor, Director Water, MCAs, CECs, CPHOs, Members of the Health Committee and Directors Budget for Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homa Bay Counties who participated in Sanitation forums and promised to be advocates for increased prioritization of investment in sanitation in their respective counties. The increased support is from the fact that the county officials mentioned, showed increased interest and participation in Sanitation forums and activities after introduction of the V4C project and their interaction with the IEA. This increased interest is from the need for information on Sanitation budgetary allocations which is useful for budget tracking as well as the social audit reports which help in highlighting the status of the various sanitation projects being implemented by the county governments. The CPHOs have continually provided us with information about any sanitation activities in Elgeyo Marakwet, Homa Bay and Kericho counties. The MCAs also expressed interest and participated in a training by IEA to take them through the budget analysis process and attended other IEA forums they were invited to. The Budget Directors also participated in the validation of the social audit process and promised to look into the issues raised and recommendations from the social audit process.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold roundtable meetings with County Officials and private engagements in public hearings to advocate for better partnership and improvement of resource allocation toward sanitation and adoption of investment plans in the three counties. Continued efforst are expected to result in further increased support at the county level. The policy maker ratings were conducted for 28 individuals and it is expected that, also because some individuals are already at a high score, at least 15 will show increased support.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="20.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: IEA held the county MCA roundtable meetings with County Officials for Elgeyo Marakwet, Homa Bay and Kericho counties  to advocate for better partnership and improvement of resource allocation toward sanitation and adoption of investment plans in the three counties. The policy maker ratings were also conducted during this period for 28 individuals. In summary,we have seen increased support and influence from the policy makers.There has been improved commitment and political will from the Governor, Director Water, MCAs, CECs, CPHOs, Members of the Health Committee and Directors Budget for Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homabay Counties who participated in Sanitation forums and promised to be advocates for increased prioritization of investment in sanitation in their respective counties. The increased support is from the fact that the county officials mentioned, showed increased interest and participation in Sanitation forums and activities after introduction of the V4C project and their interaction with the IEA. This increased interest is from the need for information on Sanitation budgetary allocations which is useful for budget tracking as well as the social audit reports which help in highlighting the status of the various sanitation projects being implemented by the county governments.The CPHOs have continually provided us with information about any sanitation activities in Elgeyo Marakwet, Homa Bay and Kericho counties. The MCAs also expressed interest and participated in a training by IEA to take them through the budget analysis process and attended other IEA forums they were invited to. The Budget Directors also participated in the validation of the social audit process and promised to look into the issues raised and recomendations from the social audit process.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA in partership with local stakeholders will focus on building realtionships with the current and new duty bearers at the county level. This will be done to include them in the forums and one-to-one engagements. We intend to rate the same 28 positions as during the baseline and expect that at least 10 of these will show an increased support.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="20.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: There has been an increase in the number of policy/decision makers with increased support for sanitation from 15 in 2017 to 20 in 2018. There has been improved commitment and political will from the Governor, Director Water, MCAs, CECs, CPHOs, Members of the Health Committee and Directors Budget for Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homabay Counties who participated in Sanitation forums and promised to be advocates for increased prioritization of investment in sanitation in their respective counties. The increased support is from the fact that the county officials mentioned showed increased interest and participation in Sanitation forums and activities after introduction of the V4C project and their interaction with the IEA. This increased interest is from the need for information on Sanitation budgetary allocations which is useful for budget tracking. The CPHOs have continually provided us with information about any sanitation activities in Elgeyo Marakwet, Homa Bay and Kericho counties. The MCAs also expressed interest and participated in a training by IEA to take them through the budget analysis process and attended other IEA forums they were invited to. The Budget Directors also continued in providing budget information more easily to the public which was not the case before their interaction with IEA through the V4C project. This information is based on the baseline for the policy marker rating conducted in the month of May 2018. The subsequent rating will be done in May 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree of inter-ministerial coordination at the national level</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Currently there is poor coordination between the relevant national ministries (Water, Health and Environment)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO has planned to engage the relevant ministries in round table meetings and other forums</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: Though round table meetings and a public forum have been held at the national level in 2017, the CSO has not yet establish a proper working relationship with the three ministries,enough to influence inter-ministerial coordination at the national level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: IEA convened a National Sanitation stakeholder&apos;s meeting with representatives from the ministry of Water, Sanitation and Irrigation, Ministry of Environment and Natural resources . The representatives indicated that the various ministries are working together to ensure improved sanitation service delivery. Among the issues they are working towards is the  creation of sanitation budget codes for ease in budget analysis. The budget code is however not yet in place although a committee overseeing this process is in place with all the three  ministries taking part as stakeholders.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold a Public forum meeting engaging on why ministry with sanitation programmes should work together and have better inter-ministerial coordination as well as hold a roundtable meeting with representatives from the ministry to discuss the effect of poor inter ministerial coordination on sanitation service delivery.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: IEA convened a National Sanitation stakeholder&apos;s meeting with representatives from the ministry of Water, Sanitation and Irrigation, Ministry of Environment and Natural resources . The representatives indicated that the various ministries are working together to ensure improved sanitation service delivery. Among the issues they are working towards is the  creation of sanitation budget codes for ease in budget analysis. The budget code is however not yet in place although a commitee overseeing this process is in place with all the three  ministries taking part as stakeholders.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold a public forum/roundtable meeting engaging on why ministry with sanitation programmes should coordinates better and work together to ensure better service delivery in the sanitation sector.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The IEA organised a National Sanitation Stakeholder&apos;s Roundtable meeting held on 6th December 2018 where all the representatives from the three ministries (Ministry of Water, Ministry of Environment and Natural Resources and the National Treasury) were invited and attended the meeting to discuss the budgetary allocations towards the Sanitation sector and the need for introduction of budget codes. Government staff from different ministries do meet on a regular basis to discuss issues that are cross-cutting.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree of inter-ministrial coordindation at the county level</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Currently there is poor coordincation between the relevant county departments (Public Health, Department of Water and the Department of Environment)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO and other county civil society actors will engage more closely during the planned WASH Forums, public hearings, round table and other meetings</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: Held a public forum at the county level where CSOs,County Official were all invited and were in attendance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: IEA  held Public forums in Elgeyo Marakwet, Homa Bay and Kericho counties and discussed the importance of the various departments to work together and have better inter-ministerial coordination and how this will improve sanitation service delivery and avoid the issue of role overlaps hence improving efficiency in the use of public resources.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold a Public forum meeting engaging on why ministries that deal with sanitation programmes should work together and have better inter-ministerial coordination as well as hold a roundtable meeting with representatives from the ministry to discuss the effect of poor inter ministerial coordination on sanitation service delivery. In all meetings where government officials are invited we will emphasise the request to invite representatives from all ministries and other key stakeholders like NEMA, the water and sanitation companies etc.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: IEA  held Public forums in Elgeyo Marakwet ,Homabay and Kericho counties and discussed the importance of the various departments to work together and have better inter-ministerial coordination and how this will improve sanitation service delivery and avoid the issue of role overlaps hence improving efficiency in the use of public resources.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold more forums where relevant government ministries will be invited to attend and evidence shared to impress better coordination. In 2018 increased efforts will be made to ensure all relevant ministries are invited and actively engaged in forums and activities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Held public forums in Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homa Bay counties where CSOs and County Officials from the different ministries were all invited and were in attendance. We have seen an increase in participation and input from the different ministries during meetings. It is however realised that when ministries organise their own meetings, other ministries are sometimes invited and sometimes not invited. We look forward to seeing more invitations from one ministry to another when it comes to anything related to WASH issues.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evidence available</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of policy briefs and/or evidence based knowledge products made available to CSOs that are supportive to its advocacy plan</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">No policy briefs or knowledge products have been developed. Planning for generation of knowledge products/policy briefs is on-going and planned for 2017. See Evidence Generation Proposal</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2017, two knowledge products will be available to the CSO and county stakeholders: Report on Budgetary allocations on sanitation and levels of access to improved sanitation at the county and national level (incl. effects of poor sanitation) (period 1); Budget guides and smart packaging of national and county budget analysis (period 2)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: Terms of Reference have been drafted for a study into the health, nutritional, social, cultural, economic, political and environmental effects of poor sanitation through levels of access to improved sanitation in the counties of Homa Bay, Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Kilifi in Kenya. The study is expected to complete in September 2017. Terms of Reference were also developed for sanitation budget analysis for the same counties. Institute of Economic Affairs has collected data for the four counties which is being analysed. The terms of reference for budget analysis will be broadened to include all 47 counties in Kenya or include other countries for a cross-country analysis at a later stage.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="6.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: IEA supported local CSO networks to identify cases in need of advocacy in each of the counties. With support of a communication consultant this resulted in six factsheets (2 per county) for the identified cases which have been used by CSOs to advocate for the envisaged change in the month of November 2019 round-table meeting and informal follow-ups. Besides these evidence products, IEA also produced the national level alternative citizens&apos; budget (1); county-level Alternative Budget Memos (3); social audit reports (3) and a sanitation budget brief as a result of the budget analysis (1).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hoping to have completed the study on sanitation and levels of access to improved sanitation at the county and national level (incl. effects of poor sanitation) by 30th June, period 2 which will end on 31st December 2017 will hope to prepare a report on Budgetary allocations and Budget guides and smart packaging of national and county budget analysis.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-11-2018: Terms of Reference were drafted for a study into the health, nutritional, social, cultural, economic, political and environmental effects of poor sanitation through levels of access to improved sanitation in the counties of Homa Bay, Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Kilifi in Kenya. However,due to delay in selecting an able consulting research organisation to carry out the study,the research work will start in early 2018 with completion expected in the first quarter of 2018. Terms of Reference were also developed for sanitation budget analysis for the same counties. Institute of Economic Affairs has collected data for the four counties which is being analysed. The planned ToR activities are expected to be updated and finalised in the third quarter of 2018.
In the first half of the year IEA conducted situational analysis of water and sanitation. Other areas of the study included the opportunity cost associated with lack of investment in sanitation. During the study, officers from the Ministry of Water were part of the Key Informants who shared information on the challenges facing the WASH sector and the need to increase investment towards Sanitation. In the second half of the year IEA prepared a budget toolkit which was used to train the CSOs and CPHOs on budget tracking and analysis.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development of case studies on private sector and social inclusion with respect to sanitation (2) will be conducted in the year 2019 through hiring of consultant working closely with IEA staff (specific topics to be confirmed). IEA will update statistics on sanitation allocation in the budget analysis report and budget guide (2) for both the national and the county government as well as the production of the national alternative budget shared with Treasury (1) and county based budget memos for the three counties (3) which will be shared with MCAs from the budget and appropriation committe and health in a roundtable meeting  in the year 2019. IEA will also come up with a social audit reports after county level CSOs conduct Social Audits on Sanitation programs at the county level (3)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="6.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: IEA supported local CSO networks to identify cases in need of advocacy in each of the counties. With support of a communication consultant this resulted in six facsheets (2 per county) for the identified cases which have been used by CSOs to advocate for the envisaged change in the month of November 2019 round-table meeting and informal follow-ups. Besides these evidence products, IEA also produced the national level alternative citizens&apos; budget (1); county-level Alternative Budget Memos (3); social audit reports (3) and a sanitation budget brief as a result of the budget analysis (1).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">From the Sanitation Study we expect reports (3) for each of the three counties with a detailed description and data representation of the effects of poor sanitation and its implications as well as compilation of all raw data obtained; Three case studies of other counties (3) which highlight lessons learnt related to sanitation; Advocacy ready products including case studies/fact sheets, SFDs, and/or poster materials (3); This will be followed by a stakeholder meeting during which the research study, policy briefs and advocacy products are presented. For the second half of the year, from the IEA budget analysis, IEA expects county advocacy packages including budget guides, an infographic and poster.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="6.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The study into poor effects of sanitation in Kenya was conducted and finalised which included the compilation of all raw data obtained. This resulted in a synthesis report and three county reports; Advocacy ready products for each of the counties including Posters, SFDs, F-diagrams,GIS booklets and water testing guidelines (3).  Three case studies of three counties which highlight lessons learnt related to sanitation (3). For each county we also generated Powerpoint presentations. Validation meetings and dissemination of the intial products was done in the first and the second quarter to ensure ownership by the county officials and stakeholders. This was followed by a stakeholder meeting during which the research study, policy briefs and advocacy products were presented. All final products were dissimated to the counties in the third quarter and the SFD reports in the fourth quarter. Dissemination was also done at the WEDC Conference to a nationa land international audiencce. For the second half of the year, IEA developed alternative budget memo&apos;s for each of the counties (3) while drafts have been prepared for a budget analysis report and budget guide/poster as well as socail audit report for three counties we are working with</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of portals and websites made accessible to CSOs that generate evidence for advocacy issues</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">No relevant websites and portals have been shared</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to sector and budget relevant information will be availed to IEA through the SNV website e.g. SSH4ALL documents and external websites/portals e.g. IBP</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: Institute of Economic Affairs was referred to the International Budget Partnership at http://www.internationalbudget.org/budget-work-by-country/ibps-work-in-countries/kenya/. Institute of Economic Affairs has access to relevant documentation and reports from the Sustainable Sanitation and Hygiene For All (SSH4) as well as other SNV sanitation projects. In addition, Institute of Economic Affairs has created a google drive where all information collected will be stored and made accessible to those with access rights. The Organisation is following Facebook and Twitter accounts of Sanitation related projects with SNV and other partners to keep up to date with sanitation progress and news.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: IEA was able to have access to IFMIS, the Integrated Financial Management Information System (Kenya National Treasury) through the newly established connection with WASHFIN at the national level. IEA now also uses the website of WASPA (https://waspakenya.or.ke/) as a result of the WASPA Conference, the website of AFRICASAN (https://www.africasan.com/) following the AFRICASAN/FSM5 participation and the website for the National Sanitation Conference (https://sanitationconference.go.ke/) following this national level conference in 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to sector and budget relevant information will be availed to IEA through SNV website e.g. SSH4ALL documents and external websites/portals e.g. IBP as well as the IEA website</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-11-2018: In the first half of the year Institute of Economic Affairs was referred to the International Budget Partnership website at http://www.internationalbudget.org/budget-work-by-country/ibps-work-in-countries/kenya/. IEA also has access to relevant documentation and reports from the Sustainable Sanitation and Hygiene For All (SSH4) as well as other SNV sanitation projects. In addition, Institute of Economic Affairs has created a google drive where all information collected will be stored and made accessible to those with access rights. The Organisation is following Facebook and Twitter accounts of Sanitation related projects with SNV and other partners to keep up to date with sanitation progress and news. In the second half of the year IEA also accesses and increasingly uses WASH information from the Ministry of Health website at http://www.health.go.ke/ as well as budget information from the National Treasury website at http://www.treasury.go.ke/. The IEA also has its own website at http://www.ieakenya.or.ke/. This website is used to share publications as well as reports on Sanitation and the budget making process and available to other CSOs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will continue to access the IBP,World Bank,SNV, Ministry of Health, IEA and the three counties websites where they share information. The CPHRM website, WEDC website incl susana platform as well as the Treasury website will also continue to provide information relevant to the social effects of poor sanitation  and the National budget.  New access is expected for the website that relates to the AfricaSan/FSM Conference.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: IEA was able to have access to IFMIS, the Integrated Financial Management Information System (Kenya National Treasury) through the newly established connection with WASHFIN at the national level. IEA now also uses the website of WASPA (https://waspakenya.or.ke/) as a result of the WASPA Conference, the website of AFRICASAN (https://www.africasan.com/) following the AFRICASAN/FSM5 participation and the website for the National Sanitation Conference (https://sanitationconference.go.ke/) following this national level conference in 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The CPHRM website and products will become available for use once the study on the poor effects of sanitation is completed. Related to the study IEA will have acccess to Mango Maps where GIS data is available. It is also expected that the WEDC website and papers and reports published will be a source that will become availabe in the second half of the year. It is expected that one more information source will be looked for and made available.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The Institute of Economic Affairs has access to and provided the International Budget Partnership website (http://www.internationalbudget.org/budget-work-by-country/ibps-work-in-countries/kenya/) to its partner CSOs at the county level and to the Stakeholders at the National level. IEA also visits the Ministry of Health website at http://www.health.go.ke/ as well as budget information from the National treasury website at http://www.treasury.go.ke/.  Institute of Economic Affairs also has access to relevant documentation and reports from the Sustainable Sanitation and Hygiene For All (SSH4A) as well as other SNV sanitation projects. In addition, Institute of Economic Affairs has created a google drive where all information collected is stored and made accessible to those with access rights. The organisation continues to follow Facebook and Twitter accounts of Sanitation related projects with SNV and other partners to keep up to date with sanitation progress and updates. The IEA also has its own website at http://www.ieakenya.or.ke/.This website is used to share publications as well as reports on Sanitation and the budget making process. IEA gained additional access to the CPHRM website as well as WEDC website and Susana platform.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced awareness of CSOs and other stakeholders on the state of public investment in sanitation</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of  budget analysis documents (sanitation budget guides) shared with  National and County government</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sanitation budget guides are not available. Development of budget analysis documents has been planned for 2017</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that each focus county willl receive a budget analysis document. Including one at the national level. These documents will be used during national and county prebudget hearings</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: The IEA did an analysis of the cost of poor sanitation for each county by showing how much each county lost annualy to poor sanitation, and how else the money could have been used in other county projects had there been access to improved sanitation in Homabay,Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet counties. The analysis was shared with varous stakeholders at the counties including;CPHOs,Members of the public and other County CSOs involved in Sanitation issues.The organisation also worked on the analysis of sanitation budget information which resulted into three county budget memos that were shared with the three county government sanitation stakeholders. The budget memos were shared during county public forums held. In addition to budget memos, budget guides will be developed in 2018 and include analysis of trends in allocations after the budget estimates are out. In 2017 this was not possible as the budget cycle was changed because of the election year and pushed to December 2016.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="5.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: IEA prepared the 2019  Citizen&apos;s Alternative Budget guide that was shared at the national level. The Citizen&apos;s Alternative Budget contains budget proposals which could either be tax, regulatory or expenditure related or even reform oriented. The Alternative budget gives the citizen an opportunity to make or influence government decisions and also help civil society develop viable alternatives to government policy in the budget process.  Alternative budget memos were also shared with each of the three counties.                 
IEA published  the sanitation budget analysis; a case of Homa Bay, Elgeyo Marakwet and Kericho Counties .The anayisis show the level of budgetary allocation in the counties with respect to sanitation programmes</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IEA will prepare a Citizen&apos;s Alternative Budget memo that will be  shared at the national level.The Alternative budget gives the citizen an opportunity to make or influence government decisions and also helps civil societies develop viable alternatives to government policy in the budget making process. The National budget analysis will be shared with the Ministry of Water and Sanitation, Ministry of Environment and Natural resources and the National Treasury representatives to show the allocations towads Sanitation as well as the need to create sanitation codes for ease in budget analysis.
&gt;The analysis of sanitation budget information will result into three county budget memos that will be shared with  Elgeyo Marakwet,Kericho and Homa Bay county government sanitation stakeholders.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: IEA prepared the 2019  Citizen&apos;s Alternative Budget guide that was shared at the national level. The Citizen&apos;s Alternative Budget contains budget proposals which could either be tax, regulatory or expenditure related or even reform oriented.The Alternative budget gives the citizen an opportunity to make or influence government decisions and also help civil society develop viable alternatives to government policy in the budget process.  Alternative bduget memos were also shared with each of the three counties.                 
IEA published  the saniation budget analysis; a case of Homa Bay, Elgeyo Marakwet and Kericho Counties .The anayisis show the level of budgetary allocation in the counties with repect to sanitation programmes</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;IEA will draft, print and dissemination of budget guides and budget memo&apos;s for Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homabay counties.This will be shared through roundtable meetings with the county executives and CSOs on the need for inclusion of sanitation investment plans in planning and budgeting. In addition one alternative bduget memo will be prepared and shared at the national level. 
&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA prepared a Citizen&apos;s Alternative Budget guide that was shared at the national level. The Citizen&apos;s Alternative Budget contains budget proposals which could either be tax, regulatory or expenditure related or even reform oriented. The Alternative budget gives the citizen an opportunity to make or influence government decisions and also help civil society develop viable alternatives to government policy in the budget process.                  
IEA worked on the analysis of sanitation budget information which resulted into three county budget memos and budget guides that were shared with  Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homabay county government sanitation stakeholders. The budget memos were shared during county public forums held  in Elgeyo Marakwt,Kericho and Homabay counties. The National budget analysis was also shared with the Ministry of Water and Sanitation, Ministry of Environment and Natural resources and the National Treasury representatives to show the allocations towards Sanitation as well as the need to create sanitation codes for ease in budget analysis.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development and improved implementation of County Sanitation Investment Plans and Inter-ministerial coordination mechanisms</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting and implementing County Sanitation Bills in kericho</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">As stated above, Kericho is the only county that did not draft a county sanitation bill yet</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By end of 2017 it is expected thatat least three focus counties will have adopted the County Sanitation Bill</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: The three counties (Elgeyo Marakwet,Kericho and Homabay) drafted County Sanitation Bills in place which need to be enacted.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: Kericho county does not have a County Sanitation Bill in place. However, this is in the pipeline as the county has already developed a draft County Sanitation Bill which is  awaiting approval.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kericho county does not have a County Sanitation Bill in place.However,this is in the pipeline as the county has already developed a draft County Sanitation Bill which is  awaiting approval.iea Will continue engaging the relevant MCAs and county executive members to ensure approval and adoption of the County Sanitation Bill  preferably within 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Kericho county does not have a County Sanitation Bill in place. However,this is in the pipeline as the county has already developed a draft County Sanitation Bill which is  awaiting approval.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will continously track the progress in the development and adoption of the County Sanitation Bills and give input in the various stages of the adoption process. It is expected that the Bills will be enacted in 2018 and that convincing application and enforcement will take time.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Kericho county does not have a County Sanitation Bill in place. However, this is in the pipeline as the county has already developed a draft County Sanitation Bill which is awaiting approval. The bill is at the county assembly stage.  The different ministries have not been able to agree on how this bill relates to other existing and newly expected bills e.g. from the environment and water departments. Bringing the different stakeholders together to resolve this is planned for 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting and implementing County Sanitation Bills in Elgeyo Marakwet</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. No legislative framework in the form of policies, laws, standards, regulations and/or guidelines exists, or existing/new suggested legislative framework is detrimental to issue
1. A new/adjusted legislative framework is considered 
2. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been drafted
3. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR framework detrimental to issue has been prevented
4. New/adjusted legislative framework is applied and/or enforced, but without appropriate means and/or not equally applied (across geographical areas, socio-economic groups, men/women &#x2026;.)
5. New/adjusted legislative framework is effectively and equally applied and/or enforced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">As stated above, Kericho is the only county that did not draft a county sanitation bill yet</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By end of 2017 it is expected thatat least three focus counties will have adopted the County Sanitation Bill</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: The three counties (Elgeyo Marakwet,Kericho and Homabay) drafted County Sanitation Bills in place which need to be enacted.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: Elgeyo Marakwet county does not have a County Sanitation Bill in place. However, this is in the pipeline as the county has already developed a draft County Sanitation Bill which has been tabled in the house .</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elgeyo Marakwet countty does not have a County Sanitation Bill in place.However,this is in the pipeline as the county has already developed a draft County Sanitation Bill which is  awaiting approval.iea Will continue engaging the relevant MCAs and county executive members to ensure approval and adoption of the County Sanitation Bill preferably within 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Elgeyo Marakwet county does not have a County Sanitation Bill in place. However, this is in the pipeline as the county has already developed a draft County Sanitation Bill which has been tabled in the house .</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will continously track the progress in the development and adoption of the County Sanitation Bills and give input in the various stages of the adoption process. It is expected that the Bills will be enacted in 2018 and that convincing application and enforcement will take time.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Elgeyo Marakwet county does not have a County Sanitation Bill in place. However, this is in the pipeline as the county has already developed a draft County Sanitation Bill which is awaiting approval. The bill is at the county assembly stage.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting and implementing County Sanitation Bills in Homabay</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">As stated above, Kericho is the only county that did not draft a county sanitation bill yet</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By end of 2017 it is expected thatat least three focus counties will have adopted the County Sanitation Bill</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: The three counties (Elgeyo Marakwet,Kericho and Homabay) drafted County Sanitation Bills in place which need to be enacted.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: Homa Bay county does not have a County Sanitation Bill in place. However, this is in the pipeline as the county has already developed a draft County Sanitation Bill which is  awaiting approval.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Homabay county does not have a County Sanitation Bill in place.However,this is in the pipeline as the county has already developed a draft County Sanitation Bill which is  awaiting approval.iea Will continue engaging the relevant MCAs and county executive members to ensure approval and adoption of the County Sanitation Bill  preferably within 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Homabay county does not have a County Sanitation Bill in place. However,this is in the pipeline as the county has already developed a draft County Sanitation Bill which is  awaiting approval.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will continously track the progress in the development and adoption of the County Sanitation Bills and give input in the various stages of the adoption process. It is expected that the Bills will be enacted in 2018 and that convincing application and enforcement will take time.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Homabay county does not have a County Sanitation Bill in place. However, this is in the pipeline as the county has already developed a draft County Sanitation Bill which is awaiting approval. The bill needs to be taken to the county assembly stage.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting and implementing County Sanitation Investment Plans (CSIPs) in Elgeyo Marakwet</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. No legislative framework in the form of policies, laws, standards, regulations and/or guidelines exists, or existing/new suggested legislative framework is detrimental to issue
1. A new/adjusted legislative framework is considered 
2. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been drafted
3. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR framework detrimental to issue has been prevented
4. New/adjusted legislative framework is applied and/or enforced, but without appropriate means and/or not equally applied (across geographical areas, socio-economic groups, men/women &#x2026;.)
5. New/adjusted legislative framework is effectively and equally applied and/or enforced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">As stated above, the only county that did not draft a sanitation specific investment plan is Elgeyo Marakwet</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By end of 2017 it is expected that at least three focus counties will have adopted the CSIP.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: By the end of 2017, all the three counties (Homabay, Elgeyo Marakwet and Kericho) counties had their sanitation investment plans in place and implementation is expected to be taking place. However there are concerns that implementation is lagging behind. Increased buy-in from key officers as well as budget allocation are required to change this.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: Elgeyo Marakwet county has their sanitation investment plan developed and adopted by government stakeholders as an advocacy product. The county  governments continue using it to advocate for funding identified. For these advocacy efforts to be efficient increased willingness to invest in sanitation and CLTS needed to be created. IEA continued advocating for increased investment to the sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elgeyo Marakwet county has their sanitation investment plan awaiting implementation.IEA will continue advocating for its adoption and implementation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Elgeyo Marakwet county has their sanitation investment plan developed and adopted by government stakeholders as an advocacy product. The county  governments continue using it to advocate for funding identified. For these advocacy efforts to be efficient increased willingness to invest in sanitation and CLTS needed to be created. IEA continued advocating for increased investment to the sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will advocate for the enforcement of the County Sanitation Investment Plans by emphasising the importance of having the Sanitation Plans in place and budget allocated for the same, during the public forums with various sanitation stakeholders.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Elgeyo Marakwet county has their sanitation investment plan developed and adopted by government stakeholders as an advocacy product. The county has started using it to advocate for funding identified. For these advocacy efforts to be efficient increased willingness to invest in sanitation and CLTS needed to be created. The advocacy products developed through the study into the effects of poor sanitation have contributed to the awareness of the importance of toilets, handwashing etc. as promoted by CLTS.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting and implementing County Sanitation Investment Plans (CSIPs) in Homabay</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">As stated above, the only county that did not draft a sanitation specific investment plan is Elgeyo Marakwet</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By end of 2017 it is expected that at least three focus counties will have adopted the CSIP.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: By the end of 2017, all the three counties (Homabay, Elgeyo Marakwet and Kericho) counties had their sanitation investment plans in place and implementation is expected to be taking place. However there are concerns that implementation is lagging behind. Increased buy-in from key officers as well as budget allocation are required to change this.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: Homa Bay county has its sanitation investment plan finalised. The county has started using it to advocate for funding identified.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Homabay county has their sanitation investment plan awaiting implementation.IEA will continue advocating for its adoption and implementation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Homa Bay county has its sanitation investment plan finalised. The county has started using it to advocate for funding identified.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will advocate for the enforcement of the County Sanitation Investment Plans by emphasising the importance of having the Sanitation Plans in place and budget allocated for the same, during the public forums with various sanitation stakeholders.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Homa Bay county has their sanitation investment plan finalised. The county has started using it to advocate for funding identified.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting and implementing County Sanitation Investment Plans (CSIPs) in Kericho</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">As stated above, the only county that did not draft a sanitation specific investment plan is Elgeyo Marakwet</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By end of 2017 it is expected that at least three focus counties will have adopted the CSIP.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: By the end of 2017, all the three counties (Homabay, Elgeyo Marakwet and Kericho) counties had their sanitation investment plans in place and implementation is expected to be taking place. However there are concerns that implementation is lagging behind. Increased buy-in from key officers as well as budget allocation are required to change this.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: Kericho county has its sanitation investment plan finalised. The county has started using it to advocate for funding identified.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kericho  county has their sanitation investment plan awaiting implementation.IEA will continue advocating for its adoption and implementation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Kericho county has its sanitation investment plan finalised. The county has started using it to advocate for funding identified.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will advocate for the enforcement of the County Sanitation Investment Plans by emphasising the importance of having the Sanitation Plans in place and budget allocated for the same, during the public forums with various sanitation stakeholders.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Kericho county has their sanitation investment plan finalised. The County has started using it to advocate for funding identified.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree to which key sanitation issues are adequately included in the County Investment Development Plans (CIDPs) in Elgeyo Marakwet</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2013-2017 CIDPs mostly include sanitation as one category with water or health e.g. water and sanitation or health and sanitation. Even if specific sanitation issues are identified, detailed and holistic strategies are often not included, interventions are likely to be project based  (see analysis of CIDPs for more county detailed information)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The subsequent CIDPs are expected to include strategies that are more detailed and adequate in addressing the identified sanitation issues</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homabay counties have adopted County Sanitation Investment Plans for the period of 2013-2017. The Sanitation Investment Plans are to guide investment in sanitation and indicate which areas need the most urgent attention in the sanitation sector. IEA did a CIDP analysis which saw that sanitation related issues included were foccused on waste management/dump sites; sewer systems as well as latrine coverage at the household level as well as public toilets. An overage of 3 issues was included in the plans. During the second half of 2017 the counties started preparing the CIDPs for 2018-2022. The budget memos and related round-table meetings and engagements were an input to this. It is expected that in the first quarter of 2018 the new CIDPs will be approved by the respective county assemblies.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: The IEA team analysed the 2019 CIDP and  Annual Development Plan (ADP) for Elgeyo Marakwet county  to show the priority areas for the county government. Under the Health, Water &amp; Sanitation sector, the focus is on Curative and Rehabilitative
Health, Preventive and Promotive health, Environmental Management and Protection, Lands, Physical Planning and Urban Development, Solid Waste Management  and Water and Sanitation Management.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IEA team will continue analysing the new CIDPs and ADPs for Elgeyo Marakwet county  to assess the level of prioritization for Sanitation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: The IEA team analysed the 2019 CIDP and  Annual Development Plan (ADP) for Elgeyo Marakwet county  to show the priority areas for the county government. Under the Health, Water &amp; Sanitation sector, the focus is on Curative and Rehabilitative
Health, Preventive and Promotive health, Environmental Management and Protection, Lands, Physical Planning and Urban Development, Solid Waste Management  and Water and Sanitation Management.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will analyse the 2018-2022 CIDPs and from there monitor and analyse the implementation of the plans in the three counties. It is expected that at least three sanitation issues are reflected and that there is an increase in the depth in which they are described and prioritised.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The IEA team analysed the CIDP for the three counties to see whether implementation took place and analysed the new CIDPs from the three counties to assess the level of prioritization for Sanitation. The analysis of the CIDP is contained in the budget analysis reports to show the number of sanitation programmes the counties are planning to implement for the period 2017-2022. IEA did an analysis of the CIDPs which can be shared for detail on sanitation issues included.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree to which key sanitation strategies adequately included in the County Investment Development Plans (CIDP) in Homabay</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2013-2017 CIDPs mostly include sanitation as one category with water or health e.g. water and sanitation or health and sanitation. Even if specific sanitation issues are identified, detailed and holistic strategies are often not included, interventions are likely to be project based  (see analysis of CIDPs for more county detailed information)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The subsequent CIDPs are expected to include strategies that are more detailed and adequate in addressing the identified sanitation issues</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homabay counties have adopted County Sanitation Investment Plans for the period of 2013-2017. The Sanitation Investment Plans are to guide investment in sanitation and indicate which areas need the most urgent attention in the sanitation sector. IEA did a CIDP analysis which saw that sanitation related issues included were foccused on waste management/dump sites; sewer systems as well as latrine coverage at the household level as well as public toilets. An overage of 3 issues was included in the plans. During the second half of 2017 the counties started preparing the CIDPs for 2018-2022. The budget memos and related round-table meetings and engagements were an input to this. It is expected that in the first quarter of 2018 the new CIDPs will be approved by the respective county assemblies.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homabay counties have adopted County Sanitation Investment Plans for the period of 2013-2017. The Sanitation Investment Plans are to guide investment in sanitation and indicate which areas need the most urgent attention in the sanitation sector. IEA did a CIDP analysis which saw that sanitation related issues included were foccused on waste management/dump sites; sewer systems as well as latrine coverage at the household level as well as public toilets. An overage of 3 issues was included in the plans. During the second half of 2017 the counties started preparing the CIDPs for 2018-2022. The budget memos and related round-table meetings and engagements were an input to this. It is expected that in the first quarter of 2018 the new CIDPs will be approved by the respective county assemblies.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: The IEA team analysed the 2019 Annual Development Plan (ADP) for Homa Bay county to show the priority areas for the county government. The plan envisages improved development and expansion of water supply schemes, rainwater harvesting as well as increased access to sanitation services. Over the medium-term period, prioritized projects included:  renovation and upgrading of health facilities across the county, construction of modern toilets in the facilities, and reduce morbidity associated with poor hygiene and sanitation. Some of the sanitation projects planned include: To promote sanitation in all EYE centres with an estimated budget of 38.9 Million  and Improved water system infrastructure and sanitation in all EYE Centers with an estimated cost of 22.9 Million</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IEA team will continue analysing the new CIDPs for Homabay county  to assess the level of prioritization for Sanitation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: The IEA team analysed the 2019 Annual Development Plan (ADP) for Homabay county to show the priority areas for the county government.The plan envisages improved development and expansion of water supply schemes, rainwater harvesting as well as increased access to sanitation services.Over the medium-term period, prioritized projects included:  renovation and upgrading of health facilities across the county, construction of modern toilets in the facilities, and reduce morbidity associated with poor hygiene and sanitation.Some of the sanitation projects planned include: To promote sanitation in all EYE centres with an estimated budget of 38.9 Million  and Improved water system infrastructure and sanitation in all EYE Centers with an estimated cost of 22.9 Million</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will analyse the 2018-2022 CIDPs and from there monitor and analyse the implementation of the plans in the three counties. It is expected that at least three sanitation issues are reflected and that there is an increase in the depth in which they are described and prioritised.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The IEA team analysed the CIDP for the three counties to see whether implementation took place and analysed the new CIDPs from the three counties to assess the level of prioritization for Sanitation. The analysis of the CIDP is contained in the budget analysis reports to show the number of sanitation programmes the counties are planning to implement  for the period 2017-2022. IEA did an analysis of the CIDPs which can be shared for detail on sanitation issues included.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree to which key sanitation strategies adequately included in the County Investment Development Plans (CIDP) in Kericho</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2013-2017 CIDPs mostly include sanitation as one category with water or health e.g. water and sanitation or health and sanitation. Even if specific sanitation issues are identified, detailed and holistic strategies are often not included, interventions are likely to be project based  (see analysis of CIDPs for more county detailed information)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The subsequent CIDPs are expected to include strategies that are more detailed and adequate in addressing the identified sanitation issues</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homabay counties have adopted County Sanitation Investment Plans for the period of 2013-2017. The Sanitation Investment Plans are to guide investment in sanitation and indicate which areas need the most urgent attention in the sanitation sector. IEA did a CIDP analysis which saw that sanitation related issues included were foccused on waste management/dump sites; sewer systems as well as latrine coverage at the household level as well as public toilets. An overage of 3 issues was included in the plans. During the second half of 2017 the counties started preparing the CIDPs for 2018-2022. The budget memos and related round-table meetings and engagements were an input to this. It is expected that in the first quarter of 2018 the new CIDPs will be approved by the respective county assemblies.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homabay counties have adopted County Sanitation Investment Plans for the period of 2013-2017. The Sanitation Investment Plans are to guide investment in sanitation and indicate which areas need the most urgent attention in the sanitation sector. IEA did a CIDP analysis which saw that sanitation related issues included were foccused on waste management/dump sites; sewer systems as well as latrine coverage at the household level as well as public toilets. An overage of 3 issues was included in the plans. During the second half of 2017 the counties started preparing the CIDPs for 2018-2022. The budget memos and related round-table meetings and engagements were an input to this. It is expected that in the first quarter of 2018 the new CIDPs will be approved by the respective county assemblies.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: The IEA team analysed the 2019 Annual Development Plan (ADP) for Kericho county to show the priority areas for the county government. The plan recognises that Sanitation is a county challenge due to poor waste management. Some of the sanitation projects planned for include: Construction of Sanitation facilities; Drilling a borehole at Tugunon primary -chepsir to provide access to safe drinking water</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IEA team will continue analysing the new CIDPs fo Kericho  county  to assess the level of prioritization for Sanitation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: The IEA team analysed the 2019 Annual Development Plan (ADP) for Kericho county to show the priority areas for the county government.The plan recognises that Sanitation is a county challenge due to poor waste management. Some of the sanitation projects planned for include: Construction of Sanitation facilities; Drilling a borehole at Tugunon primary -chepsir to provide access to safe drinking water,</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will analyse the 2018-2022 CIDPs and from there monitor and analyse the implementation of the plans in the three counties. It is expected that at least three sanitation issues are reflected and that there is an increase in the depth in which they are described and prioritised.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The IEA team analysed the CIDP for the three counties to see whether implementation took place and analysed the new CIDPs from the three counties to assess the level of prioritization for Sanitation. The analysis of the CIDP is contained in the budget analysis reports to show the number of sanitation programmes the counties are planning to implement  for the period 2017-2022. IEA did an analysis of the CIDPs which can be shared for detail on sanitation issues included.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of County Sanitation Investment Plans adopted</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The CSIPs (2016-2020) were drafted in Kericho, Homa Bay and Kilifi but not yet approved by the county assembly. In Elgeyo Marakwet a county health strategic and investment plan was drafted, also awaiting approval</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least three counties are expected to have adopted the CSIP in 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homabay counties have adopted five-year County Sanitation Investment Plans in 2015. The Sanitation Investment Plans are to guide investment in sanitation and indicate which areas need the most urgent attention in the sanitation sector. In 2017 the plans have been reviewed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: All the three counties (Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homa Bay counties) have their sanitation investment plans awaiting implementation for some of the sub-counties. These plans were developed under the SSH4A. Counties do not have a county-wide investment plan yet.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">All the three counties (Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homa Bay counties) have their sanitation investment plans for specific sub-counties of attention awaiting implementation hence once the counties are adopted, implementation is expected to commemce. IEA will continue to create awareness on the importance of adopting and implementing the County Sanitation Investment Plans.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: All the three counties (Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homabay counties) have their sanitation investment plans awaiting implementation for some of the sub-counties. These plans were developed under the SSH4A. Counties do not have a county-wide investment plan yet.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The three counties (Homabay,Elgeyo Marakwet and Kericho) are expected to implement the revised County Sanitation Investment Plans.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: All the three counties (Elgeyo Marakwet, Kericho and Homabay counties) have their sanitation investment plans awaiting implementation for some of the sub-counties. These plans were developed under the SSH4A. Counties do not have a county-wide investment plan yet.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of County Sanitation Bills adopted</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The National government developed a proto-type sanitation bill which was adopted and shared with the counties. Homa Bay, Elgeyo Marakwet and Kilifi counties have developed a draft for the county sanitation bill. The bill has not passed the CIC and/or county assembly. Kericho has not developed a draft bill yet</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Besides the adoption of the national government of the prototype bill, at least two counties are expected to have adopted the sanitation bill</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: The three counties (Elgeyo Marakwet,Kericho and Homabay) do not have County Sanitation Bills/Acts in place. However, this is in the pipeline as the counties have already developed draft County Sanitation Bills which are in various stages awaiting approval. Due to the change in government officers after the 2017 general elections, the enactment process needs to be reactivated.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: Kericho, Homa Bay and Elgeyo Marakwet counties do not have a County Sanitation Bill in place. However, this is in the pipeline as the counties have already developed  draft County Sanitation Bills which are awaiting approval.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kericho, Homa Bay and Elgeyo Marakwet counties do not have a County Sanitation Bill in place. However, this is in the pipeline as the counties have already developed a draft County Sanitation Bill which is awaiting approval. Increase efforts by SSH4A and V4CP will focus on removing identified bottlenecks.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Kericho, Homa Bay and Elgeyo Marakwet counties do not have a County Sanitation Bill in place. However, this is in the pipeline as the counties have already developed  draft County Sanitation Bills which are awaiting approval.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will support the enactment processes of the draft County Sanitation Bills by emphasising the importance of having the Sanitation Bill in place during the public forums with various sanitation stakeholders.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Kericho county, Homabay and Elgeyo Marakwet counties do not have a County Sanitation Bill in place. However, this is in the pipeline as the counties have already developed a draft County Sanitation Bill which is awaiting approval.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased budgetary allocation to sanitation services by counties (including gender responsiveness)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase/decrease (in%) annual country expenditure on sanitation (absolute increase in expenditure)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of absolute increase in expenditure on specific issue</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0%" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Figures for expenditure are often only available a significant amount of time after the financial year has ended. Calculations will be updated as soon as more information becomes available</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0,3%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The estimated targets are based upon pre-liminary analysis of the national and county budgets through documents available to CSO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: 0= -
IEA has held pre-budget hearing meetings advocating for increased investment in sanitation and prepared proposals on allocations towards sanitation for input into the main budget both at the national and county government. However,due to the fact that the national and county budgets do not have budget codes, tracking allocations remains a challenge .IEA however will continue to engage stakeholders on the importance of having sanitation lines and budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. Before a budget code is in place, IEA will make an effort to collect any budget information available at the national and county level. Especially at the county level it is expected that different types and levels of budgets will allow the stakeholders to draw out information on the increase of budget allocation. A percentage increase in allocation, relative annual allocation, expenditure and relative annual expenditure is however a challenge to monitor yearly. It is therefore adviced this will be done over the V4CP Project period instead while for each year a qualitative analysis of budget documents will be shared to make progress on budgetary allocation visible.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: It is expected that the national governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget after advocacy on the need to increase investment to the sanitation sector. There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="n/a">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that the national governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget.There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: It is expected that the national governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget after advocacy on the need to increase investment to the sanitation sector.There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold pre-budget hearing meetings and prepare proposals on allocations towards sanitation for input into the main budget both at the national and county government. This will include proposals for the need for introduction of budget codes for sanitation in order to track allocations towards the sector. Different types of budget documents will be collected and analysed to be able to report on budget allocation trends. This will result in a more qualitative based reporting on increased budget allocation and expenditure which can be used for planning purposes and inform advocacy activities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA held national pre-budget hearings on 14th February 2018 for the corporate sector and 15th February 2018 for the Social sector at the Sarova Stanley Hotel Nairobi. The budget proposal were synthesized and shared with the national treasury for possible consideration in the national budget in the Month of February 2018. 
However,due to the fact that the national and county budgets do not have budget codes,tracking expenditure  remains a challenge.IEA however will continue to write proposals on the importance of having sanitation budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. A draft report has already be done by IEA on the extent to which the national government allocate resources toward sanitaion and the report will be ready in the year 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase/decrease (in%) of relative annual budget allocation for sanitation in county annual budgets (budget for sanitation as percentage of total annual budgets)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage is based on increase of budget for issue X as percentage of total sector budget</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0%" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2015/16. the counties have allocated 0.16%  toward sanitation issues</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0,2%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The estimated targets are based upon pre-liminary analysis of the national and county budgets through documents available to CSO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: 0= -
IEA has held pre-budget hearing meetings advocating for increased investment in sanitation and prepared proposals on allocations towards sanitation for input into the main budget both at the national and county government. However,due to the fact that the national and county budgets do not have budget codes, tracking allocations remains a challenge .IEA however will continue to engage stakeholders on the importance of having sanitation lines and budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. Before a budget code is in place, IEA will make an effort to collect any budget information available at the national and county level. Especially at the county level it is expected that different types and levels of budgets will allow the stakeholders to draw out information on the increase of budget allocation. A percentage increase in allocation, relative annual allocation, expenditure and relative annual expenditure is however a challenge to monitor yearly. It is therefore adviced this will be done over the V4CP Project period instead while for each year a qualitative analysis of budget documents will be shared to make progress on budgetary allocation visible.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: It is expected that the county governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget. There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="n/a">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that the county governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget.There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: It is expected that the county governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget.There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold pre-budget hearing meetings and prepare proposals on allocations towards sanitation for input into the main budget both at the national and county government. This will include proposals for the need for introduction of budget codes for sanitation in order to track allocations towards the sector. Different types of budget documents will be collected and analysed to be able to report on budget allocation trends. This will result in a more qualitative based reporting on increased budget allocation and expenditure which can be used for planning purposes and inform advocacy activities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA held County based pre-budget hearings on 13th to 17th August 2018 for the sub county based CSOs in all the three counties of Homa Bay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet. The budget proposals developed were then synthesized and shared with the County Treasury, County Assembly Health Committee and the department of Health for possible consideration in form of a Citizen&#x2019;s Alternative budget memorandum..However,due to the fact that the national and county budgets do not have budget codes,tracking allocations remains a challenge.IEA however will continue to write proposals on the importance of having sanitation budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. This we are positive will lead to the adoption of sanitation budget codes which will make it easy to isolate the county  sanitation expenditure .</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase/decrease (in%) in relative annual country expenditure on sanitation (expenditure on sanitation as percentage of total annual expenditure)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of increase of expenditure for issue X as percentage of total sector expenditure</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0%" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2015/2016, Kenya is estimated to have spent 0.2% of the total budget on sanitation</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The estimated targets are based upon pre-liminary analysis of the national and county budgets through documents available to CSO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: 0= -
IEA has held pre-budget hearing meetings advocating for increased investment in sanitation and prepared proposals on allocations towards sanitation for input into the main budget both at the national and county government. However,due to the fact that the national and county budgets do not have budget codes, tracking allocations remains a challenge .IEA however will continue to engage stakeholders on the importance of having sanitation lines and budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. Before a budget code is in place, IEA will make an effort to collect any budget information available at the national and county level. Especially at the county level it is expected that different types and levels of budgets will allow the stakeholders to draw out information on the increase of budget allocation. A percentage increase in allocation, relative annual allocation, expenditure and relative annual expenditure is however a challenge to monitor yearly. It is therefore adviced this will be done over the V4CP Project period instead while for each year a qualitative analysis of budget documents will be shared to make progress on budgetary allocation visible.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: It is expected that the national governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget after advocacy on the need to increase investment to the sanitation sector. There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="n/a">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that the national governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget.There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: It is expected that the national governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget after advocacy on the need to increase investment to the sanitation sector.There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold pre-budget hearing meetings and prepare proposals on allocations towards sanitation for input into the main budget both at the national and county government. This will include proposals for the need for introduction of budget codes for sanitation in order to track allocations towards the sector. Different types of budget documents will be collected and analysed to be able to report on budget allocation trends. This will result in a more qualitative based reporting on increased budget allocation and expenditure which can be used for planning purposes and inform advocacy activities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA held national pre-budget hearings on 14th February 2018 for the corporate sector and 15th February 2018 for the Social sector at the Sarova Stanley Hotel Nairobi. The budget proposal were synthesized and shared with the national treasury for possible consideration in the national budget in the Month of February 2018. However,due to the fact that the national and county budgets do not have budget codes,tracking expenditure remains a challenge.IEA however will continue to write proposals on the importance of having sanitation budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget.A draft report has already be done by IEA on the extent to which the national government allocate resources toward sanitaion and the report will be ready in the year 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase/decrease (in%) in relative annual county expenditure on specific issue (expenditure on sanitation as percentage of total annual expenditure)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of increase of expenditure for issue X as percentage of total sector expenditure</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0%" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2015/2016, the counties are expected to have spent 0.17% of the total budget on sanitation</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0,2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The estimated targets are based upon pre-liminary analysis of the national and county budgets through documents available to CSO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: 0= -
IEA has held pre-budget hearing meetings advocating for increased investment in sanitation and prepared proposals on allocations towards sanitation for input into the main budget both at the national and county government. However,due to the fact that the national and county budgets do not have budget codes, tracking allocations remains a challenge .IEA however will continue to engage stakeholders on the importance of having sanitation lines and budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. Before a budget code is in place, IEA will make an effort to collect any budget information available at the national and county level. Especially at the county level it is expected that different types and levels of budgets will allow the stakeholders to draw out information on the increase of budget allocation. A percentage increase in allocation, relative annual allocation, expenditure and relative annual expenditure is however a challenge to monitor yearly. It is therefore adviced this will be done over the V4CP Project period instead while for each year a qualitative analysis of budget documents will be shared to make progress on budgetary allocation visible.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: It is expected that the county governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget after advocacy on the need to increrase investment to the sanitation sector. There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="n/a">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that the county governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget.There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: It is expected that the county governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget after advocacy on the need to increrase investment to the sanitation sector.There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold pre-budget hearing meetings and prepare proposals on allocations towards sanitation for input into the main budget both at the national and county government. This will include proposals for the need for introduction of budget codes for sanitation in order to track allocations towards the sector. Different types of budget documents will be collected and analysed to be able to report on budget allocation trends. This will result in a more qualitative based reporting on increased budget allocation and expenditure which can be used for planning purposes and inform advocacy activities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA held County based pre-budget hearings on 13th to 17th August 2018 for the sub county based CSOs in all the three counties of Homa Bay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet. The budget proposals developed were then synthesized and shared with the County Treasury, County Assembly Health Committee and the department of Health for possible consideration in form of a Citizen&#x2019;s Alternative budget memorandum. However, due to the fact that the national and county budgets do not have budget codes, tracking expenditure remains a challenge. IEA however will continue to write proposals on the importance of having sanitation budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. This we are positive will lead to the adoption of sanitation budget codes which will make it easy to isolate the county  sanitation expenditure.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase/decrease (in%) of relative annual budget allocation for sanitation in country annual budget (budget for sanitation as percentage of total annual budget)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage is based on increase of budget for issue X as percentage of total sector budget</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0%" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2015/2016 national budget allocated 0.2 % of its budget toward sanitation</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The estimated targets are based upon pre-liminary analysis of the national and county budgets through documents available to CSO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: 0= -
IEA has held pre-budget hearing meetings advocating for increased investment in sanitation and prepared proposals on allocations towards sanitation for input into the main budget both at the national and county government. However,due to the fact that the national and county budgets do not have budget codes, tracking allocations remains a challenge .IEA however will continue to engage stakeholders on the importance of having sanitation lines and budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. Before a budget code is in place, IEA will make an effort to collect any budget information available at the national and county level. Especially at the county level it is expected that different types and levels of budgets will allow the stakeholders to draw out information on the increase of budget allocation. A percentage increase in allocation, relative annual allocation, expenditure and relative annual expenditure is however a challenge to monitor yearly. It is therefore adviced this will be done over the V4CP Project period instead while for each year a qualitative analysis of budget documents will be shared to make progress on budgetary allocation visible.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="n/a">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that the national governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget. There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: It is expected that the national governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget after advocacy on the need to increase investment to the sanitation sector.There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold pre-budget hearing meetings and prepare proposals on allocations towards sanitation for input into the main budget both at the national and county government. This will include proposals for the need for introduction of budget codes for sanitation in order to track allocations towards the sector. Different types of budget documents will be collected and analysed to be able to report on budget allocation trends. This will result in a more qualitative based reporting on increased budget allocation and expenditure which can be used for planning purposes and inform advocacy activities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA held national pre-budget hearings on 14th February 2018 for the corporate sector and 15th February 2018 for the Social sector at the Sarova Stanley Hotel Nairobi. The budget proposal were synthesized and shared with the national treasury for possible consideration in the national budget in the Month of February 2018. Some of the issues shared out included;
&#x2013; Low Budget allocation to Water and Sanitation. There is need for adequate budget allocation both in the National and County level. Past allocations have been low compared to other sectors and Sanitation do not have designated budget and if any the allocations are lumped in Health ministry.
&#x2013; Poor implementation of Water and Sanitation as a devolved function of the County Governments is not yet fully operationalized due to the confusion within the National Government institution functions i.e. Role of the Water Service Boards and completes transition from the Boards to Water Works. Limited human resource to implement in relation to workload and coverage.
However, due to the fact that the national and county budgets do not have budget codes, tracking allocations remains a challenge. IEA however will continue to write proposals on the importance of having sanitation budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. This we are positive will lead to the adoption of sanitation budget codes which will make it easy to isolate the extend to which sanitation issues are reflected in the annual county budget.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase/decrease (in%) of annual budget allocation for sanitation in country annual budget</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage is based on absolute increase in budget allocation</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0%" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The African Ministers&#x2019; Council on Water (AMCOW) signed the eThekwini Declaration in 2008, promising to establish specific public sector budget allocations for sanitation and hygiene programmes . The countries pledged to create separate budget lines for sanitation and hygiene and to commit at least 0.5 percent of GDP to sanitation services. Kenya has allocated 0.2 percent of GDP to sanitation as compared to the global target of 0.9 percent and eThekwini Declaration commitment of at least 0.5 percent of GDP (now succeeded by the Ngor Declaration)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1,5%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expected is that the national government will increase budget allocation towards sanitation. A budget code for sanitation would support increased allocation and therefore advocacy activities will be planned around this</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: 0= -
IEA has held pre-budget hearing meetings advocating for increased investment in sanitation and prepared proposals on allocations towards sanitation for input into the main budget both at the national and county government. However,due to the fact that the national and county budgets do not have budget codes, tracking allocations remains a challenge .IEA however will continue to engage stakeholders on the importance of having sanitation lines and budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. Before a budget code is in place, IEA will make an effort to collect any budget information available at the national and county level. Especially at the county level it is expected that different types and levels of budgets will allow the stakeholders to draw out information on the increase of budget allocation. A percentage increase in allocation, relative annual allocation, expenditure and relative annual expenditure is however a challenge to monitor yearly. It is therefore adviced this will be done over the V4CP Project period instead while for each year a qualitative analysis of budget documents will be shared to make progress on budgetary allocation visible.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: It is expected that the national government will increase budget allocation towards sanitation after advocacy on the need to increase investment to the sanitation sector. However, there is still no budget code for sanitation in place. A budget code for sanitation would support deliberate allocation and enable tracking of funds</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="n/a">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that the national government will increase budget allocation towards sanitation. A budget code for sanitation would support increased allocation and therefore advocacy activities will be planned around this</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: It is expected that the national government will increase budget allocation towards sanitation after advocacy on the need to increase investment to the sanitation sector.However,there is still no budget code for sanitation in place. A budget code for sanitation would support deliberate allocation and enable tracking of funds</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold pre-budget hearing meetings and prepare proposals on allocations towards sanitation for input into the main budget both at the national and county government. This will include proposals for the need for introduction of budget codes for sanitation in order to track allocations towards the sector. Different types of budget documents will be collected and analysed to be able to report on budget allocation trends. This will result in a more qualitative based reporting on increased budget allocation and expenditure which can be used for planning purposes and inform advocacy activities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA held annual pre budget forum in the month of February 2018. The budget proposals developed were then synthesized and shared with the County Treasury in form of a Citizen&#x2019;s Alternative budget memorandum. However, due lack of budget codes, tracking allocations remains a challenge. IEA however will continue to write proposals on the importance of having sanitation budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. This will lead to the adoption of sanitation budget codes which will make it easy to isolate the county sanitation expenditure.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase/decrease (in%) of annual budget allocation for sanitation in county annual budgets</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage is based on absolute increase in budget allocation</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0%" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The baseline include available figures for four counties: Kericho, Elgeyo Marakwet, Homa Bay and Kilifi - (see document on national and county allocations and expenditures for more detailed information)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0,06%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expected that the county will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget.There is need to lobby for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: 0= -
IEA has held pre-budget hearing meetings advocating for increased investment in sanitation and prepared proposals on allocations towards sanitation for input into the main budget both at the national and county government. However,due to the fact that the national and county budgets do not have budget codes, tracking allocations remains a challenge .IEA however will continue to engage stakeholders on the importance of having sanitation lines and budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. Before a budget code is in place, IEA will make an effort to collect any budget information available at the national and county level. Especially at the county level it is expected that different types and levels of budgets will allow the stakeholders to draw out information on the increase of budget allocation. A percentage increase in allocation, relative annual allocation, expenditure and relative annual expenditure is however a challenge to monitor yearly. It is therefore adviced this will be done over the V4CP Project period instead while for each year a qualitative analysis of budget documents will be shared to make progress on budgetary allocation visible.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: It is expected that the county governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget after advocacy on the need to increase investment to the sanitation sector.However,there is still no budget code for sanitation in place. There is a committee in place lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: It is expected that the county governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget after advocacy on the need to increase investment to the sanitation sector.However,there is still no budget code for sanitation in place. There is a committee in place lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold pre-budget hearing meetings and prepare proposals on allocations towards sanitation for input into the main budget both at the national and county government. This will include proposals for the need for introduction of budget codes for sanitation in order to track allocations towards the sector. Different types of budget documents will be collected and analysed to be able to report on budget allocation trends. This will result in a more qualitative based reporting on increased budget allocation and expenditure which can be used for planning purposes and inform advocacy activities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA held County based pre-budget hearings on 13th to 17th August 2018 for the sub county based CSOs in all the three counties of Homa Bay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet. The budget proposals developed were then synthesized and shared with the County Treasury, County Assembly Health Committee and the department of Health for possible consideration in the form of a Citizen&#x2019;s Alternative budget memorandum. However, due to the fact that the county budgets do not have budget codes, tracking allocations remains a challenge. IEA however will continue to write proposals on the importance of having sanitation budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. This will lead to the adoption of sanitation budget codes which will make it easy to isolate the county sanitation expenditure. IEA&apos;s county budget analysis report to be published in 2019 will also give more detail on which allocations for sanitation we have been able to isolate for each of the counties. Analysis of the CIDP will also given an indication of increase or decrease of budget for sanitation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase/decrease (in%) annual county expenditure on sanitation (absolute increase in expenditure)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of absolute increase in expenditure on specific issue</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0%" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">When figures for expenditure are released, data will be updated for the different years (where possible starting iwith the first financial year after devolution 2013/2014)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0,2%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The estimated targets are based upon pre-liminary analysis of the national and county budgets through documents available to CSO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: 0= -
IEA has held pre-budget hearing meetings advocating for increased investment in sanitation and prepared proposals on allocations towards sanitation for input into the main budget both at the national and county government. However,due to the fact that the national and county budgets do not have budget codes, tracking allocations remains a challenge .IEA however will continue to engage stakeholders on the importance of having sanitation lines and budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. Before a budget code is in place, IEA will make an effort to collect any budget information available at the national and county level. Especially at the county level it is expected that different types and levels of budgets will allow the stakeholders to draw out information on the increase of budget allocation. A percentage increase in allocation, relative annual allocation, expenditure and relative annual expenditure is however a challenge to monitor yearly. It is therefore adviced this will be done over the V4CP Project period instead while for each year a qualitative analysis of budget documents will be shared to make progress on budgetary allocation visible.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: It is expected that the county governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget. There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="n/a">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that the county governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget.There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: It is expected that the county governments will allocate resources toward sanitation as a share of the county budget.There is a committee in place  lobbying  for sanitation to be given a code which will be essential in resource allocation as well as ease tracking of funds allocated and spent on sanitation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will hold pre-budget hearing meetings and prepare proposals on allocations towards sanitation for input into the main budget both at the national and county government. This will include proposals for the need for introduction of budget codes for sanitation in order to track allocations towards the sector. Different types of budget documents will be collected and analysed to be able to report on budget allocation trends. This will result in a more qualitative based reporting on increased budget allocation and expenditure which can be used for planning purposes and inform advocacy activities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: IEA held County based pre-budget hearings on 13th to 17th August 2018 for the sub county based CSOs in all the three counties of Homa Bay, Kericho and Elgeyo Marakwet. The budget proposals developed were then synthesized and shared with the County Treasury, County Assembly Health Committee and the department of Health for possible consideration in form of a Citizen&#x2019;s Alternative budget memorandum. However, due to the fact that the national and county budgets do not have budget codes, tracking expenditure remains a challenge. IEA however will continue to write proposals on the importance of having sanitation budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. This we are positive will lead to the adoption of sanitation budget codes which will make it easy to isolate the county  sanitation expenditure .IEA will also analyse the allocation on sanitation in the year 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusive planning and budgetary prioritisation in sanitation by National and County Government</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree to which key sanitation issues are reflected in annual country budget</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The annual budget for Kenya includes solid waste management. Other sanitaiton related issues are not clearly indicated</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that only solid waste management will be clearly indicated in the national level budget until such a time that a budget code for sanitation is approved and implemented. This will enable other sanitation issues to reflect within the budget</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: It is expected that only solid waste management will be clearly indicated in the national level budget until such a time that a budget code for sanitation is approved and implemented. IEA however will continue to engage the relevant actors on the importance of having sanitation budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. This is expected to lead to the adoption of sanitation budget codes which will make it easy to isolate the extend to which sanitation issues are reflected in the annual county budget. In 2017 this was mainly done through verbal encounters.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: Solid waste management sector is the only one which  is clearly indicated in the national level budget on sanitation. Health and water sectors do not clearly indicate sanitation allocations and this can only be achieved when a budget code for sanitation is developed. However, discussions on the chart of accounts for the creation of budget codes is ongoing and we expect the Sector to have its budget codes in due course, making it easy to reflect the level of prioritization for sanitation issues.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solid waste management sector is the only one which  is clearly indicated in the national level budget on sanitation.Health and water sectors do not clearly indicate sanitation allocations and this can only be achieved when abudget code for sanitation is developed. IEA however will continue to write proposals on the importance of having sanitation budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. This will lead to the adoption of sanitation budget codes which will make it easy to isolate the extend to which sanitation issues are reflected in the annual country budget. IEA continues to advocate for incresed prioritization of sanitation service delivery through increased budgetary allocations. However,discussions on the chart of accounts for the creation of budget codes is ongoing and we expect the Sector to have its budget codes probably by the end of 2019 making it easy to reflect the level of prioritization for sanitation issues. This is therefore a long-term objective which will start resulting in information beyond 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Solid waste management sector is the only one which  is clearly indicated in the national level budget on sanitation.Health and water sectors do not clearly indicate sanitation allocations and this can only be achieved when abudget code for sanitation is developed. However,discussions on the chart of accounts for the creation of budget codes is ongoing and we expect the Sector to have its budget codes in due course, making it easy to reflect the level of prioritization for sanitation issues.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA  will continue to write and share proposals on the importance of having sanitation budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. Adoption of a budget code is a long process which has now been initiated by the government in the strategic framework. In the meantime IEA will deduct sanitation activities within budget lines as best as possible.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Solid waste management sector is the only one which is clearly indicated in the national level budget on sanitation. Health and water sectors do not clearly indicate sanitation allocations and this can only be achieved when a budget code for sanitation is developed. IEA however will continue to write proposals on the importance of having sanitation budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. This will lead to the adoption of sanitation budget codes which will make it easy to isolate the extend to which sanitation issues are reflected in the annual country budget.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree to which key sanitation issues are reflected in annual county budgets</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The county budgets mainly include all or some of the following sanitation issues: hygiene, CLTS and solid waste management</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that the same issues will reflect in next year&apos;s budget. This year the budget will be drafted early because of the upcoming national elections. Due to the planned interventions, we expect a more significant change during the budget planning the year after</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: With the lack of sanitation budget guides and sanitation specific budget lines in county budgets, tracking sanitation issues in the county budgets is a challenge. IEA however engages the relevant actors on the importance of having sanitation specific activities and where possible budget lines/codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. Access to budget documents has increased. One example is the access to the budget document in Elgeyo Marakwet. The analysis of the CIDPs also emphasised that sanitation issues need a more prominent place in plans and budgets. The budget memo&apos;s advocated for sanitation allocations. In 2018 there will be an increased focus on uncovering saniation related expenses in detailed county budgets as well as a review of both estimates and actuals.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: With the lack of sanitation budget guides, tracking sanitation issues in the county budgets is a challenge.  However, discussions on the chart of accounts for the creation of budget codes is ongoing and we expect the Sector to have its budget codes in due course, making it easy to reflect the level of prioritization for sanitation issues.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the lack of sanitation budget guides, tracking sanitation issues in the county budgets is a challenge. IEA however will continue to write proposals on the importance of having sanitation budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. This will lead to the adoption of sanitation budget codes which will make it easy to isolate the extent to which sanitation issues are reflected in the annual county budget. However, discussions on the chart of accounts for the creation of budget codes is ongoing and we expect the sector to have its budget codes probably by the end of 2019 making it easy to reflect the level of prioritization for sanitation issues. In the meantime we encourage labelling of specific budgets as sanitation specific to be able to follow the trends and allocations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: With the lack of sanitation budget guides, tracking sanitation issues in the county budgets is a challenge.  However,discussions on the chart of accounts for the creation of budget codes is ongoing and we expect the Sector to have its budget codes in due course, making it easy to reflect the level of prioritization for sanitation issues.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IEA will continue to write and share proposals on the importance of having sanitation budget lines/codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. Counties will be encouraged to clearly indicate where expenses relate to sanitation to ease tracking, accountability measures and allocation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: With the lack of sanitation budget guides, tracking sanitation issues in the county budgets is a challenge. IEA however will continue to write proposals on the importance of having sanitation budget codes in order to reflect the sanitation issues in the annual budget. This will lead to the adoption of sanitation budget codes which will make it easy to isolate the extent to which sanitation issues are reflected in the annual county budget. IEA is currently using the available information to attempt to isolate sanitation related budgets based upon the CIDPs and other county specific information.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved sanitation service delivery in counties</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of ODF achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator is measured as part of the SSH4ALL Programme. The score indicates minimal dialogue and a sector that is not structured (see Tool Sustainability Indicator 6 for more detail)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="50" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya initiated the Open Defecation Free (ODF) Rural Kenya Campaign in May 2011, adopting Community Led Sanitation (CLTS) as the core strategy to achieve the objective. This ODF indicator is measured as part of the SSH4ALL Programme.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="70.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: This indicator remains a challenge to measure as the national level data system for the ODF Campaign in Kenya is not populated regularly. Similarly data from the counties is mostly incomplete, outdated and/or not verifiable. We intend to provide a comprehensive update on the data that is available mid 2020. This will also include data for the sub-counties that are part of the SSH4A programme. We also hope to use data from the 2019 census.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="70.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: This indicator remains a challenge to measure as the national level data system for the ODF Campaign in Kenya is not populated regularly. Similarly data from the counties is mostly incomplete, outdated and/or not vertifiable. We intend to provide a comprehensive update on the data that is available mid 2020. This will also include data for the sub-counties that are part of the SSH4A programme. We also hope to use data from the 2019 census.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The V4Ch project in collaboration with the SSH4All project will continue advocating for improved access to sanitation and better sanitation service delivery to ensure all counties attain the ODF Status.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved sector alignment at local level</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">These indicators are measured as part of the SSH4ALL Programme. A template is used to score specific elements under each indicator.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1,1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The score indicates minimal dialogue and a sector that is not structured see Tool Sustainability Indicator 6 for more detail)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: The end-line survey of SSH4A shows an increase in sector alignment at local level. The baseline was 2.2. See report SSH4A for more details.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2.3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IEA will continue advocating for investment in the sanitation sector through increased budgetary allocations and prioritization of sanitation projects.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: The end-line survey of SSH4A shows an increase in sector alignment at local level. The baseline was 2.2. See report SSH4A for more details.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1,5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target was exceeded by 0.1. Analysis done in June 2007 by SSH4A. For 2018 indicators are expected to reach an average of 2 and therefore the target was set to 1.5.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The Elgeyo Marakwet, Homa Bay and Kericho county governments have incorporated sanitation programmes and activities in their CIDPs. However, allocation of funds for implementation of the activities still remains a challenge.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1,3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will also be measured in June 2017 and is expected to have improved slightly. The new government setting might provide new challenges and opportunities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity of local government to steer sanitation demand creation at scale</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">These indicators are measured as part of the SSH4ALL Programme. A template is used to score specific elements under each indicator.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="2,1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">This score indicates that generally there is a plan for demand creation covering entire Sub County/county&#x2013;even if in phases but no adequate resources and systems are in place (see tool Sustainability Indicator 1 for more detail)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2,3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will be measured again in June 2017 by the SSH4ALL Project and by then the score is not expected to have changed much. With the upcoming elections in August, the local government setting might change which can then in turn influence the second half of 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.40">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: The ODF campaign is ongoing in all the three counties (Elgeyo Marakwet, Homa Bay and Kericho) with the aim for all counties to be declared Open Defacation Free. However, more resources need to be set aside for this exercise since it requires continous follow up to avoid those who are ODF from going back to the OD status and reach the entire population. For the campaign to be succesful it is essential for the county governments to steer the demand. Through the SSH4A and V4CP, SNV and IEA build the capacity of the local governments to steer the demand and sanitation processes. This required increased prioritisation, planning, coordinaation and budget allocation towards CLTS and sanitation activities. IEA contributes to this through county forums and sharing evidence based advocacy products.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-10-2020: The end-line survey of SSH4A shows an increase of local government to steer sanitation demand creation at scale. See report SSH4A for details.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2.7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The V4Change project in collaboration with the SSH4A project will continue advocating for improved access to sanitation and better sanitation service delivery to ensure all counties attain the ODF Status. The SSH4A programme will end December 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: The end-line survey of SSH4A shows an increase of local government to steer sanitation demand creation at scale. See report SSH4A for details.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2,5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target was exceeded by 0.1. Analysis done in June 2007 by SSH4A. For 2018 indicators are expected to reach an average of 2 and therefore the target was set to 2.5.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The ODF campaign in (Elgeyo Marakwet, Homa Bay and Kericho) is ongoing in all the three counties with the aim for all counties being declared Open Defacation Free by 2020. IEA continuously advocates for CLTS and the ODF campaign. This year we have seen an increase in capacity of the local government to steer sanitation demand creation through the CLTS programme to which SSH4A contributes.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
