<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41152786-1796-2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41152786" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voice for Change Partnership-Kenya-Renewable energy</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya-Renewable energy</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the &#x2018;Voice for Change Partnership&#x2019; (V4CP) programme, SNV works to strengthen civil society organisations (CSOs) in their role as advocates and lobbyists. We work together with IFPRI and over 50 CSOs to foster collaboration among relevant stakeholders, and influence decision-makers with solid and contextualized evidence to get the interests of communities embedded into government and business policies and practices. For this specific project in Kenya, our advocacy activities focus on Renewable Energy (RE), in particular clean cooking.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim to increase the adoption of clean stoves and fuels in Kenya by addressing the gaps in the legal and policy framework through inclusion of clean cooking in national and county plans and budgets. To mainstream clean cooking in the existing extension network, guidelines on clean cooking promotion will be developed for use by the extension workers while advocating for increased budget allocation for implementation of clean cooking programmes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41152786" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="3995" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>kenya@snv.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ngong Lane, off Ngong Road
P.O. Box 30776, 00100 Nairobi
Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="5"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-1.292066 36.821946</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="23010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">209307</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-01-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">267017</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">267017</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41152786-3552" ref="NL-KVK-41152786" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">209307</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41152786-3552" ref="NL-KVK-41152786" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/3995/Project_3995_current_image_2016-03-07_14.03.27.PNG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41152786-3552" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evidence of impact of traditional cooking and technologies used available</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evidence made available by SNV, IFPRI and/or other research/knowledge institutes</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of policy briefs and/or evidence based knowledge products made available to CSO that are supportive to its advocacy plan</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">No comprehensive policy briefs are available on clean cooking. Further, whilst some knowledge products are available due to efforts by various stakeholders e.g. GACC, SEI, GIZ and Energypedia the aim would be to develop products packaged appropriately with key messages for decision makers, development partners and the general republic in Kenya and also make them readily available online (through one stop shop portals) which is not the case for all of them</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">These are Clean cooking related portals with evidence for advocacy such as Global Alliance of Clean Cookstoves  website and Stockholm Environment Institute</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: Using a consultant supported by local enumerators, GROOTS Kenya conducted a community-led study on the health impacts of traditional and existing clean cooking technologies in the eight sub counties of Kitui County. Prior to the study, a launch had been done which brought together different Government, private sector and the civil society organisation stakeholders. The study relied on qualitative and quantitative data analysis. Detailed desk literature review was undertaken where various reports, policy documents and research papers published by the Government, non-governmental organizations, research institutions and individual researchers were analysed. Literature review provided insights on cooking practices in Kenya and households energy sources. Through a field study, primary data was collected from 455 households, 49 health Centres and facilities and 74 Improved Cooking Stoves traders sampled from the eight sub counties. A key finding of the study was that 80% of the people living in Kitui County use the traditional three - stone cook stoves which is unclean cooking technique. Households that did not use Improved Cook Stoves for everyday cooking manifested above average respiratory ailments with chest tightness and watery eyes being some of the most common symptoms of the ailments. The study report has been validated and is complete. The Organisation has packaged the report in a policy brief that, with the final study report are yet to be printed. The Civil Society Organisation have developed policy briefs on Gender and Institutional Cook stoves. Currently, the briefs are undergoing a quality review and will be uploaded to in the organization&#x2019;s website afterwards. These briefs will be shared with different stakeholders in different forums and platforms.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: The Baseline and Market Impact Assessment for the Design and Implementation of Clean Cooking Standards and Labelling in Kenya is ready and will be validated this year and used for engagements planned by CCAK even beyond the V4CP project. CCAK will engage private sector and business, S&amp;L steering committee (Health, KIRDI, KEBS). The report will form basis for rolling out voluntary labelling of cookstoves and fuels</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCAK will develop evidence materials inform of reports, fact sheets, bulletins and policy briefs from the new studies as well as the studies carried out in 2018.
The briefs and reports are; 
1. Voluntary labelling policy brief
2. Voluntary labelling report 
3. Sector Bulletin brief
4. 2018/2019 County and national Budget tracking policy briefs
As part of the 2019 action plans, 
5.GROOTS Kenya plans undertake a context analysis of Kilifi County and generate a report to inform the next advocacy steps.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: 2 policy briefs made available;
1. GROOTS Kenya  Policy brief titled &quot;Linking Energy, Health and Sustainable Livelihoods: Policy Options for Scaling Up Improved Cooking Solutions in Kitui County of Kenya
2. CCAK Policy brief on biomass cookstoves and fuels use in Kenyan instituions

2 evidence products namely;
1. CCAK study on biomass cookstoves and fuels use in Kenyan instituions
2. GROOTS Kenya Context analysis on the progress towards improved clean cooking energy at household level in Kilifi County</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;&gt;The final report of the study: Community Led Mapping On The Health Impact Of Unclean Cooking Technologies and The Suitable Clean Cooking Technologies In Kitui County is expected in 2018
&gt;A study on Improved Biomass Stoves Regulatory Impact Assessment of Insitutions in Kenya is expected in 2018&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The evidence products by  GROOTS Kenya are as follows; 
1. The report on the Health Impacts of Unclean cooking technologies in Kitui
2. Health impacts of unclean cooking in Kitui inforgraphics
3. Health impacts of unclean cooking in Kitui policy brief. 
4. Kiambu County context analysis report towards clean cooking
5. Kiambu County context analysis Policy Brief
6. Kitui Market study report on clean cooking technologies and fuels
7. Kiambu Market study report on clean cooking technologies and fuels
The reports were presented to county staff in different formats including power point. Lastly the Kitui and Kiambu Market study report on clean cooking on market analysis of entrepreneurship opportunities for women in clean cook stoves and fuels as well as inputs required and possible markets available. The latter will be disseminated in 2019 to catalyse women led cookstoves manufacturing.
CCAK evidence generated were as follows;
1. Instituional biomass cookstoves study report by CCAK
2. Instituional biomass cookstoves policy brief
3. Instituional biomass cookstoves inforgraphics
4. 2017/2018 energy budget tracking brief</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clean Cook stoves Association of Kenya has developed policy briefs on Gender and Institutional Cook stoves. These briefs will be shared at the Council of Governors meeting in October 2017 and at the Clean Cook stoves Association of Kenya stand during the Agricultural Society of Kenya show from 2nd to 6th October 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of portals and websites made accessible for CSOs that generate evidence for advocacy issues</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">No comprehensive portals/websites on clean cooking evidence currently exist for Kenya. Information is available other on websites e.g GACC, Energypedia etc but the aim will be to provide a one stop shop for this information via the CSOs websites.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">These are policy briefs related to clean cooking, Charcoal Policy brief, Kitui County Policy brief on clean cooking, Energy Bill policy and Biomass standards policy brief</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: The Civil Society Organisations are developing web based portals. The portals will be used to discuss and share project related information. The portal, will also discuss the interventions the county champions are taking to address the impacts of unclean cooking practices and the policies which have been developed for advocacy. Additionally, all publications about clean cooking done under this project such as the policy briefs will be uploaded. Below is the link to the portal. Through internet service providers, the portals being developed will include new features among others that will incorporate the clean cooking, security certificate to ensure online users security.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: 2 calls for funding shared; with Energia and Hivos on Gender and clean cooking (https://www.energia.org/hivos-energia-endev-and-mecs-launch-gender-and-energy-innovation-facility/) and one with Education out loud supporting CSOs on advocacy (https://educationoutloud.org/grants/open-now-open-call-concept-notes-component-3)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&gt;Kenya budget calendar, national and county - IBP Kenya
&gt;Website with information on indoor air pollution e.g. Cleaner burning charcoal as a transition step to save lives and climate  
Africa shifting to cleaner charcoal cooking</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: 2 Portals made availble; ACCESS Coalition Website (https://access-coalition.org/). Documents CSOs collective advocacy work on SDG 7 (electriciation and clean cooking) and World Resources Institute (https://www.wri.org/our-work/project/energy-access-explorer) Energy Access Tool for use by CSOs to inform energy planning.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clean Cookstoves Association of Kenya has contracted an internet service provider to redesign its website to include new features that will incorporate the clean cooking portal (www.kenyacookstoves.org). Member profiles will be updated onto the site to showcase the diverse technologies available in Kenya</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-11-2018: &gt; http://www.oagkenya.go.ke/This is the Auditor general&apos;s website. The site publishes audit reports of National and County government expenditure which is useful information for CSOs in advocacy on budget allocation and expenditure
&gt;http://cleancookstoves.org/ - very useful for CSO advocacy. The site contains updated resource material (research reports, market assessments, customer segmentation and adoption studies, issue briefs, and fact sheets) &#x2013; on various aspects of the clean cooking sector globally, including Kenya</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV will share websites that provide information on clean cooking technologies and case studies on clean cooking regulations</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Kenya Climate Innovation Center Sector mapping and market assessment on the ICS sector in Kenya (https://www.kenyacic.org/sites/default/files/publications/KCIC%20ICS-3.pdf)
Stockholm Environment Institute (SEI) ISO Cookstove Standards: FAQ and Stakeholder Guidance (https://www.cleancookingalliance.org/binary-data/RESOURCE/file/000/000/556-1.pdf)
SEI report on Research on Charcoal and ICS gender perspectives</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Testing protocols &amp; standards developed by Kenya Bureau of Standards</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting, implementing new/adjusted fuel standards</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="2" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCAK was represented in important committes for labelling in 2017and progress can be reported for; 1. biomass stove standard which was adjusted for emissions and published now awaits adoption after consolidation of inputs from public hearings 2. Ethanol stove standard where draft is ready 3. Ethanol handling standard and ethanol fuel standards which are in first drafting stage . 2 fuel standards were developed during 2017</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: Development ongoing for charcoal and carbonised briquettes standards with likely finalisation in September.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Standards on briquettes and pellets will be completed and disseminated (Sub Committee constituted by CCAK to adopt South African standards and update to capture Kenya needs) as well as the standards on denatured technical ethanol fuel.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Standards for charcoal and carbonised briquettes -2 
Standards for charcoal and carbonised briquettes are currently  under development, only pending data on sieve test analysis and drop resistance that will support in setting the Kenya sector parameters. This process is envisioned for accomplishment in 2020. 

Additionally (not included in the score but being monitored by CCAK)are: Standards for ethanol fuelled appliances and technical denatured alcohol - 4
Standards for ethanol fuelled appliances and technical denatured alcohol had been approved in 2018 and beginnning of Q1 of year 2019 respectively.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specifically following on the biomass standard, CCAK will continue to advocate its adoption</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: No new standards adopted on fuels in 2018, however draft denatured ethanol standards were developed to be adopted in 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specifically following on the biomass standard, CCAK will continue to advocate its adoption</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: No new standards adopted on fuels in 2018, however draft denatured ethanol standards were developed to be adopted in 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting, implementing new/adjusted cookstove standards</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. No legislative framework in the form of policies, laws, standards, regulations and/or guidelines exists, or existing/new suggested legislative framework is detrimental to issue
1. A new/adjusted legislative framework is considered 
2. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been drafted
3. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR framework detrimental to issue has been prevented
4. New/adjusted legislative framework is applied and/or enforced, but without appropriate means and/or not equally applied (across geographical areas, socio-economic groups, men/women &#x2026;.)
5. New/adjusted legislative framework is effectively and equally applied and/or enforced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO has engaged KEBS to understand standards and testing protocols development processes but has not been actively involved in the process of adjusting and developing them.  CSO will participate in ISO processes to facilitate this</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A biomass stove standard developed for consideration</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: CCAK was represented in important committes for labelling in 2017and progress can be reported for; 1. biomass stove standard which was adjusted for emissions and published now awaits adoption after consolidation of inputs from public hearings 2. Ethanol stove standard where draft is ready 3. Ethanol handling standard and ethanol fuel standards which are in first drafting stage. 2 Cook stove standards were developed during 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: KEBS called on CCAK members to review the Biomass cookstove standard and later opened for public review. The standard has not yet been published by KEBS. However good to note that CCAK lobbied for this Kenyan standard that is now only pending gazetting</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Biomass cookstoves standards approved in 2018 will be reviewed in 2019 following recommendations by the sector. This will allow for review of various technical issues raised by the members that would stifle the growth of the sector. Highlight of the issues included; efficiency performance should be defined in terms of tiers, in addition to the percentages,  review of emissions i.e. -Most technologies could not meet PM 2.5 (5mg/MJ) and CO emissions (18.3g/MJ) and on ceramic lining, new innovative technologies not incorporated for lining in the clause needed to be captured</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Biomass cookstoves standards were reviewed and approved in July 2019 and are in force following sector deliberations and justification for PM2.5 and CO emission parameters. CCAK provided key sector input and participation. The standards have so far been diseminated to the sector members and enforced by KEBS.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specifically following on the biomass standard, CCAK will continue to advocate its adoption</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="9.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Biomass cookstoves standards and ethanol fueled appliances approved and implemented in June 2018. | 30-04-2019: Biomass cookstoves standards and ethanol fueled appliances approved and implemented in June 2018. | 30-04-2019: Biomass cookstoves standards and ethanol fueled appliances approved and implemented in June 2018.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting, implementing adjusted  clean cookstoves testing protocols</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. No legislative framework in the form of policies, laws, standards, regulations and/or guidelines exists, or existing/new suggested legislative framework is detrimental to issue
1. A new/adjusted legislative framework is considered 
2. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been drafted
3. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR framework detrimental to issue has been prevented
4. New/adjusted legislative framework is applied and/or enforced, but without appropriate means and/or not equally applied (across geographical areas, socio-economic groups, men/women &#x2026;.)
5. New/adjusted legislative framework is effectively and equally applied and/or enforced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO has engaged Kenya Bureau of Standards to understand standards and testing protocols development processes but has not been actively involved in the process of adjusting and developing them.  CSO will participate in Kenya Bureau of Standards Technical Committees to facilitate this</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target is to reach the drafting stage for the harmonised protocol</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: &quot;CSO has fastracked through convening stakeholder meetings towards drafting and customizing testing protocols and standards for biomass cookstovesd and ethanol handling. CSO is waiting for ISO process from which it will particpate  and collaborate with kenya Bureau of standard (KEBS)  in customizing a Kenya testing protocol for clean cook stoves.  Currently,the methodologies used are on the Gllobal Alliance for Clean Cookstoves  website and they are WBT 4.2.3 and  WBT 4.2.2 (Charcoal Test protocol).
&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: KIRDI only one that has capacity to implement the Laboratory Test Protocols ISO 19867-1:2018 in Kenya (now KS ISO 19867-1:2018). It is voluntary but recommended by KIRDI. There are few cookstoves tested with this protocol (according to a consultant, cost of compliance  may be determining factor) but there is not enough data from KIRDI.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs will particpate in the KEBS technical  committee to customize ISO international standard for laboratory testing of cookstoves. CCAK will loby for harmonisation and domestication of lab testing protocol including the Water boiling test , Biomass Stove Safety Protocol, Controlled Cooking Test, Durability Test, and Kitchen Performance Test which were published in 2018 by the TC 285.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: In July 2019, KIRDI adopted the ISO KS ISO 19867-1:2018 lab protocols which are currenty in use 
CCAK was instrumental in development and adoption of  KS ISO 19867-1:2018 for biomass cookstoves whose standard was approved and adopted in July 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs hope that ISO guidelines will be ready for customizing in 2018</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: ISO published the first international standard for laboratory testing of cookstoves. This was developed and approved by international experts from 45 countries, the new standard includes protocols to test and report the emissions, efficiency, safety and durability of cookstoves in a lab setting. Link: - http://cleancookstoves.org/about/news/06-21-2 018-first-ever-international-standard-for-laboratory-testing-of-cookstoves-published.html and this https://www.iso.org/standard/66519.html. The harmonised testing protocol has been received and disseminated through a training of KIRDI staff and CCAK members by KENAS through CCAK facilitation. The training is a process towards the accreditation of the KIRDI testing centre. Kenyan testing centres eventually will have to comply with the newly harmonised ISO testing protocols, this will level the standards of the cookstoves in the Kenyan market.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved collaboration between CSOs, government &amp; the private sector</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">degree of collaboration between CSOs, government and businesses</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. no or only occasional formal or informal encounters between CSOs, government and private sector take place that are related to the issue
1. regular meetings and communications take place between CSOs, government and/or the private sector which are related to the issue
2. relevant theme related information / data are sought, shared and discussed among CSOs, government and/or the private sector.
3. plans that include CSOs interests are (jointly) made by CSOs, government and/or the private sector.
4. follow up actions are taken that includes CSOs interests</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs meet private sector, CSOs and governments in various meetings  but have had limited requests for input/data or joint development of plans/projects with the exception of the SE4All Action Agenda editing to include clean cooking and KEPSA/MoEP bioenergy strategy development to promote clean cooking</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Continue collaborating with Ministry of Environment, Ministry of Planning and Ministry of health in Kitui.  Strenghten the  partnership with KMA to help in join  training and facilitation of county officials on how to develop energy policies in 2018.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2018: CSOs collaboration with various stakeholders is promising being 3 and 2 for national and county respectively Government but fairly weak with private sector, 1

County level:
&gt;GROOTS Kenya is frequently invited to meetings by County Governments to contribute to designing of their Energy plans.  
&gt;CCAK has engaged the chair of the First Ladies Association to champion the clean cooking agenda at County level. 
National level:
&gt;National Environmental Trust Fund (NETFUND) invites GROOTS Kenya as a key stakeholder to push clean cooking agenda at national level. 
&gt;CCAK has continued to collaborate with several Government agencies. CCAK is collaborating with the Energy Regulatory Commission and Ministry of Health in undertaking studies that will provide recommendations for policy development and implementation of clean cooking. The biomass regulatory impact assessment study in particular will lead to the validation and release of the Biomass Regulations of 2013 while giving insight into institutional cooking solutions important for planning. Cooking is a key element in the new Energy Policy, the Government has involved CCAK in development of plans and policies regarding bioenergy. CCAK participated in the Parliamentary Energy Committee retreat by KEPSA between 5th and 7th April 2018 which saw discussion on  inputs to the Energy Bill  fast-tracked by the parliamentary committee  towards assent of the Bill by the president.  
&gt;CCAK also engaged the Principal Secretary for Gender who indicated her interest in seeing more incentives for production of ICS among women and a study to establish economic cost of use of non ICS for cooking among women.  
Private sector:
&gt;There is partnership with members from private sector (stove manufacturers) in developing a voluntary labelling framework in line with approved standards.
&gt;CSOs participated in a meeting organized by GIZ and KAM to learn how to apply the framework to develop county energy plan.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&gt;GROOTS Kenya looks forward to an effective collaboration with the three targeted counties especially in the implementation of the planned actions as initiated by GROOTS; development of kitui master plan. Development of the Kiambu energy policy
&gt;GROOTS will also collaborate with Kitui county in the efforts to engage private sector in supplying clean cook stoves.
&gt; CCAK will advocate for clean cooking in institutions and lobbying for the full implementation of the Draft Improved Biomass Cookstoves regulations 2013</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: County level average- 3
At county level, GROOTS Kenya has continued to collaborate with CSOs like CAFOD in various activities  with positive results: 
&gt;Kiambu - 3 
The county has shown interest household clean cooking energy. 
GROOTS Kenya is collaborating with  County Government of Kiambu in  development of the climate change and energy policy; working together with the county, a consultant has been identified and recruited for the exercise. A technical committee to develop the policy (comprises directors from 12 departments in the county, Kenya Forest service, CSOs e.g. PACJA, GROOTS and clean cooking champions) has been set up in the county.  
&gt;Kitui- 3
GROOTS Kenya is collaborating with  County Government of Kitui to develop  master plan for energy.  Technical committee to formulate the policy has been set up (comprises all county departments, artisans, energy centre, CAFOD, GROOTS, community based organisations and clean cooking champions)  
 &gt;Kilifi - 3
GROOTS Kenya is working together with Kilifi county and has developed TOR for a context analysis on clean cooking. The county has been very receptive to  having the study conducted and there has been co-sharing for expenses in preparatory meetings related to the study  

National Government - 3
&gt;CCAK has this year so far entered into an MoU with KEFRI and Fine Aromas to jointly develop the standards for charcoal and carbonised briquettes standards. 
&gt;CCAK has participated in the consultative meeting to develop the Gender in Energy Policy with Ministry of Energy and other stakeholders
&gt;CCAK through the technical working group on Climate, Energy and Health working group is on course with the development of the Curriculum, Manual and Job aids with Ministry of Health.
&gt;CCAK has partnered with KEBS and KIRDI to finalise the development of Biomass Cookstoves standards. 
Private Sector
&gt;CCAK has continued to attract more private sector stoves and fuels manufacturers engaging them in the sector issues  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">As stated, the collaboration has not been structured but rather adhoc, going forward, it is envisaged that this will be more structured with joint planning and review sessions</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018:  GROOTS Kenya visited financial institutions and retail traders who are the main distributers of cook stoves. The agenda was to understand what technologies are available in the county.  There are several stoves in the micro finance institutions like Jiko koa that are sold on credit. Most of the retailers have the metallic, ceramic and Liquid Petroleum Gas. There are four companies that have also reached out to GROOTS Kenya to help in increasing awareness of their products through the champions. For example a demonstration session was held by BIOLITE Company for GROOTS Kenya staff and later with the champions. Clean Cook stoves Association of Kenya has had regular meetings with National Environment Management Authority, Ministry of Energy and Petroleum and regarding clean cooking. However, Clean Cook stoves Association of Kenya is yet to fully get incorporated in plans by these government agencies. The most successful engagement has been with Energy Regulatory Commission, which has resulted in the advertisement for a consultant to be recruited for to conduct the regulatory impact study. Additionally, Clean Cook stoves Association of Kenya received feedback from the Commissioner of Domestic Taxes at Kenya Revenue Authority clarifying the implication of the Value Added Tax Exemption on clean cook stoves.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.70">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: County (Kitui- 3; Kilifi - 4; Kiambu -4); National - 4 
County:
&gt; In Kitui county, progress on Kitui Energy master plan was delayed to accommodate partner interests. However, engagement with GROOTS clean community champions remains good. They participated in annual development plan meetings in the county and continue to influence allocation for clean cooking 
&gt;GROOTS was unable to hold multistakeholder meetings in Kilifi due to COVID-19 restrictions but collaboration remains good from the joint action with the county Government in development of draft Kilifi energy policy
&gt;Collaboration in Kiambu is high with a large multistakeholder meeting in August towards review of the county climate change policy  

National:
&gt;There is increased commitment from EPRA team based their promise to include impact assessment in FY 2021/22 following the study on institutional cookstoves presented by CCAK
&gt;There has been good reception from public and sector members both from  carbonised briqquette and non-carbonised briquette sector for standards on charcoal and carbonised briquettes. Members participated in KEBS technical committee meeting. Indications are good that the standard will be approved this September.
&gt;A consultant for the study on the Market and Impact assessment for Voluntary standards and labeling contracted by SNV has had interviews with government  and private sector. A focus group discussion with private sector on this engagement will be held this September. Related to this, a pilot on the biomass cookstoves voluntary labelling was undertaken by clean cooking alliance and the technical report for the pre-test is awaiting approval. A communication consultant is developing IEC material and visual label in collaboration with private sector, KEBS, KIPRA and EPRA.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clean Cookstoves Association of Kenya will continue to convene regular meetings with National Environment Management Authority Ministry of Energy and Petroleum, and Energy Regulatory Commission regarding clean cooking.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-11-2018: GROOTS Kenya has continually  had  interraction with  the Ministry of Environment,  Ministry of Planning and Ministry of Health in Kitui County and preliminary engagements with the Kenya Association of Manufacturers(KAM) . In Kitui, GROOTS kenya had its interests in clean cooking cooking  included in the Environment sector planning. Further commitment  by the Minister was  shown by  extending an invitation to brief the Kitui Governer on the clean cooking project. Interest in the clean cooking project has been contributed by the alarming deforestation experienced in Kitui for charcoal production. The sector committed to incorporate clean cooking in the CIDP and allocate a budget.                                                                                           
CCAK  has also been collaborating with government minisries ( Health and Energy ) and Energy Regulatory commission to undertake studies that will provide recommendations for policy development and  implementation on clean cooking</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">County 

GROOTS Kenya will continue to work with the existing CSOs in Kitui and Kiambu counties. In addition, GROOTS  looks forward to establishing a network of CSOs in Kilifi county.

&#x200B;

National

&gt;CCAK will advocate for clean cooking in institutions and lobbying for the full implementation of the Draft Improved Biomass Cookstoves regulations 2013.

&gt;CCAK will ensure the standards for charcoal and carbonised briquettes developed and approved as per the MoU signed with KEFRI and Fine Aromas.

&gt;Together with the Clean Cooking Alliance, SNV and the Private sector members, CCAK will oversee the development and piloting of the voluntary standards and labelling for the biomass cookstoves. This will be an aspirational and voluntary label which shall use the KEBS standards as the bare minimum for setting the tier voluntary labelling for biomass cookstoves products in Kenya.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.35">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: National -3 
1. The review of the Draft Improved Biomass Cookstoves regulations 2013 received a positive boost as during the IMC CCAK together with stakeholders engaged EPRA  urging them to fastrack the process. CCAK had as well submitted a letter requesting EPRA to conduct the regulatory impact assessment with the findings of the study report on Institutional Cookstoves and Fuels Use in Kenya 2018. 

2. CCAK convened a sector working group and a KEBS TC meeting aimed at fast tracking the development of charcoal  and carbonised briquettes standards in line with the MoU signed with KEFRI and Fine Aromas with delays for standards public review stage occassioned by lack of adequate test data with which to set the parameters.

3. CCAK continues to collaborate with the private sector and partners and the commencement of the  Voluntary Standards and Labeling development process for biomass cookstoves is one such area. An advert for Market and Impact assessment study on voluntary labelling was placed in December 2019.

County average for GROOTS - 3.7
Kiambu-4
&gt;GROOTS Kenya worked with CSOs, community champions and the Kiambu county government to produce the Climate change draft policy. GROOTS Kenya engaged the Department of Water Environment,Energy &amp; Natural Resources during the drafting of the Kiambu climate change Policy. Clean cooking is entreched in the climate change policy as a mitigation action as a result of the champions engagement further, the policy was validated in December 2019  following  close follow up by GROOTS champions; the steering committee has received inputs before handing  over to the Minister in 2020 for tabling in the assembly.
Kitui-3
&gt;GROOTS Kenya staff &amp; champions continued to participate in the development of the Kitui energy master plan                                                     
Kilifi-4
&gt;GROOTS  Kenya in partnership with the county govenment of Kilifi mapped and engaged stakeholders  during the validation of Contex ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&gt;Collaborations established will continue in the next half of the year. For instance, Kitui county has called for a meeting of stakeholders (Ministry of Environment, Kenya Forest Service, KEFRI, GIZ, SNV, HIVOS, Practical Action, Office of the Govenor in Kiambu, Local community stove builders, CBOs engaged in promotion of clean cooking) to contribute to the development of the Kitui Energy framework. GROOTS Kenya will support in facilitating the meeting. 
Engagement with Kiambu can evolve into level 3 collaboration this year, but with Nairobi engagements are still more exploratory. 
&gt;CCAK seeks to further engage the Ministries in accomplishing the regulatory impact assessement. CCAK as well targets to finalize guidelines on health workers with the Ministry of Health.  
&gt;CCAK will engage the County First Ladies&apos; association into championing mainstreaming clean cooking agenda into their strategic plan agenda, a concept note for this engagement is ready. Engagement with County Governments during the devolution conference in April 2018 requires follow up to sensitize county officials on clean cooking, planning for clean cooking and to assist counties in preparing renewable energy policies among other areas, CCAK and GROOTS will follow on this.
&gt;GROOTS will work with KAM in developing County Energy plan for Kitui County</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The level of collaboration is as follows: national government 3; county government 3; businesses 3
&gt;CCAK in liaison with the government state agencies (Energy Regulatory Commission) and government ministries ( Ministry of Energy) and SNV, commissioned a national survey titled &quot;Study on the biomass cookstoves and fuel use in Kenyan institutions&quot;. The study was finalised and validated on 14th September, 2018, the report findings will be used to advocate for clean cooking in institutions and lobbying for the full implementation of the Draft Improved Biomass Cookstoves regulations 2013.
&gt;CCAK managed a first introductory meeting with the County First Ladies Association (CFLA) on 12th October, 2018. The meeting sought partnership opportunities in promoting the uptake of improved cooking solutions in the counties and also to fast track the interest of clean cooking sector in Kenya. 
&gt;CCAK collaborated with NETFUND to improve the advocacy agenda to the council of governors, this was achieved through organizing the annual clean cooking forum where the county representatives were able to be trained on various renewable energy issues as well as clean cooking agenda.
&gt;Collaboration between Kitui county and Kiambu county with GROOTS Kenya has strengthened. In both counties, they agreed to co-finance some of the stakeholders meetings together with GROOTS Kenya. They both agreed to use the lists of champions developed by GROOTS Kenya and selected some of them as part of technical committees. 
&gt;CCAK and GROOTS Kenya followed up with KAM on collaboration on clean cooking. Both CSOs attended the KAM RE conference in April 2019 where in partnership with the Clean Cooking Alliance; there was discussions on Energy efficiency - focus on clean cooking with discussions on how to catalyse private sector investments in clean cooking and adoption</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved service provision in clean cooking by governments and private sector</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase in number of manufacturers producing quality stoves (ISO-IWA Tier 2 and above)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">From the EnDev RBF project for higher tier stoves, few products are truly clean in the Kenyan market in terms of emmisions - these are basically LPG and ethanol stoves.  CSOs envisage that by working with KEBS to develop standards including emissions and engaging private sector on the importance of adhering to  standards and testing their products to prove their performance, there will be an increase in quality products offered by private sector. The testing of 13 stoves under the RBF project revealed that out of the 13, only one achieved performance of of Tier 2 in IWA parameters</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 3 manufactuers produce stoves that meet IWA Tier 2 and upwards</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: 0= TBD
SNV to check reporting on this indicator from RBF project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: One entrant in the market, Lean energy ltd solutions producing improved cookstoves. Stoves not yet launched in the market, however the stove is at testing stage.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCAK will be sharing the tool to collect data in increase in stoves manufactured in 2019 by June with no baseline data. Will rely also on data from the RBF cookstoves programme.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Number of manufaturers producing ISO-IWA tier 2 and above (efficiency) increased from 11 in 2018 to 14 in 2019. New stoves manufactured are; 
1. Biolite Ecozoom Stove (T3 eff)-Charcoal Stove
2. Koko Networks- Ethanol Stove T3-eff
3. Burn-Jikokoa Extra T2 Eff 

In November, 2019 , the Kenya Household Cooking Sector Study was launched and will be one of the pieces of evidence for a baseline. 
In July, 2019, new mandatory cookstoves standards were adopted and their roll out is ongoing with current efforts focused on capacity building and awareness creation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV to check reporting on this indicator from RBF project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: RBF data will be captured in 2019, in 2018 this was not done due to instituional memory loss following exit of the sector leader at SNV who was tracking the data. However the new advisor and energy colleagues will collate the data for reporting in the future. RVO sector study will provide the data in 2019. CCAK will also be working in coalition with Clean Cooking Alliance to track this.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage increase in sales of quality stoves (ISO-IWA Tier 2 and above)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is related to the above remark.  Annually there are many stoves sold, howeverat this poinit there is no data on the percentateg sale of stoves of ISO-IWA Tier 2 and above</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Depending on the production of Tier 2 and above stoves, it is expected that the percentatge sales of these stoves will be 5%</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: 0= TBD
SNV to check reporting on this indicator from RBF project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: In 2020, sales of quality stoves (ISO-IWA Tier 2 and above Efficiency) increses by 84%* (115,000 stoves sold in 2020 compared to 62442 stoves sold in 2019)  *Data as at October 7th 2020, hence cannot be interpretted as annual (source SNV-RBF cookstoves programme.) 

In July, 2019, new mandatory cookstoves standards were adopted and their roll out is ongoing with current efforts focused on capacity building and awareness creation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">New data will be collected and percentage increase estimated following data collected by CCAK and RBF project.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="16.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: In 2019, sales of quality stoves (ISO-IWA Tier 2 and above Efficiency) increased  (53638 stoves sold in 2018  compared to 62442 stoves sold in 2019)  

In July, 2019, new mandatory cookstoves standards were adopted and their roll out is ongoing with current efforts focussed on capacity building and awareness creation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV to check reporting on this indicator from RBF project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: RBF data will be captured in 2019, in 2018 this was not done due to institutional memory loss following exit of the sector leader at SNV who was tracking the data. However the new advisor and energy colleagues will collate the data for reporting in the future. Sector data on percentage increase not available, however the 2019 census through Kenya National Bureau of Statistics (KNBS) will provide data after the census</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementation of Clean cooking programs and projects implemented at county and national levels</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase in number of projects  in clean cooking at county level</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Kitui county, there is some collaboration with Caritas to promote rocket stoves.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least an additional project  supporting clean cooking in the county of Kitui</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: In October and November 2017, Clean Cooking Champions were supported with special tree seedlings for planting. They planted in their homes and public institutions. CSOs has little influence in the design of this program but in its implementation GROOTS Kenya lobbied for it community champion in clean cooking to be among the beneficiaries.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: CCAK and HIVOS project in Kwale County | 21-10-2020: CCAK and HIVOS project in Kwale County</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">KOSAP project targeting lastmile counties in Kenya-component on clean cooking; catalyse private sector investments in clean cooking</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: 1. Improved cookstoves for schools  in Kiuti e.g. clean cookstove constructed in Kamanyi Primary school in Kawongo location, Kitui rural, Kitui County. 
2. Establishment of wood fuel woodlots across the county
3. KOSAP project targeting lastmile counties in Kenya-component on clean cooking; catalyse private sector investments in clean cooking</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The County has committed to allocate budget for clean cooking in 2018 from which GROOTS Kenya intends to push for development of 2 key concrete projects in clean cooking.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: In December 2018, Kitui emerged the best county countrywide in allocating budgets  and implementing projects on Renewable energy including clean cooking. Kitui County commissioned at least  three projects on training artisans and  building stoves for vulnerable houses. The county is now developing  the county energy plan.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase in number of projects  in clean cooking at  national level</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The current known national projects on clean cooking include biogas, Ministry of energy centres promoting improved cookstoves and charcoal kilns development and Prisons biogas project.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The current known national projects on clean cooking include biogas, Ministry of energy centres promoting improved cookstoves and charcoal kilns development and Prisons biogas project.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: The Government of Kenya working with the Ministry of Energy and Petroleum through National Oil Corporation is rolling out a National LPG enhancement project dubbed Mwananchi Gas Project.   Under this project, 6Kg complete cylinders (gas, burner &amp; grill), trading under the brand name &#x201C;Gas Yetu&#x201D;, is being distributed at a discounted price of Kshs 2000 to households which would otherwise not afford. The objectives of this project will ensure LPG penetration from approximately 10% currently to 70% within the next 3 years, reduction of respiratory diseases and mortality rates associated with household air pollution as a result of sustained use of firewood, Kerosene and charcoal, reduction in deforestation as beneficiaries move away from the use of biomass (charcoal &amp; firewood).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: 1. Endev III project - begun proper in 2020 
2. GCF Clean cookstoves project in Kenya and Senegal - ongoing. CCAK and GIZ
3. AFDB &amp; Clean Cooking Alliance cookstoves project with CCAK - Ongoing . pilot for voluntary labeling is ending Sept</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCAK intends to be involved in the GCF cookstoves project in Kenya and Senegal. The project has 3 components. The Kenya ones being (1) ICS market knowledge sharing and replication platform created and (2) Accelerating market development for climate-friendly cooking in Kenya.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: 1.CCAK is among the implementing partners in the GCF cookstoves project in Kenya, with a major role in the enabling environment component.
2. CCAK is also an implementor of ENDEV-3</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government proposing national biogas program for schools</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: 1. Kenya off-grid Solar Access Project (KOSAP) now with a component on clean cooking at national level on capacity building.  CCAK intends to be involved in its implementation. 
2. CCAK engaged with Kenya Forestry Research Institute (KEFRI) on the briquettes and pellets sector development, knowledge linkages on fuel production (calorific value, tree maturity etc). 
3. GCF funded GIZ project on clean cookstoves in Kenya and Senegal. The proposal was presented to the National Treasury-Kenya&apos;s National Designated Agency and letter of no objection issued. Project approved by GCF in 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased inclusion of clean cooking in policies, regulations and frameworks adopted and implemented, or detrimental policies are prevented at National and County Government</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in adopting, implementing Kitui Charcoal Act</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. No legislative framework in the form of policies, laws, standards, regulations and/or guidelines exists, or existing/new suggested legislative framework is detrimental to issue
1. A new/adjusted legislative framework is considered 
2. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been drafted
3. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR framework detrimental to issue has been prevented
4. New/adjusted legislative framework is applied and/or enforced, but without appropriate means and/or not equally applied (across geographical areas, socio-economic groups, men/women &#x2026;.)
5. New/adjusted legislative framework is effectively and equally applied and/or enforced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Act exists however, there isnt inclusion of clean coooking, the conversation is yet start with relevant stakeholders</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Willingness by the county to review the Act and actions towards this</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: The acts exist but ther isnt inclusion of clean cooking. There were attempts to start the discussion but are yet to advance as the issues of charcoal have taken a political dimension in Kitui  limiting the advancement of the discussion of clean cooking as an alternative.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: Led by CAFOD, a consultant has been contracted to consolidate feedback from the EDM&apos;s towards the draft Energy master plan.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="n/a">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not relevant to follow Kitui Charcoal Act anymore. Instead GROOTS willl focus on  Kitui energy framework: GROOTS will track the development of the Kitui energy framework to include clean cooking tehnologies and capacity building for women, youth and other groups in the county.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: After the ban on  charcoal  in January 2018, this outcome became irrelevant. Instead GROOTS Kenya focused on supporting the development of the Kitui County Energy Framework:
GROOTS Kenya staff &amp; champions participated in some forums (e.g. one held in Mwingi) towards the development of the Kitui master plan. In 2019, the lead partner in this process (CAFOD) finalized the data collection (EDMs).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">GROOTS Kenya will engage with the Governor and the Ministry of Enviroment and advocate for Clean cooking to be incoporate in the charcoal act review  as an alternative to charcoal  use</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: After the ban on  charcoal  in January 2018, this outcome became irrelevant. Instead GROOTS Kenya focused on supporting the development of the Kitui County Energy Framework; this will be finalised in 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in adopting  CIDPs to include clean cooking.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. No legislative framework in the form of policies, laws, standards, regulations and/or guidelines exists, or existing/new suggested legislative framework is detrimental to issue
1. A new/adjusted legislative framework is considered 
2. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been drafted
3. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR framework detrimental to issue has been prevented
4. New/adjusted legislative framework is applied and/or enforced, but without appropriate means and/or not equally applied (across geographical areas, socio-economic groups, men/women &#x2026;.)
5. New/adjusted legislative framework is effectively and equally applied and/or enforced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Kitui CIDP has not included any actions towards promotion/adoption of clean cooking hamoering any investiments by the county into this sub sector</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least inclusion of clean cooking in two CIDPs realised</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: GROOTS Kenya has held over 5 meetings with official from the with Ministry of Environment, Champions and Ministry of Planning  in an effort yo get the county to  prioritize clean cooking issues in the CIDP  and into their sectoral planning. As a commitment to including clean cooking there were joint activities planned together.e.g The Rwandan visit  to the briqette production line</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: Kitui clean cooking champions make submissions to the Annual Development Plans (ADPSs)  that are 1 year plans to ensure implementation of CIDPs. For the year 2021/22, women champions shared their inputs with the County Government of Kitui to ensure continued allocation to clean cooking sector though this was on  short notice limiting a wider stakeholder engagement. Submissions were done online. 
Participation in Kiambu and Kilifi ADP process was not possible due to short notice to women champions to submit memorandum on the budget.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">GROOTS will monitor implementation of CIDP through the annual development plan.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: GROOTS Kenya continued to monitor the implementation of CIDP through the annual development plan. Clean cooking has gained a lot of support since it was included in the CIDP. As a result of this participation there is allocation to clean cooking activities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusion of clean cooking in the CIDP and a budgetary allocation to clean cooking</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The 2018-2022 Kitui CIDP now includes projects on clean cooking. It is as a result of numerous meetings held by community clean cooking champions in every sub-county during which they prioritized clean cooking in public participation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing and implementing bioenergy strategy for Kenya</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. No legislative framework in the form of policies, laws, standards, regulations and/or guidelines exists, or existing/new suggested legislative framework is detrimental to issue
1. A new/adjusted legislative framework is considered 
2. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been drafted
3. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR framework detrimental to issue has been prevented
4. New/adjusted legislative framework is applied and/or enforced, but without appropriate means and/or not equally applied (across geographical areas, socio-economic groups, men/women &#x2026;.)
5. New/adjusted legislative framework is effectively and equally applied and/or enforced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Ministry of Energy has been calling upon stakeholder support in the development of the bioenergy strategy, however, this is yet to lead into a document that can be resourced</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">MOEP developing and resourcing the implementation of the strategy</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: &quot;The following have happened in support of the bioenergy strategy: 1. Committee formed by ministry of Energy and Kenya Private Sector Alliance (KEPSA) 2. briquettes and pellets strategy for kenya provided  3. budget allocation for briquettes and pellets in medium term plan (MTP) III)
Additionally, several meetings have been held with Ministry of Energy which resulted in agreement to anchor the bioenergy strategy under sustainable energy for all project within government as plans for establishment of an authority are considered/ deliberated.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: Last meeting on the bioenergy strategy was in March. CCAK is part of Bioenergy Committee. CCAK will seek detailed feedback during the upcoming inter-ministerial committee meeting.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The bioenergy strategy process is moving slowly. It might not be useful to track this process anymore as the National Government has instead asked CCAK to lead in the hosting of data and country action towards attainment of SE4ALL. The e-knowledge platfrom by CCAK will be used to host the data and following a number of studies, CCAK will update clean cooking sector data and updating of the Country action plan</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: The bioenergy strategy process is moving slowly. It might not be useful to track this process anymore as the National Government has instead asked CCAK to lead in the hosting of data and country action towards attainment of SE4ALL. The e-knowledge platfrom by CCAK will be used to host the data and following a number of studies, CCAK will update clean cooking sector data and updating of the Country action plan

CCAK participation in the Bioenergy Strategy development committee, a process which is currently under the MInistry of Energy. It has proven to be a lengthy process, and we anticipate that the Ministry of Energy will provide a clear way forward on next steps, after which CCAK will make a decision on whether to engage further or not.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs will monitor and interrogate implementaton of the strategy in 2018</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: CCAK has been working closely with the Ministry of Energy through the Biomass Energy task force to revive the push for a bioenergy strategy (draft), the Sustainable Energy for All (SE4ALL) secretariat and structures proposed in the new Energy bill which will enhance prioritisation of biomass energy and by extension clean cooking. There was no legal frameworks to spur growth of the bioenergy in Kenya. However moving forward in 2019, the energy bill of 2017 clearly provides directives on the growth of the bioenergy sector in Kenya by promoting and developing it.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased CSO participation in meetings with Governments, Community Champions and the private sector</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of formal and informal encounters with government and/or businesses</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of encounters is total number of encounters, divided by number of CSOs</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The CSOs have had both formal and informal encounters with Government through the clean cooking interministerial committee, presentations to the finance deparmental committee in parliament standards meetings, KEPSA parliamentary round table, KEPSA ministerial stakeholder forum, courtesy visits in Kitui county and CCAK working groups in the past. Nevertheless, these need to be streamlined with more structured clean cooking advocacy interventions</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">New encounters with county government and stakeholders  in Kiambu county.The stakeholder to engage with with be mapped out the Kiambu county context analysis  GROOTS Kenya and CCAK will also invest in sustaining established relationships at the  national level and in Kitui county</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2018: &gt;GROOTS Kenya established relationships with key officers at the National level Ministry of Energy, Directorate of Renewable Energy; through the Director and his team GROOTS sought government inputs/ feedback on the Kitui mapping report. &gt;GROOTS Kenya has also established partnership with Kenya Association of Manufacturers on County Energy Policies
&gt;GROOTS Kenya has had meetings with Department of Environment, Nairobi County on championing for adoption of clean cooking in the city.
&gt;Also, there are several engagements CCAK has had with National and County governments regarding partnership for resource mobilization; and input to proposals on fiscal incentives for clean cooking by NetFUND to be presented to the Minister for Environment and Forestry.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&gt;CCAK will engage various ministerial stakeholders, the county government (Tharaka Nithi, Kisumu, Kakamega, Narok, Kilifi), state agencies (KEBS, KEFRI, KIRDI), private sectors, partners, relevant consultants and Ministry of Health.
&gt;GROOTS Kenya is up scaling to Kilifi. It is expected that we will engage with additional partners from government, CSOs and Private sector working in the county.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="9.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: 1.In February 2019, GROOTS Kenya initiated her engagement with officers in Kilifi county including the Chief Executive Committee (CEC) Member hosting the department of energy, Chief Officer and Director Department of Energy. Discussions centered on undertaking a context analysis for Kilifi County on clean cooking.  TORs for this study have been discussed with the county.
2. GROOTS Kenya has continued to engage with Council of Governors (COG) on clean cooking agenda in May 2019, during the quarterly County Energy committee meeting. GROOTS Kenya held consultative meeting with a Senior  representative of the committee about how to reach all the 47 counties in kenya. Related discussions were  held with CECs of responsible County Departments from Marsabit, Baringo and Migori 
3. During the County energy committee meeting in May 2019, GROOTS Kenya also met with the lead officer at the Ministry of Energy and discussed collaborative efforts  in support of the Gender in Energy policy.
4. GROOTS Kenya held discussions with Senior Officers from World Resources Institute about joining efforts in supporting  development Energy plans for Kitui county
5. GROOTS kenya met Lead Auditor &amp; Technical Manager, AfriCert ltd about how to partner to support clean cooking artisans get markets for their products 

CCAK has engaged with several national government ministries, state agencies, private sector and other sector NGOS with the need to champion the clean cooking agenda. 
1. CCAK entered into an MoU with KEFRI (Kenya Forest Research Insititute) and Fine Aromas, to develop the standards for the charcoal and carbonised briquettes standards. The MoU has seen both parties committing to technically and financially support the activity. 
2. CCAK has frequently engaged with the Kenya Bureau of Standards and Kenya Industrial Research Development Institute in fastracking the review of the Biomass cookstoves standards. In addition, KEBS has been provided  technical advise towar ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This will only measure the strategic encounters</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: The Civil Society Organizations have had encounters with different government stakeholders in various occasions. These encounters were to share the project goals and advocacy plan and possible opportunities at the county level for integrating clean cooking. Through these visits, personal contacts and relationships were established with the relevant officers. The Civil Society Organisation staff have been informed of other opportunities for mainstreaming clean cooking in Kitui County. There is good will by the technical officers towards adoption of clean cooking. Some of the officers met include Kenya Forest Service, Ministry of Agriculture, and Ministry of Health, National Environment Management Authority, Kenya Forest Research Institute and Public planning office. The technical support they accorded GROOTS Kenya was in the mapping of the Clean Cooking Community champions, provision of data during the community led survey of unclean cooking impacts in Kitui County and invitation to attend the Mid Term Plan 111 meeting in Kitui County. Clean Cookstoves Association of Kenya has engaged with SE4All Technical Committee, National Climate Change Secretariat, wPower Hub, Pamoja Life, WEEWORKS, Energy Regulatory Commission, National Environment Management Authority, Ministry of Health, United Nations Habitat, Powerspot and attended and interview at Radio Maisha, local radio station, on various clean cooking advocacy interventions. Engagements focused on SE4All web portal design, Value Added Tax exemptions on Clean Cookstoves, developing a clean cooking catalogue and further partnership opportunities with Clean Cookstoves Association of Kenya.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="11.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: GROOTS -6 
Kiambu: 
&gt;Technical working group meetings on Kiambu climate change and energy policy took place. Meetings were held with County Dept. Energy, clean cooking champions, other CSOs including SACDEP, PACJA and national government through the meteorological dept., private sector on the climate change policy: The draft Kiambu climate change and energy policy is now ready to be submitted to Asssembly Committee on Environment 
Kilifi: 
&gt;In quarter 1, meeting with Chief Officer and Principal Energy Officer, KOSAP about mapping clean cooking champions in Kilifi North Ganze sub-county. In quarter 2 mapping was done 
&gt;In quarter two, Zoom meeting with Kilifi county Government and other stakeholder for validation of Kilifi Energy policy
&gt;Public campaigns in last week of July on clean cooking. 
&gt;Had meeting with energy officer on engendering the Kilifi Energy Policy.
&gt;GROOTS paid a courtesy call to DCC Kaloleni and Ganze. This was a familiarisation meeting with the county on clean cooking. Discussed charcoal burning and its effect  on Kilifi forest during the meeting

CCAK - 5
&gt;CCAK has had 2 physical and webinar meetings to finalize the MOUs with Kisumu and Kakamega Counties. The legal office in Kisumu is now reviewing the draft MoU. In Kakamega it had been submitted to legal team but was delayed due to change of Key Officer (CEC, Water Environment and Natural Resources). CCAK anticipates that the MoU will be signed within 2020
&gt;Meetings were held with private sector  (KOKO Networks, Burn Ltd and Envirofit)  Min of Energy, Ministry of Petroleum and Mining on VAT amendment bill 2019/20.  CCAK developed a position paper on why zero rating status on LPG was needed. The paper was submitted to Treasury, Parliament and Min. of Energy.
&gt;Several virtual meetings with AMREF and Min of Health meeting for more research on household air pollution and to increase capacity of community health volunteers (CHVs)
&gt; Meetings with GIZ, SNV, NIKO Green, KEMRI, MoH, AMRE ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&gt;GROOTS Kenya will engage with more stakeholders in Kilifi and Kiambu during validation of the context analysis and finalization of the energy and climate change policy in Kiambu. 

&gt;CCAK will engage various ministerial stakeholders, the county government (Kisumu and Kakamega), state agencies (KEBS, KEFRI, KIRDI), private sectors, partners and relevant consultants</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="9.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: CCAK engaged key Government agencies and ministries at national level but also expanded reach to the counties of Kisumu and Kakamega. The following were the key engagements: 
1. Ministerial engagement. 
CCAK convened an Interministerial Committee meeting on 23rd October, 2019 with attendance from  the following ministries: Energy, Industrialization, Education, Agriculture, Sports and Heritage and the following state agencies: EPRA, KIRDI, KNBS. The agenda included dissemination of standards quick guide, plans for the clean cooking forum, Institutional Cookstoves and Fuels Study in Kenya way forward by EPRA. There was renewed committment to implement the interministerial clean cooking agenda. 
2. County government (Kisumu and Kakamega)
CCAK met with Kisumu County CEC Energy, Industrialization and Enterprise Development and Kakamega County CEC Water, Natural Resources and Environment to discuss cross cutting issues on clean cooking within the county activities and development plans. Key highlights: 
- Cascading Interministerial Committee on Clean Cooking in the counties.
- Review and abolish double taxation of the clean cooking fuels and stoves  in Kisumu county.
- Awareness creation on relevant cookstoves standards at regional level  and inclusion of clean cooking in policies and county plans in partnership with CCAK.
- Formal engagement  with the association through Memorandum of Understanding. 
3. State agencies (KEBS, KEFRI, KIRDI)
CCAK convened a KEBS technical committee meeting on 24th September, 2019. The KEBS TC  approved the official standards development process, taking ownership of the standard development process supported by the stakeholders. 
4. Private sectors
 On 17th December, 2019, CCAK convened a private sector working group meeting discussing the following key issues:
-Understanding roles of standards, regulations and ISO harmonised test protocols in the clean cooking sector.
-Outline priorities of private sector and CCAK in standa ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clean Cookstoves Association of Kenya will engage with Kenya Bureau of Standards, Ministry of Energy and Petroleum and the Energy Regulatory Commission on various clean cooking advocacy interventions. Engagements will focus on completion of biomass standard and cookstoves standards and labelling</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="9.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-11-2018: GROOTS and CCAK have had at total of 8 formal and 1 informal meetings within Kitui County which targeted , the Governer, with County Minister for Environment and Natural Resources , Chief officer for Environment. and the Director of Enviroment, NETFUND ,KAM , the Department of Public health, Ministry of Energy and Energy Regulatoy Commission .The meeting held with the Minister and the Directors introduced the project The two participated in the development of 2018 GROOTS Kenya annual plan and committed to support some of the activities. They also allocated financial resources to train clean cooking and subsides installation of clean cook stoves for poor households. The Minister later invited GROOTS Kenya to a meeting with the Governer to whom the plan on clean cooking was prosented as an alternative source to the charcoal crisis that has started looming in Kitui. CCAK and GROOTS also had a meeting with the Director of NETFUND on energy ministiries at the county level and how to lobby inclusion if clean cooking in the county integrated Development plan. CCAK has also had several meetings with ministy of Health (Department of Public Helath) to discuss guideleines on clean cooking for extension workers. GROOTS Kenya and informal meeting with a senior representative of KAM to build rapport for a future partnership in the production of more affordable cook stoves. Each formal meeting that GROOTS has held has also incorporates at least 2 community champion as a way of creating sustainablity in engagement CCAK has engaged with the Energy Regulatory Commision and the Ministry of Energy and Petroleum towards ensuring collaboration on the conduct of the clean cooking regulatory impact assessment. Through the Kenya Beareau of Statisctics , CCAK has been able tp initiate meetings aimed at drafting of Biomass Stoves Standards and draft standards on ethanol handling.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&gt;After the stakeholder validation meeting in Kiambu Planned in  August 2018, GROOTS expects to hold a number of meetings  to engage more with Government and CSOs working in Kiambu county. Discussions were on GROOTS Kenya supporting the Kiambu County on review of the county Energy policy that was a KAM initiative. GROOTS identified the new Directorate of Energy and Climate change as the department for engagement. Discussions also pursued the need to support more research on Renewable energy and training of county staff on policy processes for clean cooking adoption.
&gt;CCAK plans to conduct stakeholder working group meetings monthly for the next half year. CCAK targets to engage the first ladies association, KEBS on matters of standards and regulations, KRA and relevant bodies on the import duty follow ups. CCAK plans to conduct meeting on Climate Change and Technical working group, over the next two quarters. The CC&amp;T working group is expected to engage Ministry of Health in development of community health guidelines for clean cooking to be used by community health workers in dissemination of the need to adopt clean cooking technologies and fuel and reduce impacts/deaths caused by HAP.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="17.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The target was achieved. Several key stakeholders from the government ministries, state agencies and private sector were met during the final half of the year. 
1CCAK met with the ministry of energy- RE directorate on Fiscal incentives for ICS sector; reduction on import duty culminating with a letter to the Treasury
2. Ministry of energy on discussions on  sector data on ICS, this lead to the sector study currently underway
3. Ministry of energy on CCAK leveraging on Kenya&apos;s action agenda towards SE4ALL; it was agreed the clean cooking data will be hosted by CCAK in their new website
4. Ministry of health on updating community health workers manual and curricula, the manuals will be updated in 2019.
5. CCAK meeting with the inter-ministerial committee  on clean cooking where Kenya&apos;s clean cooking action plan was agreed. CCAK will lead in the drafting of the action plan. The Meeting also discussed on the  roadmap for mainstreaming of clean cooking agenda into Ministries annual  plans. 
6. Through the technical working group on climate change, health and energy, GROOTS Kenya and CCAK also met the Ministry of Health  to fast-track the need to review the curriculum and manuals for the community health workers and volunteers, this will be undertaken in the start of 2019.
7. CCAK and GROOTS Kenya in the same meeting engaged with NETFUND to build on the advocacy agenda through co-organizing the annual clean cooking forum. 
8. A meeting with the Numerical Machining Complex and SME Support Centre which envisioned the start of the revolving fund to support the clean cooking SMEs. 
9. CCAK together with NIKO Green managed to enhance the CSO sustainability by strengthening and collaboration through proposal writing for resource mobilization.
10. During the second half of 2018, GROOTS Kenya engaged with additional stakeholder from government in Kiambu County and met the County Executive on Energy,Natural Resources and Water and agreed on the need for a policy o ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of knowledge/research products shared with relevant stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of evidence based knowledge/research products shared is total number of evidence based knowledge/research products shared, divided by number of CSOs</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">There hasn&#x2019;t been any knowledge products shared, as CSOs havent generated any knowledge</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2 knowledge products will include ;  one Kiambu County fact sheet that wiil be developed using the Kiambu county context analysis report.                         GROOTS and CCAK also will produce  1 policy briefs based on the research reports of other stakeholder working in clean cooking which include but not limited to Biogas International whom we have preliminary engagements with.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2018: CSOs were not able to produce a policy brief on clean cooking as planned as more efforts have been towards finalizing the Kiambu county context analysis report which is at an advanced stage and from it a fact sheet will be developed in the remaining half of the year. 
&gt;GROOTS Kenya however shared the finalised Kitui mapping report with the Ministry of Energy at National level (Director for biofuels was present) and Ministry of Environment at county level where Minister for Environment Kitui County was present.  
&gt;CCAK has also shared the Common External tariffs handbook with several stakeholders to highlight the implication of taxation when trading across the East Africa Community.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&gt;Popular version for standards (briquettes and pellets, biomass cookstoves standards, ethanol appliances standards and denatured technical ethanol standards), policy briefs (analysis on briquettes standards, budget tracking in 5 high impact counties) and report fact sheets.
&gt;GROOTS Kenya will collaborate with other partners and disseminate at least one study related to energy plan formulation and climate change and energy formulation in Kitui and Kiambu.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: 1.GROOTS Kenya developed posters, banner and pamphlets on SDGs 7  about Clean cooking  which was shared out during the devolution conference held in Kirinyanga County.
CCAK shared:
2.Popular version for Ethanol fuelled appliances standards have been developed and shared with the sector members through mail. 
3. Sector bulletins informing sector members on Key issues; Inclusion of clean cooking question in th upcoming October 2019 census in Kenya. The bulletin has been shared via mails and website to the sector members. 
4. Final report on the Use of Biomass Cookstoves and Fuels at the institutions in Kenya was published in Q2 and has been  shared with NGOs e.g. Clean Cooking Alliance and the Technical Committee on biomass study.
5. Policy brief on Institutional biomass cookstoves survey and Fact sheets on Institutional biomass cookstoves survey shared with sector members (private sector stoves manufacturers, NGOs and fuel manufacturers). The briefs captured the outcomes of the report on the need to revive sector discussions on the stalled Biomass cookstoves of 2013 including creating awreness to institutions, innovative finance for institutional stoves uptake and propoer record keeping on fuel used.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baseline report for regulations, sector status report and Kitui clean cooking socio economic study.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: Clean Cookstoves Association of Kenya has shared Global Alliance for Clean Cookstove factsheets with its working groups. Global Alliance for Clean Cookstove factsheets provided the global outlook. The local fact sheets are still under review and will be shared in September 2017 with the Council of Governors. They will be shared with the members of public during the Agricultural Society of Kenya exhibition in October 2017 in Nairobi at the Clean Cookstoves Association of Kenya stand. However, no knowledge products have been shared with government officials.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: GROOTS- 2
Kiambu Climate Change and Energy Policy has been drafted and shared with stakeholders while the Kilifi Context Analysis was used in the process towards development of Kilifi Energy Policy

CCAK - 2
1. Internal bulletins  were prepared by CCAK  weekly communicating financial and capacity building opportunities in the sector and relevant issues e.g. how sector members can cope with COVID etc. The bulletins were shared with members every Friday via email.  
2. Quick guides - a standards booklet has been developed which contains in one: biomass cookstove standard, ethanol fueled appliances standard, technical denatured alcohol standard . Copies have been shared with members through WhatsApp , email and website.

*However, delays in development of other products was experienced partly due to COVID-19 restrictions that limited the necessary engagement
&gt;S&amp;L (Market and Impact assessment study led by Multiarch ltd contracted by SNV) is ongoing. Once its done policy brief and fact sheets will be developed
&gt;HAP materials are not yet designed. One week campaign is planned and will be tied to SoC still in progress. Pictorial on household air pollution developed by Climate, Health and Energy technical working group will be validated this September.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clean Cookstoves Association of Kenya will share fact sheets, and policy briefs with the Council of Governors and select parliament committees and government agencies.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-11-2018: GROOTS Kenya shared with the  ministries of Enviroment, Health,Planning and enegy  in Kitui county and Community champion  3 knowledge products . These included ;  the &quot;Community Led Mapping on the Health Impact of Unclean Cooking and cooking technologies used in Kitui County &quot; report , policy briefs produced together with Global Alliance for Clean Cook Stoves y  and pamphlets with a catalogue of Clean cooking technologies.
At the county energy meeting organised by NETFUND, CCAK  also shared 3 more   evidence products including: policy brief on institutional stoves and improving regulatory frameworkon clean cooking and 2 fact sheets - one improving regulatory environment and the second on addressing  low adoption of clean cooking technologies in kenya. CCAK has also shared the briefs to visitors who came to their stand at the annual agricultural trade fair. The documents shared during the trade fair has seen CCAK membership improving from 35 members to 41 members in 2018 with interested parties calling to inquire on clean cooking products.                                                                                                  The pamphlets with a catalogues on clean cooking was termed as very informative by the Kitui county ministry of energy and highly assisted in creating awareness among communities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&gt;Draft Climate change and Energy policy for Kiambu county and context analysis report for Kilifi county will be shared once finalized

&gt;Plans to disseminate the final study report, fact sheets, policy brief on the Use of Biomass Cookstoves and Fuels at Institutions in Kenya to Energy and Petroleum Regulatory Authority in Q3 to inform the need for Regulatory Impact Assessment to kick start discussions on the draft Biomass reulations of 2013.

&gt;Clean Cooking sector bulletins will be shared with the sector, standards quick guide on the ethanol cooking appliances, charcoal and carbonised briquettes standards and the biomass cookstoves standard.

&gt;Brief on the budget tracking for the two high impact counties(Kisumu and Kakamega)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: CCAK disseminated the following knowledge products: 
1.Fact sheets on Institutitonal Use of Biomass Cookstoves and Fuel through emails to all CCAK members &amp; partners during the sector working group meetings, Interministerial Committee meeting, Clean Cooking Forum 2019, 1st Health, Environment and Climate Change conference.
2.Policy brief Institutitonal Use of Biomass Cookstoves and Fuel through emails to all CCAK members &amp; partners during the sector working group meetings, Interministerial Committee meeting, Clean Cooking Forum 2019, 1st Health, Environment and Climate Change conference.
3. Clean Cooking sector bulletins were share on email to sector members and partners.
4. Standards quick guide on ethanol fuelled appliances, technical denatured alcohol and Biomass Cookstoves standards were disseminated during the V4CP exchange visit on 31st October, 2019,CCAK members &amp; partners during the sector working group meetings, Interministerial Committee meeting, Clean Cooking Forum 2019, 1st Health, Environment and Climate Change conference.

Final study report on Institutitonal Use of Biomass Cookstoves and Fuel was again shared (20 hard copies), through emails to all CCAK members &amp; partners and powerpoint presentations during the sector working group meetings, Interministerial Committee meeting, Clean Cooking Forum 2019, 1st Health, Environment and Climate Change conference)

GROOTS- Kenya:
1. GROOTS Kenya supported the Kiambu Technical team to develop a draft  Climate change and Energy policy for Kiambu county. The draft policy was shared during a validation forum in December 2019.                                                      

The Kilifi Context analysis report was again shared and validated in December 2019 at a stakeholders meeting in Kilifi County</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&gt;GROOTS plans to share The Kiambu context analysis report and fact sheet with Ministry of Environment, Kenya Forest Service, KEFRI, GIZ, SNV, HIVOS, Practical Action, Office of the Govenor in Kiambu, Local community stove builders and CBOS enaged in promotion of clean cooking.  
&gt;CCAK plans to design and share half year newsletter relying on documentations from the climate change technical working group and sector working group meetings. Also, prepare a policy brief on logging ban and its impact on the biomass sector and Fiscal incentives brief for clean cooking and fuels sector

&gt;The biomass regulatory study is also expected to be ready and will be disseminated to stakeholders. The institutional cook stoves and fuels survey will provide information to guide Government on enactment of the draft Energy (Biomass cook stoves) regulations of 2013 by showing the cascade effects of institutions using cookstoves and fuels in regulated and unregulated markets. The law will make it mandatory for instituions to install ICSs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: &gt;Following the finalization of the mapping report in Kitui, GROOTS Kenya organized a launch in August 2018 during which the report was shared by government stakeholders including the Minister for environment in Kitui.  Additionally, ON November 28th, a report of the Kiambu context analysis was shared with government; Ministry of Energy- Directorate of RE and CSO partners in Kitui. it was during this meeting that a technical committee was commissioned to develop the climate change and energy policy. On December 20th, a report of the market study was shared and validated by community champions. 
&gt;CCAK has generated evidence materials from the case study on the uptake of biomass cookstoves and fuel in the institutions in Kenya. The evidence materials including an infographic, a policy brief and a best practice and lessons learned report on the management and practical use of the clean cooking technologies. The evidence materials will be disseminated during the 2019 period during the 5 county engagements, review retreat with the Ministry of Health, CCAK membership weeks, AGM, members working group meetings, Nairobi Trade Fair, Courtesy visits to members and partners.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased CSO (community champions) influence on agenda setting in interaction with governments &amp; the private sector</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree of CSO influence on agenda setting related to clean cooking</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. CSO has no or only occasional interaction with key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector 
1. CSO has regular interactions with key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector
2. CSO gets opportunity to explain its interests towards key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector
3. CSO&#x2019;s interests are &#x2018;put on the agenda&#x2019; and are discussed among stakeholders in government and/or the private sector</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The CSOs participate in various forums through bilateral meetings with decision makers, KEPSA and the clean cooking  interministerial committee  but have had limited success in pushing clean cooking to the agenda e.g. the review of the SE4All action agenda to prioritise clean cooking. This needs to be scaled up</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs will participate in stakeholders meeting and mapping events . They will also share evidence material at the  TWG for consideration and action</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2018: The score represents average level of influence at both national and county level.  CSO influence shows  strengthening at both levels but especially at national with the passing of fuel and biomass standards.   

National level influence: 3
&gt;CCAK inputs on clean cooking are being considered under various climate change and health policy documents.
&gt;CCAK convened two technical working group meetings on Climate Change, Energy and Health at the Ministry of Health on dates 27th March and 20th June, 2018. The meetings  discussed the development of the extension workers training manual. 
&gt;Kenya National Climate Change Action Plan has a section on clean cooking and adoption of clean fuels use as contributing to reduction in Green house gases by the year 2030 as compared to a business as usual scenario and CCAK private sector members have given input to the NCCAP which should be considered. The private sector members influenced government to consider taking action on responding to GHG gas emissions emanating from unclean cookstoves and how to mitigate against indoor air pollution. 
&gt;Ministry of Health officials between 23rd - 25th July underwent a training on Household Air Pollution monitoring organised by the alliance partner, Global Alliance for Clean Cookstoves. The Ministry of Health has now incorporated clean cooking agenda in their planning. 
&gt;standards on Cookstoves; The standards (142.KS 1814: 2018 Kenya Standard &#x2013; Biomass stoves &#x2013; Specification, second Edition; 141.KS 2759:2018 Kenya Standard &#x2013; Ethanol fuelled cooking appliances &#x2013; Specification, First Edition) were approved by the 119th approval committee meeting of 29th June 2018. Members of the private sector were also involved in the technical committee that drafted and reviewed the standards. 

County level influence: 2
CSOs continue to participate in stakeholders meeting at county level with their contributions being acknowledged and considered. The estimated level of influence at county level ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&gt;CCAK will finalise review of Curriculum and Manuals for CHVs, influence fiscal incentives for clean cooking in counties and national government, coordinate and implement clean cooking action plan under the interministerial committee meeting, influence an impact assessment for the biomass cookstoves regulations. 
&gt;GROOTS Kenya will continue to work with County governments of Kilifi, Kitui and Kiambu to ensure that Clean cooking agenda is not dropped in the annual budgets.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.80">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: County level average score - 2.7
&gt;Kilifi - 3
On 2nd of February 2019,  The county government of Kilifi through The CEC Lands, Energy, Housing &amp; Physical planning, agreed to partner with GROOTS Kenya in enhancing adoption of clean cooking in the county. 
&gt;Kitui - 2 
Discussion were on course to develop an Energy Master Plan for Kitui county but this has been slowed by competing partnership interests in the county. Kitui County has received a number of partners willing to support it on Clean energy. These include CAFORD, WWF, World Resources Institure, Purpose aamong other local and international NGOS. All these partners driven by their project goals and outcomes have led to delayed process in the county.  The county however remains receptive to clean cooking agenda; in June 2019, during EDM workshop  organized by CAFOD in Mwingi town, stakeholders (including government officers) showed keen interest in considering clean cooking when analyzing energy needs and solutions for the county.
&gt;Kiambu - 3 
Kiambu County had planned to develop a climate change policy but after context analysis on clean cooking was conducted, the county decided to expand scope to have a County Climate Change and Energy Policy instead; clean cooking is given good focus in this draft policy.  

National Government -3
1. CCAK has coordinated the final review and approval of the curriculum and manuals for the community health workers and volunteers in collaboration with the Ministry of Health and other sector stakeholders. 
2. Through the support from the sector and the government (Ministry of Energy, Ministry of Environment, Ministry of Health and the National Assembly), CCAK has finally lobbyed for the zero rating of the denatured technical alcohol under the new FY 2019/2020. 
3. CCAK has sought an appointment with EPRA to discuss the need for a RIA and kick start discussions on Biomass Regulations
Private Sector
4. CCAK has over the period been part of consultative forums aimed  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO is positioning to be a lead organisation in matters clean cooking in Kenya</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: One GROOTS Kenya clean cooking champion from Kitui Rural Sub County, participated in Mid Term Plan 111 meeting held in Kitui County on June 16th 2017, which is part of the vision 2030 implementation plan for counties. During this meeting, she participated in the group discussion on the economic pillar and suggested for inclusion of clean cooking in 2018-2022 targets. 
Clean Cook stoves Association of Kenya engagement with Energy Regulatory Commission has initiated the recruitment of a consultant to conduct a regulatory impact assessment of the draft Energy (Improved Cook stove) Regulations of 2013 which was advertised on Clean Cook stoves Association Of Kenya website at (https://www.kenyacookstoves.org/images/opportunities/RFP_Improved_Biomass_Stoves_Regulatory_Impact_Assessment.pdf). The report will be submitted to the Ministry of Energy and Petroleum Cabinet Secretary for consideration. Clean Cook stoves Association of Kenya participation in Kenya Bureau of Standards Technical Committee has resulted in a plan to expedite the KS 1824 standard review. Further engagement with the Climate Change Health and Energy Technical Working Group under Ministry of Health has resulted in development of Terms of Reference for the development of Extension Worker Manual on Household Air Pollution in Kenya.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: National and county level - 3 
&gt;Influence both at national and county remains high. During covid period, GROOTS used animation modules to induct champions on clean cooking. KOSAP (Government project supported by World Bank) organised a meeting in which GROOTS community champions attended. The champions tasked government about interventions for women/ communities who do not have access to the main grid. GROOTS is recognised as key contributor in issues of energy and is playing a leading role e.g. Kiambu  climate change policy development. In Kitui, GROOTS clean cooking champions had a meeting and developed a memorandum submitted to government on clean cooking (measures such as wood lots and seedlings proposed) for FY 2021/22

&gt;CCAK is working with MoH in finalizing design and final editing of HAP manual (module 13b Household air pollution). The process is also supported by GIZ. The products should be ready for review 1st week of September and final validation on 22nd September. Full roll out (for eight or more counties) to CHV planned is planned in October 2020 with support from GIZ following pilot run in Nyeri county where CHVs  were trained with support from SNV.  One or two staff from CCAK will be trained as TOT with the roll out
&gt;Biomass draft regulation approval. Biomass cookstoves and fuel use in institutions study was formally shared with EPRA this year (hard copies). This as well received with commitment to include a related impact assessment study in 2021/22 FY budget 
&gt;CCAK held virtual engagements with its members on sustainable charcoal and carbonised briquettes standards, charcoal and carbonised briquettes standards. Their comments were consolidated and shared with KEBS for incorporation. CCAK is closely following up with KEBS with target to have these approved by September.

*Inter-ministerial committee meetings have not been held this year due to COVID-19. The first meeting is planned this 9th Sept. All ministries will be required to r ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clean Cookstoves Association of Kenya participation in Kenya Bureau of Standards Technical Committee has resulted in a plan to expedite the KS 1824 standard review during a meeting scheduled for October 2017. Further engagement with the Climate Change Health and Energy Technical Working Group under Ministry of Health has resulted in development of Terms of Reference for the development of Extension Worker Manual on Household Air Pollution in Kenya.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25-11-2018: Influenced TOR for contextualizing Indoor air pollution guidelines. RE workshop by the ministry of environment to ensure that household clean cooking became a key agenda of the workshop
CCAK convened technical working groups (TWG) on clean cooking for Health and Energy ministries</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&gt;GROOTS Kenya will continue to work with champions in Kitui to ensure that Clean cooking agenda is not dropped during the 2020 annual development plan review. 

&gt;CCAK through the Ministry of Health will finalise the design and approvals for the curriculum , manuals and job aids to be piloted alongside the Universal Health Coverage pilot counties.

&gt;CCAK will coordinate and implement the clean cooking action plan under the interministerial committee meeting.

&gt;CCAK will focus on influencing discussions to kick start the impact assessment study for the biomass cookstoves regulations.

&gt;With private Sector, CCAK will continue coordinating the sector to bring together the members to discusss issues affecting the clean cooking sector e.g. Tarrif barriers, standards etc. CCAK through consultation from the sector members and partners will ensure standards for the, biomass cookstoves and the  charcoal and carbonised briquettes developed and approved for sector.  

&#x200B;

&#x200B;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: National level - 3
CCAK continues to position strongly at natioanal level as demonstrated in the following:
1. Through CCAK intervention - clean cooking is now reconised as one of the pathways for preventive healthcare with the Ministry of Health and stakeholders finalizing the review  and approval of the  curriculum, manuals and job aids  content for Community health workforce . Pilot trainings have been conducted in Kisumu, Machakos and Uasin Gishu counties in October during the Universal Health Coverage pilot 2019.
2. CCAK &apos;s sector mandate and convening power is strongly recognised and has improved due to the continous cordination of the  Interministerial Clean Cooking committee and progressive follow up of implementation of the IMC Action Agenda.
3. Discussion on the impact of asseeement study for adoption  of the draft biomass cookstoves regulations 2013 have been influenced strongly throgh communivations made between CCAK  and the Energy and Petroleum Regulatory Authority. Informative letters on need for the Regulatory Impact assessment have been shared with the Director General for action as well as a follow up discussion  during the IMC meeting held in October 2019.
4. CCAK  partners and sector membership engagement has inproved through the quarterly sector working group meeting . Iin December, 2019, CCAK convened a sector working group meeting for standards dissemination , implementation and planning for 2020. Additionally, CCAK participated in the KEBS TC meeting in September, 2019 together with the private sector discussing the development of charcoal and carbonised briquettes standards.  

County level ( Kitui, Kiambu and Kilifi) - 3
GROOTS has strongly positioned in clean cooking matters in all the three counties: 
&gt;In 2019, GROOTS Kenya continued to work with champions in Kitui to ensure that Clean cooking agenda was not dropped during the 2020 annual development plan review to ensure that interventions for clean cooking are included  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unlike the Kitui county integrated development plan (CIDP), the Nairobi and Kiambu CIDPs lack specific activities and budgets for clean cooking. GROOTS Kenya will be having more discussion in Kiambu and Nairobi and hopes to influence their plans so that they include  specific priority measures to improve household cooking energy. 
At national level, CCAK plans  continued engagement with government ministries in addition the Ministry of Health to mainstream clean cooking in their action /work plans.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: &gt;CCAK contributed to the strategic framework development of the Primary Health Care under the Family Health department and the Public Health between 5th and 9th November,2018. Primary Health Care aims at enhancing three key areas; empowered people and communities; multisectoral policy and action; and primary care. A research gap on impacts of household air pollution was proposed to build evidences on ill health effects from HAP which will define key policy measures for the Primary Health Care and entire health system. 
CCAK on 14th August, 2018 met with the Ministry of Health to finalise on the concept for revising the curriculum and manuals for the community health workers and volunteers to include the household air pollution component. In addition, discussions on building evidence to secure policy imperatives within the indoor air pollution scope have been initiated e.g. the need to have the component on indoor environment consideration in the Green Building Standards.
&gt;GROOTS Kenya is part of the Renewable Energy Working group in Kitui county. While planning for the national energy conference in December 2018, GROOTS Was able to integrate key issues including gender equality, prioritization of  household energy and discussion on private sector engagement in the program. Additionally, in Kitui County while working with CAFOD and Purpose, GROOTS Kenya influenced Kitui County and partner CSOs in the county  to work with women champions as key stakeholders to develop the Kitui Energy Master Plan. GROOTS will support this by providing technical support on matters clean cooking in the county . GROOTS Kenya also convinced the partners (CSOs) to ensure that Kitui county was on forefront of developing their energy master plan. This will ensure ownership of the plan for which then Groots can later track how inclusive policies will ensure increased adoption of clean cooking technologies in the county</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Appropriate budget allocation and expenditure by national and county government on clean cooking</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase (in%) of annual budget  for clean cooking at the national  level</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The data is from the Ministry of Energy Budget estimates for the year 2016/2017. Relevant clean cooking data is only biogas and energy efficient charcoal kilns development</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0,5%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This includes Biogas, biomass cooking and clean cook stoves initiatives.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: Due to national election in 2017, the budget cycle was expedited leaving very little room for CSO participation. It was difficult to access and interrogate allocation figures for 2017/18. The government programme based budgets begins in the preceeding year taking over 8 months hence the budgetting face for 2016/2017 had been accomplished earlier 2016.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="13.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">22-10-2020: In 2019/2020 financial year, government allocates 15.8Billion* shillings to clean cooking sector (Industry development, Capacity building and purchase of related products) representing a 13% increase from 2018/2019 allocations.
 *CCAK budget tracking analysis 2020. | 22-10-2020: In 2019/2020 financial year, government allocates 15.8Billion* shillings to clean cooking sector (Industry development, Capacity building and purchase of related products) representing a 13% increase from 2012/2019 allocations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCAK will track budget allocation on clean cooking sector for FY2019/2020. Budget estimates are expected to be released within the first half of 2019. A modest increase is projected for clean cooking based resources required to implement fuel and labelling standards</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Without budget codes and a tracking criteria, it is difficult to estimate the exact increase/ decrease to clean cooking. However, CCAK tracked the finance bill and budget 2019/2020 for clean cooking sector. In line with fiscal incentive proposal submitted to the National Treasury, and with support from Ministry of Energy the following wins were realised: 
1. VAT zero rating on ethanol fuel.
2. Import duty reduction for biomass cookstoves from 35% to  25%.
3. Increased excise duty on kerosene to discourage its use for cooking.
This marks an increase in the annual budget for clean cooking which we may not be able to quantify at the moment.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs will interogate 2018/19  budget estimates to determine appropriate targets</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: No increase in budget allocation to clean cooking. In fact, no budgets were set aside for the sector. This is because the sector is overshadowed by the electrical and petroleum sectors. Budget analysis of national government financial year 2017/2018 estimates showed no increase in allocations</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase (in%) of annual  expenditure for clean cooking at the national  level</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The data on expenditure is yet to be collected, this will be established after the closure of 2016/17 financial year</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The data on expenditure is yet to be collected, this will be established after the closure of 2016/17 financial year. Data will analysed to find out the extent of Increase (in%) of annual  expenditure for clean cooking at the national  level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: Due to national election in 2017, the budget cycle was expedited leaving very little room for CSO participation. It was difficult to access and interrogate allocation figures for 2017/18. The government programme based budgets begins in the preceeding year taking over 8 months hence the budgetting face for 2016/2017 had been accomplished earlier 2016.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">22-10-2020: Difficulty in accessing audited account reports</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCAK will in the first half of 2019 pursue access to expenditure figures for FY 2018/2019 to be able to project possible expenditure</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Without budget codes and a tracking criteria, it is difficult to estimate the exact increase to clean cooking.
While CCAK was to pursue access to expenditure figures for FY 2018/2019 to be able to project possible expenditure, we were unable to access this figures due to beauraucracy at the national treasury.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs will interogate 2018/19  budget estimates to determine appropriate targets</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Unable to access expenditure figures as the Auditor General budget report is not yet published to the public. This will be done in 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase (in%) of annual  expenditure for clean cooking at the County  level</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The data on expenditure is yet to be collected, this will be established after the closure of 2016/17 financial year</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The data on expenditure is yet to be collected, this will be established after the closure of 2016/17 financial year. Analysis will determine if there have been an Increase by 50% of annual  expenditure for clean cooking at the county  level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: There was no expenditure for clean cooking at the county.Clean cooking had not been identified as a key priority area in the CIDP and consequently there was neither an allocation nor a expenditure incurred</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">22-10-2020: Difficulty in accessing audited account reports</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">GROOTS will pursue  access to expenditure figures for FY 2018/2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Without budget codes and a tracking criteria, it is difficult to estimate the exact increase to clean cooking. However, a general review of clean cooking related programmes in the FY 2018/2019, Kitui County had budgeted Kshs 1.2 Million for materials  woodlots. This was expended 100% and clean cooking champions benefitted from trees for woodlots in their areas. In addtion, the county set aside KSHS 1.8 million for promotion of modern technology productions of kilns &amp; briquette  technology on charcoal hot spot.(source Kitui county website)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">From the allocation given in the CIDP and annual budgets, GROOTS Kenya will be  able to evaluate the expenditures.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Although Kitui spent some money on clean cooking projects, we have not been able to quantify the costs. This is because the expenditure reports are not readily shared.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase (in%) of annual budget  for clean cooking at the County  level</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is no specific budget for clean cooking initiatives by government</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0,05%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This target includes budgets from county government only to support actions towards clean cooking</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: There was no budget allocation for clean cooking.Clean cooking had not been identified as a key priority area in the CIDP and consequently there was no budgetary allocation  in annual allocations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">22-10-2020: Kakamega and Kisumu counties allocate 126M to clean cooking (122 by Kakamega and 4 million by Kisumu Counties). Data from Kilifi, Kiambu and Kitui Missing.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">GROOTS will work to see more allocation in the 2019/2020 budgets in Kitui county. A modest budget increase is projected towards clean cooking in Kitui county based on previous allocation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Without budget codes and a tracking criteria, it is difficult to state the exact increase/ decrease in allocation to clean cooking. Also, financial budgets for Kitui County are not publicly available online but GROOTS consulted Rachel (Energy Officer) who indicated that there was more allocation to clean cooking activities in Kitui county in the financial Year 2019/2020 inluding activities towards: Establishment of County Energy master plan, Establishment of wood fuel woodlots across the county,  Promotion of briquettes technology  and training of  communities on briquettes making technology  were budgeted for Kshs. 3,676,523 and implemented.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CIDP and the annual budgets will be in operation by the end of 2018. Although there are commitments to allocate budget for clean cooking this will only be verified once the finance bill for 2018/2019 is finalized in the first quota of 2018 and a comparison of the allocation done</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: In the 2018/19 budget Kitui allocated 110 million shillings to clean cooking .Kiambu also allocated Ksh.1million towards development of the energy policy in their 2018/19 budget. 2018/19 forms the baseline because of elections in 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advocacy strategies and CSO action plans available</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of CSO action plans developed versus number of CSOs involved</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="100%" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">These have been developed by CSOs in close liaison with the SNV advisory team through a capacity building process for 2017. other plans will be due at the end of 2017 for 2018</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100%"></target>
     <actual value="50.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: Only GROOTS Kenya had developed  CSO activity plans by Febraury   2018</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">22-10-2020: 2 CSOs develop and implement 2 annual advocacy plans i.e. GROOTS Kenya and CCAK</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">GROOTS Kenya and CCAK will be 100%  involved in 2019 activity plans implementation including working together to ensure the joint activity plan is implemented in 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: 2 CSOs activity plans developed by CSOs with 100% engagement in the development process</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV will support both CSOs in developing action plans for 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: CCAK and GROOTS have developed each their 2018 action plans and implemented their 2018 harmonised advocacy plan with support from SNV. GROOTS implemented 100% however transitional challenges in CCAK only saw them implement around 40% of the plans.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual advocacy plan developed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thematic annual advocacy plan developed</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="yes" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">This has been developed by CSOs in close liaison with the SNV advisory team through a capacity building process</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="yes"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: no=0
yes=1
Annual plans have been developed and are ready to be implemented.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: 2 CSOs develop and implement their annual advocacy plans i.e. GROOTS Kenya and CCAK</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="yes">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019 RE advocacy plan reviewed and developed</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: Joint Advocacy Plan developed by Renewable energy Thematic sector CSOs (CCAK and GROOTS Kenya) for 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="yes">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The advocacy plan  will collaboratively be updated for 2019 by both CCAK and GROOTS Kenya with support from SNV</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: CCAK and GROOTS have developed the harmonised advocacy plan for 2019 with support from SNV</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National and county government provide tax incentives for clean cooking providers</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting, implementing new/adjusted tax regulations if favour of clean cooking at national level</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. No legislative framework in the form of policies, laws, standards, regulations and/or guidelines exists, or existing/new suggested legislative framework is detrimental to issue
1. A new/adjusted legislative framework is considered 
2. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been drafted
3. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR framework detrimental to issue has been prevented
4. New/adjusted legislative framework is applied and/or enforced, but without appropriate means and/or not equally applied (across geographical areas, socio-economic groups, men/women &#x2026;.)
5. New/adjusted legislative framework is effectively and equally applied and/or enforced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. VAT Exemption on Clean Cookstoves, 2.Import duty waiver on biomass stoves and 3. Excise Duty waiver on Ethanol 4. zero rating of LPG</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The import duty is still at 15% while biomass fuels are not VAT exempt, this is</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: The situation is as before 1. VAT Exemption on Clean Cookstoves, 2.Import duty waiver on biomass stoves and 3. Excise Duty waiver on Ethanol 4. zero rating of LPG  . The target of 3 was not achieved due to national election in 2017 which left  very little room for CSO . It was difficult to influence the implementation/lobby on tax regulations</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: Achieved import duty retention at 25% for complete cookstoves (EAC team wanted to increase to 35%) and 10% for components. CCAK had meeting with EAC team (wanted to increase to 35%)
Once standards for briquette and pellets  are in place, it might be possible to make a successful lobby for further reduction. On the downside, CCAK was not able to lobby against reintroduction of VAT on clean cooking, however the government reduced the VAT from 16% to 14% due to COVID-19 pandemic.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCAK will support Development  fiscal incentives on clean cooking fuels and taxation policy regime.(Import Duty waiver, duty remission practicability and formula, VAT exemption on pellets and briquettes). CCAK will lead on pushing for fiscal incentives and standards for briquettes. This will be achieved through meeting with the Ministry of Energy and Treasury to push for fiscal incentives. CCAK will convene the various sub committees to discuss pertinent issues on the standards (Briquettes and pellets) leading to development of the standards. KEBS will be engaged/lobbied to form technical team to draft the new standards and later CCAK will actively participate in review and later adoption of the standards.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: 1. CCAK tracked the finance bill and budget 2019/2020 for clean cooking sector. In line with fiscal incentive proposal submitted to the National Treasury, and with support from Ministry of Energy, the following proposals were effected in the budget 2019/2020: 
a). VAT zero rating on ethanol fuel.
b). Import duty reduction for biomass cookstoves from 35% to  25%.
c). Increased excise duty on kerosene to discourage its use for cooking. 

2. CCAK convened a KEBS technical committee meeting on 24th September, 2019. The KEBS TC  approved the official standards development process, taking ownership of the standard development process supported by the stakeholders. The Standards are still in development.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCAK will advocate zero rating of clean cook stoves, ethanol, briqquette and pellets in futher to the exemptions and waivers that exist</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Government&apos;s Big Four Agenda (Local Manufacturing) has had negative impact on clean cookstoves importers linked to increased import duty on cookstoves from 10% to 35%, however, local manufacturers of stoves are favoured with a 100% duty remission on inputs for production of cookstoves as an incentive to open up the manufacture of cookstoves industry to local players. The government introduced a new fiscal incentive on duty remission -100% for local stove manufacturers while negating on the import duty gains by increasing it to 35%. Moving forward, the partners will be seeking redress on remission rebate formula and mechanisms for the rebate.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting, implementing new/adjusted tax regulations in favour of clan cooking at county level</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. No legislative framework in the form of policies, laws, standards, regulations and/or guidelines exists, or existing/new suggested legislative framework is detrimental to issue
1. A new/adjusted legislative framework is considered 
2. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been drafted
3. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR framework detrimental to issue has been prevented
4. New/adjusted legislative framework is applied and/or enforced, but without appropriate means and/or not equally applied (across geographical areas, socio-economic groups, men/women &#x2026;.)
5. New/adjusted legislative framework is effectively and equally applied and/or enforced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is yet to be introduced at the county level</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least have 1 county consider and start planning</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: There is some progress seen by community members especially in the reduced prices of LPG, increased prices of Kerosene.but this needs to be formalized by the county regulations</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: CCAK lobbied at national level on briquettes and pellets but unsuccessful due to lack of standards. For counties (Kakamega and Kisumu), this process has further been slowed with delay in MOU signing. CCAK has however created awareness on climate change solutions which are expected to influence the counties in favour of reduced taxation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCAK will support Development  fiscal incentives on clean cooking sector and double taxation policy regime for briquettes and pellets. Of importance will be the lobbying to counties against double taxation of briquettes and pellet manufacturers. The Government collects VAT while counties levies.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: CCAK lobbied Kisumu and Kakamega counties to abolish the tax on briquettes and pellets which amounts to double taxation. Lobbying will continue in 2020 with the CSO signing agreement with county for joint partnership and one of the expected outcomes is fiscal incentives for briquettes sector in the counties.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">GROOTS will advocate for government regulations/measures in support of clean cooking</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Government&apos;s Big Four Agenda (Local Manufacturing) has had negative impact on clean cookstoves importers linked to increased import duty on cookstoves from 10% to 35%, however, local manufacturers of stoves are favoured with a 100% duty remission on inputs for production of cookstoves as an incentive to open up the manufacture of cookstoves industry to local players. The government introduced a new fiscal incentive on duty remission -100% for local stove manufacturers while negating on the import duty gains by increasing it to 35%. Moving forward, the partners will be seeking redress on remission rebate formula and mechanisms for the rebate.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clean Cooking Guidelines and regulations for Extension Officers, Regulations Developed by Ministry of Health</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting, implementing clean cooking standards and labelling system</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. No legislative framework in the form of policies, laws, standards, regulations and/or guidelines exists, or existing/new suggested legislative framework is detrimental to issue
1. A new/adjusted legislative framework is considered 
2. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been drafted
3. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR framework detrimental to issue has been prevented
4. New/adjusted legislative framework is applied and/or enforced, but without appropriate means and/or not equally applied (across geographical areas, socio-economic groups, men/women &#x2026;.)
5. New/adjusted legislative framework is effectively and equally applied and/or enforced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Meetings have taken place between CSO, government and/or the private sector  related to clean cooking standards, CSOhas recently been approached for information on clean cooking. The discussion on the need for labels has just begun, this will require the development of standards to be completed first</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A labelling system that is supported by all stakeholders- private and public</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: CCAK and Global Alliance for Clean Cookstoves initiated a steering committee on voluntary clean cooking labeling system with focus on biomass stoves. members of the committee included the CCAK secretariat as the implementors of the private labelling framework, Representatives from Global Alliance for Clean Cookstoves and Kenya Beareau of Standards . Two meetings were held for the year. CCAK chosen as custodian/ implementor of private labeling framework. The framework will see clean cooking sector adopt a voluntary , standardadized label for cookstoves within the sector.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: Standards and Labelling system developed and validated by sector members. Sector consulted on the need for a S&amp;L system. Pending finalisation of the market assessment for a voluntary standards and labelling mechanism.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCAK will through a consultant, undertake to conduct and present a market assessment report to inform the voluntary labelling designs for the clean cooking sector. The Market and Impact Assessment shall inform the design and success of the implementation of the cookstoves voluntary labelling in Kenya and inform the understanding of all the various factors that will impact the design and successful implementation of the cookstoves voluntary standards and labelling (S&amp;L) label in Kenya</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: CCAK together with Clean Cooking Alliance, SNV and the Private sector members commenced the  Voluntary Standards and Labeling development process for biomass cookstoves. An advert for Market and Impact assessment study on voluntary labelling was placed in December 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A consultant will contracted in 2018 to develop framwork for private labeling</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Framework for private labelling has not been developed yet but discussions  towards this have begun. A market study for voluntary labelling will be done in 2019 following discussions on the clean cooking sector having a labelling system in Kenya.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in developing, adopting and implementing extension guidelines for health workers</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. No legislative framework in the form of policies, laws, standards, regulations and/or guidelines exists, or existing/new suggested legislative framework is detrimental to issue
1. A new/adjusted legislative framework is considered 
2. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been drafted
3. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR framework detrimental to issue has been prevented
4. New/adjusted legislative framework is applied and/or enforced, but without appropriate means and/or not equally applied (across geographical areas, socio-economic groups, men/women &#x2026;.)
5. New/adjusted legislative framework is effectively and equally applied and/or enforced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the Technical Working Group on Climate change, Energy and Health convened by the Ministry of Health, CSOs will engage Government service ministries (Agriculture, Health and Education) to develop guidelines for extension workers to promote clean cooking</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least a draft framework available by year 1</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: discussions at the national level faciliatted through CCAK are yet to be finalized, they will influence the guidelines at county level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: manual developed by the Health and climate change technical working group is expected to be rolled out this year</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCAK plans to finalise review, approval and validation of the Curriculum and Manuals for Community Health Workers and Volunteers to include household air pollution. GROOTS will work with CCAK at national level and ministry of health at county level to integrate clean cooking into Community Health Workers (CHWs guidelines). The guidelines will be used by CHVs on data collection concerning clean cooking at household level. The data will be used by the government to grow the clean cooking sector towards realisation of the goal of adoption of 5M clean cook stoves by 2010</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: The Curriculum and Manuals for Community Health Workers and Volunteers  have been reviewed to include household air pollution. The approval for inclusion into the Non-Communicable Diseases Manual (13b) happened in August, 2019 with a  pretest training conducted in October for Kisumu, Machakos and Uasin Gishu counties.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCAK together with  ministry of health and other stakeholders have agreed on terms of reference for a consultant to develop a manual for extension workers on clean cooking. GROOTS will work with CCAK at national level and ministry of health at county level to integrate clean cooking into Community Health Workers (CHWs guidelines)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: Ministry of Health is receiving recommendations for review of the manuals and curriculum on Community Health Workers Guideline. Even as this is ongoing, GROOTS Kenya have influenced Kitui Community Health workers to begin reporting on unclean cooking  health related issues. This process is independent of the national process of developing the manuals and curricula. In November 2018, GROOTS Kenya facilitated a meeting with community health volunteers from the 8 sub-counties. After understanding the relationship between clean cooking and health, they agreed to begin reporting on clean cooking related heath issues. This report will help to ensure that the ministry Integrated clean cooking in the CHVs training modules .</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of new/adjusted guidelines developed at national level</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the Technical Working Group on Climate change, Energy and Health convened by the Ministry of Health, CSOs will engage Government service ministries (Agriculture, Health and Education) to develop guidelines for extension workers to promote clean cooking</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">An guideline to support mainstreaming of clean cooking into Ministry of Agric and Health</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: discussions at the national level faciliated through CCAK are yet to be finalized, they will influence the guidelines at county level</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: Process ongoing towards finalisation of curriculum, manuals and job aids for community health workforce on Household Air Pollution . Final manual and job aids will be validated and rolled out in partnership with other development partners and Government. Should be ready in Sept 2020.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finalise review, approval and validation of the Curriculum and Manuals for Community Health Workers and Volunteers to include household air pollution.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: The Curriculum and Manuals for Community Health Workers and Volunteers  have been reviewed to include household air pollution. The approval for inclusion into the Non-Communicable Diseases Manual (13b) happened in August, 2019 with a  pretest training conducted in October for Kisumu, Machakos and Uasin Gishu counties.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCAK together with  ministry of health and other stakeholders will foresee the domestication and the development of a manual for extension workers on clean cooking. Term of Refernce for the consultant has been agreed upon.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: CCAK through the Climate Health and Energy TWG with the ministry of health and other stakeholders have identified the existing curriculum and manuals for the community health workers and volunteers for review to include the Household air pollution component. This will be accomplished  in March, 2019 following a concept proposal to have the said revision in the first quarter of the year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO capacities improved</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of CSOs with increased advocacy (incl. use of evidence) capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their advocacy capacities guided by a list of advocacy criteria. The score is the average of individual CSO&apos;s scores.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of CSOs with increased leadership capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their leadership capacities guided by a list of leadership criteria. The score is the average of individual CSO members&apos; scores.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs with increased thematic knowledge</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their thematic knowledge guided by a list of knowledge related criteria. The score is the average of individual CSOs&apos; scores.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">total number of CSOs that have increased their organisational capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The organisational sustainability of CSOs has been assessed via a guided self-assessment,</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased commitment / political will to adopt practices and/or policies</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of policy makers/decision makers that demonstrate increased support for clean cooking at the national level</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: Out of the 5 decision makers identified, only 1  (Deputy Director of Renewable Energy) has shown increased support as expressed in her demand for CSOs to be included in all working group meetings as important sector representatives. There are new office beares since the national elections held in 2017, increase in support will be possible to report after engagement in 2018. New Officers have not yet been rated but CSOs expect to do so in the first half of 2018 as Officers settle in and begin to play active role in their office.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="5.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: 1. Directorate of RE- Dan Kithinji, - Increased support noted. During Renewable Energy Day, he spoke strongly for clean cooking. Also during lobby efforts reversal of VAT amendment bill proposed, he and others supported memo to parliament. The department has also supported Energy resource centres at county level and sought support from development partners to capacity build energy officials at the county 
2. MoH department of preventive and promotive health- Dr.  Lolem Lokolile Increased. Initiative on HAP manual progressing well. The document is used as substantive training kit for CHV. Due to their commitment more partners e.g. University of Liverpool and GIZ have joined agenda to address HAP
3. KEBS standard directorate- Ms. Betty and Mary have shown increased support. They have been key in fastracking process on the carbonised briquettes standard
4.KIRDI lab testing and protocols- Nathan Bogonko and Eng. Erastus Gatebe - increased support. Have given clear direction on what is needed for the sector including Voluntary labeling for biomass cookstoves. They have also given support to the consultant on the S&amp;L study, readily providing data compared to before
5. Kepsa energy sub-committee; Eng. James N. Mwangi - Increased support noted. Ensured issues RE sector are incorporated in the KEPSA lobby matrix. Lobbied for review of VAT on clean cook stoves.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCAK and GROOTS will monitor  support from the following for clean cooking:
&gt;NETFUND Ag. CEO- Samson Toniok 
&gt;Directorate of RE- Dan Kithinji, MoH department of preventive and promotive health- Dr.  Lolem Lokolile
&gt;KEBS standard directorate- Mr. Lukorito, KIRDI lab testing and protocols- Nathan Bogonko and Mr. Makoha
&gt;Other committees include: Parliamentary committee on energy; Chairperson Hon. Gikaria, David and  Vice Chairperson Hon. Pukose, Dr Robert
&gt;Kepsa energy sub-committee; Eng. James N. Mwangi 
&gt;senate round table; Chairperson Sen. (Eng.) Ephraim Mwangi and  Vice Chairperson Sen. Seneta Mary Yiane</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: The strategies employed to reach out to policy makers included boardroom lobbying and co convening of technical working groups/meetings etc. e.g. CCAK was able to engage KEBS through the working groups that bring together its members to discuss sector issues (policy/standards). CCAK analysis of 2019 engagements confirms increased support from 3 key decision makers:                                                    

1. Directorate of RE- Dan Kithinji; In 2019, CCAK engaged positively with Dan Kithinji of Ministry of Energy who provided support in houeshold cooking sector study report development; interministerial committee meeting convening, coordination &amp; chairing, fiscal incentives development and follow up (Ministry did a letter of support to the National Treasury). Mr. Kithinji was instrumental to the launch of the Sector Study (joint effort between Ministry &amp; CCAK) in November 2019, by the Minister for Energy resulting in increased partnerships and media mentions for CCAK.        
2. MoH department of preventive and promotive health- Dr.  Lolem Lokolile - the engagement with Mr. Lokolile has been positive, resulting in the development of the Household Air Pollution (Non communicable diseases) curricullum and manual; and in CCAK nomination to the planning committee for the First Climate Change, Health and Energy conference. Furthermore, CCAK staff were incorpotated as ToTs for the UHC pilot for this particular curriculum.
3. KEBS standards directorate- Mr. Lukorito - CCAK engaged positively with Mr. Lukorito, with KEBS fully involved in the development of standards for carbonised briquettes and charcoal. Through the engagement, KEBS also picked CCAK to be in the Technical Committee for cookstoves standards. The review of the biomass cookstoves standards also benefitted from this relationship. 
4. CCAK engaged NETFUND although the engagement was not at CEO level (Mr. Samson Toniok) but at Heads of Department level. HoDs engaged included Dr. Mwan ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs will continue close engagement with the identified offices, explain its agenda convincingly with evidence support and seek collaboration</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: &gt;The policy maker rating will be done early 2019. It was not possible to assess support  in the early phase of 2018 as coming from the elections  there were new office bearers, only getting started and with little known about them. Their interest could only be confidently assessed after some period of engagement in the sector and this will be done in 2019. However, indications so far show a number of key stakeholders as having interest in clean cooking:
&gt;Support for clean cooking was observed in word and action during the RE conference in Diani by Dr. Mwaniki of NETFUND. In planning for the conference GROOTS lobbied for a gendered approach in the conference session structure  and the award process. 2 Women enterpreneurs won in the clean cooking award. Following the engagement in Diani on RE conference, Kilifi county approached Groots Kenya for collaboration. This has been captured in the 2019 action plan and a context analysis will be done in Kilifi entry point being the CEC incharge of Energy and Environemnt.   
&gt;NETFUND agreed to include CCAK and GROOTS Kenya in the RE sector working group; through RVO project CCAK co-partners with netfund on the RE conference while Groots mobilises its women champions to attend and engage in the discussions

&gt;Ministry of Health through Mr. Lolem Lokolile Bosco is showing increasing support for clean cooking: Household Air Pollution control prioritized as a key preventive measure for consideration during the consultative workshop to develop strategic framework for Primary Health care held between 5th - 9th November, 2018 in Nokras Riverine, Sagana. Manuals on CHV will be updtaed in 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of policy makers/decision makers that demonstrate increased support for clean cooking at the county level</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-06-2018: office bearer are different after the election in 2017 hence we are starting from scratch in rating support for clean cooking. The new office bearers are yet to be rated.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21-10-2020: &gt;Kilifi draft Energy Policy was validated. GROOTS is supporting efforts to engender the energy bill. Directors in Kilifi county are more vocal on issues of clean cooking. 
&gt;Kiambu CEC Energy was changed this year, despite this change the office has remained supportive and draft climate change policy has now been presented to the county  
&gt;Challenges were experienced in Kitui this year due to staff changes. Energy Officer Kitui, Rachel Mwangangi continues embrace GROOTS champions as advocates of clean cooking. The champions are involved in the development of the annual development plan. 
&gt; MOU signing has taken longer than expected in Kakamega and Kisumu counties. Even so the lead officers show keen interest on clean cooking by involving their legal offices for finalisation on the MoUs. In Kakamega the MoU had been submitted to legal team but was delayed due to change of Key Officer (CEC, Water Environment and Natural Resources).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&gt;GROOTS Kenya and CCAK will target continue to track support form the related county departments and other policy makers in Kitui-Minister John Mokua and Kiambu- Esther Wangombe of the Energy and climate change directorate and CEC. Mr. Kuria especially at the county assembly to ensure that the master plans and the policies being developed are passed. 
&gt;GROOTS will work with Kilifi county- Dr.James Kapanya Nguzo to ensure that they institute policies that support the clean cooking agenda.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">26-04-2020: GROOTS analysis of 2019 engagements confirms increased support from 3 key decision makers:
1. Kiambu climate change and energy  Director Esther Kaguima - her support has increased. She was earger to learn about clean cooking After interacting with GROOTS and exposure to Kitui and Kwale county she started on high note and has supported the climate change policy. Her office convenes the Technical committtee meetings on the policy   
2. Kiambu, CEC Water Environment,Energy &amp; Natural Resources Mr. David Kuria  - His support has increased since 2019. He has been very vocal on clean cooking. In community meetings he speaks about the clean cooking technologies and biogas. He selected GROOTS to seat in the environment committee.
3. Kilifi, Chief Officer Dr. Nguzo Kapanya - He has been supportive, was involved in contracting cosultant and in validation meeting for context anlysis for Kilifi

In addition, GROOTS has noted inceased  support from the following key officers:
&gt;Energy Officer Kitui, Rachel Mwangagi - She proudly and openly says that she heard about clean cooking and became passionate from interacting with GROOTS work. It was through her efforts that Kamanyi Primary school in Kawongo location, Kitui rural, Kitui County was supported with an improved cook stove. She always works with the clean cooking champions 
&gt;Kilifi energy officer Mr. Baya  - He is the only officer in his department. He rallies champions to support clean cooking and in his social media he talks about clean cooking and available technologies. He mobilizes his seniors and community leaders to attend meetings to discuss clean cooking. He only spoke about solar and grid energy before.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target  5 leaders i.e the Governer, CEC environment/ Energy, CEC Health, Majority party leader and Directors in the three department  that are now in office</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30-04-2019: The policy maker rating will be done early 2019. It was not possible to assess support in the early phase of 2018 as coming from the elections  there were new office bearers, only getting started and with little known about them. Their interest in clean cooking could only be confidently assessed after a period of engagement in the sector and this will be done in 2019. However, indications so far show a number of key stakeholders having interest in clean cooking:
The two Ministers of Environment from Kitui and Kiambu and the renewable Energy Lead at the ministry of energy at the national level have been on the forefront in supporting the clean cooking agenda. They allocated budgets to clean cooking initiatives. In Kiambu they allocated budget to develop the energy plan. In Kitui county they allocated budgets to clean cooking projects. 
In Kiambu, Department of Energy and natural resources through the County Executive Committee Member(CECM) office; 
&gt;&gt;On 28th  November  2018, The County government of Kiambu facilitated the first  stakeholders meeting towards development of the Kiambu County Climate Change and Energy Policy
&gt;&gt;On 28th of November 2018, The County Government of Kiambu-Ministry of Environment, Energy and Natural Resources accepted to include one of the Community Clean Cooking Champions as part of the Technical Committee members to develop the energy and climate change policy. 

County Executive Committee Member(CECM) Kitui, Department of Health
&gt;&gt;on 13th November 2018  the Ministry of Health through Community health workers agreed to collect Clean cooking data 

CECM Kitui,  Department of Energy and natural resources, 
&gt;&gt;In the draft 2018/19 budget released by Kitui County in Feb 2018, the Ministry of Environment budgeted for building of 80 rocket stoves for poor households, training champions on clean cooking, procuring of 20 briquette machines and supplying of 800 Maendeleo stoves. 
&gt;&gt;In March 2018 the County Government of Kitui set a b ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
