<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41152786-SP1167</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41152786" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity to Account - Phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Boundary partners (direct beneficiaries) in dairy and sunflower market systems,
- Strategic partners in government, private sector, media and research/NGOs relevant to the two market systems.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact: 
Improved and inclusive access to basic services, and strengthened business environment for sunflower and dairy small holders and agribusinesses.
Outcomes: 
&#x2022;	The formal institutions of government at local and national level that control and impact on Dairy and Sunflower markets, promote inclusive market development 
&#x2022;	Policy reforms and institutional changes (formal and informal) that promote Sunflower and Dairy development are implemented</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TAM programme was established in August 2018 and funded by UKAID. TAM is a flexible, learning programme that is responsive to the dynamics of local agricultural market issues and builds the capacity of citizens to hold government accountable and enabling governmental institutions&#x2019; ability and willingness to respond by focusing on getting both sets of actors to solve problems collectively. The programme will work flexibly with agricultural smallholder farmers, farmer organisations, women and youth, value chain associations, multi-stakeholders platforms, public and private sector organisations, research institutes, civic action, lobby and advocacy groups, and media. We will make connections and relationships horizontally and vertically and at all levels of government in order to identify governance barriers to agricultural market development and work together to develop solutions. 
The project approach aims for systemic change in the targeted markets of dairy and sunflower and also selected issues that will impact on the agricultural business environment overall.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="7" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The range of SNV&#x2019;s role in working with partners in this TAM programme includes: 
&#x2022;	Provide objective information and analysis: starting with joint mapping, tracking and studies, i.e. develop local knowledge, to provide data, market intelligence and analysis on &#x2018;what is the reality on the ground&#x2019;? (especially private sector, women and youth); 
&#x2022;	Support the analysis of the market systems and support the development of the ToC and action plan that will enable change;
&#x2022;	Guide the planning, monitoring and evaluation of Interventions using rolling case studies linked to Outcome Mapping as a tool;
&#x2022;	Support groups and actors to engage with government around key issues;
&#x2022;	Coordinate the actions and build the capacity of the actors involved in the action, including political actors e.g. councillors; 
&#x2022;	Provide technical assistance to ensure that lesson learning takes place; 
&#x2022;	Support actors as they start to scale vertically and horizontally.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transforming Agricultural Markets (TAM) project aims to improve livelihoods and economic opportunity for smallholder farmers by empowering these marginalised players to affect changes in market systems through engaging with government and private sector providers. 
Our Theory of Change is that working with citizens, private sector and government at sub-national level on specific, actor-led systems issues to produce data and facilitate stakeholder analysis which broadens understanding and builds consensus, can strengthen accountability relationships for collective action which makes existing policies work at the local level and provides visible and written evidence for national level policy dialogue and reform.  
As a result of working in this manner to address agricultural market development, we aim to achieve the following impact and outcomes:
Impact: Improved and inclusive access to basic services, and strengthened business environment for sunflower and dairy small holders and agribusinesses.
Outcomes: 
&#x2022;	The formal institutions of government at local and national level that control and impact on Dairy and Sunflower markets, promote inclusive market development and reflected by;
-	The extent to which these institutions demonstrate behaviours that indicate they are advancing dairy and sunflower market development  
&#x2022;	Policy reforms and institutional changes (formal and informal) that promote Sunflower and Dairy development are implemented reflected by;
-	The level to which governance stakeholders (government, market actors, networks) engage with the partners to identify and address the policy issues and institutional obstacles to inclusive sunflower and dairy market development
-	The level to which dairy and sunflower smallholders and agribusinesses (men, women, youth, bottom of the pyramid) engage and contribute to identify and address the constraints to market development with governance stakeholders</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transforming Agricultural Markets TAM</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Tanzania</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="7483" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tom Ole Sikar</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+255 754 481 802</telephone>
   <email>tolesikar@snv.org</email>
   <website>http://www.snv.org/country/tanzania</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation 
P.O. Box 13304 | Off Simeon Road | Kijenge Area | Arusha | Tanzania</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Edgar Philberth</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">M&amp;E Advisor</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>ephilberth@snv.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-3.37171 36.694771</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="311" percentage="100" vocabulary="98"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-31">800000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="100"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.MS-WORD.DOCUMENT.MACROENABLED.12" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/7483/document/Final%20narrative%20at%20800%2C000%20August_O7b3nnG.doc">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Proposal</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/7483/Project_7483_current_image_2018-12-28_17.29.50.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved and inclusive access to quality services and strengthened business environment for sunflower and dairy small holders and agribusinesses</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For sunflower, the programme will be implemented in Mbeya, Songwe, Rukwa and Katavi regions.
On the other hand, for dairy the programme will be implemented in Siha and Hai districts in Kilimanjaro region in Tanzania.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of small holders using extension and input supplier services</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="250000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% annual sales increase generated by market actors (SHFs, processors, input suppliers) in target commodities</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of SHFs who have adopted 1 or more climate smart production techniques</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of female headed smallholder households using extension and input supplier services</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of processors who are initiating inclusive business arrangements with new producers</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The formal institutions of government at local and national level that control and impact on Dairy and Sunflower markets, promote inclusve market development</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">District council planning processes and council plans reflect intention to advance agricultural market development</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policy reforms and institutional changes (formal and informal) that promote sunflower and dairy development are implemented</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local government and regional staff and councillors meaningfully contribute to identifying and addressing constraints to inclusive service delivery and business enabling environment</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Smallholder farmers, processors and input supplier representatives, especially women and youth, meaningfully contribute to identifying and addressing constraints to inclusive service delivery and business enabling environment</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
