<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41152786-1801-3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41152786" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voice for Change Partnership-Honduras-Food and nutrition security</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Honduras-Food and nutrition security</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the &quot;Voice for Change Partnership&quot; (V4CP) programme, SNV works to strengthen civil society organisations (CSOs) in their role as advocates and lobbyists. We work together with IFPRI and over 50 CSOs to foster collaboration among relevant stakeholders, and influence decision-makers with solid and contextualized evidence to get the interests</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim to improve the food and nutritional security status of the population. This will be achieved through the forming of alliances and platforms, the development, approval and implementation of FNS policies, adequate budget allocation, and improved FNS services that align with policy operational planning and budget.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Honduras</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Honduras</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41152786" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The International Food Policy Research Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="4005" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>honduras@snv.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Col. Florencia Norte, Blv. Suyapa
Edificio Corporativo Solaire, Tegucigalpa
Honduras</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="HN" percentage="6"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.072275 -87.192136</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">246871</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-01-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">284419</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">284419</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41152786-3552" ref="NL-KVK-41152786" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Honduras</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">246871</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41152786-3552" ref="NL-KVK-41152786" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/4005/Project_4005_current_image_2016-03-07_16.40.19.PNG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41152786-3552" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strong evidence supporting the proposal of CSOs available.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">nr of evidence-based policy reports and/or knowledge products made available to CSOs that support their advocacy plan</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="8" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. The study on Improving Food Security and Small Scale Agriculture in Honduras is available through the Information and Communication Technologies (ICT), made available by the Sustainable Development Network (RDS),  www.santic.rds.hn
2. Analysis of legislation on Food and Nutrition Security, El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras and Nicaragua, made available to the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations - FAO, http://www.fao.org/publications/en/
3. Evaluation of the Impact of FNS Policy, Programs and Projects in Regions 12 and 13, available through the Sustainable Development Network (RDS), www.rutasan.hn
4. Contribution of Water to Food Security and Nutrition, published by FAO, http://www.fao.org/cfs/cfs-hlpe/informes/es
5. The state of Food Insecurity in the world, economic growth is necessary, but not enough to accelerate the reduction of hunger and malnutrition, published by FAO , http://www.fao.org/cfs/cfs-hlpe/informes/es
6. National Strategy for Food and Nutrition Security, published by Technical Unit for Food and Nutrition Security -UTSAN,siteresources.worldbank.org/.../Estrategia_de_Seguridad_Alimentaria_Honduras.pdf
7. Current situation of Food and Nutrition Security in Honduras to December 2013, published by UTSAN , rutasan.hn/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/InformeSituacionActualSANvFInal2014.pdf
8. Situation of poor rural women in Honduras and their access to land and credit, Made available by V&#xED;a Campesina.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The   target for 2020 is tree knowledge products available to CSOs. Two by IFPRI   and one for the CSOs/SNV:
     1) Update of the FNS budget, 2019. IFPRI
     2) Analysis of the FNS budget for two municipalities. IFPRI. Municipalities   will be defined by CSOs.
     CSOs will a) select two municipalities that have approved FNS municipal   policies, and b) will accompany the field work.
 

    3) Final measurement of the degree of perception of the Quality and   Accessibility of Food and Nutrition Security services in Honduras. CSOs/SNV</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="11.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: The target for this indicator was 3 knowledge products produced, to date 11 have been developed, described below:

1) Study: The budget for Food and Nutrition Security in Honduras: 2017-2019. Prepared by IFPRI.
2) Study and analysis of investment differentiated by FNS pillars: Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a, Choluteca, Tambla, Lempira. Prepared by IFPRI, supported by partner CDH and ASONOG. April 27, 2020
3) Summary sheet Knowing the situation of Food and Nutritional Security (FNS), water and gender in some villages of Lempira, Choluteca and Ocotepeque. Prepared by IFPRI, supported by partner RDS.
4) IFPRI discussion paper, July 2020. Gender and Food Security in Honduras.
5) Bifolio: What should we know about the situation of Food and Nutritional Security (FNS) in Lepaterique? prepared by RDS with the accompaniment of CDH, FOPRIDEH, ASONOG; August 5, 2020; IFPRI approved.
6) Bifolio: What should we know about FNS Food Security and Nutrition budgets? prepared by RDS with the accompaniment of CDH, FOPRIDEH, ASONOG; August 5, 2020. Approved by IFPRI.
7) Social Oversight Bifolio &quot;Tool to strengthen community participation in Food and Nutrition Security&quot;; prepared RDS with the accompaniment of CDH, FOPRIDEH, ASONOG; August 7, 2020. Approved by IFPRI.
8) Informative card on Climate Change, agricultural practices and Food and Nutritional Security (FNS) in Taragual; prepared by RDS with the accompaniment of CDH, FOPRIDEH, ASONOG; August 5, 2020. Approved by IFPRI
9) Bifolio: FNS in our municipalities (Choluteca); challenges of climate change, migration and access to productive resources. Prepared by RDS with the accompaniment of CDH, FOPRIDEH, ASONOG; August 5, 2020. Approved by IFPRI
10) Informative card on Why should we know about Food and Nutritional Security in the southern zone? Prepared by RDS with the accompaniment of CDH, FOPRIDEH, ASONOG; August 5, 2020. Approved by IFPRI
11) Informative card on Let&apos;s talk about water, gender and FNS in our communities. Prepa ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected to generate 5 knowledge products by IFPRI:
1) Study of mono crops, such as, for example, African palm and the effects on the FNS of Honduras.
2) Budget and expenditure analysis broken down by municipalities and target groups.
3) Analysis of laws and other regulations that are a barrier to an inclusive FNS policy.
4) Analysis of gender, empowerment of women and vulnerable groups.
5) Analysis of access to water for irrigation and drinking water in the dry corridor

by the SNV, a knowledge product will be generated to measure the perception and quality of services in FNS, with the same population consulted and in the same geographical areas.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="8.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: &quot;Eight products of (8) knowledge were developed during the year 2018, (6 elaborated by IFPRI, 2 led by FOPRIDEH)
1) Framework of policies related to FNS. Report completed May, 2018.
2)  Framework of policies related to FNS. Summary report and PPT completed May, 2018.
3) 2015-2017 budget for Food and Nutrition Security. Report completed March, 2018.
4) Production of African palm and sugarcane in Honduras. Report completed May, 2018.
5) Production of African palm and sugarcane in Honduras. Summary report and PPT completed May, 2018. 
6) Water, Gender and FNS in Honduras. Summary completed December, 2018. 
7) PyENSAN&#xB4;strategic positioning of CSOs: a participative analysis. Report completed October, 2018.
8) Contributions to the proposal of the PyENSAN 2018-2030, a view from the civil society organizations participating in the V4CP program and other organizations and related spaces. Report completed September 21, 2018.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eight policy reports and/or knowledge products have been identified that are available to CSOs. Under the IFPRI program, 6 studies on FNS will be made available to CSOs to be prepared in 2017: Analysis of Conditional Transfers in the Dry Corridor, Analysis of the Budget and Budgetary Expenditure 2016 in FNS, Prioritization and M&amp;E of Investments, among others.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: Three (3) knowledge products were developed during the reporting period:
1) Compendium of FNS Laws. Prepared by CSO partner FOPRIDEH, as part of V4CP products. Its edition and publication is pending
2) FNS informative sheet. Prepared by IFPRI, March 2017. It was requested by partner SCO and used by them in their meetings with EU, Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, and FNS governmental technical unit.
3) FNS informative brief. Prepared by IFPRI, June 2017. It was requested by partner SCO and used by them in the workshops and meetings with the private sector, educational institutions, commonwealths and other groups to get information about regional FNS priorities and proposed actions to face the main challenges, as inputs for the actualization process of the national FNS policy. It includes a word summary and a pp presentation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">One on-going SNV knowledge product: Measurement of perception of population from selected communities on quality of and access to FNS and RE- clean cook stove services. The results of this research will be presented in a workshop to CSO in August and to political candidates in the last quarter of 2017.
For the second semester 2017 IFPRI will deliver to CSO the following four (4) knowledge products:
1. Status of nutrition and health in the Honduran population
2. FNS budget analysis
3. Impact of direct-conditioned cash transfer mechanism
4. Access to water for human consumption
Progress on these researches will be present to CSO in the September learning event.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="10.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: &quot;The goal for the second semester was to have 5 knowledge products (1 by the SNV and 4 by IFPRI). A total of 10 knowledge products were produced exceeding what was proposed, since the CSOs subsequently requested executive summaries of each of the studies. The following knowledge products are described:

IFPRI developed and presented to the program 9 summaries and knowledge products during the reporting period:
1) Poverty and Nutrition in Honduras, August 1, 2017
2) Executive Summary Poverty and Nutrition in Honduras, August 2017
3) Prioritization of Investments, 2017
4) Executive Summary Prioritization of Investments in Honduras
5) A Review of Public Expenditures for Food and Nutrition Security of Honduras, September 2017
6) Summary Public Expenditure for Food and Nutrition Security in Honduras.
7) Budgets for the FSN, September 2017
8) Water and Food and Nutritional Security in Honduras, 2017
9) Summary Water and Food and Nutrition Security in Honduras

SNV generated 1 knowledge product in the framework of the measurement on the quality and accessibility of services in FSN, some results were presented in the forums / discussions held in different areas of the country:
10) Measurement of the perception of the degree of Quality and Accessibility of FNS services in Honduras, July 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Two (2) knowledge products have been identified and will be available to CSOs in 2019, which will be prepared by IFPRI.
1) Access to productive resources and their relation to food security and nutrition.
2) Analysis of the budget in FNS 2018.

IFPRI will hold a series of workshops to strengthen the capacities of CSOs in the generation of evidence. The CSOs will accompany the field survey and work together to analyze the data.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: The set target for this indicator was 2, however, seven knowledge products were developed: four (4) by IFPRI and tree (3) by partner CSOs.
1) Access to productive resources and Food and Nutrition Security in Honduras, September 19. IFPRI developed the product with participation of partner CSOs. At the same time, IFPRI developed 3 workshops to train and empower CSOs for the development of the study:
a. Workshop 1: Identification of objectives and specific topics of the study.
b. Workshop 2: Methods to generate questions that work well for the objectives of the study. Define indicators, the sample, places, prepare the survey and define the roles for the study.
c. Workshop 3: Survey review and piloting, define work plan in the field, how to use tablets, data monitoring and cleaning.

2) Summary sheet on the Food and Nutrition Security Situation (FNS), water and gender in Honduras, Oct. 19. Prepared by IFPRI with support of partner CSO RDS.
3) The budget for Food and Nutrition Security 2018. Prepared by IFPRI
4) Differences in the estimate of FNS expenditure between FAO/UTSAN and IFPRI. Prepared by IFPRI.                                                                                                                                             These documents were shared and discussed with the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO) and the Technical Unit for Food and Nutrition Security (UTSAN).

5) Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a, Choluteca FNS Municipal Policy with a climate change approach. Prepared by the Municipal FNS Table with support of partner CSO CDH.
6) El Triunfo, Choluteca FNS Municipal Policy with a focus on climate change.  Prepared by the Municipal FNS Table with support of partner CSO CDH.
7) Report &quot;&quot;Analysis of the FNS Law and proposal for reform or regulation&quot;&quot;.  Study led by FOPRIDEH with participation of ASONOG, CDH, RDS and SNV/V4CP</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of portals and websites that are accessible to CSOs that generate evidence for advocacy issues, including a portal or sub-portal of the V4CP on a FNS system operated by IFPRI</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="6" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The portals and websites that CSOs consider available and used are the following:
i) SAN-ECLAC Portal: dds.cepal.org/san/;
ii) Regional Observatory of Food and Nutritional Security: http://www.sica.int/obsanr/;
iii) International Food Policy Research Institute: http://www.ifpri.org/en;
iv) Central American and Caribbean Food Security Portal (PSA): http://cac.foodsecurityportal.org/regional-sub-portal/latin-america;
v) FAO: Food Security: http://www.fao.org/economic/ess/ess-fs/en;
vi) Integrated Portal of Food and Nutrition Security of Central America: http://www.sica.int/san
Portals and websites will be accessible by SNV, programs and projects from international donors and lenders.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is   not expected to make new portals or websites available to CSOs.
     CSOs will participate with IFPRI and SNV in the generation of knowledge   products. So they will be exposed to new information.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: No new target was set for this indicator, since CSOs participated with IFPRI in the generation of knowledge products.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Currently, CSOs have access and use twenty-three portals and websites, however, not all of them in the same way: 1 OSC (22), (2), (14) and (8), the most frequently used sites are:
1. http://www.agrifood.net/
2. https://www.facebook.com/vozparaelcambio/?fref=ts
3.http: //www.paho.org/hq/index.php? Option = com_content &amp; view = article &amp; id = 8861 &amp; Itemid = 1355 &amp; lang = en
4.http: //www.territorioscentroamericanos.org/content/%C2%BFqu%C3%A9-es-ecadert
The less frequently used sites are:
5. http://rutasan.hn/centro-de-recursos/
6. http://www.ifpri.org/publication/2013-global-hunger-index
7. http://voz.bonnykoo.com
8. https://www.sica.int/san/
9. https://www.sica.int/san/
10. http://www.worldbank.org/region/lac
The other sites are used very little.
It is expected to facilitate access to at least two portals or websites that are useful for the generation of evidence.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="9.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The target established for this indicator was 2 and the CSOs have shared nine sites and web pages with relevant information on the FNS theme such as:
1) http://infocafes.com/portal/biblioteca/analisis-de-la-cadena-de-valor-del-cafe-con-enfoque-de-seguridad-alimentaria-y-nutricional. Analysis of the value chain of coffee with focus on Food and Nutrition Security,
2) http://www.fao.org/docrep/019/as545s/as545s.pdf/ Final document of the study &quot;Analysis of the Value Chain of the Coffee with Focus on Food and Nutritional Security&quot; Swisscontact.
3) https://www.icefi.org/comunicados/honduras-icefi-advierte-que-el-incremento-de-isv-general-al-15-sumio-en-la-pobreza-66000/ Impact of the increase in the ISV in poor households.
4) https://www.cepal.org/en/publicaciones/42281-perspectivas-la-agricultura-desarrollo-rural-americas-mirada-america-latina/ Perspectives of agriculture and rural development in LA 2017.
5) http://www.observatoriodescentralizacion.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Mancomunidades-de-Honduras-Julio-2015.pdf/ Guide of Commonwealths in Honduras.
6) cespad.org.hn/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Seguridad-y-soberania-alimentaria.pdf/ Food Security and Sovereignty                7) https://obsan.unah.edu.hn/propuesta-politica-publica-para-la-san-en-honduras-2016-2030/ FNS&apos;s Public Policy Proposal
8)https://germanwatch.org/sites/germanwatch.org/files/publication/20398.pdf/ Climate risk index
9) https://www.flacsoandes.edu.ec/libros/digital/52365.pdf/ Public policies on food.

The information available on these web pages on the topic of FNS, was used in local workshops and also as part of context analysis for proposals that two CSOs have formulated on the subject; it has not been used for advocacy actions. Information was also used for the Forum on FNS and Coffee in the community of Tambla, Department of Lempira.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Currently 6 portals and websites are being used by CSOs, it is hoped to facilitate access to at least one portal.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: In the base line CSO reported six (6) known webpages related to FNS. During the reporting period, IFPRI identified ten (10) webpages related to FNS which were linked to the V4CP webpage: http://vozparaelcambio.org/ (http://voz.bonnykoo.com/en/page/enlaces-externos). The 10 websites are listed below:

Apart of the 10 websites identified, V4CP created during the reporting period two (2) websites: 1) facebook: https://www.facebook.com/vozparaelcambio/ created and administered by CSO partner RDS. In there, information related to FNS and RE as well as news of the program activities are posted; 2) A wapp chat &quot;Voz para el Cambio SNV&quot; was created to share news on both topics.

List of websites linked to the V4CP webpage:
1) Red de Sistemas de Alerta Temprana contra el Hambre (FEWS NET): http://www.fews.net/es/central-america-and-caribbean
2) Observatorio de Seguridad Alimentaria para las Am&#xE9;ricas (Infoagro): http://infoagro.net/programas/Seguridad/default.aspx
3) Instituto de Nutrici&#xF3;n de Centroam&#xE9;rica y Panam&#xE1; (INCAP): http://www.incap.org.gt/index.php/es/acerca-de-san
4) Plataforma CELAC Honduras (CEPAL): http://plataformacelac.org/pais/hnd
5) Programa regional de CGIAR en Cambio clim&#xE1;tico, Agricultura y SAN (CCAFS): https://ccafs.cgiar.org/es/regions/latin-america
6) Banco Mundial: http://www.bancomundial.org/es/region/lac
7) Banco Interamericano de Desarrollo - BID: http://www.iadb.org/es/temas/agricultura/agricultura-y-seguridad-alimentaria,1163.html
8) Programa Mundial de Alimentos-PMA: http://es.wfp.org/hambre/el-hambre
9) Organizaci&#xF3;n Panamericana de la Salud y Organizaci&#xF3;n Mundial de la Salud: http://www.paho.org/hq/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=8861&amp;Itemid=1355&amp;lang=es
10) Climate Change Agriculture and Food Security: http://es.csa.guide/</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target set for the first semester 2017 was to facilitate to the CSO a website to post news and other relevant information related to the program and its two themes FNS and RE. The web page was designed by IFPRI and it is administered by SNV communication specialist located in the Nicaragua office. 
On top of that 10 websites of interest have been identified and linked to the V4CP web site and a Facebook page for V4CP was created.
For the coming months the effort will focus on facilitating and monitoring the use of this sites for the CSO instead of adding more web sites. As part of this a workshop on information and communication search techniques will be developed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-03-2018: There are no new websites. Effort was focused on facilitating and monitoring the use of this site for the CSO instead of adding more web sites.
14.62% frequency of access to portals or websites
26.92% Content satisfaction

For the second semester of 2017, the program&apos;s effort was aimed at monitoring the use of the sites created and or made available to CSOs. CSOs were consulted on how often they access these sites and how they rate the contents of the site. Valuations are shown below:
1. http://www.territorioscentroamericanos.org/content/%C2%BFqu%C3%A9-es-ecadert: frequency use 20% (3 CSOs use -1 no) and the content was rated between good and excellent.
2. http://www.agrifood.net: use frequency 25% (3 CSOs use -1 do not) and good and excellent content.
3. www.foodsouvereignty.org: use frequency15% (1 CSO uses it and 3 do not), good content.
4. http://rutasan.hn/centro-de-recursos: frequency use 20% (2 CSOs use it and 2 do not), good content
5. http://obsan.edu.hn/, this page is not working
6. ftp://ftp.fao.org/en/ESA/policybriefs/pb_02_en.pdf/, this page is not working
7. http://www.ifpri.org/publication/2013-global-hunger-index: frequency use 20% (2 CSOs use it and 2 do not), good content.
8. RLC-Prensa-L@LISTSERV.FAO.ORG: frequency use 5% (2 CSOs use it and 2 do not), bad and excellent content.
9. http://www.fao.org/americas/publicaciones-audio-video/panorama/2016/es: frequency use 15%, good and excellent content.
10. https://www.facebook.com/FIANHonduras: frequency use 10% (2 CSOs use it and 2 do not), regular and good content.
11. https://www.facebook.com/vozparaelcambio/?fref=ts: frequency use 30% (2 CSOs use it and 2 do not), good content. This page is administered by RDS. A total of 1,251,949 people reached directly and 2,311, 875 people indirectly throughout the national territory, with 256,264 people interacting with publications. In the interaction there was a greater participation of women (60,%). There is greater participation of the you ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The effort of the program for this year is to focus more on the issue of advocacy using the evidence that has been generated to date, therefore, it is not expected that more portals or websites will be made available to CSOs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: CSOs got information from current portals they already have available so no new target was set for this indicator. V4CP efforts were oriented to support CSOs advocacy actions. Therefore, there are no new portals or websites made available to CSOs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased influence of CSOs on the agenda setting of main actors of the SINASAN (UTSAN, FNS Regional &amp; municipal tables or committees) located in their geographical areas</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of influence of CSOs on agenda setting in several instances of the SINASAN and other platforms of their interest in this topic.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. CSO has no or only occasional interaction with key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector 
1. CSO has regular interactions with key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector
2. CSO gets opportunity to explain its interests towards key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector
3. CSO&#x2019;s interests are &#x2018;put on the agenda&#x2019; and are discussed among stakeholders in government and/or the private sector</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">A joint analysis with the CSOs on their degree of influence in setting the agenda was carried out using the rubric of evaluation and it was concluded that only one CSO has had occasional contacts with the UTSAN, however, it has not been possible to establish In its agenda, basically this relation is on the FNS Program Route that executes the organization. Each organization gave its score on the evaluation rubric, agreed on the score and considered that its influence level is 0.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2.5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs   will maintain the target 0f 2.5 for this indicator as they believe they will   not be able to influence UTSAN and FNS Regional Tables &#x2018;agendas. They expect   that with the implementation of their action plans, their level of   coordination and collaboration with UTSAN and regional tables will   remain.
     CSOs efforts will focus on the actions at national level of the   Coordination Committee of FNS Municipal Tables. Workshops, forums, and   meetings will be held to strengthen thematic knowledge and advocacy and   negotiation skills. Summaries of V4CP knowledge products will be   socialized.
     The Coordination Committee is expected to interact with governmental   agencies related to FNS, such as the Technical Unit for Food and Nutrition   Security (UTSAN), the National FNS Council (CONASAN) and the FNS Technical   Committee (COTISAN) and with FNS Regional Tables established.
     Similarly, the implementation of the PyENSAN will be monitored, which   includes the participatory design of the action plans prioritized by CSOs.   The implementation of the communication strategy will continue to influence   key actors and the general public.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: The target of this indicator was 2.5, the CSOs applied the evaluation rubric to measure their degree of influence on the agenda of the UTSAN, Municipal and Regional Tables of Food and Nutrition Security (MMSAN and MRSAN) and in consensus the 4 CSOs maintain their score of 2.5 almost reaching the maximum mark within the evaluation rubric.
CSOs have frequent communication and meetings with members of the MMSAN and FNS Regional Tables in their area of influence. They managed the preparation of studies on the subject of COVID-19 and its impact on FNS, and also supported the Coordination Committee of the FNS Network advocacy actions on municipal authorities of some municipalities in the southern and western areas of Honduras. Actions are planned and executed accordingly to the institutional agendas at the regional level. CSOs kept the communication with UTSAN teams in the central and western regions of the country and advocate to include the municipal tables in SINASAN structure, however it has not been possible to put CSO interests on the agenda.
FOPRIDEH with accompaniment of CDH, ASONOG and RDS succeed in keeping alive the space that the FNS Surveillance Commission represents. The first COVISAN Report on FNS situation is currently being prepared, as well as its action plan 2021.

On the other hand, the FNS Municipal Tables with support of CSOs are advocating for the design and allocation of budget for the implementation of FNS municipal policies. It is expected that as the Network of Tables is consolidated at the national level, advocacy actions at the local, regional and national levels will be able to continue even if V4CP ends.

An awareness and advocacy campaign is being implemented with the objective of promoting the FNS issue and influence the implementation of the PyENSAN.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs do not expect significant changes in their level of influence in the second semester but next year on regional and municipal tables in view of the effects of the actions to strengthen the capacities of the FNS tables and their strategic allies and also for the advocacy actions in 2018.

Some CSOs consider that it is not easy to place in the agenda of regional tables the program`s topics since they focus normally on very specific topics such as production, and socialization of new projects that arrive in the area. They are willing to listen but not to add new topics in the agenda. They also commented that they are tired of being in processes of advocacy and training, but they want to carry out awareness actions, school gardens. It has not been possible to define work plans due to the lack of resources for the execution of the activities. They also commented that there is a lot of training process without direct action.

With the FNSTU UTSAN there is little communication and coordination. Coordination and cooperation actions are somehow isolated although there are already efforts to bring together both the SNV as CSOs. There is no willingness of UTSAN to take in account the data generated by V4CP. A strategy to capture the interest of UTSAN on what the program and the CSOs can contribute to the update of the PyENSAN is needed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: A joint analysis was done with the CSOs using the evaluation rubric to measure their degree of influence, resulting in an average value of 2.41667 which is adjusted to a value of 2.5 the Target for this semester was 1.

No significant changes were expected in the level of influence this year, however, there was more openness by the actors given the update of the PyENSAN. Regional consultations were carried out as the base for the discussion with regional key actors and the UTSAN in relation to the update of the PyENSAN. In the consultations, participants had the opportunity to offer opinions, suggestions and concerns, and present their demands to key actors in each region. Taking in account the findings of the regional consultations the partner CSOs and other allied organizations prepared a document that includes the differences, congruencies and divergences they found in the draft proposal of the PyENSAN, and their recommendations and contributions to the proposal, document that was the base for the discussion with UTSAN and the evidence for advocacy.
The relationship with UTSAN is more fluid and the FNS issue is on the table, as a result of CSOs and SNV advocacy actions as well as the influence of two important actors (FAO and the EU) that have participated in meetings promoted by V4CP to advocate for the inclusion of the CSOs contributions to the proposal PyENSAN, which is pending approval. 

For some CSOs the participation of FOPRIDEH and the consultant hired to facilitate the process of developing the contributions of CSOs to the PyENSAN in the Meeting on the National Council of Food and Nutritional Security (CONASAN), where representatives of the General Coordination of Government Secretariat (SCGG), UTSAN, FAO, Secretariat of Agriculture and Livestock, Secretariat MiAmbiente, Honduran Council of the Private Sector (COHEP) and FOPRIDEH (member of CONASAN by law), also contribute to improve the relationship with UTSAN, and it was also an opport ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that by 2017 there will be greater communication and meetings with key stakeholders such as NSFNS (SINASAN), political parties, government, private sector and other platforms and alliances. Target set for the second semester of 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: A jointly analysis was done to measure the level of influence of CSOs in the agendas of key actors. The main conclusion is that CSOs have no influence or limited influence on key actor&#x2019;s agendas. CSOs keep occasional communication with key actors. With the FNS governmental Technical Unit there are just verbal agreements to consider for the FNS policy actualization the evidence that the V4CP is generating with the workshops, focal groups and meetings with the private sector, educational institutions, commonwealths, NGOs, and root-based organizations.
One of the partner CSO participates by law in the FNS`s Interinstitutional committee COTISAN. It monitors and inform SNV and the rest of CSOs. There is not political will to open the space for other CSOs in the FNS official structure and the space to influence the agenda of international organizations, and the private sector is very narrowed and difficult to open.
Progress in creating alliances and opening spaces at local level is reported by CSOs. For example in the South region, partner CSOs are influencing the agenda of the FNS Regional committee. In the West region partner CSOs are influencing local government to open spaces to advocate for the municipal FNS policy to be approved and budget to be allocated.
V4CP activities contribute to improve the interinstitutional coordination in the North region. At national level partner CSOs play a more informative role even though some have been interviewed on FNS theme.
Three CSO filled the rubric with score of 0 and just one CSO filled the rubric with score of 1. (1/4=0.25 rounded to 0). CSOs expressed their interest to increase their influence on key actor&#x2019;s agendas and highly value the efforts done. New strategies are needed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs do not consider that there can be a significant change, but it is expected that by the first semester of 2018 the level of influence with the municipal boards can be increased, not at the regional level, nor with the FNSTU.

CSOs have the expectation that they can influence some deputies and mayors who could be elected in the general elections and who participated in the various forums, discussions held and that at the level of the regions a political pact was signed, which is going to affect on it.

CSOs consider that there must be a strategy of approach, differentiated to take an approach and the best way is through the strengthening of the tables and grassroots organizations that support this issue. The tables are not multi-stakeholder and can integrate civil society organized and linked to FNS processes; there if you can manage an agenda or propose it.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-11-2018: &quot;Using the Evaluation Rubric, a joint analysis was made with CSOs about their degree of influence giving an average value of 1.16657 that will be adjusted to 1, the goal for this first semester was 1.
(FNSTU) UTSAN: a CSO has had occasional and circumstantial contacts and was invited once to a FNSITCO (COTISAN) meeting. Another CSO commented that its relationship is more local. Another CSO has a by-law relationship with COTISAN. As a member, it has occasional contact, and participate in COTISAN meetings, without concrete actions being taken. One CSO expressed that they have frequent communications and can express themselves on some issues, but they do not have a high degree of influence since the actions of interest of the program are not placed on the agenda. They have contact with decision makers but not concrete results at national level, for example, they do not know what will happen with the FNS system SINASAN, they do not have access, and they have not been able to express in this space the interest of the regional and territorial tables on some topics such as transgenic. As tables they have differentiated positions.
Regional Tables: A CSO in the western area has already structured an agenda, has influenced local public policies, many in implementation and has a strong coordination work, frequent meetings, in spite of that, it has not yet been possible to place the interests of the program and define work plans due to the lack of resources for the execution of the activities, the actors indicate a lot of training process without direct action. A CSO participates in the Table R13 south zone, there is an agenda that is discussed and the points are placed in that agenda, information is shared and the actions are planned. The last months they have talked about the process of the policy, however, the interests of the program are not yet placed on the agenda and they are not discussed between the parties. A CSO has frequent communication and conside ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are confident that the events programmed for the second semester of 2017 will contribute to increase the communication with key actors but they are not optimistic about increasing their influence on key actor&#x2019;s agendas in the short run. Still, CSO`s have moderate expectations to influence new candidates to take in account the evidence generated by V4CP in the workshops, focal groups and meetings with the private sector, educational institutions, commonwealths, NGOs, and root-based organizations about FNS priorities and proposed actions.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: &quot;The level of influence on the FNSTU agenda and the regional and municipal tables was analyzed with the CSOs, although the proposed goal was 0, the CSOs assessed that their level of influence has improved specifically with the municipal tables in the south, center and West of Honduras, so when evaluating the evaluation rubric it averaged 0.83333 rounded to 1.
With the FNSTU in the West there have been sporadic communications, spaces have been shared, presentations of the program have been made, but we can not say that they have an interest in it. At the central level, occasional contacts have been made with some technical staff, but spaces have not been opened at the level of decision makers.
There&apos;s participation in the regional tables of the western zone and the central zone. No decision-making is still involved. There is a risk of being used to validate governmental processes.
With the municipal tables it has worked in the West and South, it is of interest the approval of a FNS national public policy, which supports the work they have done at the local level and that incorporates the demands they have, There has been shared and reflected on the role of the municipal tables and generation of policies at the municipal level.
There has been support from the tables in the stakeholder mapping for the invitations to the consultation days and relevant information generated from the program has been shared.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2.5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;CSOs consider that the events scheduled for the second semester of 2019 can maintain their level of influence and will contribute to increase their communication with key stakeholders. CSOs do not consider that a significant change can be generated with the UTSAN and the FNS Regional Tables to influence their agendas, but the relationships with the different actors that have been achieved so far will be maintained and become more solid.
For the second semester, CSOs plan to work, in their geographic areas, with FNS Municipal Tables and influence their agendas. Efforts will also focus on the creation of the National Network of FNS Municipal Tables with the purpose of advocating on national and local FNS public policies. 
It is expected that the National Network will interact with governmental bodies related to FNS, such as the Technical Unit on Food and Nutrition Security (UTSAN), the Council of Ministers, the Ministry of Finance, International Cooperation Agencies, among others, without neglecting the support to Municipal Tables that constitute the main base of the Network.
A series of visits will be made to different regions of the country to identify and characterized the FNS Municipal Tables to find out: when they were created, who participates, liaison with the municipality, sources of funding, organizations that have been accompanying them; and, to explore if they are interested in participating in a structure like the National Network.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: &quot;The target for the period was 2.5 and CSOs gave a score of 2.5 based on the evaluation rubric..
The coordination with UTSAN has been more fluid in 2019, compared to previous years. UTSAN has shown greater openness, CSOs had frequent communications and meetings both in the central and western areas of the country. They had the opportunity to present V4CP experiences. CSOs succeed influencing UTSAN for the reactivation of COVISAN. But it is not yet possible to influence UTSAN to incorporate civil society in the development of action plans and in UTSAN actions for the implementation of PyENSAN.

CSOs participate and have frequent communication with the regional tables in their area of influence. CSOs had the opportunity to present V4CP experiences and main findings of studies. However, it has not been possible to put on the agenda the actions that the program is carrying out. 
CSOs participate and maintain a permanent communication with municipal tables in their area of influence. They jointly define agendas and advocacy plans focused on the design and approval of municipal FNS public policies. Partner CSOs provide technical assistance and accompaniment in the advocacy actions. A meeting was held on November 13 and 14, 2019 with representatives of FNS municipal tables. As a main result, a Coordination Committee was established and partner CSOs are working with it to prepare a basic action plan to join the V4CP advocacy actions and promote FNS theme in their regions. Partner CSOs succeed in influencing the Coordination Committee agenda.
&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs consider that the events scheduled for the first semester of 2019 can maintain their level of influence and will contribute to increase their communication with key stakeholders. They are not optimistic about increasing their influence on the agendas of decision makers, at least in the short term, given their distrust of the state bodies that are a political entity with little interest in developing effective processes in the communities. On the other hand, CSOs consider that is not easy to place V4CP agenda in the Regional Tables since they usually focus on very specific topics, such as the production and socialization of new projects that reach the south and west.
The CSOs do not consider that a significant change can be made, but the relationships with the various actors that until now have been achieved are maintained, established and made more solid. CSOs consider that effective strategies should be developed to continue advocacy processes, an internal analysis of what has been done well and what actions should be improved internally.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actualisation, approval and implementation of an inclusive and participatory FNS Policy for the provision of quality FNS services</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree of progress in the actualization, approval and implementation of the FNS policy.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. No legislative framework in the form of policies, laws, standards, regulations and/or guidelines exists, or existing/new suggested legislative framework is detrimental to issue
1. A new/adjusted legislative framework is considered 
2. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been drafted
3. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR framework detrimental to issue has been prevented
4. New/adjusted legislative framework is applied and/or enforced, but without appropriate means and/or not equally applied (across geographical areas, socio-economic groups, men/women &#x2026;.)
5. New/adjusted legislative framework is effectively and equally applied and/or enforced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">A new FNS Policy is being considered, since the previous one was no longer valid in 2015, through the National Autonomous University of Honduras, a draft FNS Policy was prepared, which will be presented to the corresponding instances in the next few days .
The evaluation rubric was applied and 1 was agreed as a score.
The actors involved in formulating the FNS Policy are:
Public Sector: General Coordination Secretariat, Ministry of Health, Ministry of Development and Social Inclusion of Honduras (SEDIS), National Congress of the Republic, Ministry of Agriculture and Livestock (SAG).
Those who approve the policy is the National Congress and can also approve the executive by Decree of the Council of Ministers.
Those implementing the policy are:
Public sector: Ministry of Health, SAG and SEDIS.
Private sector: companies that are in the food sector, all companies that supply inputs to the agri-food sector, among others.
Academy: Universities linked to nutrition such as: National Autonomous University of Honduras (UNAH), National Pedagogical University (UPNFM) and technical schools.
Actors related to the topic:
Civil Society: RDS, ASONOG, FV, HdH, FOPRIDEH, V&#xED;a Campesina, Sara Alliance, Foodfirst Information &amp; Action Network (FIAN), among others.
International Cooperation and Funding Agencies: World Bank (WB), European Union (EU), International Fund for Agricultural Development (IFAD), among others
The specific elements of this enabling environment that will be reflected in the content of the policy will depend on the results of the consensus process that CSOs will carry out with potential partners and alliances. When agreements are reached, new indicators will probably be added to monitor the content of the FNS inclusive policy.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: The target of this indicator remains at 3, CSOs applied the evaluation rubric and consider that no significant progress has been made to increase the score.

During 2020, the COVID-19 pandemic has changed government priorities. In this context, PyENSAN is left out of government plans, FNS strategies, programs and activities from the government are executed under a new regulatory framework, emergency decree PCM-030-2020 and not under PyENSAN, which was approved in 2019. Additionally, the Government assigns null or very limited responsibilities to the governance structure of SINASAN, especially to UTSAN, being one of the main actors identified to advocate on for being the entity in charge of the theme. There is an approved PyENSAN, but without a budget or plans for its execution. The CSOs consider that there is no political will to implement the PyENSAN , it seems that it was not part of the government agenda but part of international agreements as the PyENSAN is an initiative assisted by the &quot;Impact, Resilience, Sustainability and Transformation of Food and Nutrition Security &quot;(FIRST for its acronym in English) contract signed for the European Union and the United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) to actualized FNS policies in 40 countries.
Therefore, V4CP concentrated its advocacy efforts on UTSAN to highlight the role of FNS Municipal Tables, influence budget allocation through the study, analysis and presentation of its main findings on investment differentiated by FNS pillars: Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a, Choluteca, Tambla, Lempira. Social media and radio campaign to promote the implementation of the PyENSAN and the rol of FNS Municipal Tables. The radio messages focus on: 1) Script 1: Guideline 1 PyENSAN, 2) Script 2: Guideline 4 PyENSAN, 3) Script 3: Guideline 5 PyENSAN, 4) Script 4: Guideline 7 PyENSAN, 5) Script 5: Guideline 9 PyENSAN; scheduled in 23 community radio stations in the North, South, Center and West parts of the country. Tw ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Progress is expected in the updating of FNS policy, given that FNSTU within its work plan has contemplated its approval in November 2018.

This means that by 2018, program activities will focus on increasing participation, improving coordination between CSOs and municipal and regional FNS committees to disseminate and socialize the updated policy, define their intervention strategies and roles in the implementation, monitoring and social auditing of FNS policy, it is hoped that said policy will be inclusive and participatory.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: The target of this indicator was 2, the assessment rubric was applied jointly with CSOs and resulted in a score of 2 and all CSOs agreed to this rating. The National FNS Policy and Strategy (PyENSAN) has been drafted but it has not yet been approved and there is no clarity about the budget that will be assigned to it and how it will be considered in the current fiscal year. 
The process and the draft of the policy were socialized, it was not by decision of the  governmental entity but by the advocacy and management that the CSOs have made for the update of the PYENSAN. The CSOs associated with the V4CP and other allies delivered, in September 2018, to the governmental entity the document containing the first observations on the Policy document. Subsequently a series of meetings were held to influence the incorporation of the contributions to the PyENSAN proposal.2018 - 2030. A look from the civil society organizations participating in the program and other organizations and related spaces.
The meetings were key to work together in the drafting of the incorporations, share information and identify spaces for collaboration and advocacy at the local and regional level. As a result of the evidence-based advocacy process led by the partner CSOs of the V4CP, the incorporation into the PyENSAN of the agreed contributions presented by V4CP was achieved. It is expected that the Policy will be approved 2019. 
The Firts/FAO coordinator informed that the implementation of the PyENSAN has already begun, there are advances in the preparation of: the Action Plan for Nutrition in Honduras (PANH), the Plan for the indigenous population and Afro-descendants, and in the socialization and validation of the methodology of the PyENSAN in workshops with commonwealths.
The UTSAN and FAO are planning meetings in February 2019 with the Planning Units (UPEG) of the different Secretaries of State to socialize the PyENSAN and advocate for the inclusion in their budget of 2020 f ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No major progress is expected in this indicator in 2017. Giving that 2017 is a political year it is expected to have progress around May 2018 with the new FNS participative policy.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: &quot;The goal of this indicator was 1, the evaluation rubric was applied with CSOs and a score of 1.25 was considered (3 CSOs gave score 1 and 1 CSO gave a score of 2).
At the ordinary meeting of COTISAN on April 6, 2017, UTSAN (FNSTU) presented the plan for the review and update of the FNS policy and strategy. The proposal of the General Secretariat for Government Coordination (SCGG) is to prepare a single document since many chapters of the policy are part of the strategy. Also to facilitate the coherence between both instruments. The goal of the FNSTU is to have the proposal ready for approval in November 2018. The CSOs, as well as the National Autonomous University of Honduras (UNAH), have expressed their interest in participating in a transparent and inclusive process.
The FNSTU contracted a consultant to update the FNS Policy. The UNAH, National Autonomous University of Honduras prepared a draft FNS Policy which was delivered to the FNSTU. It is considered that there is already a proposed FNS policy updated by the consultant, although it has not yet been socialized. The European Union and FAO are supporting this initiative.
Due to the above, strong advocacy work will be required with the following actors: i) FNSTU (Responsible for updating the strategy and FNS policy and the FNS investment plan), to make available the evidence generated in the research that supports the strategic points of the CSOs in the different regions, especially in the area of the ACS-GAFSP; ii) the National Congress (body that approves the reforms and laws of the country), is an advocacy effort led by FOPRIDEH with the support of international organizations and donors such as the G16); iii) the regional and municipal FNS committees. At this level, the promotion is promoted by CSO participants in these platforms, contributing their experience and institutional capacity to strengthen and monitor actions at the municipal, departmental and regional levels; iv) Invest-H, which i ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that the PYENSAN will be approved and published in the official newspaper &quot;La Gaceta&quot; by mid-2019. This will ensure that the contributions of CSOs have actually been incorporated. According to the law, the step that follows is that PyENSAN passes for review to the Secretary of Government, Public and Social Policies and then to the Council of Ministers for approval.
The CSOs consider that 2019 advocacy should be oriented to influence the FNS action plans and their implementation, especially the nutrition guidelines; open other spaces such as AMHON to work at national and local levels; keep the relationship with the municipal tables to socialize the PyENSAN; impact on transparency, social oversight and accountability. Develop an strategy to approach the National Anti-Corruption Council (CNA), National Commissioner for Human Rights (CONADEH) as they belong to the monitoring committee of the FNS to be reactivated; develop tools that can be applied for evidence on the use of public resources. Advocate for the legal recognition of the municipal and regional tables and propose law reforms on the subject.
Strengthen the capacities of the FNS committees in terms of social oversight, follow-up on policy, raise awareness and socialize the PyENSAN, support in municipal policies, definition of budgets, so that people can prioritize the FNS and allocate budget in the municipalities plans. In the same way, conduct awareness-raising processes for the population and campaigns on the subject.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: &quot;The goal of this indicator was 3, applying the evaluation heading the 4 CSOs gave a score of 3. Given that on February 5, 2019, under executive decree PCM-086-2018, the National Food Security and Nutritional Policy and Strategy 2018-2030 was approved . However, to date it has not been implemented, the policy was approved with the objective that it has a regulatory scope at the level of public institutions and an indicative character at the level of the different private, non-governmental organizations and different actors at the national level, Regional and local.
Participating CSOs of V4CP developed a collaborative work for the construction of inputs needed to make evidence-based advocacy at different levels. They carried out consultations to know the problem of Food and Nutritional Insecurity (INSAN) in some regions of the country. The consultations generated information that the CSO partners of V4CP and interested FNS instances incorporated an inclusive proposal for positioning before the update of the PyENSAN.
The CSOs followed up on the update of the PyENSAN through meetings with the UTSAN. As a result of the advocacy process led by the CSO members of the V4CP, the incorporation of several of the agreed contributions was achieved, which was corroborated in the PyENSAN published document.

From the perspective of CSOs, they identify certain weaknesses: lack of responsibility, unequal participation of key actors and lack of information and understanding of their role in the real organizational structure, inefficient budget allocation, inadequate and insufficient coordination between agencies and weak integration from the private sector and universities in response to this multisectoral problem. Together, these factors make the governance system fragile and inefficient to generate the desired results.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved functioning of the accountability mechanisms of the FNSTU and the V4CP CSOs</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree to which the accountability mechanisms of the FNSTU and the FNS-CSOs are functioning.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. CSOs are not provided with information - about decisions, decision making processes, policies - by government / companies
1. CSOs are provided with information - about decisions, decision making processes, policies - by government / companies
2. Existence of ad-hoc fora for consultation with CSOs.  CSOs are given the opportunity to provide information to decision makers
3. Government /companies are transparent in their decisions and actions. Government / companies provide feedback on demands of CSOs
4. Formal structures / procedures for feedback/consultations with CSOs are established
5. Government/ companies act on the demands of CSOs through changes in rhetoric and changes in policies and practices
6. Government / companies pro-actively engage with CSOs in determining the policy agenda, in seeking information and possible options</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">An analysis was carried out jointly with the CSOs and an analysis was made of how the mechanisms of accountability are perceived and it was concluded that although there are formal structures to inform decision making, at the national level these structures are not functional. At the local level they work better, but fail to influence the national agenda and FNS policy design, let alone accountability processes. In Honduras, the demands of citizens or organizations are not answered, there is no transparency of decision-making, there is no political will or mechanism that obliges government and companies to justify their decisions and actions, the voice of CSOs Is not as heard, although there are positive examples of advocacy work and achievements obtained through it.Each organization gave its score on the evaluation rubric, agreed on the score and considered that the result is 0.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs   are not optimistic about the increase in this indicator for 2020, given the   current conditions of the country, loss of confidence in the current   authorities, as well as the short time remaining for V4CP in Honduras.
 

    On the other hand, according to the evaluation rubric, CSOs do not consider   UTSAN will inform them about decisions, decision-making processes regarding   FNS. UTSAN portal has not updated information accessible to CSOs. So far   there has been a good relationship, but it has not been possible to establish   a greater bond.
 

    However, they will focus their efforts on continuing to influence COVISAN   and will work to strengthen the monitoring capacities of COVISAN and its   links with the National Anti-Corruption Council (CNA) and other government   audit units through the development of workshops and field trips with members   of COVISAN and UTSAN to learn about experiences in neighbouring countries,   analyse the inputs and get agreements for the implementation of accountability   mechanisms.
 

    Links will also be established with the CNA and the Secretariat of Human   Rights, Justice, Governance and Decentralization to know the mechanisms of   responsibility established for Civil Society Organizations (CSOs).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: The target of this indicator is 0, the CSOs applied the evaluation rubric and jointly maintain their score of 0. Since they consider that the government makes decisions without consulting, nor is their practice to inform about policies or laws that they elaborate. The accountability mechanisms established by the government are not appropriate to carry out actions of social oversight, there are no spaces for consultation and dialogue with the public.

Giving that V4CP is in its final phase, CSOs prioritized COVISAN as supervising unit of the FNS System (SINASAN) created by Legislative Decree 25-2011. According to Executive Decree PCM-28-2015, COVISAN is made up of a representative of: 1) The Federation of Non-Governmental Organizations for the Development of Honduras (FOPRIDEH), which presides over it, 2) The National Convergence Forum (FONAC), and 3) The person who holds the presidency of the National Congress Commission that deals with FNS, and the actors contemplated in executive agreement 041-A-DP-2013: the National Anticorruption Council, and the National Commissioner for Human Rights (CONADEH).

Even though the SAN Law approved in 2011 establishes the figure of COVISAN and that said instance was regulated in 2015, it is until June 2019 that it is activated and holds its first ordinary meeting organized by V4CP partner FOPRIDEH. With the activation of this space, the preparation of the First COVISAN report is in process, binding on reprogramming, reform, adaptation and social oversight of policies, laws, programs and projects. FOPRIDEH together with CSOs will influence so that this report is presented to the National Council for Food and Nutrition Security (CONASAN), Interinstitutional Technical Committee for Food and Nutrition Security (COTISAN), Technical Unit for Food and Nutrition Security (UTSAN) and to the public opinion in general, as defined by law and that the findings and recommendations can be followed up accordingly and actions to be ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are no actions in 2018 related to the improvement of accountability mechanisms, so no progress is expected in this year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: There were no defined advocacy actions to be carried out in 2018 on this indicator, therefore the result is kept at 0. An analysis of how the the governmental entity accountability mechanisms are perceived was carried out jointly with the CSOs. The conclusion is that CSOs are not provided with information about decisions and decision-making processes related to the FNS issue. In Honduras, one of the difficulties in this area is that there is no information available, there is no budget line for the FNS issue, and anything is for them taken as FNS execution because the budget lines are not clearly defined or identified. There is not transparency in decision-making, there is no political will or mechanism that forces the government, institutions and companies to justify their decisions and actions. It is difficult to generate an execution report of what has been invested or contributed to the FNS theme. CSOs seek information on their own and in some cases there is openness of decision makers, but it is not their initiative to provide information. However, there are other CSOs that are related to government institutions that provide and share information. 
The form of accountability of the CSOs is differentiated, some make periodic reports to the contributing entities, perform internal and external audits, present reports to the Board of Directors and Assembly, present a report to URSAC, SAR. In some projects the progress of the processes or the results are presented to the population. But they also consider that there are always opportunities for improvement and consider that other mechanisms can be established such as: a broader accountability to beneficiaries and other actors. ASONOG, a partner CSO started the instalment and implementation of a planning and monitoring system and find the process challenging, as it is a new experience.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are no action in 2017 related to improvement of the accountability mechanisms and so no expected progress on it in 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: &quot;An analysis was carried out with CSOs to assess the degree to which progress has been made with accountability mechanisms and it was determined that it continues at 0. There are no actions in the 2017 plan that contribute to this indicator, however, CSOs commented :
a) CSOs are not provided with information on decisions, decision-making processes, performance reports, etc. Example: there is no disaggregated information for the FNS issue, there is no specific line and when information is obtained it is outdated and the waiting period is long.
Limited access to information. There is a Law of Secrecy that prevents access to information, and if it is obtained, it can not be assured that it is reliable.
b) There are formal structures to inform decision-making, but at the national level these structures do not work. At the local level they work better but they can not influence the national agenda and the design of the FNS policies, much less in the processes of accountability.
c) There is no official information on the status or progress of the FNSTU in updating the FNS Policy. By other means an OSC learned that the FNSTU would make a presentation at the R13 table (only table at that time and with little participation from civil society). It was decided to participate and in this way we had access to the methodology that FNSTU would apply in the regional tables for updating the FNS Policy and Strategy.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No significant changes are expected for this indicator in 2019 but some actions will be carry on to establish links with the National Anticorruption Council (CNA) and the Office of Planning and Follow-up of the Secretariat of General Coordination of Government (SCGG). The purpose of these links is to get to know the accountability mechanisms established for the government offices and validate tools for social control and accountability that a CSO has. Advocate for their implementation by UTSAN and the follow-up of the CSOs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: &quot;The target set for this indicator is 0 and the score given by partner CSOs is 0 based on the application of the evaluation rubric. Currently the CSOs are not provided with information on decisions, decision-making processes - government policies and platforms related to Food and Nutrition Security issue - FNS. In partner CSOs opinion, there is little government interest in the FNS issue, and there is an increase in political instability.
In spite of the above, CSOs advocate to install the FNS Surveillance Commission (COVISAN) that is the body responsible for monitoring the National FNS system SINASAN. By law COVISAN meets twice a year and issue an annual report to the National Food Security Council (CONASAN) and the Technical Unit for Food and Nutritional Security (UTSAN) and to the general public. By law, FOPRIDEH is member of COVISAN. FOPRIDEH invited other CSOs to participate in these meetings, and they are supporting the process. Three meetings were held in 2019:
1) First meeting to inform the actors about the process of updating the National Policy and Strategy of FNS (PyENSAN 2018-2030) and the contributions made from civil society to the PyENSAN and to municipal FNS policies. Also a summary of what is expected for the COVISAN, its role and structure. Tools and experiences of social auditing in FNS.
2) Presentation of regulations and laws regarding compliance with the Right to Adequate Food.
3) Construction of the main lines for the first report of the commission.

With the FNS Regional Tables, partner CSOs will keep participating and searching for more spaces for civil society participation. These tables are promoted from the state, and have little participation of FNS municipal tables and civil society.
&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased commitment and political will for the participatory development of FNS policy, enabling the provision of quality FNS services</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of decision makers that demonstrate increased support for the initiative for an enabling inclusive policy for the delivery of quality FSN services.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advocacy   efforts will focus on UTSAN, and the other bodies of the SINASAN as well as   related state Secretariats such as Health, Finance, and the General   Coordination of Government, and the National Congress. CSOs will advocate to   join efforts with the SUN Movement and with FAO.
 

    CSOs believe that there is no political will for the design and   implementation of the Action Plans of the PyENSAN since there is a lack of   responsibility and unequal participation of key actors who also do not understand   their role in the current organizational structure. Lack of budget allocation   for implementation. Improper coordination and integration between agencies   and entities linked to the FNS. Fragile and inefficient FNS governance system   that does not generate desired results. Add to the above, the lack of   confidence and trust in the government, in its willingness to properly   implement programs and projects that favour the status of the FNS of the   population.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: The target of this indicator is 1, the CSOs identified and evaluated 3 political leaders and/or decision makers who have demonstrated support for the V4CP program and the actions that have been carried out on the FNS issue.

The CSOs evaluated Municipal Mayor of Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a, in Choluteca they consider that she is a solidary person. The Municipal Council as well as technical staff supported the construction and approval of the Municipal Policy of FNS and participated in V4CP different events. She allowed IFPRI consultant access to municipal financial information for the study on FNS Investments. She requested support from CDH to prepare the 2021 budget proposal in which it is expected to consider the FNS pillars. She is an influential and trustworthy person as she assumed a leadership role to support the construction and approval process of the FNS policy of Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a.

Municipal Mayor of Santa Ana de Yusguare, Choluteca is considered a supportive person as he convened many actors and participate in the assembly for the constitution of the FNS Municipal Table. He is an influential and trustworthy person as he supported the constitution and strategy and actions of the FNS Municipal Table. 

Municipal Mayor of Tambla, Lempira, evaluated as a supportive person, has opened the way for the gathering of information for IFPRI study of FNS investments in two municipalities. With the support of ASONOG he organized events to present said results to the personnel of the Municipal Corporation and members of the FNS Municipal Table. In view of the results of the study, he asked for technical support to prepare the 2021 municipal budget, which is expected to consider the pillars of the FNS. He is an influential and trustworthy person as he assumed leadership and has the political will to provoke changes working jointly with ASONOG promoting FNS issue in Tambla.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">04-07-2018: &quot;In 2016, 9 influential people were identified and evaluated. The evaluation done by the CSOs indicates that these actors did not support much the inclusive policy of FNS and considered that they had a certain level of confidence. For 2017, the CSOs considered that with the programmed activities the interest of 2 decision makers could be awakened. However, due to the political situation in the country, as a result of the general elections held in November 2017, these decision makers are no longer in the positions that had been considered relevant to support the program&apos;s objective in terms of updating of the FNS policy, so it is not possible to perform the measurement at this time. It is expected that in the first quarter of 2018 the names of the new officials will be announced.
A mapping of new actors will be done. The activity is scheduled to take place in the April Workshop where a political analyst will be invited to give a general overview of the situation in the country, presenting various possible scenarios in the immediate future.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: The target of this indicator is 0, however, has been identified 1 person who has demonstrated support to V4CP initiative reached at the end of the year 2018. Given the expiration of the (FNS) Food and Nutrition Security Policy and Strategy of Honduras and its lack of regulation and implementation, the State of Honduras decided to update the FNS Policy and Strategy (PYENSAN) 2018-2030 in response to current needs in FNS material, led by the UTSAN.
The participating CSOs of the V4CP developed collaborative work for the construction of the necessary inputs to make evidence-based advocacy at different levels.
They made consultations to know the problem of Food and Nutrition Insecurity, in the regions: South zone, Atlantic littoral, Central, West and zones bordering the Central District. The consultations generated information that the CSO partners of V4CP, and stakeholders interested in FNS incorporated into an inclusive positioning proposal before the update of the PyENSAN. As a result of the advocacy process, the incorporation of the consensual contributions presented by the CSOs into the PyENSAN was achieved, which was corroborated by the partner CSOs in the final draft received from of the governmental entity ; Still pending approval.
The meetings were key to work together in the drafting of the incorporations, share information and identify spaces for collaboration and advocacy at the local and regional level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected to achieve greater support and interest from different actors, given the actions that will take place in 2019. The CSOs have identified some actors and institutions to influence in 2019, such as: the Ministry of Health, General Directorate of Social Networks, Secretariat of Finance, in the Management Planning and Evaluation Units of each of the institutions that will work on the plans of the PyENSAN, its Ministers and Secretaries, Representatives of FAO.
Continue advocating with Representative-UTSAN reminding him of the agreements for the participation of CSOs in the elaboration of the action plans; sharing the updated schedule of the conferences and the methodology of socialization, the Work Plan for the implementation of the Action Plan for Nutrition and the presentation of the results of the FNS Expenditure Study in Honduras.
It is expected that in 2019 the Embassy of the Netherlands promotes periodic meetings in the countries with the alliances that have been built in Honduras or with new that have been identified internationally,especially networks that have a regional influence. CSOs would like to have more presence of the Embassy in their actions, accompaniment to EU, UTSAN, MiAmbiente, President of the Republic and others.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: &quot;The target set for this indicator is 1. CSOs identified and evaluated 3 influential people such as: Direction of the Technical Unit for Food and Nutrition Security - UTSAN and Sub Secretary of the United Nations and Global Coordinator Scaling Up Nutrition and Municipal Mayor of Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a.
The evaluation carried out by the CSOs indicates that in the case of the Person 1 he is not a very supportive person, since he is a person with little interest to incorporate civil society in the actions carried out by institution in the FNS theme. They have coordination meetings and he participates in events organized by the CSOs.  He is a somewhat reliable person since he responds more politically.
In the case of the Person 2, CSOs consider that she is a supportive, influential person and a somewhat trustworthy person, not much is known about her actions. On May 16, 2019, Honduras sent official letter to be part of this movement. UTSAN and FOPRIDEH jointly advocate for a visit of Mrs.Verburg to Honduras to influence high level authorities in favour of FNS. During the visit, FOPRIDEH organized a meeting for CSOs to present their work on FNS and their topics of interests. In her meeting with the National Council of FNS-CONASAN , she stated the importance of implementing the PyENSAN, the budget allocation and the coordination of actions with Civil Society.
The Person 3 was also evaluated, it was assessed that she is a supportive person. She participated in the meetings for the design of the FNS Municipal Policy with focus on Climate Change. She also set an open hall with the participation of the Municipal Board for the approval of the policy. She is an influential person and is very committed to open spaces for the participation of organized civil society. She is a reliable person since she made commitments and supported the entire process developed by civil society.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capabilities of CSOs strengthened</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs with increased leadership capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their leadership capacities guided by a list of leadership criteria.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="3" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Some changes are expected in 2018 given the effect of the actions done in 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: &quot;The average score was obtained through guided self-evaluations which results were tabulated in google. The consolidation of the data was done and shared by SNV Netherlands.

In 2018 target a small increase was considered compared to the reported value for 2017. The data generated shows that 3 CSOs have increased their leadership capacities by a small percentage, since they went from 3.5 to 3.6, from 3.3 to 3.6 and from 3.0 to 3.4.

Workshops and meetings were the main means that contributed to the changes in the leadership capacity of CSOs. The aspects of leadership focussed and improved were: the capacity to influence, motivate, organize and carry out actions to achieve objectives that involve individuals and groups in a framework of institutional values. Greater participation and contribution to the construction of spaces at the national level. Leadership in the coordination with government agencies related to the theme of FNS. Involvement of local actors in the work process, conflict management, labour climate, negotiation and political dialogue, generation of alliances and teamwork, context analysis.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No changes are expected in the target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;It is not expected an increase in the leadership score given that the actions of the program will be more oriented to advocacy. Even though, the advocacy actions may have a conjectural influence in the leadership score.

Capacity building and leadership issues were not prioritized by CSOs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs with increased capacity in organisational sustainability</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Changes are expected in 2018 as coaching and counseling services continue for each CSOs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A small change is expected in this indicator in 2019 and also a change in the provision of the service. Short term and punctual-product services will be provided upon demand expressed by the CSOs and available resources.

The needs of the organizations are diverse and differentiated as can be seen in the following topics prioritized by CSOs: 
&#x2022; Design of investment projects for financial sustainability.
&#x2022; Sustainability and Financial Management.
&#x2022; Inclusive business
&#x2022; Resource management</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs with increased thematic knowledge</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their thematic knowledge guided by a list of criteria.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="2.8" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No major changes are expected in 2018</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: &quot;The average score was obtained through guided self-evaluations which results were tabulated in google. The consolidation of the data was done and shared by SNV Netherlands.

The target of 2 CSOs was not reached as just one CSO increased its thematic knowledge capacities since it went from 2 to 2.5 an increase of 0.5. Another CSO maintained its score of 3.3 of last year, and the other lower its score from 3.8 to 3.0 a decrease of -0.75.

A CSO did not fill out the organizational survey in 2017 given that the Director and main staff resigned. For the time the measurement was done the CSO was in the process of selecting and hiring new personnel. The new director filled the organizational survey for 2018. A comparison with 2018 data is not possible because there is no data for 2017. 2018 data will be used to compare the results of the 2019 measurement. There is a decrease in the results the cause is the rotation of personel assigned to V4CP Program. The survey was filled jointly by the executive director and the new technician assigned to the program. In 2019 there are also staff rotations in some CSOs so probably here will be decreases in the score. 

If there are changes in the scores given by the CSOs, these will be analized jointly with the CSOs to find the reasons of the changes.

A series of peer to peer capacity building workshops were held among CSOs based on their expertise: Training on political advocacy, Gender and Climate change with emphasis on public policies, generational change and masculinity, Renewable Energy and Improved Stoves, Communication plans, and Decentralization and local public policies. Also workshops promoted from SNV such as: building coalitions, evidence and advocacy, media and communication skills for development; Training of technical and administrative CSOs staff on V4CP, measurement of perceptions on quality and accessibility of services, analysis and reflexion journey on current political context.

CSOs consider tha ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2,9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No major  changes are expected in 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that changes will occur in 2019 taking into account the interventions and actions that will be carried out.

CSOs consider that they need to strengthen capacities in:
&#x2022; Certification in Organizational Management
&#x2022; Decentralization.
&#x2022; Review and update of strategic plan
&#x2022; Advice on planning, monitoring and evaluation (management by results, performance evaluation, theory of change).
&#x2022; Human Resources.
&#x2022; Updating of internal regulations and institutional policies.
&#x2022; Creation of a salary policy
&#x2022; Implementation of cost accounting.
&#x2022; Implementation and monitoring of a new accounting system.
&#x2022; Creation of a communication strategy

CSOs highly appreciate the training provided by experts, as has been done in previous years. The training in 2019 will be done by:
1) individual mini workshop (for each CSO based on  demand and resources available)
2) General workshop (for all or a group of CSOs based on demand and resources available).

A small fund has been allocated to hire coachers for short term and specific assignment. It will also be based on demand and resources available.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs with improved advocacy (including use of evidence) capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their advoacy capacities guided by a list of advocacy criteria.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="2.9" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Changes are expected for 2018</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: &quot;The target of 2 was reached. Two CSOs increased their capacities of advocacy and use of evidence. The scores were as follows: 2.3 to 3 increase of 0.67 and the other OSC 2.9 to 3.2 an increase of 0.33; 1 CSO decreased as it went from 3.4 to 3.2 a decrease of -0.22.

It is important to note that a CSO did not fill out the organizational survey in 2017, given that the Director and main staff resigned. For the time the measurement was done the CSO was in the process of selecting and hiring new personnel. The new director filled the organizational survey for 2018. Given that there is no data for 2017 a comparison with 2018 data is not possible. 2018 data will be used to compare the results of the 2019measurement.

The CSOs consider that they have strengthened their advocacy strategies both internally and externally, since one CSO commented that internally they had an impact on the inclusion of the issue of Advocacy as a strategic axis in the Annual Operational Plan. They have promoted citizen participation in public agenda issues. An advocacy work was carried out in the updating of the National Policy and Strategy for Food and Nutrition Security (PyENSAN) and contributions were made to it. We worked on methodologies for the generation of evidence for advocacy and lobby; we focused on local public policies in some areas of the country.
&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No major changes are expected in the target in 2017. Major changes are expected for 2018 given the effect of 2017 actions on Training of the human resource in actions of incidence based on evidence. -Mechanisms of access to information based on evidence relevant to the topic.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Changes are expected for 2019 given the effect of the actions to be carried out such as the workshops that IFPRI will develop to prepare the studies and the involvement of CSOs in the monitoring of data gathering process.

CSOs consider that they need to strengthen:
&#x2022; Spokesperson capacities to influence topics such as FNS, gender, climate change, and poverty. Practical training. 
&#x2022; Learn more about knowledge centres. Experiences of them.
&#x2022; Documentary repository - reservoir of information.
&#x2022; Civic technologies for advocacy.
&#x2022; Virtual spaces, blogs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategies and advocacy plan elaborated and being implemented.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of activity plans that organizations develop versus the number of CSOs involved (in%)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="100%" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Activities Plan of 2016 was formulated jointly through workshops and face-to-face meetings, with the support of a consultant and SNV. Plans of activities for 2017 of the four organizations are being developed.
The activities for this year are focused on the Outcome A.  Some examples of actions to be carried out: socialization days of the program in strategic areas of the country and meetings internally of the organizations for the incorporation of the program in its Institutional Plan.
The 100% percentage is the result of dividing the 4 activity plans among the 4 organizations that participate in this theme = 4/4 = 1 * 100%&quot;</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">V4CP   Program will end in year 2020, so it is not expected to develop any action   plans for the coming year.
 

    The CSO advocacy efforts will focus on UTSAN (as the government unit   designated to propose guidelines and investment plan for FNS), on the   Secretary of Health SESAL and on the General Government Coordination   Secretariat - SCGG. CSOs and V4CP will provide support to the advocacy   actions of the Coordination Committee of the FNS municipal tables on these   entities.
     They will also carry out advocacy activities on other platforms to monitor   actions at the municipal, regional and national levels.
 

    Continue their participation on bilateral meetings with decision makers   such as the Honduran Council of Private Enterprise-COHEP or other socially   influential groups. Develop forums and participate in interviews with   relevant media to promote PyENSAN and its budgetary allocation, among other   actions.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: No plan of CSO activities is expected as the program is in its final phase. CSOs are implementing their 2020 Action Plan. Given changes in context due to Covid &#x2013; 19, CSOs with support of V4CP the program carried out an analysis of the 2020 Action Plan according to three possible scenarios: 1) Pessimistic, where the proposed activities had to be adjusted and ended in August; 2) Intermediate, where the proposed activities would lead to a month extension; 3) Optimistic, two additional months. Following this analysis, the program approved the two-month extension of the AOP (complete all activities in October and the entire closing process in November), which led to defining a series of strategies and adaptation measures to continue with support at the local level and advocacy activities.

As for the most relevant changes in the advocacy plans on the FNS issue in this context, it has been to focus the accompaniment to the Municipal Food and Nutrition Security Tables through virtual modality, prioritize the strengthening of the FNS Surveillance Commission (COVISAN), as well as CSOs GESI visibility and communication capabilities. Development of systematization of CSOs experiences (virtual methodology); development of social media and radio campaigns, to adapt to new actions in the framework of COVID-19. With these changes, resources were reallocated in those activities and the increase of 2 months coordination and follow-up services for the implementation of the AOPs in ASONOG, CDH, FOPRIDEH and RDS.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the fourth quarter of 2018, the action plan for the year 2018 will be formulated jointly with the CSOs. Through various workshops and face-to-face meetings with each member of the CSOs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The 2019 Action Plan was formulated jointly with ASONOG, FOPRIDEH, RDS and CDH in face-to-face meetings with the support of a consultant and SNV.
Some examples of actions that will be carried out: Follow-up tours and advice for the advocacy. Regional and Municipal FNS Boards that promote FNS municipal public policies and their linkage with PyESAN, Constitution and strengthening of the National Network of FNS Municipal Tables, Development and participation of national forums and social mobilizations for socialization of contributions and proposals to the PyENSAN and studies developed by IFPRI with relevant and influential actors. Participation in bilateral meetings with decision makers in the State Secretariats participating in the SINASAN to advocate the action plans of the guidelines of the PyENSAN, Participation in meetings with the FNs Technical Unit (UTSAN), Secretariat of General Coordination of Government (SCGG ), National Congress or other related actors to follow up on the process of approval of the PySAN or construction of the plans for guidelines, meetings and interviews aimed at establishing links with the National Anticorruption Council (CNA) and the Office of planning and monitoring of the SCGG to know the mechanisms of accountability established for government offices, implement communication plan, among other actors.

The percentage of 100% is the result of dividing the 4 action plans among the 4 organizations that participate in this topic (ASONOG, CDH, FOPRIDEH and RDS) = 4/4 = 1 * 100%</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the third quarter of 2017, the plan of activities for the year 2018 would be formulated jointly with the CSOs. Through workshops and meetings with each of the CSOs members of the program to agree on actions.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: &quot;The 2018 Action Plan was formulated jointly with the CSOs through workshops and face-to-face meetings, with the support of a Consultant and SNV.Activities for this year will focus on increasing participation, improving coordination between CSOs and municipal and regional FNS committees to influence the updating of the FNS Policy and strategy. If the policy is approved this year, actions for its socialization will be developed, intervention strategies and roles in the implementation, monitoring and social auditing of the FNS policy will be defined.

The percentage of 100% is the result of dividing the 4 action plans among the 4 organizations that participate in this topic ) = 4/4 = 1 * 100%&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the third and fourth quarter of 2019, the action plans are expected to be drawn up, together with the CSOs, accompanied by a consultant and the SNV. It will be carried out through workshops to formulate plans and meetings with each organization to define actions and allocate budget.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: &quot;In the last quarter of 2019, the action plan of each CSO was formulated, taking into account the inputs of the Learning Event, V4CP 2020 Annual Plan and the 2020 Advocacy Plan. Meetings were held with each of the CSOs to define the actions that each of them would develop in 2020.
The action plan of each CSO was developed jointly between the CSOs, the SNV and an individual consultant who is an expert on FNS issue and has been leading this process since the program began. The main activities that CSOs will develop in 2020 are: Participation in FNS platforms and committees at local, regional and national levels. Dissemination of research on issues related to FNS. Continue the implementation of the communication strategy to influence key actors and the general public about the importance of the inclusive implementation of PyENSAN, and of appropriate budgetary allocation, and accountability mechanisms. Support the Coordination Committee of the FNS municipal tables to strengthen its advocacy skills to get a space in the SINASAN. Also on the systematization of selected experiences.
&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual advocacy plan formulated</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="yes" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The advocacy plan was formulated jointly. Workshops were carried out for the formulation of it and the SNV with the support of a consultant fine-tuned the activities and finished the document that was sent to SNV Netherlands. It includes the description of the problem, goal, context analysis, change of theory, monitoring and evaluation, commitment strategy and activities and resources for 2017, outlook activities for 2018, assumptions, risks and mitigation. The Advocacy Plan of activities is based on each of the outputs and outcomes that the program hopes to achieve, in an excel template that was elaborated and it contemplates the sub activities that are related to the activities set in the FNS Advocacy Plan word document. For the year 2017, 25 major activities are expected for the Outputs: A, B and C and for the Outcomes: D, E, F, G, J and K.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="No">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">V4CP   Program will end in year 2020, so it is not expected to develop any advocate   plan for the coming year.
 

    However, advocacy efforts will focus on monitoring the implementation of   PyENSAN (2018-2030) that includes the participatory design of prioritized   action plans, the strengthening of MMSANs and the MMSAN Coordination   Committee. Strong concentration in the implementation of the communication   strategy to influence key actors and the general public about the importance   of the inclusive implementation of PyENSAN, the allocation of adequate budget   for the FNS, the mechanisms for CSOs to participate in the processes to be   able to influence decisions to improve FNS services provided by the state.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: Given that the program is in its final phase, no annual advocacy plans will be prepared for 2021. Currently, the 2020 plan is being implemented. Efforts are focused on:

Development of virtual forums and events promoted on social networks. The purpose is to expose the situation of FNS in the country and that the PyENSAN, has been relegated by policies issued by the Government in the current context. Dissemination of knowledge products on the PyENSAN guidelines to provide the basis for proposals or advocacy actions in FNS. Accompaniment to the FNS Municipal Tables (FNS) in the southern and western region of the country. Active participation in development of three municipal studies on COVID 19 effects on FNS in Sabanagrande, Francisco Moraz&#xE1;n, Yuscar&#xE1;n and San Lucas, El Para&#xED;so organized by FNS Regional Table R12. Members of the National Network of Municipal Tables visited with the accompaniment of CDH the southern and western region to influence Municipal Councils to develop FNS policies with support of municipal tables and to allocate budget for their implementation. Visitors shared their experiences on the FNS issue. Definition of guidelines for the advocacy strategy on the FNS issue at the municipal level with members of the MMSAN in the southern and western areas. Construction of the first Report of the FNS Surveillance Committee (COVISAN). The preparation of the 2021 AOP of COVISAN and the strengthening of capacities of its members is ongoing, this in response to the TOC related to accountability and transparency in the execution of policies, strategies, programs and FNS project at different levels. 

On the other hand, as part of the actions for its sustainability, the 6 partner CSOs (HdH, FV, ASONOG, CDH, RDS, FOPRIDEH) jointly with SNV formed a consortium. The first action of the consortium is to prepare a regional project proposal to get funding to continue advocacy actions onV4CP themes and scale it up thematically adding climate change an ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="yes">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the end of 2018, it is expected to draw up the 2019 advocacy plan jointly with the CSOs to send it to SNV Netherlands for review and approval.
Through workshops and meetings with each member of the CSOs of the program to agree on actions.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The advocacy plan for 2019 was developed jointly with the CSOs taking in account CSOs inputs gathered in the learning event and a series of mini workshops. The process was facilitated by an individual consultant, specialized on FNS theme. The document presents the 2019 main activities and their contributions to the products and outcomes stated in the FNS theory of change. The 2019 advocacy plan focusses on: strengthening the advocacy capabilities and thematic management of the CSOs and municipal tables for the  proper definition of their intervention strategies and roles within the FNS Policy and Strategy (PyENSAN); Socializing the contributions and proposals of the CSOs to the PyENSAN at municipal, regional and national levels; Advocating on selected secretaries of state and representatives of the private sector; Providing evidence in support of advocacy efforts.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="yes">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the middle of 2017, the advocacy plan for 2018 would be prepared in conjunction with the CSOs to be sent to SNV Netherlands for review and approval.
Through workshops and meetings with each of the CSOs members of the program to agree on actions.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: &quot;The advocacy plan was formulated jointly with the CSOs. Training workshops were held with the support of a consultant and the SNV team. The learning workshop was relevant to analyze how we are and where we want to go, and adjust the activities according to the results of the analysis. The plan was completed in October and was sent to SNV Holland. The document includes summary of context analysis, contextualized theory of change, monitoring and evaluation, commitment strategy, plan of activities and resources for 2018, main actions planned for 2019, assumptions, risks and mitigation measures.
The advocacy Plan is based on each of the products and results that the program expects to achieve. By 2018, 32 main activities are expected for the Products: A, B and C and for the Results: D, E, F, G, H, J, K and L.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="yes">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By mid-2019, the 2020 advocacy plan would be prepared in conjunction with CSOs through various workshops and meetings with CSOs, for subsequent submission to SNV Netherlands for review and approval.

It is foreseen that by 2020 the actions of the advocacy plan will concentrate on increasing the advocacy for the appropriate implementation of the participative and inclusive PYENSAN under a decentralized operating scheme and its corresponding budget allocation. With emphasis on municipal action and the realization of specific studies that contribute to the timely and systematic evaluation of the aforementioned public policy as well as the measurement of the perception of quality and access to the FNS services provided by the state.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: &quot;Based on inputs provided by the CSOs in the learning event and the meetings with each one of partner CSOs, the 2020 advocacy plan was formulated. The process was facilitated by an individual consultant, who has been accompanying these processes since the beginning of the program.
The approval of the National Food and Nutrition Security Policy and Strategy (PyENSAN 2018-2030) obliges CSOs to face new levels of advocate since the implementation of PyENSAN requires Action Plans corresponding to each of its 11 strategic lines. 
So far two Action Plans have been approved: a) Action plan for food and nutrition security and b) Action plan for nutrition (PANH 2030). In 2020 CSOs will concentrate their efforts to influence 3 action plans: a) governance, b) decentralization and c) education. They will also advocate for FNS budget allocation and open space for their participation in monitoring FNS expenditures to improve the FNS status of the population.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved FNS services aligned with the operative plan and budget of the FNS policy.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">More accessible services for people with low income</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="16,9" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the purpose of being able to determine the improvement in the accessibility of the services in FNS, a participatory Methodology for the survey was prepared and 12 focus groups were realized in diverse zones of the country with people of the communities, 188 women and 35 men. In turn, community leaders were interviewed to representatives of state institutions to learn about the communities and services present in them.

At the same 24-point scale, this indicator averaged 16.9 points, that is, an indicator of 70% of satisfaction with the ease of accessing the service, according to the category score.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There   is no certainty that the target set for previous years have been achieved so   the same target will be set for 2020 . 
 

    The main action planned for 2020 is the &#x201C;Perception measurement on the   degree of accessibility and quality of FNS services provided by the   government&#x201D;. This final study will be facilitated by the same expert that   facilitated the base line and intermediate measurements. V4CP/SNV team and   partner CSOs play an important role in these studies</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: A target had not been defined for this indicator, so it is unknown to date if there is any improvement in the accessibility of the services provided by the government in FNS services.
Training was carried out to CSOs for the field survey for the final measurement and subsequent interpretation and dissemination of data, however, the process stopped in March due to the absolute curfew decreed by the Government of Honduras because of covid pandemic. The absolute curfew is maintained nationwide until August 23, the opening process will progress gradually. If so, field work will start in September. 
The study is being facilitated by the same thematic expert who prepared the baseline and the intermediate measurement. The CSOs carry out the survey in the field with the support of SNV which also monitor the processing and analysis of the data for the final report</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10.92">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">An increase of 5% in the accessibility of FNS services has been projected, considering that the services will continue to be provided in 2018 and that given the political year that passed, more people had access to them and probably trying to calm the political situation, opportunity for more people to have FNS services could be given.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7.90">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: An increase of 5% in the accessibility of FNS services was expected, so the target set for 2018 was 10.92. For 2018 measurement, the methodology used for the baseline was adjusted. data was gattered in 12 focus groups in the same counties, with the same actors as of the baseline which involved a total of 182 people (135 women-74.10% and 36 men -25.9%). on the same services evaluated, such as: 10,000 Bonus, Vaccination Brigade, School Snack, Comprehensive Child Care, Dengue Control, Zica and Chikunkunga, Healthy School, Attention of obstetric complications, Solidarity Bag, Better Life Program and decentralized health services, which are the services that people have greater access to and that vary according to geographical areas.

The scale for the analysis of accessibility goes from 0 zero to 24 points. The indicator reached in 2018 an average score of 7.9 points which represent a 33% satisfaction with the accessibility of the services.

To assess the accessibility of the services, three categories were used: material limitations 34.4%, economic limits 32.3% and sociocultural limitations 31.5%. In general, there is no major difference in the score of the three categories, however based on these results and the socio-economic characterization of the communities consulted, the low satisfaction with the accessibility of services may be related to sociocultural limitations, for the complexity of the required procedures and the perception of the degree of inclusion with which the service is provided.   
It cannot be assumed with certainty why there was a decrease in the perception of people about the accessibility of services provided by the government, but we can indicate some comments that emerged in the focus groups. People consulted consider that the services are good, but they do not arrive to all the population that needs them and that some services are provided more frequently in the times of the election period. They also consider that these serv ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improvement in the quality of services provided by the government, private sector or academia.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="16.8" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the purpose of being able to determine the improvement in the quality of the services in FNS, a participatory Methodology for the survey was prepared and 12 focus groups were realized in diverse zones of the country with people of the communities, 188 women and 35 men. In turn, community leaders were interviewed to representatives of state institutions to learn about the communities and services present in them.

The most mentioned services in the focus groups were: School Snack, Bonus 10,000, Vaccination Brigades, Healthy School and Solidary Bag, services provided by the public sector; no private sector or academic services were found.

On a scale of zero to twenty-four points, this indicator was averaged at 16.8 points, that is, an indicator of 70% of satisfaction with the service, according to the categories&apos; score.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There   is no certainty that the target set for previous years have been achieved so   the same target will be set for 2020.
 

    CSOs actions will be oriented to:
     a) Workshops and forums to strengthen the capacities of the Coordination   Committee of the FNS municipal tables to influence the provision of FNS   services by the state.
     b) Socialize with the Coordination Committee of the FNS municipal tables   the main results of the studies carried out by V4CP 2017-2020.
     c) Participate in meetings organized by the municipal and regional FNS   tables and promote the participation of the Coordination Committee of the FNS   Municipal Tables.
     d) General forum and local workshops with key actors from the public and   private sector, universities and other stakeholders to socialize the main   findings of the Systematization of the CSO experiences in the implementation   of the V4CP program and its main contributions to the FNS theme.
     e) Perception measurement on the degree of accessibility and quality of FNS   services provided by the government. This final study will be facilitated by   the same expert that facilitated the base line and intermediate measurements.   V4CP/SNV team and partner CSOs play an important role in these studies.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: A target had not been defined for this indicator, so it is unknown to date if there is any improvement in the quality of the services provided by the government in FNS services.
Training was carried out to CSOs for the field survey for the final measurement and subsequent interpretation and dissemination of data, however, the process stopped in March due to the absolute curfew decreed by the Government of Honduras because of covid pandemic. The absolute curfew is maintained nationwide until August 23, the opening process will progress gradually. If so, field work will start in September. 
The study is being facilitated by the same thematic expert who prepared the baseline and the intermediate measurement. The CSOs carry out the survey in the field with the support of SNV which also monitor the processing and analysis of the data for the final report</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10.3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is no certainty that the goal established in 2017 has increased so this same score is reflected for 2018.
Due to the problems that have arisen in the country due to the issue of the re-election of the president, it is not considered that there is an improvement in the quality of the FNS services, there may be a lot of disagreement in the community about the current situation in the country.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="8.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: No significant changes were expected in this indicator, so the target of 10.3 established in the baseline remains. For 2018 measurement, the methodology used for the baseline was adjusted. data was gattered in 12 focus groups in the same counties, with the same actors as of the baseline which involved a total of 182 people (135 women-74.10% and 36 men -25.9%). on the same services evaluated, such as: 10,000 Bonus, Vaccination Brigade, School Snack, Comprehensive Child Care, Dengue Control, Zica and Chikunkunga, Healthy School, Attention of obstetric complications, Solidarity Bag, Better Life Program and decentralized health services, which are the services that people have greater access to and that vary according to geographical areas.

The scale for the analysis of quality goes from 0 zero to 24 points. The indicator reached in 2018 an average score of 8 points which represent a 33% satisfaction with the services and a negative move from the 10.3 of the baseline. Five categories were used to evaluate the quality of the services: Relevance 61.2%, Efficiency 34.5%, Effectiveness 22.5%, impact 23.7% and sustainability 25%. 
In general, services are perceived to meet the needs of communities since the relevant category got the highest score. Efficiency (measures the perception on the administration of the services, how acceptable the management is) got a 34.5%. Lower values on effectiveness and impact may reflect the people fear that services will not be available in the future, or that services do not meet people&#xB4;s expectations on their impact. Low satisfaction with the services may be also related to the perception of low coverage. However,
It cannot be assumed with certainty why there was a decrease in the perception of people about the services provided by the government, but we can indicate some comments that emerged in the focus groups. People consulted consider that the services are good, but they do not arrive to all the population that needs  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved coordination of CSOs with main actors of the SINASAN (UTSAN, FNS Regional &amp; municipal tables or committees) located in their geographical areas</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of coordination between CSOs and the SINASAN System (UTSAN, FNS Regional &amp; municipal tables or committees) located in their geographical areas</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. no or only occasional formal or informal encounters between CSOs, government and private sector take place that are related to the issue
1. regular meetings and communications take place between CSOs, government and/or the private sector which are related to the issue
2. relevant theme related information / data are sought, shared and discussed among CSOs, government and/or the private sector.
3. plans that include CSOs interests are (jointly) made by CSOs, government and/or the private sector.
4. follow up actions are taken that includes CSOs interests</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;A joint analysis with CSOs on their degree of coordination was carried out using the evaluation scale and it was concluded that only occasional meetings were held with European Union Delegates on 7 November where SNV and 2 CSOs participated. Regional Table of Sovereignty and Food Security 29 November with the participation of 3 CSOs. Meeting with the FNS Table of the 13 region on 9 December in which SNV and RDS participated. Meeting of the Group promoting the dialogue on the human right to food on 15 December in which 3 CSOs and SNV participated. Each organization scored on the evaluation rubric, agreed on the score, and considered that its level of coordination is 0 with the government, the private sector, academia, and other stakeholders.
Despite the above descripted, it should be noted that through the program the inter-institutional links between the four participating organizations, especially between FOPRIDEH and ASONOG, have been strengthened; FOPRIDEH and RDS; CDH and RDS that are working in a coordinated and consensual way to support the Program.&quot;</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The   target for this indicator will remain in 3. CSOs are planning to participate   in the design of the PyENSAN Actions Plans they prioritized, and also to   develop advocacy actions for the inclusion of the Coordination Committee of   the FNS Municipal Tables in the SINASAN. Partner CSOs and UTSAN got verbal   agreements to allow the participation of Civil Society in the construction of   the plans and the programmatic actions of the UTSAN. 
 

    But CSOs are not optimistic that in reality they will be invited and taken   into account since their participation has been limited so far. Although   UTSAN is more open now to civil society, it has not been possible for partner   CSOs to work together in the implementation of UTSAN programs.
 

    Greater coordination is expected with the municipal tables as well as with   the Coordination Committee of the FNS Municipal Tables. Partner CSOs will   strengthen the advocacy skill and thematic knowledge of both bodies.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: The target for this indicator is 3 and the 4 CSOs applied the evaluation rubric and jointly maintained their score of 3.
CSOs have frequent meetings and communications with the Technical Unit for Food and Nutrition Security (UTSAN) and fluid communication with the FNS Municipal and Regional Tables (MMSAN and MRSAN) in the CSO&apos;s area of influence. CSOs have created spaces for participation at the level of organizations and institutions that work on the FNS issue, which have participated in conferences promoted by V4CP. Relevant information related to FNS topic is shared and discussed in different spaces. CSOs believe that V4CP permeated UTSAN as it now is accompanying and strengthening Municipal Tables. This has been a target of V4CP advocacy but there is no evidence that the change in UTSAN toward municipal tables is due to V4CP actions.
It is important to note that UTSAN and its main program EUROSAN recognize the leadership of V4CP. It is expected that a letter of understanding will be signed by EUROSAN-Occidente with V4CP or partner CSOs.

CSOs are preparing plans and strategies with FNS Municipal Tables in southern and western regions. Example of it is the advocacy strategy defined in June to be applied in the second semester of 2020 in Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a.
They are also creating new Municipal Tables such as the Santa Ana Yusgure, El Corpus, Orocuina and Apacilagua, in Choluteca. 
At national level, CSOs with the other members of COVISAN will start in September the preparation of COVISAN 2021 action plan, as part of its capacity-building process.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that by 2017, meetings and frequent communications with other actors and with NSFNS (SINASAN), government, the private sector or other platforms and alliances can be held. Target set for the second semester of 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: CSOs indicated that even though they had participated in more events and had more interventions they do not have more frequent communication with governmental representatives. The situation is similar with educational institutions, international cooperation entities such as European Union and the United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization FAO. CSOs find much narrowed the space to establish a direct communication and advocate to influence those actors, especially governmental representatives. New strategies are needed.
CSOs have a closer relationship with CSOs, platforms and networks such as: Alianza SARA (Agrarian reform and food sovereignty), RED CASAN, Espacio Regional de Occidente Honduras-EROC, Grupo Impulsor, and Rural Development Commission, among others. CSOs have frequent meetings with municipal and regional FNS committees, and local governments. 
CSOs have had a relevant role in the discussions of FNS priorities and proposals during the workshops, focal groups and meetings developed in the South region with the private sector, educational institutions, NGOs, Commonwealths, and root-bead organizations. 
The workshops and meetings developed in the North zone contribute to the improvement of the interinstitutional relationships. The discussions about FNS status has been highly appreciated by local actors such as MAMUGA Common wealth.
Two CSO filled the rubric with score of 1. Two CSO filled the rubric with score of 0. (2/4=0.5 rounded to 1). CSOs expressed their interest to increase the coordination with the government, private sector and universities. CSOs highly value the job that they are doing together since it strengthen their links of brotherhood.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that in the first semester of 2018 it will be possible to hold meetings and frequent communications with the municipal tables, generate spaces for participation and share and discuss information since the advocacy work will be focused on supporting and strengthening the tables.They will seek to generate spaces and have a greater relationship with the FNSTU and the municipal tables, although due to the political situation of the country it is not considered that there can be much progress with these actors. So the goal will remain in 1.

CSOs expect that the scheduled events will contribute to increasing communication and participation with other actors who have similar interests.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-11-2018: Using the Evaluation Rubric, a joint analysis was made with CSOs about their degree of coordination giving an average value of 1.58333 that will be adjusted to 2, the target set for this first semester was 1.
(FNSTU)UTSAN: A CSO does not have any relationship with the FNSTU nor have participated in any of the meetings they have promoted. One CSO comments that they have been invited to meetings because by law they can participate in the Inter-institutional Technical Committee of FNS-IITC, but meetings are not frequent and they consider it a closed space with no chance to influence it. One CSO indicated that they have frequent meetings with the FNSTU since they are part of the Board of Directors of the FNS Regional Table 12 Central Region, but communication is not effective in the spaces that are shared. A CSO has frequent meetings because they are part of the Assembly and have representatives in the base structures of the FNS Regional Table Region of the West. The FNSTU in the area has had an intervention at the technical level, there is political will on both sides. The relationship with FNSTU is specifically within the framework of the program; without the agenda and approach of the program, there would be none or scarce relationship with FNSTU. The integration of other actors in the regional spaces has been facilitated and it has been requested that organization lead some issues. Spaces of participation are being generated through the structures, and frequent, fluid and respectful communication has been established. There have been exchanges of information but not in a systematic way.
Regional Tables: Currently a CSO has no direct relationship with the regional tables, but it received an invitation from the Center Regional Table R12 to participate in their General Assembly. A partner CSO is currently part of the Board of Directors of Regional Table R12. This CSO is advocating to open space for the participation of other partner CSOs. It also has a ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are confident that the events programmed for the second semester will contribute to increase the communication with actors that have similar interests but at a modest rate.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: &quot;An analysis was conducted with the CSOs to determine the degree of coordination. The established goal was 1 and  1,166667 was determined for this period.
The CSOs indicated that, although they have participated in more events and had more interventions, it has not been possible to generate processes of coordination of concrete actions with the FNSTU, only some meetings and sporadic telephone communications. Same with the Inter-institutional Technical Committee of FNS-COTISAN. Efforts were made to approach the various political parties.
The situation is similar with educational institutions, international cooperation entities such as the European Union and the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO). CSOs find that spaces have been greatly reduced, there is very little openness to establish direct communication and to influence those actors, especially the government representatives.
There is a greater level of progress with the South and West municipal tables . The meetings are monthly, they have a structured agenda and the CSOs have participated in these spaces when they are allowed, providing information for the consultation and meeting between tables. In Comayagua and Yoro the approaches have been null. In the Central zone, the FNSTU formed the R.12 table at the end of 2017. Our partner RDS was selected as the sub-coordinator of the R.12 table, which is chaired by the UNAH. In the case of regional bureaus and local governments in the West and South, meetings are more sporadic.
CSOs have a closer relationship with CSOs, platforms and networks such as: Alliance SARA (Agrarian Reform and Food Sovereignty), the Impelling Group on the Human Right to Food, Rural Development Commission, among others. The forums, talks, workshops and meetings held in the zones have contributed to the improvement of relations with some actors. Institutional relations among CSOs have been strengthened.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;The target will remain at 3. CSOs expect that with the implementation of their action plans, they will contribute to improve the coordination and participation of CSOs with UTSAN and the FNS Regional Tables.
Once the study to identify and characterized the FNS Municipal Tables is made, the feasibility to create the National Network of FNS Municipal Tables will be analysed, taking into account the regulations of the Table and the FNS Law.
CSOs will promote the participation of representatives of the FNS Municipal Tables in the Regional FNS Tables, in their zone of influence, to keep informed of what is happening in these Tables, and to advocate for space to present the V4CP studies. Regional FNS Tables are relevant since the Government uses them for consultation on FNS theme.
&quot;FNS Municipal Tables are the voice of FNS in the country. They have the legitimacy to advocate and make proposals in name of the communities they represent. 

The National Network will make Municipal Tables stronger and force the Government to recognized their role. On the other hand, the National Network will be the advocacy arm of CSOs to influence the implementation of the PyENSAN and the FNS Law reforms.
The National Network will be the louder voice of the communities speaking at the different levels of the SINASAN. CSOs are advocating for the creation of the National Network. CSOs believe that once the National Network is strengthen it will open spaces for its participation in the SINASAN.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: &quot;The set target for this indicator was 3. CSOs applied the evaluation rubric and their jointly score is 3 given that: Partner CSOs have frequent meetings and communications with UTSAN, participating in different events related to FNS, and exchanging information on the subject. Partner CSOs led the advocacy process on UTSAN to reactivate the Monitoring Committee of FNS-COVISAN and worked together to reactivate it. Partner CSOs participate in meetings of the SINASAN structure such as COVISAN and COTISAN that are bodies created to promote the FNS from the public sphere and to articulate the work on the subject of all related actors.

Municipal Tables: Partner CSOs participate in monthly meetings, and join efforts with other organizations to develop municipal public policies. They have permanent communication and provide technical support for thematic and advocacy management in conferences, workshops and other public events in their geographic areas of influence.

Regional Tables: Sporadic meetings are held. Partner CSOs participate according to the calls of the FNS Table of Region 12 and 13. They have been articulated with some actors and worked together in the planning of the assemblies. CSOs expect those regional tables will be more active in 2020 and that CSOs will participate and develop actions in close coordination and collaboration.

However, partner CSOs have not succeeded in opening spaces for them to participate in the UTSAN and Regional Tables Action Plans design. Normally these Action Plans are done without participation of civil society. Only in the case of municipal tables, partner CSOs participate in the Action Plans design and implementation providing technical assistance especially in advocacy and preparation of FNS municipal public policies.
&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the second semester, CSOs will hold frequent meetings and communications with key actors, since the advocacy work will focus on supporting and strengthening the tables, generating opportunities for participation in the regional and national structures. They will also socialize the studies generated by the program and discuss relevant information with key actors.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target will remain at 3 expected events that contribute to improve coordination and participation. The first semester of 2019 frequent meetings and communications with key stakeholders will take place since the advocacy work will focus on: decision makers for CSOs participation and influence on the PyENSAN&#xB4;s action plans and its budget; at regional and local level advising the FNS Tables and advocating for their legal recognition, constitution and strengthening of the National Network of FNS Municipal Tables. Also socialize the studies generated by the program and analyse relevant information with key actors, among other actions.

CSOs face a series of limitations for their advocacy work such as the fragile democracy that does not allow their participation in policy design, their plans, and any other governmental planning. Although UTSAN made a commitment to involve CSOs, it is not a guarantee that this will happen, since participation will depend on the will of other State Secretariats involved.
Another limitation comes from inside the CSOs such as their limited prepositive capabilities since they normally do not have specialized staff for accompaniment and contribution to policy making proposals. 
Another limitation is access to economic resources to hire specialized personnel or consultancy services to strengthen their capabilities to have a chance to influence public policies at national level.
For the above, CSOs must focus on some specific aspects of the PyENSAN or its process to advocate for such as the governance structure to include the municipal tables or committees or the participation of community organizations in the regional tables or committees, or in the budget allocation at local or national level, or in specific action plans, as an example of possible targets.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased participation of CSOs in participatory spaces in the Food and Nutritional Security System SINASAN (UTSAN, FNS Regional &amp; municipal tables or committees) located in their geographical areas</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of evidence based in knowledge/research products shared and socialized by CSOs with stakeholders.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Knowledge products have not been generated or shared within the framework of the program. Within the framework of FNS Route program, the Impact Assessment of the Policy was carried out and shared with UTSAN authorities within the framework of the South regional table, in turn they have been shared with local authorities.  To determine the 0.25 it was counted the number of documents shared between the number of CSOs participating in the topic this equals: 1/4</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The   first semester of 2020, IFPRI will develop one knowledge product to be shared   with local and national actors: 1) Analysis of the FNS budget for two   municipalities selected by CSOs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: The target for this indicator was 1 product of knowledge shared with interested parties, to date 2 products have been socialized.
1) Informative chart language adapted to target public &quot;Let&apos;s talk about Water, Gender and FNS in our communities&quot;, prepared by the RDS with the accompaniment of CDH. A validation session was held with representatives of the FNS Municipal Tables of the southern zone of Honduras. The validation raised people&apos;s understanding and perception of the usefulness of the information for advocacy issues.
2) Study and analysis of investment differentiated by FNS pillars: Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a, Choluteca, Tambla, Lempira. Prepared by IFPRI. Several conferences were held to present and share the results of the study with: a) representatives of the FNS Technical Unit (UTSAN), members of the FNS Surveillance Commission (COVISAN), NGOs affiliated to FOPRIDEH and members of the Municipal Tables of FNS of Region 12; b) Municipal Council, mayor, technical staff, members of the FNS Municipal Tables of Tambla, Lempira, c) Technical staff of ASONOG and its affiliated CSOs; d) Municipal Council and mayor of Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a, Choluteca; e) FNS Municipal Tables of the southern zone and CDH technicians.

Participants learnt how investment can be evidenced on the FNS pillars (availability, access, consumption, biological use and stability) at the municipal level for the period 2018 and 2019; likewise, a series of findings and recommendations were given for aspects of improvement.
As a result of these findings, both municipal governments expressed interest and request support to ASONOG and CDH for the preparation of their 2021 budget with the FNS approach, ordering their prioritized community projects in programs, subprograms, projects and activities to make all the investment visible with the FNS approach, V4CP is providing technical support to them. 

The analysis of the differentiated investment by FNS Pillar is extremely importance to know how  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the second semester CSOs will socialize with different actors, the knowledge products generated by IFPRI such as:
1) Policy framework related to Food and Nutrition Security (FNS),
2) The Budget for Food and Nutrition Security 2015-2017.
3) The production of African palm and sugar cane in Honduras.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The target set for this indicator for the second semester was to share 3 knowledge products, and it was achieved: 
1) Poverty and Nutrition in Honduras prepared by IFPRI, was taken in account by partner CSO RDS for the preparation of the Municipal Public Policy in FNS for the municipalities of San Antonio de Flores and San Isidro, Choluteca. 
2) Report on Situation of the FNS in Honduras, prepared by IFPRI. A friendly presentation on it was used by RDS in the awareness-raising seminar with municipal boards of San Antonio and Pespire on the topics of Municipal Public Policies and Food and Nutrition Security. Key actors that participated in the event: commonwealths: Pespire-San Antonio de Flores, aldermen, deputy mayor and mayor of San Antonio de Flores.
3) Contributions to the proposal of the PyENSAN 2018-2030, a view from the civil society organizations participating in the V4CP program and other organizations and related spaces, elaborated by the CSOs with support of a consultant team. September 2018. Presented at the following events in which three CSOs participated RDS, CDH, ASONOG: a) Conference with representatives of organizations part of the Dialogue Steering Group (Grupo Impulsor del Di&#xE1;logo) for the human right to food, SARA Alliance and other allied organizations to share opinions on the positioning of the partner CSOs in the face of the update of the PYENSAN. Key actors that participate: NGOs, civil society, knowledge institutes. b) UTSAN Meeting &quot;Presentation of the draft National Policy and Strategy for Food and Nutrition Security PyENSAN 2018-2030. Key actors that participate: Government institution, international cooperation, where all partner CSOs and part of their alliances participated.
The consultations that took place in the different regions to collect inputs and prepare the CSO approach with respect to the PyENSAN was carried out jointly with the participation of the 4 CSOs with the accompaniment of SNV.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that during the first semester IFPRI will develop two knowledge products and be shared with local and national actors:1) Study of monocultural crops, such as, for example, African palm and the effects on the FNS of Honduras; 2) Analysis of laws and other regulations that are a barrier to an inclusive FNS policy.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-11-2018: The established target of this indicator was 2 shared knowledge products to key stakeholders, currently only one knowledge product has been shared, such as:
Presentation of data from the &quot;budget for Food and Nutrition Security 2015-2017&quot;, prepared by IFPRI, in the Forum &#x201C;Nutrition Services Provision&#x201D; organized by the Civil Society council of Marcala, La Paz. 136 people participated in the forum such as representatives of knowledge institutes, community representatives, parents&apos; society, water boards, civil society, public sector, NGOs, municipality, among others.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that by 2017 (5) knowledge/research products will be developed by IFPRI and (1) by SNV local team. The bi-annual target is (1) for the first semester and (5) for the second semester</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: For the reporting period the target was set in six knowledge products to be share with the CSOs. Instead, two of the three products generated were shared with seven actors (7/4=1.75). 
The FNS informative sheet prepared by IFPRI on March 2017, was used and shared by partner SCOs in their meetings with representatives of the European Union the EU, Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, Dutch Embassy in Costa Rica, and FNS governmental technical unit.
The informative brief on FNS status and pp presentation prepared by IFPRI on June 2017, was used and shared by partner SCOs in the South region workshops and meetings with the private sector, educational institutions, commonwealths, NGOs and root-based organizations. Events organized to share information and to get information about regional FNS priorities and proposed actions to face the main challenges, as inputs for the actualization process of the national FNS policy. It includes a word summary and a pp presentation. 
The pp presentation was highly appreciated by the CSO`s and local actors..</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the second semester 2017, it is expected to share with partners CSOs and with local and national actors the following knowledge products: Compendium of FNS Laws prepared by FOPRIDEH; the Measurement of perception of population from selected communities on quality of and access to FNS services that is being prepared by SNV; and the 4 knowledge products from IFPRI (Status of nutrition and health in the Honduran population, FNS budget analysis, Impact of direct-conditioned cash transfer mechanism, Access to water for human consumption)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="6.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: &quot;The goal set for reporting in the second semester was 6 knowledge products shared with local and national actors. 6 knowledge products were shared in total, in the consultation sessions in various areas of the country on the situation of Food and Nutritional Security (FNS) and the construction of proposals for joint guidelines for the FNSNP with private sector, the academy, mancomunidades , community bases and mancomunidades, also presented the results of the products in forums and talks with mayoral candidates, local deputies Choluteca, West zone, and with candidates for deputies, technical and presidential staff in Tegucigalpa, also in various meetings held with the various political parties, meetings with the FNS committees and with other relevant actors. Interactive presentations were made, the information was highly appreciated by the various actors.

The information presented of the knowledge products that were shared were:
1) Information on the situation of the FNS in Honduras (IFPRI) shared by CDH, ASONOG and RDS.
2) Poverty and Nutrition in Honduras (IFPRI), shared by all 4 CSOs.
3) A Public Expenditure Review for Food and Nutrition Security of Honduras. (IFPRI), shared by all 4 CSOs.
4) Budgets for FNS (IFPRI), shared by all 4 CSOs.
5) Water and Food and Nutritional Security in Honduras (IFPRI), shared by all 4 CSOs.
6) Measurement of the perception of the degree of Quality and Accessibility of FNS services in Honduras (SNV), shared by all 4 CSOs.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;In the second semester CSOs expect to socialize 3 knowledge products in different events: 1) Study Access to resources and its effect on FNS to be presented to local authorities. Staff of partner CSOs have been trained on how to do the research and also participated in the selection of communities target by the study. 
2) Study  FNS, Water and Gender, prepared by IFPRI will be presented to FNS Municipal Tables to facilitate the design of FNS Municipal policies to address local problems based on evidence provided by the study.
3) Study measurement of the perception on quality and accessibility of services in FNS prepared by SNV and partner CSOs will be presented to FNS Municipal Tables of Conception de Mar&#xED;a and El Triunfo, Choluteca to promote actions to address local problems based on evidence provided by the study. Main results of the study will be presented at other spaces where CSOs participate such as FNS Region Table #13, the Coalition against impunity, UTSAN and other units of the SINASAN.

Radial capsules to be played by community radios will be produce based on main findings of the studies to reach awareness of citizen on FNS issues. They will also be shared in different media in accordance with the FNS communication plan led by RDS.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="6.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: &quot;For the 2nd semester, 6 knowledge products were expected to be socialized, the result of this indicator is 6 knowledge products shared and socialized by CSOs.

1) FNS Municipal Policy with a climate change approach in the municipality of Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a. Concepci&#xF3;n de Maria&#x2019;s Policy was approved in the open town hall on 11/28/19
2) FNS Municipal Policy with climate change approach in the municipality of El Triunfo.
The main elements in both policies (Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a and El Triunfo) are: Environmental Protection and Climate Change, Citizen Participation and Local Governance, Local Production, Education for Food Security and Climate Change, Employment and Self Employment generation. For the design and approval of the policies the FNS Tables carried out the following actions: 2 Days for the design of advocacy strategies; 2 workshops for the design of local FNS policy proposals; 8 sectoral assemblies and 2 Municipal Forums to socialize the FNS policy proposals; Participation in 2 meetings of the Municipal Council to advocate for the development of open councils to present and approve local FNS policies; Participation in open council where the FNS policy of Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a was presented and approved.

3) Study of Water, Gender and FNS in Honduras, 2018.
4) Study Access to productive resources and the FNS, year 2019.
These two products were socialized in events with the participation of representatives of universities (UPNFM and UNAH-CURLP), Technical schools such as El Triunfo Institute, and FNS Tables such as El Triunfo and Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a.
Also in a meeting of the FNS Region 12 Table with the participation of representatives of Lepaterique, Oropol&#xEC;, Guinope, Yuscar&#xE0;n, CMDC municipalities; CSOs such as World Vision, CDH, RDS, FOPRIDEH; Programs and projects such as EUROSAN Project; Governmental units such as MiAmbiente Secretariat, National Plan and Country Vision, UTSAN; and the FNS Observatory of the National University UNAH.
5) Contr ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the first semester, it is expected to socialize the knowledge products that were elaborated in 2018, such as:
1) Water, Gender and FNS in Honduras, completed in December 2018.
2) 2015-2017 budget for Food and Nutrition Security, completed in March 2018.
3) The production of African palm and sugarcane in Honduras, completed in May 2018.
4) Measurement of the perception of the degree of Quality and Accessibility of FNS services in Honduras. Prepared by SNV.
5) Contributions to the proposal of the PyENSAN 2018-2030, a view from the civil society organizations participating in the V4CP program and other organizations and related spaces. Completed September 21, 2018.

To be share by different means according to the communication plan to be implemented in 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of formal and informal meetings of CSOs with government and/or private sector, international cooperation agencies, academia (universities), and platforms.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="7" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;CSOs participated in and held meetings and exchanges. The meeting they have had are:

Meeting with EU Delegation in Honduras, Meeting Strategic and Political Agenda Regional Table of Sovereignty and FNS, Santa Rosa de Cop&#xE1;n, Meeting FNS 13 regional Table in Choluteca, Region 12, Regional Tables Yoro, Group Drive the Dialogue on the Human Right to Food.

The main stakeholders represented in the meetings have been: European Union, Civil Society, private sector, national governmental institutions.
Calculation 7 meetings / 4 CSO = 1,75&quot;</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="14">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The   actions of the program will focus on: monitoring the implementation of the   PyENSAN (2018-2030) that includes the participatory design of prioritized   action plans. Support the Coordination Committee of the FNS Municipal Tables   to influence the inclusion of the FNS municipal tables in SINASAN and their   participation in the implementation of the PyENSAN and definition of   appropriate intervention strategies and roles. Systematization of selected   experiences as critical interpretation and understanding of the processes   lived. Dissemination of research on issues related to FNS. Continue the   implementation of the Communication Strategy to influence key actors and the   public in general about the importance of the inclusive implementation of   PyENSAN, adequate budgetary allocation, accountability mechanisms and open   spaces for the participation of CSOs in the process to advocate for the   improvement of the FNS services provided by the state.
 

    Participation and support of CSOs to COVISAN meetings will continue as an   essential element for transparency and accountability of FNS investments at   the national level. Similarly in the formal and informal meetings of SINASAN,   especially with UTSAN, COTISAN. Organization and participation in forums,   talks and meetings to present the main findings of the FNS studies to   influential actors.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="24.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: The target for this indicator was 14 encounters; CSOs participated and coordinated 24 formal and informal meetings:
* 1 ordinary meeting of COVISAN and coordination committee meetings with the participation of OBSAN-UNAH, IAIP, FONAC, CNA, Feed the Children, CONADEH, CDH, FOPRIDEH, RDS, SNV, UTSAN.
* National Meeting of the National Network of FNS Tables face-to-face, Training session on Analysis of the Legal FNS Framework and virtual meetings with the National Network. Participation of representatives of FNS Municipal Tables, CSOs and V4CP.
* Meetings with UTSAN to advocate for CSOs topics of interest and follow-up to the 2020 government plan.
* Participation in the meeting organized by UTSAN to present the Agricultural Development Program for Honduras in which participated representatives of UTSAN, World Vision, ADRA, FOPRIDEH, other CSOs, Army Force, and SNV.
* Virtual meetings with the FNS Regional Table 12 Region. participated representatives of Nation Plan,  OBSAN, CDH, FOPRIDEH and UTSAN.
* Day of systematization, with the FNS Table of Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a (Virtual). Municipal Directorate of Education, Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a FNS Municipal Table, Youth Network, Women&apos;s Network, CDH.
* Honduras Humanitarian Network Meetings. Participants: IOM, Misiones del Agua, NRC, Sphere Honduras, FAO, USAID, UNDP, IOM, Ayuda en Acci&#xF3;n, OXFAM in Honduras, CDH, M&#xE9;dicos del Mundo, Trocaire, UNFPA, UNHCR, World Vision, CRS, ACI, WFP, COSUDE, FLM / SMCA, MSF, UNDP, CASM, Red Cross, Habitat for Humanity, MNIGR, ADRA.
* Meetings with Mayors of the Municipalities of Santa Ana Yusguare, Corpus, Orocuina, Apasilagua, Choluteca; Visits members of the Regional Committee of FNS Tables, with the accompaniment of CDH.
* Meetings with Mayors of the Municipalities of San Marcos, San Francisco, Mercedes; Ocotepeque; Visits members of the FNS Regional Committee of Tables, with the accompaniment of ASONOG.
* Meeting of FNS Municipal Tables nationwide (virtual), with the participat ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="24">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the second semester actions will be carried out to provide accompaniment and follow-up to municipal and regional FNS committees in the CSO&apos;s influence area, setting up of political agendas, promote in the different spaces and media the validation and positioning of the FNS committees in face to the updating of the FNS Policy and Strategy; socialize the studies and implement the communication strategy to position the program&apos;s agenda.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="38.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The target established for the second semester was 24 events and the result reached is 38 events. A series of formal events were held with different actors in the area of influence of V4CP partners CSOs, as describe below: * Meetings with UTSAN Executive Director and Coordinator of FIRST FAO and technicians of UTSAN and FAO such as FAO Nutrition specialist, and UTSAN FNS specialist to monitor the PyENSAN -2018-2030 development process and advocate for the incorporation of the CSOs contributions to the draft version of the policy. * Workshops  in the North, South, West, and West-Central regions to get inputs on CSOs positioning in front of the update of the PyENSAN. * Participation in meetings of the National Council for Food and Nutrition Security - CONASAN in which progress and draft versions of the PyENSAN were presented. * Regional consultation workshops in the South, Central, West-Central, Atl&#xE1;ntida and the West for the construction of the positioning of the CSO partners of the program and other related organizations in front of the update of the PYENSAN 2018-2030. Participation of several actors of civil society, municipal and regional tables, NGOs, living forces of the communities, among others. * Forum with representatives of the organizations of the SARA Alliance and social movements in the framework of the World Food Day with the aim of establishing alliances with the Social Movement for its support in the approval of an inclusive FNS public policy and the support to the Contributions provided in the process of updating the PYENSAN. * Conference with representatives of different organizations such as &quot;Grupo Impulsor&quot; &quot;SARA alliance&quot; and others to present the positioning of partner CSOs in terms of the PyENSAN. * Exchange visit: representatives of municipal tables or committees of the South (San Antonio de Flores, Pespire, San Jose, San Isidro) shared experiences on advocacy, strategies, practices and results  with FNS tables in the West reg ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="28">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the first quarter, it is expected to carry out various relations with the new municipal authorities of the regions, days of follow-up on the progress of the work of the municipal FNS Tables in the regions and in the central zone. Meetings with the FNS to search for synergies and joint work.

For the second semester, it is expected to continue with several meetings of relationship and search for synergies and construction of political agendas.We will promote spaces for consultation and talks to socialize the studies of FNS, proposals for public policies of FNS in the different spaces and media.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="28.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The target set for this first semester of 2018 was 28 events and the result reached is 28 events. In addition, a series of events was held within the framework of the program, including the Induction Workshop for the new CSO`s technical liaisons and administrative staff. As part of 2018 operative strategy, the figure of CSO technical liaison was introduced in each partner CSO (paid by the program) to support the executive directors to implement the action and advocacy plans. Also two workshops were held, the first one to analyse the political context in FNS, and the second to review, analyse and adjust the action plans of the 4 CSOs in the FNS theme, based on the findings of the first workshop. Peer-to-peer workshops were initiated for CSOs to strengthen the capacities of other CSOs in their thematic areas of expertise, the workshop was on: Gender and Climate Change. A workshop was held to review and adjust the FNS`s regional profiles that will serve as inputs for the updating of the National Policy and Strategy of Food and Nutrition Security-PyENSAN. A workshop to prioritize the communication products for 2018 and define the role of the new CSO`s technical liaisons in the communication strategy was held in April.
One informal event was reported by our partner RDS: Middle level officers of the Technical Unit for Food and Nutrition Security (UTSAN) visited RDS to know the work RDS does on local public policies. As a result, RDS was invited to participate in the meeting of the Inter-institutional Technical Committee of SAN-COTISAN which has very little civil society participation.
Other formal events took place as described below:
* Meeting with CSOs working on FNS topic in the western region (Regional FNS Table (MRFNS), Regional unit of UTSAN (RUFNS), and National Pedagogical University Francisco Moraz&#xE1;n-UPNFM), to define the approach and relationship strategy of the MRFNS with the new municipal authorities for advocacy in FNS.
* Meeting with the boa ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="28">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the first semester, it is expected that they will be carried out and participate in a series of meetings and actions aimed at monitoring and advising for the incidence in the regional and municipal FNS committees in the areas of influence of the CSOs that promote municipal public policies in FNS and its link with the PyENSAN. Constitution and strengthening of the National Network of FNS Tables. Informative sessions with the spaces, alliances and/or platforms, regional and municipal tables on the fundamental aspects of the PyENSAN and its implementation process. Participate in formal and informal meetings with the UTSAN and the municipal, regional and national FNS Tables in their areas of influence. Development and participation of national forums and social mobilizations. Development of conversations, meetings and forums for socialization of the FNS studies with interested and influential actors. Participation in bilateral meetings with decision makers in the Secretariats of State participating in SINASAN to influence the action plans of the guidelines of the PyENSAN. Follow-up to the process of approval of the FNS national policy and strategy (PyENSAN 2018 -2030) developed by UTSAN. Workshops for the design of strategic advocacy actions for participation in the construction of the action plans of the PYENSAN guidelines (lobbying, media campaign, public opinion training) and mapping of key actors to identify strategic alliances, partners and advocacy targets. Meetings with the public, private and civil society sectors participating in the SINASAN, COTISAN and COVISAN in which the evidence generated by the V4CP will be presented. Coordination meetings with COVISAN to define articulation mechanism for its reactivation and participate in the formulation of the Nutrition Plan and the FNS Education Plan derived from the PYENSAN and other action plans for its guidelines, among other actions and participations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="34.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: &quot;The established target for this indicator the first semester was 28 events. The result achieved for this period is 34 formal meetings.
The most relevant meetings are: 1) Meetings and assemblies with the food and nutrition security municipal tables in the area of Ocotepeque, Lempira, Choluteca; National Table of risk management, and the Regional Table FNS #12. 2) Workshop for journalists and communicators in the Western zone to train them in how to use FNS information; Community Voices event to strengthen the capacities of FNS Tables to use the media for profiling FNS topic in the municipalities. 3) Forum Challenges and Opportunities for the FNS, Santa Rosa de Cop&#xE1;n. 4) Participation in community radios. 5) Ordinary meeting of COVISAN. 6) Meeting Director of the National Directorate of Climate Change (DNCC) to socialize the PyENSAN and the advocacy actions carried out to date at local and national level. 6) Meeting Sub director of the Scientific Research Directorate of National University (DICU-UNAH). 7) Workshop on indicators for Integrated Classification of Phases of Food Insecurity (CIF). 8) Workshop to socialize the main findings of the Study of FNS, Water and Gender. Directed to members of the Municipal Food Safety Board of the Municipality of El Triunfo, Choluteca. 9) Sixth NGO Congress &quot;&quot;Linking NGOs as a key actor, to promote sustainable development in Honduras&quot;&quot;. 10) Meeting with the Interinstitutional Decentralization Commission. 11) UTSAN-FAO Presentation of main results of the analysis of central government investments in FNS 2014-2018.

Relevant actors that have participated in these events are: Community Leaders, Mayor of Nueva Ocotepeque, communication media and community radio stations in the Western Zone, National Autonomous University of Honduras-UNAH, Commonwealth MANOFM, Technical Unit of Food and Nutritional Security - UTSAN, DNCC, Municipal Boards of El Triunfo and Concepcion de Maria-Choluteca, Mayor and Councilor of Concepci&#xF3; ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that by 2017 CSOs can participate in at least 5 meetings, forums or meetings each. The bi-annual target will be that each CSO participate in 2 meetings during the first semester and in 3 during the second semester of 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="39.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: The target set for the first semester 2017 was 5 and the achieved result is 9.75 (39 meetings/4 CSO). Contrary to expectations, the electoral process to elect municipal and national authorities has awakened the interest on CSO and V4CP themes. On the other hand, V4CP has organized a series of workshops and meetings with FNS authorities and other actors of interest, given the increased interest of CSO to participate in those events.
Most events have been formal meetings and workshop with a couple of informal meetings such as: Forums, workshops, focal groups, meetings of regional committees and CSO`s boards. The main events are listed below:
1) Meetings with EU and Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations officials, to inform about the V4CP and explore opportunities for coordination and collaboration.
2) Meeting with TU-FNS,  FNS governmental technical Unit Executive Director Mariano Jimenez and the First Secretary of the Dutch Embassy, Desiree Hagenaars. Inform about the progress of the V4CP. He expressed interest in the support that the program can provide in generating evidence for the actualization of FNS policy. Meeting with Cindy Serna &#x2013; TU-FNS west Office, and Iveth Izaguirre TU-FNS main office. Lobbing to get their support for the organisation of the FNS central region committee.
3) Focal groups and meetings with root-based organizations, NGO`s, Commonwealths, Educational institution and Private sector representatives. To inform about the V4CP and gather information about regional FNS priorities and proposed actions to face the main challenges, as inputs for the actualization process of the national FNS policy.
4) Participation in two meetings of the Interinstitutional Technical Committee for FNS ITC-FNS to get information about the process that will follow the TU-SAN to actualize the FNS policy and national strategy.
5) Meeting with the Presidencial Designated for climate change, Marlon Escoto. 6) Participation in meetings of r ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The higher score that expected is due mainly to the introduction of the workshops, focal groups and meetings with root-based organizations, NGO`s, Commonwealths, Educational institutions and Private sector representatives. To inform about the V4CP and gather information about FNS priorities and proposed actions to face the main challenges in the South region, as inputs for the actualization process of the national FNS policy. Actions that were introduced to move timely in line with the governmental plan to actualize the FNS policy and strategy. For the second semester of 2017, the CSO will continue with these meetings and focal groups to complete the process in the other four regions selected. 
In the second semester of 2017, the CSOs will also be lobbing to have meetings with representatives of main political parties at municipal and national to advocate for the FNS and RE themes to be include in their proposals for national agendas.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="44.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: &quot;The target set for the second semester of 2017 was 20 meetings and the result reached is 44 events. The result is much higher due to the election year that allowed several meetings, forums and talks to  position the topic FNS in the agendas of candidates for popular election.
V4CP also organized a series of consultation days, workshops and meetings with the authorities related to the subject and other stakeholders. 
All events have been formal, described below:
1) Consultation session in the South zone of the country, Atlantic and Center with: Academic sector (universities and technical schools), NGOs, Mancomunidades, Private sector and grassroots community organizations on the situation of Food and Nutrition Security (FNS) ). Report on the V4CP and collect information on the regional priorities of the FNS, proposed actions to face the main challenges and build proposals for joint guidelines as inputs for the process of updating the FNS National Policy.
2) Meetings with the representatives of the main political parties at the municipal and national levels, the Liberal Party (CEPL), the Innovation and Unity Party (PINU), the Christian Democratic Party, the Freedom and Refoundation Party (LIBRE) and the National Party; to influence the inclusion of FNS and RE issues as a priority in their national agendas.
3) Conferences and Political Forums at municipal and national level &quot;&quot;Challenges of the FNS and RE in Honduras&quot;&quot; with technical personnel, candidates for deputies, mayors and presidential level.
4) Meetings of municipal tables, meetings with FNS tables R. 12 in downtown and FNS tables in the West. The visibility of the program in the various events and in the media has allowed political pronouncements regarding the FNS issue.
5) I and II meeting of consumers, it was attended by the Committee for the Defense of Consumers, Women&apos;s Networks, Media, Center for Research and Promotion of Human Rights, Alliance SARA, FIAN International, among others. It i ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;For the second semester, it is expected that a series of meetings and actions aimed at advocacy at local, regional and national levels will be carried out based on the FNS Policy and Strategy-PyENSAN 2018-2030. A survey will be done to identify which FNS Tables are active to contact them and explore their interest in a National Network of FNS Tables. 
Informative sessions will be developed to present and analyse the PyENSAN and its implementation process through the Action Plans. The main audiences are: Grassroots organizations, NGOs, CSOs, Interinstitutional Platforms, municipal and regional FNS Tables.
Participation in the formal and informal meetings of SINASAN, especially with UTSAN, COTISAN, COVISAN.
Organization and participation on forums, talks, and meetings to present main findings of FNS studies to influential actors.
Bilateral meetings with decision makers in State Secretariats members of SINASAN to influence them in favour of a participative design and implementation of prioritized action plans of the PyENSAN. 
Lobby, media campaign, the formation of public opinion and mapping of key actors to identify strategic alliances, partners and advocacy objectives.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="42.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: &quot;The target of this indicator was 30 events. CSOs organized and participated in 42 formal and informal events. Some of the events are detailed:
1) I meeting to reactivate the FNS Surveillance Commission. Representatives of organizations such as Caritas, FNS Technical Unit (UTSAN), National Convergence Forum (FONAC), Save the Children, FOPRIDEH, ASONOG, CDH, SNV.
2) II COVISAN meeting: Presentation of regulations and laws about compliance with the Right to Adequate Food.
3) III COVISAN meeting: socialization of the progress and structure of the COVISAN report to be presented to the National Food and Nutrition Security System (SINASAN).
4) National Forum on Migration, Development and Food Security.
5) Global Gathering &quot;&quot;Scaling Up Nutrition&quot;&quot;.
6) Civil Society Platform meeting represented by V4CP with Gerda Verburg - Global Coordinator SUN Movement.
7) Meetings with the National Commission of FNS -CONASAN.
8) National Meeting of Municipal Food and Nutrition Security Tables.
10) Meetings, conferences for the elaboration and socialization of the proposal of FNS Municipal Public Policy. El Triunfo Municipality and Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a.
11) Planning and advocacy meetings with the Municipal Corporation from El Triunfo and Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a.
12) Concepci&#xF3;n de Maria Open Town Hall for approval of the FNS Public Municipal Policy of Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a.

Among the more relevant actors that participated in the events are: World Food Program-WFP, Global Director of the SUN Movement, Technical Unit of SAN-UTSAN, Secretariats of State: Health, Agriculture, Education, General Coordination, United Nations Organization for the Food and Agriculture-FAO, Economic Commission for Latin America and the Caribbean-ECLAC, Ministry of Development and Social Inclusion - SEDIS, Parliamentary Front against Hunger, Latin American Faculty of Social Sciences-FLACSO, European Union-EU, International Fund for Agricultural Development-FIDA, representatives of FNS Municipal Tables nat ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of verbal interventions by CSOs at relevant meetings.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="7" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;In the same interventions mentioned above the CSOs jointly with SNV have presented the program and its actions in the FNS topic, in some meetings it has been used Power Point slides.
Calculation 7 meetings / 4 CSO = 1,75&quot;</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Verbal   interventions are expected as a series of meetings, workshops, and forums   will be held to support the advocacy actions of the FNS Municipal Tables to   influence municipal budgets. Meetings with UTSAN to advocate for the   inclusion of partner CSOs in the process of design of the prioritized action   plans of the PyENSAN, and the inclusion of the Coordination Committee of the   FNS municipal tables in the SINASAN. Continue the support to COVISAN and the   implementation of the communication strategy, among other actions.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="12.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: A target of 7 verbal interventions by CSOs in relevant meetings had been defined. CSOs achieved 12 interventions in different events related to:
* Face-to-face and virtual follow-up meetings with UTSAN to carry out advocacy actions for the implementation of PyENSAN and its budget allocation. Presentation and socialization of the Investment Study and Analysis in two municipalities.
* Virtual sessions for &quot;Presentation and Socialization of the Study and Analysis of Differentiated Investment by FNS Pillars in the municipality of Tambla, Lempira and Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a, Choluteca&quot; emphasizing the conclusions, findings and recommendations.
* Meetings to prepare the first COVISAN Report, coordination and gathering of information with the accompaniment of a consultant and CSO members of the V4CP, SNV and members of the FNS Surveillance Commission. A participatory meeting was held to provide feedback to the methodology and tools to collect the information.
* Meetings and face-to-face conferences National Network of FNS Municipal Tables, Coordination Committee of Tables and FNS Regional Network Tables southern zone. An analysis of the FNS 2011 law and PyENSAN and identification of spaces for advocacy was carried out. Facilitation for the construction of the action plan of the coordination board of the National Network of FNS Tables during 2020. Accompanying the construction of guidelines for the political advocacy strategy on the FNS issue at the municipal level, to be applied in the second semester of 2020.
* Meetings with Mayors of the Municipalities of Santa Ana Yusguare, Corpus, Orocuina, Apasilagua, Choluteca and San Marcos, San Francisco, Mercedes; Ocotepeque. Visits made by the members of the Regional Committee and the Coordination Committee of FNS Tables, with the support of CDH and ASONOG with the aim of influencing the creation of a FNS municipal table and design of FNS policy and budget allocated to its implementation.
* Meetings with the FNS Regi ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that CSOs have a greater intervention in the second semester given the series of municipal and regional events planned such as regional workshops to validate the FNS regional profiles and to discuss the potential impact of the new PyESAN. V4CP aims to generate a positioning in front of the new PyESAN. Planned actions include to implement a strategy and plan for dissemination and advocacy and to build alliances at the municipal, regional and national levels.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="20.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The target established for the second semester was 12, however CSOs and SNV have had 20 relevant verbal interventions in different events, especially in the second semester. Some of the interventions that have been made focused on: a) pronouncements on the importance of a multi sectorial approach where FNS is seen not only from the availability of food but also quality, nutrition, climate change and variability, risk management, among others factors. Key actors on those meetings: Minister of Agriculture and Livestock-SAG, Secretary of General Coordination of Government-SCGG, FOPRIDEH, Secretary of My Environment, Representative of the Honduran Council of the Company Private - COHEP. b) It was reiterated in different meetings that the contributions presented by V4CP are in line with the 11 guidelines of the PyENSAN that addresses topics such as: * Access to productive resources such as land,  Community-municipality articulation, from the political to the operative level * Decentralization and participation: role of Secretaries of Education and Agriculture, both key actors for production. The systemic approach should prevail in the plans. * Make visible the FNS tables in the Policy and strategy. Make a specific decentralization plan that includes the FNS tables and provides them legal representation in the SINASAN (CONASAN, COVISAN and COTISAN). Key actors on those meetings: Executive Director of the Technical Unit of FNS in Honduras and Coordinator IRS FAO. c) Presentation of regional FNS profiles in the Atlantic littoral, South, West, North-west, Central regions where FNS problems were analysed and prioritized and profiles revised. Key actors on those meetings: FNS Municipal Tables, Lenca de la Paz Indigenous Movement (MILPAH), UTC, GOAL, among others. d) Reading of positioning and contributions provided by the CSOs to the draft of the PYENSAN. Key actors on these readings: Association of Women in Defence of Life (AMDV) Peasant Association in Defenc ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are expected to have greater participation and intervention, given the different actions at local and national levels  planed for 2019, as mentioned in the previous indicator.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="26.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: &quot;A target of 10 interventions by CSOs at relevant meetings was set. However, CSOs had 26 intervention in the different events described in the paragraph above. Partner CSOs have worked in a coordinated manner and accompanied national advocacy actions led by FOPRIDEH who is the CSO with legal participation in the National System of Nutritional Food Security (SINASAN).

The main interventions have been oriented to the following: Socialization of the FNS Policy and Strategy PyENSAN, capacity building, and advocacy with local governments-Mayors. Presentation of the roadmap to design FNS Municipal Policies and the Advocacy strategy. CSO support the preparation of the 2019 operative plan of the FNS Municipal Table.
At the COVISAN meeting, the UTSAN Director was consulted regarding the municipal budget for the FNS. What mechanism or procedure should be followed for the budget allocation for the FNS in the municipalities? His answer is that no more budget lines should be opened in favour of the FNS, since there are already lines for investment in sewerage projects, water systems, letrinization, among others. In the same way, he was addressed in the Forum about the role of the FNS Municipal Tables in the implementation of the PyENSAN. His answer is that there is no budget for the functioning of the Municipal tables, the resources were channelled through the commonwealths so Municipal tables should join efforts with them.
The actions carried out by the V4CP program to date at the local and national level have been socialized, and information on FNS problems has been presented. The capacities of the membership of the FNS Tables have been strengthened to use the media to position the FNS theme in the municipalities.
In the Forum, Challenges and opportunities for the FNS, Santa Rosa, 2 magisterial presentations were made on: Challenges and opportunities for the FNS Global to Local // questions and answers. b) The PyENSAN Challenges and Opportunities for the FNS. ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are expected to have greater intervention, since a series of actions have been established at the local and national levels.

Work will be done to build alliances at the municipal, regional and national levels with the new actors in the food and nutrition security sector.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="24.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-11-2018: The target set for the first semester is 12 interventions by all CSOs, but it was possible to carry out 24 interventions in different events to generate opportunities for coordination and association with other organizations working on FNS. Spaces have been open for the participation of partner CSO through presentations and open discussions of the program, FNS problems at local, regional and national level, and the FNS advocacy plan to face the update and approval of the FNS National Policy and Strategy. From the action of the program, the political advocacy is promoted from local governments to the national level, and it is being brought into the strategic agendas.
Some of the actors that have participated in the events where these interventions were carried out are: FNS-FNSTU Technical Unit, Food Security, Nutrition and Resilience Program in the Dry Corridor (EUROSAN), Municipal Mayors of La Paz-Marcala-San Antonio de Oriente-Ojojona-Guinope-Lepaterique, Institutes of knowledge such as: Zamorano, UNAH, UPNFM; NGOs such as: Inter-American Disaster Mitigation Network-GOAL, CARE International; Save the Children; international organizations such as Canadian Cooperation; Government institutions such as: Ministry of Health, National Institute of Statistics, Community radio stations in the southern zone and Lepaterique and community representatives.
Some of the agreements or results that have been achieved so far have been to propose a process of socialization of the actions of the FNS-FNSMT in the Assembly of the FNS-FNSMT Territorial Table of the Comayagua area, the FNSUT will facilitate the rapprochement between the FNSMT and the FNSMT in that area. It was agreed to hold a technical meeting in the territory to identify the lines of work and coordination between ASONOG, FAO and FNSTU. The presentations attracted the interest of the participating organizations. Commitments were defined by the board of directors of the Independent Lenca de la Paz Indigen ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are expected to have 3 verbal interventions each in 2017. The bi-annual target will be that each CSO have one intervention during the first semester and 2 during the second semester of 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="13.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: CSOs and SNV had 13 relevant verbal interventions at different meetings (score of 3.25 versus target of 3). In those meetings V4CP and its progress has been introduced, lobbing to establish liaison with relevant organizations has been done; dialogue and consent process have taken place with local actors related to join actions to advocate for FNS policy actualization.
The interventions have been well received by local actors who expressed that they find the V4CP relevant. As a result, some partners CSOs have been interviewed by local media to talk on FNS.
Some of the organizations that have been represented in the events, where those interventions took place, are: FNS governmental technical Unit TU-FNS, European Union EU, United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization -FAO, Commission for Rural Development and Protected areas, root-based organizations, local governments, Regional FNS Committees, Presidencial Unit for Climate Change.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The score for the reporting period is a little bit higher than the set target of 3 interventions for each CSO. 
For the second semester similar trend is expected giving the different focal groups and meetings that will take place at local and national level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="33.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: &quot;The CSOs together with SNV and IFPRI have had 33 relevant verbal interventions in different events. The goal established for the second semester was 12 of them, however, it was overcome in view of the fact that a series of meetings, discussions and forums were held to influence the different agendas, in the same way a change was made to the score defined by SNV Netherlands .
A series of events had been established to generate pressure and establish relationships with the relevant organizations; processes of dialogue and consensus have been carried out with local actors to carry out joint actions to advocate for the updating of FNS policy.
The interventions have been well received by local actors, some candidates for deputies and mayor expressed in the political talks that they were unaware of the problem in the FNS issue and that they would support the program in this subject if they were elected in the general elections. It is also important to mention that in some cases, CSOs are the reference points in FNS theme and they have searched for interviews.
Some of the organizations that have been represented at the events where these interventions were carried out are: FNS Technical Unit-FNSTU, European Union-EU, United Nations Organization for Agriculture and Food -FAO, Commission for Development Rural and protected areas, local and municipal governments, municipal committees, academia sector, political parties of greater relevance in the country, among others.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="21">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;CSOs action plans for the second semester include a series of meetings and events with Municipal and Regional FNS Tables that have the potential for CSOs verbal interventions:
At national level, CSOs plan to influence the review of the FNS Decree Law No. 25-2011, published in the official gazette on July 7, 2011. This initiative has the potential for CSOs verbal interventions in meetings with UTSAN, Finance Secretariat, FAO/FIRST, Budget Committee of the National Congress, Social Forum of External Debt and Development of Honduras-FOSDEH, and the Central American Institute of Fiscal Studies-ICEFI.
CSOs will be supporting the El Triunfo and Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a Municipal Tables in the design and advocacy process for the approval of the FNS Municipal Public Policies.
It is expected to advocate through verbal interventions based on evidence in meetings of the FNS National System to advocate for a National Network of FNS Municipal Tables and the regulation of the FNS Law.
The partner CSOs consider that it is necessary to reform the FNS Law to align it to the current context and the PyENSAN (2018-2030) but they cannot assume the responsibility to influence it as an outcome of the V4CP Program since there are many variables they do not control and the time horizon left of V4CP is too short.                                                                                   

What SNV and the partner CSOs are doing is lobbing for a meeting with UTSAN and FAO to know their plans and explore the possibility of their participation on this matter. No answer yet.                             

The results on policies report of Honduras includes the PyENSAN (2018-2030), the FNS Municipal Policy of San Antonio de Flores and the FNS Municipal Policy of San Isidro, Choluteca.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="26.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: &quot;The target for this indicator is 21, but CSOs have had 26 interventions; which have been relevant and well received by the actors. They participated in a series of meetings, discussions and forums. They made statements to influence the agendas of different actors. Among the main interventions:
1) Reactivation of COVISAN. The meeting was organized and facilitated by FOPRIDEH with the participation of the other partner CSOs. Main agreements: Strengthen the local structures of consultation and social oversight. Focalization of the PyENSAN in the municipal budgets. Conceptualize the social observation and oversight model. Hold a socialization meeting with the COVISAN members designated by law to inform them about the main agreements of the First ordinary meeting of COVISAN. The CSOs succeed in getting UTSAN involved in the process.
2) At the II meeting of COVISAN partner CSOs made a presentation on a) the right to adequate food, and b) structure of the COVISAN report according to regulations. They also raised the attention to the need to reform or rule the FNS law that includes FNS local and regional tables in SINASAN and a country-level work approach. This initiative was supported by other participants. FOPRIDEH will coordinate the preparation of the report that by law COVISAN has to present to the National Food and Nutrition Security Council (CONASAN) and FNS Technical Committee (COTISAN).
3) At the III meeting of COVISAN, FOPRIDEH led the event and presented the progress and structure of the report to be presented to SINASAN. At the meeting, government and civil society entities participated. The initiative to reform the FNS law was also socialized. At this meeting, the representative of UTSAN commented that it would be pertinent to socialize the activation of COVISAN with COTISAN since they are open to involve other civil society organizations in the COVISAN.
4) Participation in meetings of FNS municipal tables where the structure and functions of  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alliances at local, regional and national level generated</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of alliances generated (CSO networks, platforms, tables, private sector alliances, FSN stakeholders) at local, regional and national level</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Currently, no alliances have been generated from the CSO platform, however, CSOs are holding meetings internally to socialize the program with their partner organizations and relevant stakeholders that are directly related to some programs and projects they are currently executing. It is hoped that some alliances may be generated in the future.
Generating alliances and engaging the active participation of several actors is necessary to influence a FNS policy. Potential partners to support advocacy actions include other NGOs working in the FNS topic, universities, technical schools, international organizations such as the World Bank, USAID, the European Union, the Canadian Agency for International Cooperation and others.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No   target is set for 2020. However, the Coordination Committee of FNS Municipal   Tables (CCMMSAN) will be accompanied and monitored, accordingly with the work   plan that will be developed for the rest of the V4CP program. Partner CSOs   expressed interest in continuing the support to the Committee once the   program ends. This is because the MMSANs are the legitimate voice of the   communities, they are the ones who work directly with the communities and   know their realities. Therefore, it is necessary to seek their legitimacy and   recognition for them to be taken into account.
 

    Article 19 of the FNS Law states that: &quot;The Secretariats of State of   the Presidential Office, the Ministry of Interior and Population, the   Ministry of Social Development and the Technical Secretariat of External   Planning, shall establish mechanisms for the creation of the FNS Regional and   Municipal Tables, in accordance with the Regional Councils established in the   Law Planning System for the establishment of a Country Vision and the   Adoption of a Nation Plan for Honduras&quot;. Despite the above, the law does   not indicate how these Tables should be formed. The rights and   responsibilities of these tables have not been incorporated into the National   Food and Nutrition Security System (SINASAN). Most have been made up of   cooperation programs and/or projects executed in different areas of the   country.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: No target was set for this indicator.
The Coordination Committee of FNS National Municipal Tables Network (CCMMSAN) has been accompanied, in accordance with the work plan prepared at the beginning of the year. Advocacy actions are carried out to seek legitimacy and recognition so that they are taken into account and incorporated into the internal structure of the National Food and Nutrition Security System. Spaces for analysis and discussion have been generated on the subject, for which a legal analysis of the agreements, treaties and the FNS Law 2011 in Honduras has been analysed and discussed with the CCMMSAN.
ASONOG and CDH accompanied the members of CCMMSAN on visits to the Municipal Councils of Sinuapa and Concepci&#xF3;n Ocotepeque. In both cases, the municipal mayors showed interest in forming the FNS Municipal Table and participate in the FNSMT Network. In the same way, visits were made to the Trinational and Sensenti Valley commonwealth, made up of 3 municipalities: San Marcos, San Francisco and Mercedes (MANVASEN), they were willing to coordinate joint actions in FNS. In the same way, in the southern region, visits were made to the municipal mayors of Corpus, Orocuina, Apasilagua and Santa Ana de Yusguare, with the latter, as a result of this visit, the FNS Municipal Table was formed, the board of directors was elected, in a community assembly attended by 47 people (23 women and 24 men) representing the Water Board, the Board of Trustees, the Municipal Commissioner, the FNS Regional Network of Municipal Tables and the Committee of the FNS National Network of Municipal Tables.

Leaders of the FNS Municipal Tables and V4CP made a context analysis of the governmental decreed PCM 030-2020 and its effects on financing options proposed by the government to agroindustrial companies and small producers, on CSOs and V4CP work and outcomes. An online forum called &#x201C;Analysis and reflection of the current economic, political and social context, in relation  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;It is expected to build alliances at municipal, regional and national level in 2018 to coordinate actions, exchange information and obtain support for the implementation of the advocacy plan with the new actors of the Food and Nutritional Security sector, with organizations and social movements with which there are matching points in the FNS theme.

The allies that could support the advocacy actions would be other NGOs working on the issue, universities, international organizations such as the World Bank, the United States Agency for International Development -USAID, European Union -UE, United Nations Organization for Food and Agriculture-FAO among others. Additionally, bilateral alliances with organizations, platforms and networks that CSOs have built individually could contribute to the advocacy processes of updating an inclusive FNS policy.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: The target of the indicator was to generate 2 formal alliances and it was possible to sign two alliances: one with some community radio stations in the southern region: Radio Voices Aramecina, Morolica Estereo, Stereo Pespire, Choluteca Triunfe&#xF1;a and Zapotillo Orocuina. The second one with Radio Lepaterique in Francisco Moraz&#xE1;n. The purposes of the alliances are: a) Socialization of the results of studies and/or research on the FNS and RE issues with emphasis on improved stoves for the fight against poverty. Through mechanisms agreed by the parties. b) Exchange of publications, information and experiences. c) Promotion for the generation of public policies on the topics of FNS and RE-with emphasis on improved stoves. d) Promotion of the adoption of improved stoves for the fight against poverty. e) Any other collaboration of mutual interest, these alliances were promoted by RDS.
Other formal alliances that support the actions of V4CP were established but no documents were signed with the Committee for the Defence of Honduran Consumers (CODECOH) and the Commonwealth of Northern Choluteca (MANORCHO) promoted by RDS; National Pedagogical University Francisco Moraz&#xE1;n (UPNFM) promoted by ASONOG.

ASONOG has strengthened relationships with other actors such as: a)  Mennonite Social Action Commission (CASH), member of ASONOG that facilitate to join efforts to create the FNS Table of Tambla in Lempira, which is chaired by the Municipal Corporation; In the case of Tomal&#xE1; in Lempira, CASH and a municipal councillor will follow up and support the process of activating the FNS table, b) links with west Commonwealth, with the ETEA Foundation, local governments, municipal health commissions, and the Ministry of Health that have shown interest in the process of updating the PyENSAN.   RDS joint efforts with Association of Development Persp&#xED;rense (ADEPES) to advocate for FNS municipal policies in San Antonio de Flores and San Isidro in Choluteca.  CDH strengthened i ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A strong work is expected in the area of lobbying and socialization of the program to ensure that alliances can be established with other CSOs interested in a FNS inclusive policy.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-03-2018: &quot;CSOs have not build formal alliances (no signed agreements) even though lobbying and socialization of the program has been carried out with many actors and relevant FNS information has been shared with them. On the other hand, CSOs have bbeen invited to participate in different networks and tables at local and regional level:                   
                                                                                                              CSOs held internal meetings to socialize the program with their partner organizations and relevant stakeholders directly related to some actual programs and projects. 
CDH strengthened relations with Lenca Indigenous Independent Movement of La Paz Honduras-MILPAH and UTC within the framework of the consultation sessions held in the La Paz area, they were the focal points of the consultations and supported the calls. They have also strengthened relations with the Commonwealth of Gar&#xED;funa Municipalities of Honduras - MAMUGAH and with the GAT - Territorial Support Group - (multi-stakeholder space linked to the Ayuda en Acci&#xF3;n project) who managed the calls for the talks.
CDH, ASONOG and RDS are part of the Dialogue Driving Group for the Human Right to Food. This is a very important space that should be consolidated and linked to the processes related to the program. This space was created at the beginning of the FNS Route program of RDS to work in the Forum &quot;&quot;For the Human Right to Food in Honduras&quot;&quot;. The group has been maintained and strengthened as a space for reflection on the issue of food sovereignty in which different organizations linked to the field participate.
ASONOG and RDS, through the work they have been doing in the regional and municipal tables, managed to be invited to be part of the Board of Directors of the FNS Table R.03 Occidente and the FNS R.12 Central region, respectively.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alliances were built the previous three years. These allances are expected to be maintained and strengthened for the rest of the program. 2019 action plans of the CSOs are focused on advocacy actions to achieve medium and long-term results. Main actions focus on: monitoring the implementation of the PyENSAN and influence its action plans; advocacy actions in related secretariats of state and other key actors; socialization of evidence, monitoring and accompaniment of municipal and regional FNS tables, among others. It is expected that new alliances will emerge but that they will be conjunctural by the actions to be carried out at the municipal, regional and national levels in 2019. So, CSOs do not consider a need to establish a new target for this indicator.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: &quot;A target for this indicator was not set in view that the alliances were built in previous three years. CSOs efforts concentrated in maintaining and strengthening the alliances. However, as a result of the capacity building and accompaniment work done by partner CSOs with the FNS municipal tables, a Coordination Committee of FNS Municipal Tables (CCMMSAN) was organized with the objective of strengthening thematic and advocacy capabilities in its members and develop advocacy actions to improve the FNS status of the Honduran population, particularly population of the municipalities they represent. 

This Coordination Committee of FNS Municipal Tables (CCMMSAN) has 5 members that represent the FNS Municipal Tables of: El Triunfo y San Jos&#xE9; &#x2013; Choluteca; Ocotepeque &#x2013; Ocotepeque; Tambla-Lempira; Las Lajas - Comayagua.

The functions of the Coordination Committee of FNS Municipal Tables (CCMMSAN) are:
1) Establish fluid and effective communication mechanisms with the FNS municipal tables (MMSAN). 
2) Represent MMSAN before municipal, regional and/or national entities, as well as social organizations and movements related to the FNS.
3) Share FNS information with MMSAN and social organizations interested in the subject. 
4) Maintain permanent contact with civil society organizations, international cooperation, programs and projects related to FNS.

A mapping of municipal FNS tables was carried out nationwide, so far 22 municipal tables were identified in various municipalities of the country in the departments of Ocotepeque: Bel&#xE9;n Gualcho, San Francisco and Nueva Ocotepeque; Lempira: La Iguala, Tambla and Talgua; Cop&#xE1;n: Santa Rita; Yoro: Sulaco and Victoria; Comayagua: Las Lajas and La Libertad; Choluteca: El Triunfo, Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a, El Corpus, Namasigue, San Isidro, San Jos&#xE9;, Orocuina, San Antonio de Flores, Pespire, Nacaome; Valle: Nacaome and Francisco Moraz&#xE1;n: Lepaterique.

At the southern region level, it was possible to establish alliances with t ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coherent budgetary allocation in line with the inclusive FNS policy, and its operative plan</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree in which the budget meets the structure and budget lines that respond to what is established in the POA</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="tbc" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Based on the 2016 budget analysis study and its consistency with the National Policy on Food and Nutrition Security 2006-2015, IFPRI will carry out an analysis corresponding to the coherence of the budget executed with the sectoral plans that are linked to FNS as: Health , Education, agriculture and livestock, social development and others that correspond with information at the macro level.
It is also intended to generate the experience to transfer the capacities to the CSOs that participate in the program.
IFPRI will transfer the capabilities to CSOs so that they can subsequently develop it with SNV with technical support from IFPRI by 2019.
The methods of information gathering and measurement that IFPRI will be using will be parametric, agreed upon and defined jointly with them.&quot;</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target   for this indicator is not defined. In spite of it, actions will be develop to   try to influence budget allocation for FNS such as: Workshops to socialize   the main findings of the budget analysis 2015 &#x2013; 2019 as well as the findings   of the Municipal budget analysis for FNS in two municipalities and the   specific budget lines identified to allocate FNS funds. In addition,   consistency of the allocation defined in the FNS Policy and Strategy   2018-2030 will be analysed. Key messages from these studies will be used in   intensive campaign to show the benefits and impact of investment in FNS. CSOs   will establish links with the public media to transmit their key messages.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: There is no target defined for this indicator, since the national budget does not have a specific line for the FNS issue, and there are not resources allocated for the implementation of PyENSAN.
The deficit estimated by the government for the Central Administration, in the approved 2020 budget, is 1.5% of GDP. In 2019, the Central Bank of Honduras (BCH) lowered its growth estimates to about 2.9% for both years. The inflation rate remained at around 4%. In December 2019, the IMF approved the extension of the Standby Agreement for two years for a total amount of US $ 312m. In March 2020, all the resources to be disbursed in 2020 (US $ 143m) were used to support the government in its fight against COVID-19. In 2019, the Central Administration (CA) spending represents approximately 20% of GDP, if spending on principal and interest payments is subtracted (approximately 6.5% of GDP), the CA spending that can be allocated to social and infrastructure investment is reduced to 13.5% of GDP.

In previous years, the loss of relative relevance of the FNS agenda was pointed out in the face of other social challenges such as migration to the United States, violence prevention, and the need to find synergies, since they are not antagonistic issues, but complementary. From the analysis of the execution of the 2019 budget, it is clear the budget reduction towards activities measured within FNS spending, as well as the lack of commitment to other social areas such as the city woman project or support for migrants. This reveals that the GoH, in its desire to contain public spending, does not fulfil its commitment to protect the most vulnerable sectors of its population.

The reduction in social spending has relevance in the context of global recession due to COVID-19. The reallocation of resources from multilateral programs towards the fight against COVID-19 will leave vulnerable populations in an even deeper poverty situation, with needs that will grow exponentially  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">If the CSO are trained iby IFPRI in 2017, it is expected that for year 2018 CSOs can perform this analysis for coming years with the accompaniment of the SNV.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">04-07-2018: Information will be provided by IFPRI, pending sending</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: The target for this indicator is not defined. IFPRI study on 2015-2017 FNS budget analysis and the 2016 study financed by the European Union &quot;Impact Evaluation of the Policy, Programs and Projects on FNS in Regions 12 and 13&quot; indicate that neither the FNS National Policy (PNSAN) nor the FNS National Strategy (ENSAN) have contributed substantially to reduce food insecurity. The main reasons for that are: a) The government did not assigned resources for their implementation, b) The policy and the strategy were not known by the actors that were supposed to implement them, c) There was not will to articulate the governmental actions to the guidelines and objectives of the law and strategy. The effectiveness in the use of resources was not as expected either, especially when compared with other countries. An expenditure level of 2.7-2.9% of GDP for FNS indicates that these are not central components of the development strategy, but compensatory measures within a model of development that emphasizes other axes. (D&#xED;az-Bonilla and Centuri&#xF3;n, IFPRI, August 2017).
On the other hand, the FNS policy was approved by the Government in 2006 with effect until 2015. The FNS national strategy was approved in 2010 with effect until 2022 and the Honduras General Budget does not have specific budget lines assigned for the FNS issue. Therefore, we can say that the policy is not in force and that the budget does not comply with the lines of the structure and budget for the policy. 
As mentioned in previous indicators, a PyENSAN 2018-2030 is being updated, but it is not approved yet. Once the PyENSAN is approved and under implementation, a study can be carried out to inform about its degree of coherence with the planning and the budget.
The 2017 budget project for the central administration and decentralized institutions amounts to L 228,688.1 million, which represented 46% of 2016 GDP at the time of budget approval. The budget of the Central Administration approved was L  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No target will be included for this indicator since the PyENSAN is not approved yet nor its actions plans have been developed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: &quot;The target for this indicator was not defined. The National budget does not have a specific line for FNS so it can be said that it does not comply with the strategic guidelines of the PyENSAN.
In the study conducted by the IFPRI &quot;&quot;FNS Budget 2018&quot;&quot;: The fiscal deficit of the Central Government Administration of Honduras (GdH) was reduced from 7.9% of GDP in 2013, to 2.6% in 2018; less than the 3.2% target set in the last IMF Stand-By Agreement and the Fiscal Responsibility Law.
Total Expenditure represented 38% of GDP in 2015, increasing to 45% in 2016, then lowering and maintaining around 40% in 2017 and 2018.
The tax revenue covers 75% of the total expenditure and the rest is financed with external and internal debt. If the payment of principal and interest is subtracted from the total expenditure, the expenditure allocated to other activities (productive investment, social projects, education, health, climate change support, provision of public services, etc.) is reduced, even more since 2017, year in which the expenditures begins to fall. In the budget approved in 2018, tax revenues were underestimated, presenting them around 17% of GDP, when in fact, as of 2016, the tax pressure increased to 18% of GDP in 2018. The accrued expenditure of 2018 in nominal terms grew 8% compared to 2017 and in terms of GDP, it grew almost 2 percentage points. 
The budgetary allocation to FNS activities maintained a certain priority in the use of resources, despite successive cuts in spending in productive areas and rigidity in spending.  
Debt as a proportion of total spending went from representing 12% in 2016 of total spending to 14% in 2018, however, FNS spending remained constant in proportional terms as of 2016 (this reflects a prioritization effort of this type of spending by the government). However, as of 2017, the debt accelerates its growth rate both as a proportion of Total Expenditure and in terms of GDP.
This whole situation reduces the budget space  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of the sector budgets dedicated to FNS (health, education, agriculture etc.)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="tbc" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Based on the 2016 budget analysis study and its consistency with the National Policy on Food and Nutrition Security 2006-2015, IFPRI will carry out an analysis to determine the percentage of sector budgets dedicated to SAN in a sector-specific way, such as : Health, education, agriculture and livestock, social development and others that correspond.
It is also intended to generate the experience to transfer the capacities to the CSOs that participate in the program, on the other hand there will be an accompaniment from the consultant IFPRI will contract for the elaboration of the budget analysis study to be elaborated it in 2019.
The measurement methods that IFPRI will be using will be parametric, agreed upon and defined jointly with them.
It will determine an indicator for each sector later once you have clearly defined sectors that will be parsed.&quot;</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.23%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The   target set in this indicator is the same as reported by IFPRI, since the   increase or decrease in the FNS budget allocation is beyond the control of   CSOs. IFPRI will prepare the budget document for FNS 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="-1.11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: No target is defined for this indicator, as there is no specific budget line for FNS. The study carried out by IFPRI in 2020 &quot;The Budget for Food and Nutritional Security 2017-2020&quot;, indicates that the budget allocation for FNS activities was reduced, by little more, from HDL 1,500 m, representing a fall of almost 0.5% of the GDP (2.4% of GDP). SAN spending in 2019 represented, in terms of GDP, the lowest proportion since 2015 (in the period 2015-2018 it ranged between 2.7% and 3%). The need to keep spending cuts is hitting those most in need. This contradicts the commitment made by the government, with its citizens, and its commitments with the IMF, to protect the most vulnerable sectors. Spending in FNS 2018 is 16,265.97 million lempiras and in 2019 it was 14,664.24 million lempiras, so there is a decrease of -1.11% based on total spending (capital payments and public bank debt not included).

The IFPRI study divided the data into 5 groups:
1) Agricultural development and value chains: 2018 accumulated expenditure: L. 3,114.91 million compared to 2019: 3,226.91 result is an increase of L. 112.00 million lempiras. 2018 % FNS expenditure is 19.15% and in 2019, 22.01 with an increase of 2.86% of total expenditure.
2) Rural and regional development: accumulated spending 2018: L.7969.46 million compared to 2019: 6536.47 decrease of -L. 1,432.99 million lempiras. 2018 % FNS expenditure is 48.99%compared to 44.57% in 2019 with a decrease of -4.42%. 
3) Social protection nets: the accrued expenditure in 2018: L. 1,801.19 million lempiras compared to 2019 of L. 1705.96, shows a decrease of -L. 95.23 million lempiras. The 2018 % of FNS expenditure is 11.07% and in 2019 11.63%, corresponding to an increase of 0.56%.
4) Health and nutrition: the accrued expense in 2018 is L. 2,005.47and in 2019 is L. 2117.46, with an increase of L. 111.99 million lempiras. The 2018 % of FNS expenditure is 12.33% and in 2019 it is 14.44%, with an increase of 2.11%
5) Climate c ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">If the CSO are trained iby IFPRI in 2017, it is expected that for year 2018 CSOs can perform this analysis for coming years with the accompaniment of the SNV.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">04-07-2018: Information will be provided by IFPRI, pending sending</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: A target for this indicator is not defined, given that there is no a specific budget line for FNS. The study made by IFPRI in 2017 &quot;The Budget for Food and Nutrition Security 2015-2017&#x201D;, indicates that spending on FNS increased by 0.2% (14709.49 million lempiras) of the total allocation.
IFPRI study divided the data into 5 groups: 1) Agricultural Development and Value Chains (the dimensions related to producers and value chains); 2) Rural and Regional Development; 3) Social Protection Networks (non-contributory); 4) Health and Nutrition; and 5) Climate Change and Natural Resources. The analysis above included the expenditure data of the Sectoral Cabinets (Governance and Decentralization, Development and Social Inclusion, Economic Development, Security and Defence, Productive Infrastructure, Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation, Conduction and Economic Regulation, and Prevention Cabinet). It also tried to identify the FNS expenditures by group of entities: I. Entities that are not part of the Executive; II. Entities with affiliation to the Secretariat of the Presidency; and III. Entities without Affiliation to a Cabinet. The analysis is based on Finance Secretariat Expenditure Execution Reports.
Accrued expense 2015:
&#x2022; Agricultural development and value chains: 3097.1 million lempiras% spending FNS 25.7 and % of total spending 2.3.
&#x2022; Rural and regional development: 4,923.9 million lempiras, 40.9% FNS spending and 3.6% of total spending.
&#x2022; Social protection networks: 1820.0 million lempiras, 15.1% FNS spending and 1.3% of total spending.
&#x2022; Health and Nutrition: 1231.3 million lempiras, 10.2% FNS spending and 0.9% of total spending.
&#x2022; Climate change and natural resources: 979.6 million lempiras, 8.1% FNS spending and 0.7% of total spending.
Accrued expense 2016:
&#x2022; Agricultural development and value chains: 3840.4 million lempiras %FNS spending 26.2 and % of total spending 2.0.
&#x2022; Rural and regional development: 6,304.8 million lempiras, 43.1% F ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target to be established for this indicator is the same that IFPRI reports since the increase or decrease of budget allocation is beyond the control of CSOs. The values are maintained and will be used to monitor the budget allocation once the PyENSAN is approved and under implementation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.23">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: &quot;No target for this indicator was set, since there is no specific budget line for FNS. The study carried out by IFPRI in 2019 &quot;&quot;The Budget of Food Security and Nutrition 2018&#x201D; indicates that the expenditure in FNS 2018 is 16,265.97 million lempiras and in 2017 it was 14,709.49 million lempiras, so there is a slight increase equivalent to 0.23% based on total expenditure (capital payments and public bank debt not included) and based on the Gross Domestic Product (GDP) of 0.08%.

IFPRI disaggregates the data into 5 groups:
1) Development agriculture and value chains: accrued expenditure 2018: L. 3,114.91 million compared to 2017: 3,266.03 result is a decrease of -L. 151.12 million lempiras. The% FNS expense 2018: 19.15%, 2017: 22.2 with a decrease of -3.05%. The % of total spending 2018: 1.61%, 2017: 1.8% a decrease of -0.19% and in relation to the% of GDP for 2018: 0.53%, 2017: 0.6% decrease of -0.07%.
2) Rural and regional development: the accrued expenditure 2018: L. 7,969.46 million compared to 2017: 5,945.99 increase of L. 2,023.47 million lempiras. The% FNS expense 2018: 48.99%, 2017: 40.4% with an increase of 8.59%. The% of total spending 2018: 4.13%, 2017: 3.3% had a decrease of 0.83% and in relation to the% of GDP for 2018: 1.36%, 2017: 1.1% with an increase of 0.26%.
3) Social protection networks: the expense accrued in 2018: L. 1,801.19 million lempiras compared to 2017 of L. 2,991.85, having a considerable decrease of -L. 1,190.66 million lempiras. The% of expenditure on FNS for 2018 is 11.07% in 2017, corresponding to 20.3%, with a decrease of -9.23%. In the case of% of public spending in 2018 of 0.93% and in 2017 1.7%, having a decrease of -0.77% and in the case of% of GDP in 2018 is 0.31% in 2017 of 0.55%, with a decrease of -0.24%.
4) Health and nutrition: the accrued expense of 2018 is L. 2,005.47 in 2017 L. 787.34 having a considerable increase of L. 1,218.13 million lempiras. The% of FNS expenditure for 2018 is 12.33% and in 2017 5. ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Degree in which the budget meets the structure and budget lines corresponding to the description of the policy.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="tbc" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;IFPRI will carry out a study of the analysis of the 2016 budget and its consistency with the National Policy on Food and Nutrition Security 2006-2015, the study will be carried out based on the analysis of the budget expenditure analysis in FNS in Honduras.
This study intends to have a starting study for:
a) generate information with which it can be made political incidence with evidence that the 2016 budget is insufficient and is not consistent with the current policy, regardless of whether this policy is not appropriate and is the one to be renewed.
b) generate the experience to transfer the capacities of future studies similar to CSOs.
As the new inclusive policy is in force, a new study can be made to show its coherence with the planning and budget, which can be prepared by 2019 by the CSOs and SNV that would be trained by IFPRI and with its technical support .
The methods of information gathering and measurement that IFPRI will be using will be parametric, agreed upon and defined jointly with them.
It will determine an indicator for each sector later once you have clearly defined sectors that will be parsed.&quot;</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No   target defined for this indicator in 2020. In spite of it, many actions will   be develop to try to influence budget allocation for FNS such as: Workshops   to socialize the main findings of the budget analysis 2015 &#x2013; 2019 as well as   the findings of the Municipal budget analysis for FNS in two municipalities   and the specific budget lines identified to allocate FNS funds. In addition,   consistency of the allocation defined in the FNS Policy and Strategy   2018-2030 will be analysed. Key messages from these studies will be used in   intensive campaign to show the benefits and impact of investment in FNS. CSOs   will establish links with the public media to transmit their key messages.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">03-11-2020: There is no target for this indicator given that the National Policy and Strategy for Food and Nutrition Security (PyENSAN) approved in 2019, does not have a budget for its implementation. A) FNS Action Plan (PLAN-SAN 2030) and b) Nutritional Action Plan (PANH 2030) were prepared, which do not have a budget; The other action plans of the guidelines contained in PyENSAN have not been prepared either. The National Budget of the Republic of Honduras does not have specific budget lines assigned to attend the FNS. Therefore, it can be said that the National Budget does not comply with the structure and budget lines corresponding to the description of PyENSAN. CSOs consider that there is no political will to articulate government actions to PyENSAN guidelines.

CSOs are developing a campaign to advocate for the implementation of PyENSAN and budget allocation to it. On the other hand, IFPRI developed the Study and Analysis of Differentiated Investment for FNS Pillars of Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a, Choluteca and Tambla, Lempira with the support of CSOs. Sessions were held for the presentation and socialization of the results in a virtual way, with the participation of high-level municipal authorities, FNS Municipal Tables and CSOs authorities and technical staff of the South and West zone of Honduras, as well as representatives of UTSAN, COVISAN and others.

The conclusions of the study show that: The investment considered in the Strategic Plan for Municipal Development of Tambla, Lempira, considered an average annual budget for 13 years well below the historically planned (49.4%), which indicates that investment in FNS will continue being low and therefore vulnerability to food insecurity will remain or perhaps worsen. The Concepci&#xF3;n de Mar&#xED;a Strategic Plan does have an average annual budget similar to the one historically planned, which guarantees the investment in FNS during the six years that the plan will last, whose annual average of its projected budget is  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">If the CSO are trained iby IFPRI in 2017, it is expected that for year 2018 CSOs can perform this analysis for coming years with the accompaniment of the SNV.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">04-07-2018: Information will be provided by IFPRI, pending sending</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-10-2019: The target for this indicator is not defined. IFPRI study on 2015-2017 FNS budget analysis and the 2016 study financed by the European Union &quot;Impact Evaluation of the Policy, Programs and Projects on FNS in Regions 12 and 13&quot; indicate that neither the FNS National Policy (PNSAN) nor the FNS National Strategy (ENSAN) have contributed substantially to reduce food insecurity. The main reasons for that are: a) The government did not assigned resources for their implementation, b) The policy and the strategy were not known by the actors that were supposed to implement them, c) There was not will to articulate the governmental actions to the guidelines and objectives of the law and strategy. The effectiveness in the use of resources was not as expected either, especially when compared with other countries. An expenditure level of 2.7-2.9% of GDP for FNS indicates that these are not central components of the development strategy, but compensatory measures within a model of development that emphasizes other axes. (D&#xED;az-Bonilla and Centuri&#xF3;n, IFPRI, August 2017).
On the other hand, the FNS policy was approved by the Government in 2006 with effect until 2015. The FNS national strategy was approved in 2010 with effect until 2022 and the Honduras General Budget does not have specific budget lines assigned for the FNS issue. Therefore, we can say that the policy is not in force and that the budget does not comply with the lines of the structure and budget for the policy. 
As mentioned in previous indicators, a PyENSAN 2018-2030 is being updated, but it is not approved yet. Once the PyENSAN is approved and under implementation, a study can be carried out to inform about its degree of coherence with the planning and the budget.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No goal will be included for this indicator since the PyENSAN is in its approval phase and in the preparation of the action plans for its subsequent implementation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: &quot;There is no target for this indicator in 2019 given that the National Food and Nutrition Security Policy and Strategy (PyENSAN) was in its approval phase and in the construction of its action plans for each of the guidelines defined in the PyENSAN.

The PyENSAN was approved and 2 action plans were elaborated in 2019 but they have not been implemented so far. The approved action plans are: a) FNS Action Plan (PLAN-SAN 2030) and b) the Nutrition Action Plan (PANH 2030). The National budget of the Republic of Honduras does not have specific budget lines assigned to address the FNS. Therefore, it can be said that the National Budget of the Republic does not comply with the structure and budget lines corresponding to the description of the policy.

In the conclusions elaborated by IFPRI in the 2018 FNS budget report it is indicated that the FNS issues seem to lose relevance within the national debate. Instead, issues such as migration to the United States and violence prevention are gaining ground and therefore multilateral and bilateral financing. In order to maintain the relevance of FNS, greater synergies must be generated and complementarities sought.
&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
