<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41152786-PRM00004634-Kenya</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41152786" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya Market-led Dairy Programme &#x2013; Phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">From Aid-to-Trade</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pillar-I activities of KMDP-II will focus on dairy value chain operators in Nakuru, Eldoret and Meru milksheds. The target group consists of clients and beneficiaries. Lessons learned will be shared at sector level, as will be the case with evidence-based policy influencing, for which relevant agencies are based at the national and county levels. 
&#x2022;	Clients are the actors in the dairy value chain that the project will work with directly. These include dairy lead/demo farms, dairy cooperatives and processors, input suppliers and service providers, dairy sector associations, and policy and regulatory bodies. 
&#x2022;	The beneficiaries are dairy farmers and their households, farm workers, employees of dairy coope-ratives, processors, input suppliers and service providers, and consumers. 
In the inception phase, a firm selection will be made of clients under outcomes 1-4 and interventions will be designed in more detail. For this proposal &#x2013;and subject to adjustments - the following clients and client groups have been identified in the three geographical areas:
&#x2022;	Processor-led approach: in Meru milkshed with Meru Central Dairy Farmers Cooperative Union, affiliated dairy societies and farmer groups, in the Nakuru milkshed with Happy Cow, dairy societies and farmer groups. Meru Union has 26 affiliated primary cooperative societies with a total membership of 40,000 farmers (households). Happy Cow receives milk from two dairy societies with a combined membership of 4,850. 
&#x2022;	Possible selection of a third processor with an inclusive business model in Eldoret or elsewhere in the country, based on demand and opportunities for strengthening the other outcomes under Pillars-I and II. Other possible clients are local and international input suppliers and service providers.
&#x2022;	Selection of commercial fodder producers, agricultural contractors, seed suppliers, and farm mechanisation firms (examples: Gogar Farm, Gitau, Morendat, Dejirine, Nundoroto, SPEN, Leldet and Kenya Seeds, international firms).
&#x2022;	Selection of medium and large scale dairy farmers (MSLFs) willing to take part in pilots and demos, eager to innovate, invest and open-up their farms for learning and sharing by smallholders and peer MLSFs. Preferably as testing grounds for pilots, as training farms and organized in study groups and investors&#x2019; forums for knowledge sharing, collaboration and lobbying.
&#x2022;	Selection of Technical Training Institutes (TTIs), Practical Dairy Training Centres (PDTCs) and Dairy Advisory Services (DAS). Examples: TTIs: Baraton University, Egerton University, Laikipia University, Bukura Agricultural College, DTI; PDTCs: Lewa/Mawingu/Willens PDTCs; DAS: SNV Local Capacity Builders, Fieten Ltd; international firms. 
Pillar-II will have a stakeholder and sector focus, rather than a client or geographic focus. Kenyan stakeholders (i.e. farmers, dairy societies, processors, input suppliers and service providers, training institutes, etc.) willing to invest and interested in (exploring) products and services offered by the Dutch dairy sector, will be linked to Dutch companies/parties for trade and partnerships (including joint ventures, dealerships, franchises). Besides, Pillar-II will also give support to the Dutch private sector and knowledge institutes in exploring market opportunities and developing market share. This will be done in partnership with the Netherlands Business Hub in Kenya, NABC and/or Dairy Campus/ Dairy Development Centre. A number of medium-scale farms (incl. training farms) with good dairy farming practices and business acumen will be selected, to develop into model farms for showcasing of Dutch technology and practices.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project goal is: &#x201C;To contribute to an improved business and investment climate of the Kenyan dairy sector&#x201D;. The project will promote and facilitate the transitioning from aid-to-trade relations in the dairy sector, as a strategy for increased sector competitiveness, growth and food security.

The objectives and related outcomes of KMDP-II will be: 
1.	To improve the availability of affordable &amp; good quality practical training, extension and farm advisory services for farmers and other value chain actors.
2.	To improve the availability of affordable and good quality fodder to farmers.	
3.	To improve the availability of incentives and mechanisms along the value chain that enable the supply of quality milk (food safety).
4.	To improve linkages in the dairy value chain to stimulate chain integration and inclusiveness.
5.	To improve the linkages of dairy value chain actors with international companies and institutes, as a stimulus for innovation and competitiveness in the sector.
Objectives 1-4 are grouped under Pillar-I of the project. The activities under these objectives or out-comes are more related to dairy development. Collaboration with Kenyan stakeholders under these outcomes offers a platform or entry point for piloting innovative market-based solutions with the engagement of Dutch dairy sector stakeholders. Objective or outcome 5 is more concerned with mainstream trade promotion, international exposure and exchange, and facilitation of B2B linkages. This will take place in close collaboration with the Netherlands Business Hub in Nairobi.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is a continuation of the current KMDP-I. KMDP-I made significant strides in addressing relevant and important issues in the Kenya dairy sector, such as the skills gap, feed and fodder supply, milk quality, value chain inclusiveness and entrepreneurship .  KMDP-I uses a business or market-led approach, thereby seeking for strong collaboration between the Dutch and the Kenyan dairy sector. It showed that the Kenyan dairy industry needs to further innovate and adopt and adapt international best practice, in order to enhance competitiveness and to enter into a sustainable growth path. The Dutch dairy sector has valuable knowledge and technology solutions to offer, provided these are adapted to local needs and affordable. KMDP-II seeks a deepening of KMDP-I, using the same principles but with a more deliberate strategy and design to facilitate transitioning from aid to trade relations. The project is designed along two interrelated and mutually reinforcing pillars. Pillar-I is more dairy or market development related, with a focus on intensifying and upscaling the most relevant interven-tions under KMDP-I (i.e. practical skills training infrastructure, fodder supply, milk quality and inclusive dairy value chains). Thereby deepening involvement and engagement of Dutch experts and input and service providers. Pillar-II will focus on business brokering and trade promotion related interventions, in close collaboration with the Netherlands Business Hub and Dutch organisations/agencies that represent the dairy sector in the Netherlands. 
Through these two pillars, KMDP-II will invest in enhancing professionalism and competitiveness of the Kenyan dairy sector and in doing so, the market for Dutch technology and expertise, whilst at the same time it will invest in the capacity of the Dutch private sector and knowledge providers to be inclusive and relevant for the Kenyan market.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Development Innovation/ Wageningen University &amp; Research</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29466" ref="NL-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of the Kingdom of the Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="5576" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anton Jansen</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>ajansen@snvworld.org</email>
   <website>http://www.snv.org/project/kenya-market-led-dairy-programme-kmdp</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation
P.O.Box 30776 -00100
Nairobi, Kenya
Ngong lane off Ngong Road</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-0.290385 36.112254</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="311" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-09-30"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-01">4000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-25">1066412</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29466" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Kingdom of the Netherlands Nairobi</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41152786-PRM0004634-Kenya" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-04-01">646602</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-10-01">636347.25</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/5576/update/18352/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dairy farmers in Kenya adopting good practices in record keeping</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/5576/update/19364/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dairy farmers upgrading cow houses to improve cow comfort.</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/5576/update/19326/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dairynomics, a simple and reliable tool for calculating cost price of milk.</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/5576/update/18829/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">More youths self-employed in dairy sector through fodder preservation businesses</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/5576/Project_5576_current_image_2017-01-19_08.46.28.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grazing Cows in Dairy Farm (Gogar Rongai), credit: Muchina C</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://www.cowsoko.com/kmdp2/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya Market-led Dairy Programme -II Document Repo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://www.snv.org/project/kenya-market-led-dairy-programme">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Kenya Market-led Dairy Programme</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 1: Affordable quality practical training, extension &amp; advisory services</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A major impediment to the quality of extension services that dairy farmers and farm managers receive (see figure 3). This will be achieved through capacity building and BDS of training and extension (T&amp;E) units of processors/dairy societies with an inclusive business model, dairy advisory services (DAS), practical dairy training farms or centres (e.g. PDTCs), and technical training institutes (TTIs: mid-level colleges and Universities).  Improved capacity at the top (TTIs) will trickle down to improved capacity of PDTCs, DAS and T&amp;E Units and enhanced knowledge transfer and skills at the farm or dairy production level. This in turn will lead to enhanced productivity, reduced cost price and more milk of better quality, hence contributing to food security and food safety</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of people using training, extension and farm advisory services</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">- No of people using (trained/supported) disaggregated for gender 
- Agricultural training institutes /centres (Baraton, UoE, Bukura)
- Dairy Society T&amp;E Units
- DAS (LCBs and Consultants Perfometer and North Rift teams)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5000"></target>
     <actual value="5783.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14-05-2018: 5,783 (2,671 male; 3,112 female)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10000"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5000"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of policy/sector initiatives contributed to, for supply of practical dairy training in Kenya</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of stakeholder events that indicate progress in the initiatives</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14-05-2018: TVET study dairy East Africa (ICRA/LNV) and New PDTC concept Prodairy and GAD (funded by Rabo foundation)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased linkages with international institutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">- No. of new investments/partnerships for supply of practical dairy training in Kenya e.g evidenced by formal documentation of the collaboration &#x2013;MoUs, franchise agreements, letter of intent, subscription online knowledge platform (EIP)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target></target>
     <actual></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target></target>
     <actual></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Active companies in dairy value chain and trade volume in EUR</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase in trade volume - difference between trade volumes (EUR) over two equal periods (years) divided by the preceding period between the two expressed as a percentage year on.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10%"></target>
     <actual value="0.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14-05-2018: to be determined in the next period due to unavalability of data from this firms</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10%"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10%"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">New business/dealerships/partnerships established</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="19" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14-05-2018: These firms are Fodder Innovation Team (F.I.T),Bles Dairies East Africa and Euro Dairy</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 2: Availability of affordable and quality fodder</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fodder contributes to 65% of the cost price of milk. Access to quality fodder remains a challenge for dairy farmers, both with respect to on-farm fodder production and preservation, and commercial fodders sold in the market. The latter is predominantly a hay market which supplies low quality fodder at exorbitant prices. This negatively affects the cost price of milk and causes seasonality in milk supply. The project will scale up technical assistance, business development and piloting new technologies aimed at supply of high quality fodders, with commercial fodder producers, the Service Provider Enterprise Network (SPEN), agricultural contractors and (other) input and service providers (seed, equipment and maintenance services).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased production of fodder maize per acre</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">-No. of MSF, SHF and CFPs  obtaining optimal productivity  with sustainable practices (No. of farms adapting SOPs)
-Yield per acre
-disaggregate for gender</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1500"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14-05-2018: to be determined in subsequent periods</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3500"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of policy/sector initiatives contributed to for supply of quality fodder in Kenya</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">-No. of stakeholder events that indicate progress in the initiatives</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14-05-2018: National fodder workshop, ESADA South Africa and Dairy investors forum</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of innovative &amp; scaling-up fodder solutions facilitated in the market</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">-	Innovations such as packaged maize silage bales, grass silage bales etc.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14-05-2018: F.I.T packaged maize silage project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">volume of quality fodder preserved</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unit/Method of measurement
Fodder variety- Maize silage, Grass (silage/bales) 
On-farm &#x2013;farmer, Agri contractors (SPEs, NFC, DE etc)
Off-farm &#x2013;FIT, AGVENTURE, GOGAR
 -disaggregate for gender</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="120000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">tonnes</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="26436.70">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14-05-2018: 26,463.7 tonnes (11,400 -NR-MSFs, 12588 CMSFs 2475.7- SHDFs)
2475.7 tonnes (156.7 hectares)
11400 tonnes (404.7 hectares)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80000"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 3: Availability of incentives and mechanisms to supply quality milk</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this outcome, the project addresses of lack of incentives and other mechanisms to maintain quality of raw milk in the collection chain. KMDP-II will use a processor-led approach where all actors along the milk collection chain will receive technical assistance to increase their knowledge, understanding, and application of milk quality policies and SOPs. The project expects to observe improved practices along the milk collection chains in regard to reorganization of milk collection/transport, code of milk handling and hygiene, milk testing regimes, upgrading of the cold chain, and mastitis reduction. The latter has a strong correlation with high levels of somatic cell counts and antibiotic residues</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase in no. of farmers enrolled for payment based on milk quality</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No of famers paid on quality
-No of kgs paid on quality</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">dis-aggregate for gender and youth</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20%"></target>
     <actual value="100.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14-05-2018: 71 (29 female, 42 male ) farmers 
155,212 kgs paid bonus av. Kshs1.17</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20%"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved quality control at dairy society and processor levels</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Reduced rejects of raw milk at both dairy society and processor level 
- improved testing regimes t processor and dairy society level (equipment, trained personnel, feedback to farmer/farmer training)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reduced rejects complimented by improved testing regimes at 40% of the milk routes</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14-05-2018: to be reported in 2018
Actual quantification not done however (4,883 acceptance tests were carried out)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reduced rejects complimented by improved testing regimes at 40% of the milk routes</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10%"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of policy/sector initiatives contributed to for supply of quality raw milk and payment based on quality in Kenya</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">-No. of stakeholder events that indicate progress in the initiatives</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14-05-2018: Lessons of MQT&amp;T/QBMPS presented in ESADA S.A</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased efficiency in milk collection practices from farm level to cooling centres.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of dairy societies that have adopted and/or implemented policies/regulations/SOPs for milk collection
Investments in aluminium  milk cans leading to zero milk supply in plastics</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">also 50% of these dairy societies have zero milk supply in plastics</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 5: Improved international linkages</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KMDP-II recognises the limitation of locally available knowledge and technology in fast-tracking dairy sector development. This outcome is concerned with promoting B2B linkages and trade between the Netherlands and Kenya, through a number of activities that are promotional and facilitative. The proposed activities (i.e. business brokering, study tours, trade fairs, demos, pilots, feasibility studies, etc.) are important to support the Dutch private sector to understand the market size, needs and trends, to develop local networks and market share, to showcase Dutch knowledge and technology, and to help forge B2B and other partnerships. On the skill and knowledge front the programme will facilitate internships &amp; training programs in both Kenya and the Netherlands. All the efforts within this intervention will culminate in B2B partnerships, franchises and dealership arrangement between Dutch and Kenyan dairy sector actors, and a transitioning from aid to trade.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Businesses (Dutch + local) that have been supported with scoping and/or a planning for investment, trade or service provision (active B2B/B2C linkages) in Kenya</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">-no. of businesses before and after KMDP interventions</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6"></target>
     <actual value="9.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased demand for sector information and market intelligence from Dutch investors/companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inventory of information requests throughout the project life and/or no. of requests e.g KMDP publication/ documents downloaded from SNV cowsoko website, market visit</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="81.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-05-2018: KMDP document repository</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased volume of business between Netherlands and Kenya (Dutch companies, local dealerships)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Volume of business described in terms of Increase in annual turnover
		 Additional data to be recorded where feasible is on;
		 - New jobs created/employment
		 - Geographical coverage
		 - Product volumes</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20%"></target>
     <actual value="0.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-05-2018: to be reported in next period</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased income at dairy farm level</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">increased income at dairy farm level refers to improvements made in a dairy business that indicates improved earning potential. These improvements can be cowhouse improvements, acquisition of new cows, fodder production/change in dairy farming system.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of dairy farmers with increased income</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">50,000 people(1/3 of 30,000 active DS members, 5/HH)
Increased income measured through investments and changes made on the dairy farm business. (-	bought new cows, took out loans and repaid, improved cow house, changed farm system)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baseline report on farm in take  forms and quarterly monitoring of the same farms (aggregated on annual basis)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5000"></target>
     <actual value="5624.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14-05-2018: 5624 ( 2617 male; 3007 female)
&lt;5% increase incomes  ( 1266 male; 1231 female),  5%-10% increase (1332 -male; 1762 female), and &gt;10% ( 19 male; 13 female)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
     <actual value="3007.00">
      <dimension name="gender" value="female versus male managed dairy farms"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20000"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="15000"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 4: Improved dairy value chain collaboration</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">outcome focuses on improving the functional relationships of dairy value chain actors in Kenya. This includes vertical linkages and integration between farmers, dairy societies and processors&#x2019; in more inclusive business models, and horizontal linkages with input suppliers and service providers. In this outcome KMDP-II will continue to work on both sets of linkages, with the vertical integration focusing on long term milk supply contracts, investments by processors and dairy societies in quality farmer services, notably investments in farmer training and extension units, and joint efforts by the value chain actors to improve milk quality. In KMDP-II collaboration under this outcome will be with 2-3 processors with more inclusive business models, of which Happy Cow and Olenguruone/New Ngorika and Meru Union and its affiliated dairy societies, are likely candidates.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of dairy farms with improved performance</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved performance defined by attainment of 50% and above for below parameters of performance
-all year-round fodder supply
-investments/improvement on cow housing /cow comfort
-calf growth (above 500gms per day)
-reduction of inter-calving ratio (365 &#x2013; 420 days)  
-disaggregate for gender</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="40"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-05-2018: to be reported in the next period</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of policy/sector initiatives contributed to for improved functional relationships  in the DVC in Kenya</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">-No. of stakeholder events that indicate progress in the initiatives</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-05-2018: Dairy investors conference</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of initiatives lead by processors for investing backward in the chain</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cases for inclusive DVC e.g. investment in farmer training, hardware at dairy societies.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-05-2018: Meru Central Dairy Farmer Union and Happy Cow</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developed dairy sector support structure</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No of companies in the dairy value chain that have business linkages</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="23.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Safety</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dairy societies/processors with quality controlled and quality assured milk collection systems</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quality Control &amp; Assurance (QC/QA) system
- policies and regulation on raw milk handling
- standard operating procedures being observed and practiced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baseline, sector studies, or before/after (client level)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14-05-2018: This QC/QA system is reported for Happy Cow through the MQT&amp;T/QBMPS pilot project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dairy farms with improved productivity</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase in average production per cow (total milk production/ total no. of lactating cows) tracked monthly and aggregated per year.
 --dis-aggregate farms for gender and youth</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10%"></target>
     <actual value="21.5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14-05-2018: 20% lead farmers
23% MSF farmers</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10%"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10%"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Employability</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trainers, extensionists, dairy advisories with improved skills</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased in skilled workforce measured through no of individual trained 
-No. of DASs offering services to farmers
-No. of T&amp;E units functional 
-No. of farm owner/ manager trained
-dis-aggregate for gender and youth</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="75"></target>
     <actual value="159.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14-05-2018: 131 DAS/SPEs (105 male; 26 female)
10 T&amp;E (8 male; 2 female)
18 farm managers (15 male; 3 female)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
