<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41152786-1801-1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41152786" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voice for Change Partnership-Honduras-Renewable Energy</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Honduras-Renewable energy</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the &quot;Voice for Change Partnership&quot; (V4CP) programme, SNV works to strengthen civil society organisations (CSOs) in their role as advocates and lobbyists. We work together with IFPRI and over 50 CSOs to foster collaboration among relevant stakeholders, and influence decision-makers with solid and contextualized evidence to get the interests of communities embedded into goverment and business policies and practices. For this specific business policies and practices. For this specific project in Honduras, our advocacy activities focus on Renewable Energy (RE), in particular clean cooking.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim to contribute to the provision of quality services for the adoption of eco-stoves to improve the health of users and reduce the levels of firewood consumption below 50% from conventional stoves. This will be achieved through developing, approving and implementing a national strategy, appropriate budget allocation, and inclusive business and increased investment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Honduras</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Honduras</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41152786" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="4006" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>honduras@snv.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Col. Florencia Norte, Blv. Suyapa
Edificio Corporativo Solaire, Tegucigalpa
Honduras</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="HN" percentage="6"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.072275 -87.192136</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="23010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">246871</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-01-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">284419</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">284419</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41152786-3552" ref="NL-KVK-41152786" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Honduras</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">246871</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41152786-3552" ref="NL-KVK-41152786" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Netherlands Development Organisation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://www.facebook.com/vozparaelcambio/?fref=ts">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Facebook Programa Asociaci&#xF3;n Voz para el Cambio H.</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://voz.bonnykoo.com">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Portal Programa Asociaci&#xF3;n Voz para el Cambio Hond</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/4006/Project_4006_current_image_2017-05-31_18.01.26.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41152786-3552" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solid evidence supporting CSO proposals available.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of policy summaries and / or knowledge products based on evidence supporting the advocacy plan, available to CSOs.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="4" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">* The Executive Summary of NAMA of efficient stoves is available, made available by Inter-American Development Bank (IDB) https://publications.iadb.org/.../7286/Resumen%20ejecutivo-con%20fichas-rev .pdf?
* Improved Wood Stoves in Central America: Detonating the markets, available through BUN-CA. Https://programaprepca.files.wordpress.com/2013/05/estufas_mejoradas1.pdf.
* National Standard of Improved Stoves in Honduras first draft: Requirements for Technical Conditions, made available: Honduran Organization for Standardization (HOS).
* National Strategy Proposal for the Reduction of firewood consumption, made available by the National Conservation Institute (NCI).</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">4 knowledge products will be developed by CSOs with the support of consultants specialized in the subject, and the Interinstitutional Platform of improved stoves.

1) Final measurement of community perception on access and quality of services provided by the government in the renewable energy and improve stove sector. SNV/OSCs.

2) Draft proposal of Executive Decree (PCM) for the exemption of sale tax on improved stoves. Document to be prepared jointly by V4CP-Interinstitutional Platform- Energy Secretariat to support the advocacy actions of the CSOs on this subject.

3) Draft proposal of Executive Decree (PCM) for the approval of the National Strategy for the adoption of improved stoves (ENAEM). Document to be prepared jointly by V4CP-Interinstitutional Platform- MiAmbiente Secretariat to support the advocacy actions of the CSOs on this subject.

4) Brief of knowledge products developed. Product to be developed by the CSOs with the support of consultants specialized in the subject to edit and diagram the report.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: The 2020 target for this indicator was 4 knowledge products. To date, two knowledge products are completed, and four others are in progress:
1) Completed:  &quot;Building Brotherhood around a stove&quot;. Systematization of the experience of Hermandad de Honduras in the creation and advocacy actions of the Interinstitutional Platform for the development of the value chain of improved stoves &quot;.
2) Completed:  &quot;Evidence to advocate public policies for improved stoves&quot;. Systematization of CSOs experience in evidence creation, dissemination and its used in renewable energy - improved stoves (RE-IS) advocacy 2018-2020 V4CP program.

3) Currently in progress: Executive Decree-PCM) for the request for tax exemption for the production and commercialization of Improved Stoves and their parts. An Ad hoc committee has been created with representative of the Escuela Agr&#xED;cola Panamericana (El Zamorano), Energy Secretariat (SEN), SNV, Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida (FV), Hermandad de Honduras (HdH), Asociaci&#xF3;n Hondure&#xF1;a para el Desarrollo (AHDESA), Ecofog&#xF3;n Honduras , National Directorate of Climate Change (DNCC), My Environment, and independent specialists. Consultancy services were hired to provide technical assistance to the committee and arrangements were done with the Energy Secretariat to provide legal advice in the review of the draft document and to channel it to the Finance Secretariat when it is ready.

4) Currently in progress: Final measurement of the degree of perception of the quality and accessibility of improved stove services: A workshop was held to train technical personnel to collect information, however, due to the restrictions established in the country by the subject of COVID- 19, to date it has not been possible to consult the focus groups that had been established for the survey. It is expected to start in September with a series of direct interviews in selected communities.

5) Currently in progress: Draft proposal of Executive Decree (PCM) for the approval of the ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;By 2018, five knowledge products are expected to be made available to CSOs. Specialized consultants will be hired in these areas. Knowledge products are the following:
1) The study on the Effect of the reduction / elimination of taxes on imports of metals and other imported parts used in clean kitchens.
2) The Gender Approach study in the Value Chain of Improved Stoves.
3) Study of the value chain of improved stoves
4) Pilot study to promote the supply and demand of firewood for improved stoves from sustainable sources in the surroundings of Tegucigalpa and San Marcos de Ocotepeque or another place with average demand for firewood.
5) Popular version &quot;&quot;Analysis of the legal framework and proposal content Improved Stoves Strategy&quot;&quot;

by SNV, a knowledge product will be generated to measure the &quot;&quot;Perception of the degree of Quality and Accessibility of renewable energy services - Improved stoves Honduras, with the same population consulted and in the same geographical areas.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="6.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The 2018 target was to make 5 knowledge products available to the CSO. In 2018 V4CP generated 6 knowledge products. Partner CSOs led the participative research processes starting with the elaboration of the terms of reference, selecting and contracting consultancy services, and ending with the approval and dissemination of final knowledge products. The research processes has had the accompaniment and advice of SNV and other participants of the Interinstitutional Platform for the Development of the Value Chain of Improved Stoves: EAP- El Zamorano, National Autonomous University of Honduras (UNAH), National University of Forestry Sciences (UNACIFOR), Central American Technological University (UNITEC), ENDEV/GIZ, Forest Conservation Institute (ICF), National Directorate of Climate Change (DNCC / MiAmbiente), Secretary of Agriculture and Livestock (SAG), Secretary of Energy, Secretary of Health, producers such as P. Mirador, Hojalateria Valle, NGO AHDESA, GEMA Project, CESCCO, and other key actors.  Studies developed in 2018:
1)  Educational series: Analysis of the legal framework for improved stoves in Honduras. Completed in July 2018.                                                                                                                                                            2)  Study &quot;Gender approach in the value chain of improved stoves. Completed August 2018.                    3) Study &quot;Impact of the exemption from sales tax on improved stoves and the import tax on sheets and other imported parts for the manufacture of improved stoves in Honduras. Completed in August 2018.    4)  Review and adjustment of the proposed outline or framework for the national strategy for the Improved Stoves in Honduras. Completed in September 2018.                                                                   5) Educational series: Gender Focus in the value chain of improved stoves. October 2018.
6) Study &quot;Social and Environmental analysis for a Nation ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Within the framework of the program have been considered generating knowledge products to influence the issue.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: For 2017, the following five knowledge products were planned:
1. Measurement and mitigation of indoor concentration of GEI gasses in households with traditional stoves and household with clean cook stoves. Progress so far: Terms of Reference ToR prepared and published
2. Gender issues in the implementation of clean cook stoves to increase women participation in policies and projects related to the distribution, access and adoption of clean cook stoves. Progress so far: Terms of Reference ToR prepared
3. Firewood consumption in households of selected areas. Progress so far: Acquisition process developed, two proposals received and evaluated
4. Characterization of the value chain of clean cook stoves. Progress so far: Terms of Reference ToR prepared and published
5. Effect of the reduction/elimination of import taxes for metal and other imported parts used in clean cook stoves. Progress so far: None
It was no possible to develop the studies planned for the reporting period given the lack of proposal due to the specialized knowledge and equipment that the studies required and that apparently there is not available in the country. In some cases the ToR were adjusted to extend the period to receive proposal and in other cases to narrow the geographical scope of the studio but no answer.
During the reporting period one study initiated at the end of 2016 was made available to CSOs: 
1) Legal framework analysis and outline for a national strategy for clean cook stove. February 2017. Study carried on for a team of consultants hired by a partner CSO, as part of the V4CP products: Wilfredo C&#xE9;sar Flores Castro, Gabriela Mar&#xED;a Paredes Hern&#xE1;ndez y Claudia Mar&#xED;a Castro Valle.
An inter institutional technical team reviewed and provided feedback to the draft and final version of the document. The document was distributed to partner CSOs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the second semester 2017, the number of studies to develop depends on the financial and technical proposals to receive and the available V4CP budget and available financial support from a partner CSO. Effort will focus on the following studies:
1. Firewood consumption in households of selected areas
2. Effect of the reduction/elimination of import taxes for metal and other imported parts used in clean cook stoves
3. Characterization of the value chain of clean cook stoves.
Studies that are not done in 2017 will be included in 2018 plan.  One on-going SNV knowledge product: Measurement of perception of population from selected communities on quality of and access to FNS and RE- clean cook stove services. The results of this research will be presented in a workshop to CSO in August.and to political candidates in the last quarter of 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-03-2018: &quot;The target established for the second semester 2017 was to make available to CSOs 2 knowledge products. The target was reached since 2 knwlledge products were delivered to CSOs. 1) &quot;&quot;Measurement of the perception of the degree of Quality and Accessibility of Renewable Energy services - Improved stoves Honduras , July 2017 &quot;&quot;; generated from SNV in the framework of the measurement on the quality and accessibility of the services, which was socialized to the CSOs in a Workshop carried out in the month of August of the 2017.
Also some results were presented at the meetings with members of Executive Committee of Liberal Party, Innovation and Unity Party, Christian Democratic Party, Freedom and Refoundation Party, Central Committee of National Party and in Political Conversatories &quot;&quot;Challenges of FNS and RE in Honduras&quot;&quot; with technical personnel, candidates for deputies and at the presidential level Christian Democratic Party, Liberal, National, Alliance, held in Tegucigalpa.

2) &#x201C;Faciitation of participative analysis and building of the NAMA profile for improved stoves. A serie of meetings and workshops were held with the interinstitucional platform to identify, collect and analyse related studies. Prepare a sumary in answer to the request of the National Directorate for Climate Change (NDCC) to comments 3 consultant reports. The platform decided that given the lack of crucial information required by the Convention for a NAMA profile, to prepare and submit to the NDCC a profile to request support for a national strategy for improved stoves, as a previous step for the NAMA. The profile was submitted, reviuwed and adjusted jointly with the NDCC representatives. &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;    &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;&#x201D;The studies on: Consumption of wood in households of selected areas and the study of the value chain of improved stoves were included in the 2018 plan since it was not possible to carry them out in the second half of 2017.
The study on the Effect of the r ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Four knowledge products will be developed with the support of specialist consultants in the subject:                                                                                                                                1) &quot;Intermediate Measurement of the perception of the degree of Quality and Accessibility of Renewable Energy services - Improved Stoves in Honduras&quot;                                                                     2) &quot;Cost and benefits analysis for a National Strategy for the Adoption of Improved Stoves in Honduras&quot;                                                                                                                              3) &quot;Feasibility of provision and commercialization of firewood prototypes as a renewable energy source for improved stoves&quot;                                                                                                   4) Proposal of a National Strategy for the adoption of  improved stoves.                                                                                              
As in previous studies partner CSOs will play a leading role in the participative research processes starting with the elaboration of the terms of reference, selecting and contracting consultancy services, supporting field work, and ending with the approval and dissemination of final knowledge products. The research processes will have the accompaniment and advice of SNV. Progress and final reports will incorporate the feedback of other participants of the Interinstitutional Platform for the Development of the Value Chain of Improved Stoves. The participative approach requires more effort and flexibility of all parties involved but has the added value of ownership and deeper knowledge of the product that facilitate its management as evidence for advocacy by CSOs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: The target for this indicator was to develop 4 knowledge products. CSOs developed 5 knowledge products with the support of consultants specialized in the subject, and the participants of the Interinstitutional Platform of improved stoves. The Interinstitutional Platform plays an important role providing information, feedback and validating the products. In the same way, for the gathering of information, relevant actors were interviewed. The knowledge products are:
1) Intermediate measurement of community perception on access and quality of services provided by the government in the renewable energy and improve stove sector.
2) Cost-benefit analysis for the implementation of a National Strategy for the adoption of improved stoves.
3) Proposal of an inclusive National Strategy for the adoption of improved stoves (ENAEM).
4) Feasibility study for the provision and marketing of firewood prototypes as a renewable energy source for improved stoves
5) Proposal of a road-map and scenarios for the transition from traditional stove to LPG gas stoves. ECLAC/SICA proposal.

CSOs know the knowledge products very well, since they participate in each stage of the process starting with the ToR preparation, evaluation and selection of consultants, field work for data collection, monitoring, validation and approval of products. In each stage, CSOs had the technical support of SNV/V4CP.

The evidence generated has been a powerful tool to support CSO`s advocacy actions. Given this evidence, V4CP was selected as speaker to present 4 studies in the 3er Forum of the Latin American Network of Clean Kitchen, held in Honduras in 2019. The development of the studies also plays an important role in the strengthening of capabilities and positioning of CSOs in the Interinstitutional Platform, space where actors from the public and private sector participate. Studies are considered reliable and highly appreciated by public actors such as the Environment (MiAmbiente), Energy (SEN) ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of portals and websites that are accessible to CSOs that generate evidence for advocacy issues.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is not currently known which are all portals and websites that are accessible to CSOs, only CSOs mentioned the site cleancookstoves.org which has been visited by Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida, released through the Global Alliance for Clean Stoves (GACS ), in the case of Hermandad de Honduras, they has never entered. They only know about it.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs   do not expect to access new sources in 2020 apart of the portals and websites   that they already use.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: No new target was set for this indicator. However, apart from the portals and websites they already use, they have accessed the website:   https://portalunico.iaip.gob.hn/portal/index.php?portal=458 , made available to Energy Secretariat, information on the 2018 National energy balance &quot;A look at the Honduran energy panorama&quot; presents a photograph of the current state of the different components energy sources in Honduras and historical figures that allow studying trends. Which CSOs use as a source of information in presentations they have made, newsletters and publications on the subject that have been published on Facebook and Twitter; which are complemented with the information generated by V4CP program.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the second semester 2017, the effort will focus on facilitating and monitoring the use of this sites for the CSO instead of concentrate in adding more websites. As part of this effort, a workshop on information and communication search techniques will be developed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-12-2018: Effort was focus on the measurement of the frequency and usefulness of portals and websites that were shared the previous period July 2016 to Jun 2017. We did not set target of new portal and websites for the period July-Dec 2017. The target 1 refers to a workshop for searching techniques and it was done. For 2018 a target of 2 new portals and websites was set.

13.33% frequency of access to portals or websites
36.67% Content satisfaction

For the second half of 2017, the program&apos;s effort was aimed at monitoring the use of the two sites created and or made available to CSOs. CSOs were consulted on how often they access these sites and how they rate the content of the site. The valuations are shown below:
1) http://vozparaelcambio.org/ (1 CSO: use it once a month and consider that its content is good), (1 CSO: access every two weeks and consider that its content is excellent)

2) Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/vozparaelcambio/ (2 CSOs: access every two weeks and consider that their content is good and excellent). This page is managed by RDS. A total of 1,251,949 people reached directly and 2,311, 875 people indirectly throughout the national territory, with 256,264 people interacting with publications. In the interaction there was a greater participation of women (60,%). There is greater participation of the youngsters between 13 to 17 and 18 to 24 years old.

CSOs have had access to 6 portals and websites:
1) http://aprovecho.org/, Global Alliance For Clean Cookstoves - GACC, the father of the just stove - Ing. Larry Winiersky,
2) http://es.proyectomirador.org/liderazgo/mirador-llc-honduras-proyecto-mirador-sin-fines-de-lucro, Proyecto Mirador
3) http://ahdesa.blogspot.com/ Honduran Association for Development -AHDESA
4) http://www.fhia.org.hn/ Honduran Agricultural Research Foundation - FHIA
5) http://www.iadb.org/es/recursos-para-empresas/fondo-multilateral-de-inversiones,5763.html/ Inter-American Development Bank - IDB FOMIN
6) http://cleanco ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Currently, CSOs use eight portals and websites, the most used sites are:
1. https://www.facebook.com/vozparaelcambio/
2. http://vozparaelcambio.org/
3. http://www.iadb.org/es/recursos-para-empresas/fondo-multilateral-de-inversiones,5763.html
The other sites are used very little.
It is expected to facilitate access to at least two portals or websites that are useful for the generation of evidence.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The target set for 2018 was to provide or made available to CSO 2 portals or websites useful for advocacy issues. The sites or web pages that were made available were 2:
1) http://centroclima.org/perspectiva-climatica/, information related to the theme of meteorology services in the region. The document of the Regional Climate Outlook for Central America for the period August-October 2018 was shared; the one that was elaborated between July 17 and 18 last year during the Climate Forum, and where the Meteorology services of the Region concur.
 2) http://www4.unfccc.int/sites/nama/_layouts/un/fccc/nama/NamaSeekingSupportForPreparation.aspx?ID=200&amp;viewOnly=1; Convention the NAMA &quot;National Strategy for the Adoption of Efficient Stoves&quot; (NAMA entitled National Strategy for the Adoption of Efficient Stoves/NS-289).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Currently 1 portal are being used by 1 CSO, it is hoped to facilitate access to at least one portal.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: The target set for the first semester 2017 was to facilitate to the CSO a website to post news and other relevant information related to the program and its two themes FNS and RE. The webpage http://vozparaelcambio.org/ was designed by IFPRI and it is administered by SNV communication specialist located in the Nicaragua office. 
V4CP created during the reporting period two (2) websites: 1) facebook: https://www.facebook.com/vozparaelcambio/ created and administered by CSO partner RDS. In there, information related to FNS and RE as well as news of the program activities are posted; 2) A wapp chat &quot;Voz para el Cambio SNV&quot; was created to share news on both topics.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to two portals or websites useful for evidence gathering will be provided in 2019. 
There is no expression of CSOs or demand of any evidence that should be provided by specific portals or websites, there is not much interest in this topic.
CSOs are more interested in the development of studies and/or knowledge products, so if there is a demand for knowledge, the studies that have been mentioned above have been prepared or are in process.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: &quot;The target for this indicator was 2 portals or websites. In 2019 CSOs used 3 portals and websites:
1) https: //www.iadb.org/es/energia/conjunto-de-datos-base-de-datos-de-energia; Data base with regional energy statistics
2) http://www.fao.org/energy/home/es/, information on energy in the region. 
3) https://www.cepal.org/es/publicaciones/39164-energia-centroamerica-reflexiones-la-transicion-economias-bajas-carbono. Information on transition to economies low in carbon.

Information from those sources has been used in meetings and workshops to complement the studies made by V4CP.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved coordination and collaboration between CSOs with the other members of the NAMA National Table of efficient stoves, the HOS,  El Zamorano Stoves Evaluation Center, UNAH or other coordination platforms and alliances with the public and private sector.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in coordination between CSOs, interinstitutional platform, government, and other platform and relevant national and international networks.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. no or only occasional formal or informal encounters between CSOs, government and private sector take place that are related to the issue
1. regular meetings and communications take place between CSOs, government and/or the private sector which are related to the issue
2. relevant theme related information / data are sought, shared and discussed among CSOs, government and/or the private sector.
3. plans that include CSOs interests are (jointly) made by CSOs, government and/or the private sector.
4. follow up actions are taken that includes CSOs interests</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">A joint analysis with the CSOs on their degree of coordination and collaboration was carried out using the evaluation rubric and it was concluded that they have only had occasional meetings at the NAMA Coordinating Table of Efficient Stoves on April 26, 30 June 2016 and September 1, in which 1 CSO participated and several actors were present; other CSO has not participated in any meeting. Each organization scored on the rubric of evaluation, agreed on the score and considered that their level of coordination and collaboration is 0 with the government, private sector, universities and other platforms.
Despite the above, it should be noted that the CSOs through the program have strengthened their institutional ties and are working in a coordinated and concerted manner. They share their work experiences.
It should be noted that the National Table of Efficient Stoves is in the process of forming.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs   will keep the target of 3 for this indicator, so the result of 2019 will   remain at 3, as efforts will focus on long-term results. However, CSOs expect   to keep the coordination and jointly work with the Interinstitutional   Platform, the public sector and the private sector in the actions to be   implemented in this period such as:
     &#x2022; Strengthen (institutionalization) the interinstitutional platform:
     &#x2022; Complete the National strategy for the adoption of improved stoves   (ENAEM)
     &#x2022; Advocate for the approval of the national strategy ENAEM and influence   the design of the action plan for the implementation of the ENAEM
     &#x2022; Develop Regional events to present the ENAEM to local authorities and   other relevant actors
     &#x2022; Implement the communication strategy to disseminate evidences, sensitize   main actors, general public to promote the adoption of improved stoves
 

    Advocacy will focus on the following Secretariats: Development and social   inclusion SEDIS, Health SESAL, and Energy SEN. Also on the Forestry   Conservancy Institute ICF, the Association of municipalities AMHON to provide   support to the Environment Secretariat MiAmbiente for the approval of the   ENAEM.
 

    CSOs expect the State Secretariats to have a clear role in the   implementation of the ENAEM, roles clearly defined in the implementation   plans of the ENAEM. However, not major changes are expected in 2020, for   being the last year of V4CP and also the starting of the political campaign   in the country. To raise the political will for commitments time, effort,   perseverance and other resources are needed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: The target for this indicator is 3 and CSOs applied the evaluation rubric and jointly gave a score of 4.
CSOs have frequent meetings and communications with members of the Interinstitutional Platform, public and private sectors, academia, civil society, international cooperation and NGOs. In addition, CSOs have created spaces for participation at the level of organizations and institutions that work on the issue of improved stoves. Relevant information related to improved stoves is shared and discussed in different spaces. Coordinated work has been carried out by V4CP partner CSOs with the National Directorate of Climate Change (NDCC/MiAmbiente) and its Interinstitutional Technical Committee on Climate Change and the National Mitigation Committee of Honduras to join efforts for the official presentation of the ENAEM proposal. A communication campaign is being implemented to disseminate the ENAEM and advocate for its approval. Representatives of Environment, Health, and Energy Secretariats expressed their support to the ENAEM and to the advocacy campaign to get the approval of the ENAEM by the Interinstitutional Committee for Climate Change (ICCC).

Currently, the Internal Structure of the Interinstitutional Platform is being strengthened. A series of workshops were facilitated with participants from the IP and other key actors for the collection of information and construction of the proposal of Internal Regulations, Letter of Agreement and the Work Plan for the 2020 to 2021. CSOs, the private sector, government entities, academia, international organizations and independent specialists are participating in the process and identifying activities from their own operational plans that can be linked to the actions that have been proposed in the IP Work Plan. There is evidence that the Energy Secretariat, through the Biomass department, included within its 2020 Annual Operational Plan activities such as: a) coordinate and monitor activities defined by t ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the second semester it is expected to strengthen the relationships with the Interinstitutional Platform and influence other relevant institutions to join the Platform.
CSOs will look for spaces to generate alliances and coalitions with relevant actors (CSOs, academic sector, private sector, research institutes, international cooperation), to support of the National Strategy proposal at different levels.
CSOs will continue with the validation and socialization of the studies generated by V4CP and discuss key information with relevant stakeholders.
Advocacy processes will be sought to rise interest and influence new authorities, although not much progress is expected with these actors due to the political situation in the country, so the target will remain in 2.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: A joint analysis was carried out with the CSOs to determine their degree of coordination and collaboration with the interinstitutional platform, the private sector and the public sector through the rubric of evaluation. Both CSOs gave a score of 3, and the set target for the period was 2. CSOs consider that they have frequent meetings and communications with these actors, spaces for participation, information and relevant data have been discussed and analysed. This represents a moderate increase in the coordination and collaboration with the Interinstitutional Platform and with some public sector institutions. However, they consider that the platform needs to harmonize advocacy actions to influence and have a more fluid communication with the Ministers of MiAmbiente, Institute of Forest Conservation (ICF) and Climate Plus (Clima Plus has recently join the platform and it is beginning to get involved in the platform actions). Some observations about the different groups of actors are mentioned:
1) Inter-institutional platform: Spaces have been generated, meetings have been promoted, and information has been shared and validated. There is a Route Map that guide the actions of the platform to reach the Development of the National Strategy. The Route Map is a product of a participatory process lead by our partner CSO Hermandad de Honduras, even though the platform was created mainly to exchange information and learning. There is a discrepancy between Clima Plus with MiAmbiente and ICF, as has been seen in some events of the platform especially those in which role of actors have been discussed. The platform is an inter-institutional space because it has the participation of different sectors: academia, international cooperation, CSOs, private sector and public sector. In 2018 the participation of the public sector grow significantly. The CSOs gave a score of 3 to the degree of coordination and collaboration with the Inter-institutional platform.
2) Publi ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the first semester, it is expected to strengthen relations with the Interinstitutional Platform and to influence other relevant institutions so that they can participate in it, and it is expected to formalize and establish its structure and how it can be sustainable once the program ends. It is expected to influence decision-makers, ministers, deputies so that they can support the National Strategy proposal at the different levels. CSO will continue with the validation and socialization of the studies generated by V4CP and discuss key information with relevant stakeholders. Advocacy processes to increase the interest and influence new authorities. The target will remain at 3. It has not been possible to achieve the improved stoves plans of the governmental entities and the private sector could be elaborated jointly or with the participation of the CSOs and / or with members of the interinstitutional platform for the value chain of improved stoves. 
CSOs consider that greater lobbying at the management and managerial level of the various actors is needed in an orderly and planned manner. ICF and MiAmbiente are actors that must be maintained and influence at the highest level. MiAmbiente is the focal point for the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: &quot;The degree of coordination and collaboration of the CSOs with the members of the Interinstitutional Platform, public and private sector was analysed jointly with the CSOs applying the evaluation rubric and a score of 3 was given, which is the same as the target.

The CSOs commented that they have frequent contact with the members of the Interinstitutional Platform. CSOs and SNV call for meetings, workshops and other actions of the Interinstitutional Platform and their level of influence is clearly seen in the regular participation of the different actors they achieve. CSOs create opportunities for participation of public and private sector; information related to improved stoves is shared and discussed jointly.
A series of studies have been developed, disseminated and analysed. Participants have the opportunity to share relevant data and discuss it, and also the opportunity to present their viewpoints and influence what V4CP program hopes to achieve, such as the participative design and approval of the National Strategy for the Adoption of improved stoves in Honduras that will provide an enabling environment for the development of the market of improved stoves with budgetary allocation, inclusive businesses, greater investments for the development and innovation of improved stoves, their parts and services. So far, all Interinstitutional Platform participants have shown interest and support.
Advocacy must continue so that plans that include the interests of CSOs are elaborated jointly and placed in the programmatic agendas of the Interinstitutional Platform, public and private sector.
&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that by 2017, meetings and frequent communications with other actors: government, the private sector or other platforms and alliances can be held. Target set for the second semester of 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: Measurement of the level of coordination and collaboration was set for the second semester 2017 but it is important to mention that partner CSOs have not had frequent meetings with governmental representatives but punctual meetings with the minister of MiAmbiente, vice minister of energy, director of climate change national office, presidential designated for climate change. More effort will be done to strengthen the relationship with these important actors.
CSOs have little contact with the private sector and more communication and meetings with municipal authorities in their area of influence, as well as with members of the inter institutional platform to support the development of the clean cook stove value chain: Universities (national university UNAH, Zamorano, UNITEC), Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida, Hermandad de Honduras, program for energy access - GIZ (ENDEV/GIZ), and SNV.
The launch of the OHN 97001: 2017 normative &#x201C;Improved cook stoves- requirements and test methods for classification and categorization&#x201D; is a very important step in the value chain. In the event participated relevant actors of different sectors: government, civil society, international agencies, producers, users, and others. In the event also participated Hermandad de Honduras, Fundacion Vida, and SNV. Fundacion Vida/Profogones project was an active member of the committees that designed and launch the normative.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1.5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is not expected that for the first semester the level of coordination can be increased if the level of participation, due to the change of government, should begin with a lobbying process and influence the new authorities that have been assigned to government bodies and achieve their interest, although due to the political situation of the country is not considered that we can have much progress with these actors so the goal will remain at 1.5.

It is expected to strengthen relations with the Interinstitutional Platform and influence other relevant institutions, so that they can join the Platform.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-11-2018: A joint analysis was carried out with the CSOs on their degree of coordination and collaboration using the rubric of evaluation (the same rubric of evaluation is applied to the Platform, public sector, and private sector to get the average of the three) and the average achieved is 2 while the target set by the CSOs was 1.5. This represents a moderate increase in coordination and collaboration with the Interinstitutional Platform and with some institutions of the Public Sector, however, there is still much work to do with the private sector. The relationship that CSOs have with this sector is specifically geared to projects that CSOs execute.
Some observations about the different groups of actors:
1) Interinstitutional Platform: Relationships with the Interinstitutional Platform have been strengthened and there is interest of other actors to join the platform. They participated in events developed to socialize the studies done by the V4CP. Both CSOs agree that they have meetings and frequent communications with the members of the Platform, spaces for participation are created, they have shared relevant data base on V4CP studies, there is higher empowerment because there is more involvement and support to the events of validation. In general, there is a fluid and permanent communication with the members of the platform.

2) Public sector: CSOs have meetings and frequent communication with municipalities, commonwealths (Manvasen, Mercedes, San Marcos and San Francisco, Guisayote, La Labor, Dolores Merendon, Fraternidad, Lucerna and Sensenti- Ocotepeque, Mancosol, Cololaca, Guarita, San Juan Guarita, Tambla and Valladolid-Lempira), Inter-institutional Regional Climate Change Table, Territorial Table on Climate Change and Risk Management Sensenti Valley. HdH is currently a member of the FNS Table and Social Protection Commonwealth MANCOSOL. It was directly invited to participate in it. 
3) Private sector: Scarce relationships of CSOs with the private sec ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the second semester 2017,meetings and frequent communication with other actors will take place (private sector, platform, and networks)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-11-2018: An analysis was carried out with the two CSOs to assess the degree of coordination and collaboration. The average was 1.5, of a target of 1. Target is overcomed in view of frequent communications and meetings that opened the space a little bit more. Relevant information was generated, analyzed and shared with some key actors. Some remarks about the different groups of actors:
1) Private sector: HDH has occasional encounters with AHDESA and Eco-stove of Honduras at institutional level and related to improved stoves promoted by HdH and other initiatives. &#xA0;In the case of FV in the framework of Profogones, it has strategic partners, certifies that the units implemented by partners meet the regulations. AHDESA and Proyecto Mirador are part of its partners and with them has sporadic relationships.
2) Public sector: HDH has a strong relationship with municipalities and commonwealths in the West area. HDH gets contributions to complement projects. HDH is opening these spaces to get the support and join efforts with these actors toward the actions of the program. Space is also being opened with the Territorial Action group formed by the Central American Strategy for Territorial Development, which is linked to municipality, CSOs and private entities. There are frequent communications and meetings with them. In the case of FV, it has sporadic communication and meetings with the Municipality of Comayagua. Because of the V4CP it has strenghten the relationship with sector authorities such as MiAmbiente, ICF, and other that participate in &#xA0;the interinstitutional platform for improved stoves. There are frequent communications and meetings that contribute to open spaces a little bit more. In turn, relevant data related to the topic of improved stoves is shared, due to the issue of the NAMA that they are promoting. Some exchange of communications and a meeting took place with the presidential office Clima Plus but not further developments even though the leader was  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the second semester of 2019, CSOs will maintain the target. CSOs will focus on the participative design of the National Strategy for the Adoption of improved stoves ENAEM. They will continue their advocacy actions for the approval of the ENAEM, the validation and socialization of the studies generated by V4CP and discussion of key information with relevant stakeholders.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: The target for this indicator was 3. CSOs applied the evaluation rubric and their joint weighting is 3 given that: The CSO has frequent meetings and communications with the Interinstitutional Platform, public and private sector. CSOs participate in different actions related to improved stoves. Information on the subject has been analyzed, discussed and exchanged. CSOs lead the process of building the National Strategy - ENAEM and got the involvement of key actors in participating in the survey and providing, reviewing, discussing and analyzing information. They have worked in coordination with different actors to socialize V4CP knowledge products, in turn, they were invited to participate in Climate Change Expo Talk, in the first Biomass Forum and in the meetings of the NAMA of efficient stoves.

However, it has not been possible to jointly build action plans that include the interests of the CSO and that are inserted in the public and private sector program plans. Only in the case of the DNCC there is evidence of the incorporation of topic of interest for the CSOs such as the ENAEM in its institutional action plan.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased influence of CSOs on the agenda of the interinstitutional platform for improved stoves value chain and other platform and alliances with the public sector (FCI, Climate Plus, MiAmbiente, Ag Ministry, Municipalities, and their association AHMON) and private sector (FUNDER, AHDESA, FUNDESUR, FUNDEIH, Ecofogon of Honduras)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of influence of Hermandad de Honduras and Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida on the agendas of the Interinstitutional Platform.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. CSO has no or only occasional interaction with key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector 
1. CSO has regular interactions with key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector
2. CSO gets opportunity to explain its interests towards key stakeholders in government and/or the private sector
3. CSO&#x2019;s interests are &#x2018;put on the agenda&#x2019; and are discussed among stakeholders in government and/or the private sector</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">An analysis was carried out jointly with the CSOs on their degree of influence in the establishment of the agenda using the rubric of evaluation and it was concluded that once CSO   has had occasional contacts with the NAMA National Table and the HOS , however, it has not been possible to establish the agenda on ecostoves. Each organization gave its score on the evaluation rubric, agreed on the score and considered that its influence level is 0.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs   efforts will focus on long-term outcomes. However, attention will be given to   the institutionalization of the Interinstitutional Platform. Actions to   strengthen the IP will continue, such as an internal regulation and structure   guide or legal documents that rule its structure, membership, activities and   its strategic and operational functioning permanently even if it is not   legally constituted. A consultant will be hire to facilitate the process with   Platform members.
 

    Work will be done to complete inputs to prepare the final document of the   ENAEM, prepare the draft of the PCM for its approval and advocate for its   approval. In turn, ENAEM is expected to have its action plan for its future   implementation and to prepare the draft of the PCM for the exemption of the   sales tax on improved stoves and their parts. The members of the Platform   have shown interest in supporting these actions.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: The target for this indicator was 3, the CSOs applied the evaluation rubric to measure their degree of influence on the agenda of the Interinstitutional Platform and in consensus they maintain their score of 3, which is the highest score within the evaluation rubric.
The CSOs have frequent contact with the members of the IP and have managed to place in the agenda the actions that the program is carrying out, such as: National Strategy where all the support from the IP was received to complete it. Currently, consultants were hired for the institutionalization and strengthening of the internal structure of the IP. Since its creation the IP has evolved both in its membership, going from 7 founding members to around 25 participating organizations, as well as in functions, going from space for exchange of information and share experiences in a space for consultation and advocacy on public policies. Different sectors identify that the IP plays a transcendental role in the development of ENAEM and foresee it will have a relevant role in its implementation. The IP strengthening includes: a) Internal regulations, structure and basic functions for the IP to perform its role, b) Updating the Letter of Agreement of the IP, c) Work plan for 2020-2021 and d) Training of members interested in integrating the committees and others of the IP on these tools. A series of workshops are being held where the members provide inputs and feedback and validate the products.

HdH, Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida and other members of the Interinstitutional Platform have been invited by the National Directorate of Climate Change (NDCC/MiAmbiente), to support other related national efforts such as the Concept Note of the NAMA of improved stoves, financed by the Inter-American Development Bank (IDB). Also, the main findings of the V4CP studies and the ENAEM are being used as reference of the NAMA. CSOs are part of the Ad hoc committee established to lead the advocacy actions for the exemption of  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target for this semester is maintained, the actions will focus on strengthening and structuring the platform and influencing other relevant institution. Continue influencing the agendas of the various actors and position the National Strategy proposal on the Interinstitutional Platform, private sector, public sector and in other instances, trying to achieve a high level of influence and the accompaniment of relevant actors. It is consider that the   It has been identified that there should be greater involvement at the political level, but more at the level of ministers to promote the Strategy, it is considered that the Interinstitutional Platform has the participation of relevant actors, mainly at the technical level. The current participants contribute to advocate in their own institutions about the Platform topics. In 2019, more efforts will be focussed in reaching key actors at the highest levels, such as:
Some key actors:
Minister. Secretariat of Natural Resources and Environment (MiAmbiente). Leads the NAMAS.
Minister. Health Secretariat
Minister. General coordination of the government of Honduras.
Director. Better Life program.
Director. Forest Conservation Institute (ICF).
Minister. Energy Secretariat</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The degree of influence on the agenda of the Interinstitutional Platform -IP was analysed jointly with the CSOs and with the evaluation rubric a score of 3 was given as defined in the target. CSOs concluded that there is a fluid communication between the Members of the Interinstitutional Platform, and the members have joined efforts to promote the adoption of improved stoves and the initiative of a participative design of the National Strategy for the Adoption of Improved Stoves ENAEM, promoted by V4CP partner CSOs. 
The platform analyses, discusses and validates the studies carried out by V4CP program to fill the knowledge gaps with the identified studies.
The Platform is a space for participation, coordination, and lately for reaching consensus on different issues related to improved stoves and other topics of interest. The actions carried out to date have contributed to increase the participation, coordination and influence of HDH and F. VIDA in the agenda of the Interinstitutional Platform (IP), and also in the agenda of some governmental entities participating in the IP.
Thinking on sustainability, V4CP program organized a one-day workshop, a day of reflection on the current situation and future perspectives of the Interinstitutional Platform for the development of the value chain of improved stoves. It highlights some points that were coincident among the participants: A model of institutionalization should be defined, in terms of: on what, and how the IP will work. Establish a roadmap Regulation of the membership, with duties and rights, defining criteria to be part of. Revalidate agreements through a letter of understanding with new partners. Define legal, organizational and operational level, which results in a participatory and inclusive structure. Define strategic planning process, including operational plan. Organize support committees for each of the aspects to work according to expert people or institutions. Have sustainability plans,  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the second semester the target remain. Actions will focus on strengthening the inter-institutional platform and influence other relevant institutions to join it; also on positioning the proposal for an Inclusive National Strategy in the Interinstitutional Platform, private sector, public sector and in other instances, trying to achieve a high level of influence and accompaniment of relevant actors.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The measurement of this indicator was carried out using the application of the evaluation rubric, a joint analysis was carried out with the CSO to define its degree of influence. The target established for the period was 3 and CSOs gave a differentiated score, one CSO scored 2 and the other scored 3 giving an average score of 2.5, which was rounded to 3.
Due to the actions that the program has carried out, the CSOs have had frequent communications and contacts. A fluent communication and a common space have been generated with the actors that participate in the platform, which allowed the CSOs to explain the objectives of V4CP in the theme of RE and influence the agenda of the members of the inter-institutional platform to include and prepare the inputs for the construction of the National Strategy. 
The members of the platform are active actors, who have been part of the validation and socialization of the studies, they have participated in the process of gathering the information, and they have also been part of the interview process for the preparation of the studies. The program has been built responding to common interests, there is interest in creating a more favourable environment for the issue of improved stoves.
The platform is interested in the ES NAMA and in developing the National Strategy for improved stoves. There is a common interest in creating a more favourable environment for the issue of improved stoves. Dialogue with other entities has also been sought to make of the National Strategy a topic of national interest. It has been possible to integrate a greater number of actors within the events of validation and information gathering for the studies. Most actors show interest in being part of the Platform and in the development of the National Strategy for Improved Stoves.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that by 2017 there will be greater communication and meetings with key stakeholders: political parties, government, private sector and other platforms and alliances. Target set for the second semester of 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: Measurement of the level of influence of CSOs on the agendas of NAMA National Committee of Efficient Stoves, the Honduran Organization for Norms HOS, Zamorano &#x2013; EEC, UNAH or other coordination platforms and alliances with the public and private sectors related to clean cook stoves was set for the second semester 2017. 
So far, CSOs have no influence in the governmental agenda for the NAMA design. SNV was invited to review and provide feedback on studios made by international institutions as base information required to design the NAMA.
CSOs have more meetings and influence on the inter institutional platform to support the development of the clean cook stove value chain. CSOs have less meetings and influence on other networks, private sector and the government.
At global level there is an initiative for an international normative ISO 285 for clean cook stoves. Members of the inter institutional platform were invited to send comments through ENDEV. On the other hand, the Honduran Organization for Norms HOS will review and prepare the official comments on the initiative based on the inputs provided by the members of the consent group formed by the HOS.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is not expected that there will be significant changes for this first semester, the objective of this semester is to strengthen the inter-institutional platform and influence other relevant institutions to join it. We will also focus on positioning the proposal for an Inclusive National Strategy in the inter-institutional Platform and in other instances, achieving a high level of influence.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-11-2018: Applying the evaluation rubric, a joint analysis was carried out with the CSOs on their degree of influence. The target set for the period was 2 and the achieved score is 3. Due to the V4CP actions done, CSOs have had more contact, the opportunity to explain the interests of the program, and influence the agenda of the members of the inter-institutional platform. The members of the platform are active actors, they have been part of the validation and socialization of the studies, agribusiness fair, participate in the interviews for the gender study &#x2013; and midterm evaluation. The agenda has been constructed responding to common interests, there is interest in creating a more favourable environment for the topic of improved stoves.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are confident that the events programmed for the second semester of 2017 will contribute to increase the communication with key actors but they are not optimistic about increasing their influence on key actor&#x2019;s agendas in the short run. Still, CSO`s have moderate expectations to influence new political candidates to take in account the evidence generated by V4CP in the Measurement of perception of population from selected communities on quality of and access to FNS and RE- clean cook stove services. The results of this research will be presented in a workshop to CSO in August and to political candidates in the last quarter of 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-04-2018: &quot;The level of influence that CSOs have on the agenda of the Institutional Platform was analyzed and it was concluded that there are frequent communications and that a space of interest has been generated with the actors that participate in it, enabling CSOs to explain the program objectives about the subject. (Both CSOs gave a score of 2 = 2 + 2/2 = 2).
The platform is interested in obtaining the NAMA and developing the National Improved Stoves Strategy that includes the members of the Platform.
There have been several days of analysis and participatory construction of the Profile of the National Appropriate Mitigation Action Mechanism (NAMA) of Improved Wood Stoves in Honduras.
A series of documents have been analyzed. As progress and products, on Aug. 23, 2017 the National Director of Climate Change submitted two studies for support or basis for the construction of the NAMA of efficient stoves in Honduras for review and comments to the Interinstitutional platform. Another progress is the increase in the number of organizations that participate in the platform, especially from the government and universities or academia.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Se espera que a fines de 2019, el nivel de influencia de las OSC aumente en la plataforma, ya que trabajar&#xE1;n juntas en una hoja de ruta con acciones espec&#xED;ficas para influir en las estufas mejoradas para que est&#xE9;n exentas de impuestos. Con este fin se han celebrado una serie de reuniones con entidades gubernamentales. Se continuar&#xE1; trabajando con la Plataforma para completar los aportes para la preparaci&#xF3;n de la Estrategia Nacional para la Adopci&#xF3;n de Estufas Mejoradas. Los actores coinciden en que debe elaborarse una regulaci&#xF3;n interna y que debe ser una plataforma permanente, aunque no legalmente constituida. Queremos asegurar su sostenibilidad y todos los esfuerzos se est&#xE1;n haciendo para trabajar de una manera m&#xE1;s estructurada, con planes definidos.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2020: &quot;The target for this indicator was 3, the CSOs applied the evaluation rubric to measure their degree of influence on the agenda of the Interinstitutional Platform (IP) and by consensus they gave a rating of 3 which is the maximum rating according to the evaluation rubric.

The CSOs consider that they have frequent meetings, there is a fluid communication between the members of the Interinstitutional Platform, the CSOs call the members and have been able to place on the agenda the studies developed by V4CP. All members have participated actively in the design of the National Strategy for Adoption of Improved Stoves (ENAEM), promoted by CSOs/V4CP, as well as in analyzing, discussing and validating the studies carried out by V4CP to fill the knowledge gaps identified by the CSOs.

The Interinstitutional Platform is a space for participation, coordination and consensus on different topics related to improved stoves and other topics of interest. The actions carried out to date have contributed to increase the participation, coordination and influence of HDH and F. VIDA on the agenda of the Interinstitutional Platform (IP), as well as on the agenda of some government entities that participate in the IP. As part of the actions, the IP developed a positioning on the road map and scenarios proposed by ECLAC for the transition from the use of traditional stoves to LPG gas stoves.

The Interinstitutional Platform is increasing its positioning and influence. Example of this is that the National Directorate of Climate Change (NDCC) designate the Interinstitutional Platform as the governance mechanism for the preparation of the concept note of the Efficient Stoves NAMA (DNCC/SNV/-IDB financing). It warranty a participatory process in which main actors of the value chain will participate in the discussion, will provide inputs and feedback, and participate in the decision making process related to the preparation of the concept note of the NAMA. Likewise, the inclu ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of influence of Hermandad de Honduras and Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida on the agendas of other platforms and alliances with the public sector.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">An analysis was carried out jointly with the CSOs on their degree of influence in the establishment of the agenda using the rubric of evaluation and it was concluded that only in the case of Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida has had occasional contacts with the NAMA National Table and the HOS by Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida, however, it has not been possible to establish the agenda on ecostoves. Each organization gave its score on the evaluation rubric, agreed on the score and considered that its influence level is 0.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs   will maintain the highest target (3) for the period. CSOs will continue their   actions to influence government entities such as the Development and Social   Inclusion Secretariat (SEDIS - in charge of the Better Life program), Energy   (SEN) and Health (SESAL) Secretariats and The ICF to support the Secretariat   of Environment/DNCC in the development and approval of the National Strategy   since they are all part of the Council of Ministers that approves executive   decrees in the country.
     In the same way, it is expected to keep the high degree of coordination and   joint work that is required to complete the ENAEM and advocate for its   approval. To continue the implementation of the communication strategy is key   to achieve the goal.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: The CSOs applied the evaluation rubric to measure their degree of influence on the agendas with the public sector and by consensus they maintain their score of 3, which is the maximum score, defined in the evaluation rubric.

CSOs have frequent contacts with the Energy Secretariat, the National Directorate of Climate Change, Environment Secretariat, Health Secretariat, the Forest Conservation Institute, among other government institutions; which are active members of the Platform. CSOs explain their interests and introduce in the agendas the V4CP actions. As result of the advocacy actions carried out, the ENAEM was completed with the active participation of the government sector, and the political will of the Environment Secretariat to present the National Strategy ENAEM for approval to the Interinstitutional Committee for Climate Change (CICC). The Committee is a permanent body that supports the management and in which governmental and non-governmental institutions, organized civil society and academia are represented. With this action, it is expected that important agreements will be reached for its approval.

The Energy Secretariat is supporting the preparation of the draft law document for the request of tax exemption for the production and commercialization of Improved Stoves and their parts. CSOs are part of the Ad hoc committee established to lead the advocacy actions. National Directorate of Climate Change (NDCC)/MiAmbiente) invited members of the Interinstitutional Platform to be part of the support group for the construction of the Concept Note of the NAMA (National Adaptation and Mitigation Measures) of stoves improved, financed by IDB.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is not expected significant changes in the second semester but that the participation of the governmental instances in the Platform remain and add relevant actors.
The CSOs trust that the programmed events will contribute to increase communication, coordination, and influence on decision makers but they are not so optimistic about increasing the influence on the agendas of the actors.
For CSOs is very important to carry out an analysis of the actors and develop a strategy of approach and advocacy.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: A joint analysis was carried out with the CSOs to determine their degree of influence using the rubric of evaluation and both CSOs gave a score of 2, the target for the second semester 2018 was 2.
There are frequent contacts with ICF, MiAmbiente and SAG as they participate in the Platform, but a strong work is needed with Clima Plus. Also, the municipalities and AMHON are relevant actors that the platform need to attract to strength the advocacy. 
It is also necessary to integrate FUNADEH as it is a key player.
There is a permanent contact with MiAmbiente who is the actor that has a high participation and that has shown high interest. The participation of MiAmbiente/NDCC in the platform has facilitated the achievement of the target. It can be said that the subjects of interest of V4CP have been placed in his agenda. On the other hand, there are other governmental entities such as ICF, SAG, Energy and Health that participate in the platform but not as intensively as MiAmbiente/NDCC. The participation of the academic sector and other institutions of the government have been achieved. Actions promoted by V4CP, especially the studies, knowledge exchange, and advocacy actions have contributed to the empowerment of the actors that participate in the platform meetings. Other actions such as the socialization and dissemination of information about the program and its objectives has been carried out in five municipal governments in the western area (Fraternidad, Dolores Merend&#xF3;n, La Labor, Lucerna and Sensenti) to raise interest and advocate for the platform and the national strategy but more needs to be done to reach other relevant actors to add support to these initiatives.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs consider that the events scheduled for the first semester of 2019 can maintain their level of influence and will contribute to increase communication, participation and collaboration with the key players, but are not optimistic about the increase of their influence in the policy decision makers agendas or of some governmental institutions at least in the short term since there is a level of distrust with the state instances that are a political entity more and there is little interest in developing effective processes for the good of the country. They also consider that it is not easy to place the agenda of the program, since each organization has its own agenda based on what they want to achieve. CSOs do not consider that a significant change can be made, but it is expected that the relations with the actors that have been achieved so far will be maintained, established and made more solid. CSOs believe that effective strategies should be developed to continue lobbying and advocating.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: &quot;The degree of influence on the agenda of other platforms and alliances with the public sector was analysed jointly with the CSOs applying the evaluation rubric and a score of 2 was given, which is the same as the target. CSOs consider that they have increased their level of influence with some governmental entities such as MiAmbiente, Energy Secretariat, FCI, and Health Secretariat, since frequent meetings and communications have been held; they participate regularly in the Interinstitutional Platform`s meetings; and relevant information on improved stoves have been shared with them.
CSOs consider that they have not influenced government plans and agendas to include their topics of interest. However, there is interest from the state secretariats that participate in the Interinstitutional Platform to participate and to support the processes, including the participative design of the National Strategy for the Adoption of Improved Stoves ENAEM promoted by CSOs.

For some governmental institutions, V4CP program and its partner organizations are like their technical arm that has generated and facilitated valuable information and fill the gap of scarce available information on this subject.

In the case of Hermandad de Honduras HDH, despite the fact that it is located far away from the capital city, it is considered a key player in the issue of improved stoves and has won recognition from the members of the Interinstitutional Platform, some governmental entities and private companies. Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida has experience in the dissemination of fixed improved stoves and in the commercialization of mobile improved stoves. Also, through the PROFOGONES project, F. VIDA has generated information that can be useful, especially as a reference for the National Strategy.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1.5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is not expected that there will be significant changes for this first semester, the current political environment is not so favorable for CSOs since the spaces have been closed, it is expected that the government instances that have participated in the Platform will continue to do so and there is a risk due to the general elections held in the month of November 2017, the people who participate from the government are changed from their current positions, so it will be necessary to approach with several institutions and continue lobbying.

The actions of this semester are to achieve positioning in the relevant spaces through the development of bilateral meetings with relevant actors such as: Community Development Institute for Water and Sanitation-IDECOAS, GEMA Project, Honduran Social Investment Fund -FHIS-Poder, CSOs will promote spaces and debates to socialize information, especially RE studies. Approach with Clima Plus, municipalities and AMHON.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-11-2018: A joint analysis was conducted with CSOs on their degree of influence using the Evaluation Rubric and both CSOs had a score of 2, the target for the first semester was 1.5.
CSOs have frequent contact with the National Directorate of Climate Change-DNCC, Institute of Forest Conservation-ICF and Secretariat of Agriculture and Livestock-SAG DICTA- are the institutions that have participated throughout the process and in the gender study also participated IDECOAS. There is an advocacy effort with PAHO, which is worked on the diagnosis of energy access in homes in Honduras HEART and invited Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida and the Interinstitutional Platform as important actors to join effort and work together in the study.
In the case of My Environment there is already a follow-up of the NAMA registry, there is interest in the topic and they have an active participation in the inter-institutional platform, for which reason it has been placed on the agenda of that institution. ICF also participates in the actions that are promoted from V4CP through the platform. The program has been socialized and there are direct contacts with the municipalities of the Western Zone and the Territorial Climate Change Table, Environmental Municipal Units UMAs, and Municipal Table of Climate Change. There is interest in RE topic and also on water, forest and soil.
The offices of women-OMM are the social arm of the municipalities. There is direct coordination of the program actions with the OMM and the UMAs. They participated in the events of socialization of the program in the western region. In the southern zone an event was organized with Invest H - Creative to socialize information with their partners on the context, stoves models, stage of the market of improved stoves, and national regulations on improved stoves.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are confident that the events programmed for the second semester of 2017 will contribute to increase the communication with key actors but they are not optimistic about increasing their influence on key actor&#x2019;s agendas in the short run. Still, CSO`s have moderate expectations to influence new political candidates to take in account the evidence generated by V4CP in the Measurement of perception of population from selected communities on quality of and access to FNS and RE- clean cook stove services. The results of this research will be presented in a workshop to CSO in August and to political candidates in the last quarter of 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-11-2018: An analysis was carried out with the CSOs on their degree of influence in establishing the agenda with the public sector using the evaluation rubric (1 CSO gave a score of 1 and another CSO gave a score of 2 = 1 + 2/2 = 1, 5). They concluded that there are frequent contacts with ICF, Mi Ambiente and SAG as they participate in the Platform, and they are very interested in the NAMA of improved stoves and the actions that the program is promoting, but it is necessary to raise more interest on the national strategy and to get the involment of other actors such as Clima Plus, the municipalities and their association AMHON, as well as FUNADEH, they are key actors.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that by 2017 there will be greater communication and meetings with key stakeholders: political parties, government, private sector and other platforms and alliances. Target set for the second semester of 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-04-2018: Measurement of the level of influence of CSOs on the agendas of NAMA National Committee of Efficient Stoves, the Honduran Organization for Norms HOS, Zamorano &#x2013; EEC, UNAH or other coordination platforms and alliances with the public and private sectors related to clean cook stoves was set for the second semester 2017. So far, CSOs have no influence in the governmental agenda for the NAMA design. SNV was invited to review and provide feedback on studios made by international institutions as base information required to design the NAMA. CSOs have more meetings and influence on the inter institutional platform to support the development of the clean cook stove value chain. CSOs have less meetings and influence on other networks, private sector and the government. At global level there is an initiative for an international normative ISO 285 for clean cook stoves. Members of the inter institutional platform were invited to send comments through ENDEV. On the other hand, the Honduran Organization for Norms HOS will review and prepare the official comments on the initiative based on the inputs provided by the members of the consent group formed by the HOS.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the second semester of 2019, CSOs will maintain the target. They consider that there is already a very good coordination, frequent meetings and information sharing with other platforms and alliances with the public sector. Although they will continue their actions to influence key government entities and their agendas, they are not optimistic about increasing their influence on these actors this year.
CSOs expect to maintain the level of coordination and influence on the public sector agendas given the joint work that implies the participative design of the National Strategy ENAEM.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: The target for this indicator is 2. CSOs assessment of their degree of influence on the public sector agenda applying the evaluation rubric gave a score of 3 which is the maximum rating defined in the rubric of evaluation.

CSOs consider that they have increased their degree of influence since they have frequent contact with government agencies, have opportunities to express the interests of CSOs and they have put the programmatic actions of V4CP in government agencies agenda. Events and actions have been carried out jointly with the National Directorate of Climate Change (DNCC) and the Forest Conservation Institute (ICF). An important achievement is that the DNCC included in its 2019 Operative Plan the development of the ENAEM, so they have been supporting the process and have expressed interest in continuing in 2020. The Energy (SEN) and Health (SESAL) Secretariats has accompanied the ENAEM process and actively participate in the Interinstitutional Platform. Similarly, the SEN expressed its interest in supporting the &#x201C;sale tax exemption on improved stoves and/or its parts&#x201D; initiative.

CSOs do not have evidence that they have influenced other government entities &#x2018;plans and agendas to include their topics of interest, but the case of the DNCC. However, there is expressed interest of Secretariats to participate in the Interinstitutional Platform and in accompanying, supporting the processes, including the participatory design of the National Strategy for the Adoption of Improved Stoves (ENAEM), until its approval.

It can be said, that with all the actions V4CP developed, CSOs increased the interest and commitment to participate in the construction of the National Strategy for the adoption of improved stoves, and to put the issue on the agenda of governmental institutions directly linked and relevant for improved stoves and renewable energy in general.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of influence of Hermandad de Honduras and Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida on the agendas of other platforms and alliances with the private sector.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">An analysis was carried out jointly with the CSOs on their degree of influence in the establishment of the agenda using the rubric of evaluation and it was concluded that only in the case of Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida has had occasional contacts with the NAMA National Table and the HOS by Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida, however, it has not been possible to establish the agenda on ecostoves. Each organization gave its score on the evaluation rubric, agreed on the score and considered that its influence level is 0.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are confident that the events scheduled for the second half of 2018 will help to increase communication with key stakeholders, but are not optimistic about increasing their influence on private sector agendas in the short term.
No significant changes are expected in the level of contact with private companies. The spaces will be sought to hold bilateral meetings with (FUNDER, AHDESA, FUNDESUR, FUNDEIH, Ecofogon Honduras) to advocate for their participation in the Platform.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The evaluation rubric was applied to analyse with the CSOs and determine their degree of influence in setting the agenda of other platforms and alliances with the private sector. The objective established for the period was 1 and the score determined by CSOs is 1.
There have been frequent communications with some companies that have participated in the meetings of the platform and supported the collection of information from some studies and have shared information on the subject such as: Ecofog&#xF3;n de Honduras, AHDESA, Mirador Project, Hojalatr&#xED;a Valle participated in meetings and learning tours. Envirofit has also participated in the meetings of the platform. CSOs consider that there is a strong work to be done with the private sector although they have participated, they do not consider that they have influenced their agendas; some actors participate in some moments that they consider appropriate for their own interests and to be informed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are confident that events scheduled for the first half of 2019 will help increase communication with key stakeholders, but are not optimistic about increasing their influence on private sector agendas in the short term. No significant changes are expected in the level of contact with private companies. The spaces will continue to be sought and it is expected to continue advocating and hold bilateral meetings with manufacturers and suppliers of improved stoves, Funder, AHDESA, FUNDESUR, FUNDEIH, Ecofogon Honduras to advocate their participation in the Platform and to a greater extent in the construction of the Improved Stoves National Strategy.
CSOs considered the private sector is relevant their support for the National Strategy. Involve groups such as the palm oil cooperatives and other companies could invest to provide clean stoves to their farmers as part of their social responsibility strategy. The National Strategy for the adoption of improved stoves will contribute to raise interest in the private sector to provide better products and services.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: &quot;A joint analysis was carried out with the CSOs on their degree of influence on the private sector agendas. A target of 1 was projected, however, the application of the evaluation rubric gave a score of 2. CSOs consider that their level of influence has increased. Currently there are frequent contacts related to improved stoves with some private companies. More space for interactions with the private sector are being generated, but CSOs consider that it is difficult to fully involve these actors in the processes and actions that the Interinstitutional Platform is carrying out.  It has not been possible to influence their programmatic agendas but they participate and coordinate specific actions with defined plans.

CSOs have frequent meetings and stablish commercial relations with private sector companies such as:
a) F. VIDA with Ecofog&#xF3;n de Honduras, Ecop&#xE1;n, ENAHSA, FUNADIHS, Proyecto Mirador, Instituto Hondure&#xF1;o del Caf&#xE9;-IHCAFE, Fundaci&#xF3;n para el Desarrollo Rural-FUNDER, Industrias C&#xF3;rdoba, AHDESA. Through its PROFOGONES project, F. VIDA establish purchase / sale contracts with private sector companies to promote technological innovation and scale up the implementation and adoption of improved stoves in the different population groups.
b) Hermandad de Honduras with: Honduran Development Association-AHDESA, ECOMAL, Perfection Group, Geo-Platanares and Grupo Jaremar. HdH executes a series of projects for the implementation of improved stoves in the Western zone.

It is expected to involve more private sector companies in the Interinstitutional Platform but there are very few private companies that work on improved stoves.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By mid-2018 no significant changes are expected or the level of contact with private companies be increased. The spaces to hold bilateral meetings with (FUNDER, AHDESA, FUNDESUR, FUNDEIH, Ecofogon Honduras) will be sought with the purpose of presenting the program and advocate so that they form part of the Platform, seeking joint actions and a greater relationship.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-11-2018: Applying the evaluation rubric, a joint analysis was carried out with the CSOs on their degree of influence in the establishment of the agenda of other platforms and alliances with the private sector. The target set for the period was 0 and the achieved score is 1.
Relevant actors of the private sector know the program and its impacts. Mirador Project, ADEHSA, Ecofog&#xF3;n de Honduras and Envirofit participated in the interviews and in the validation of the studies and that allowed to have frequent contacts with these actors. A CSO had the opportunity to explain the interests of the program, but not to all the actors.
One CSO commented that it has occasional contacts with the private sector, communications are sporadic and these actors participate in some moments that they consider appropriate for their own interests and to get informed on what HdH is doing. In the meetings just their technical personnel participated not the decision makers so there is the risk that they are not informed on what was discussed in the events.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that by 2017 there will be greater communication and meetings with key stakeholders: political parties, government, private sector and other platforms and alliances. Target set for the second semester of 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-04-2018: Measurement of the level of influence of CSOs on the agendas of NAMA National Committee of Efficient Stoves, the Honduran Organization for Norms HOS, Zamorano &#x2013; EEC, UNAH or other coordination platforms and alliances with the public and private sectors related to clean cook stoves was set for the second semester 2017. So far, CSOs have no influence in the governmental agenda for the NAMA design. SNV was invited to review and provide feedback on studios made by international institutions as base information required to design the NAMA. CSOs have more meetings and influence on the inter institutional platform to support the development of the clean cook stove value chain. CSOs have less meetings and influence on other networks, private sector and the government. At global level there is an initiative for an international normative ISO 285 for clean cook stoves. Members of the inter institutional platform were invited to send comments through ENDEV. On the other hand, the Honduran Organization for Norms HOS will review and prepare the official comments on the initiative based on the inputs provided by the members of the consent group formed by the HOS.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are confident that the events programmed for the second semester of 2017 will contribute to increase the communication with key actors but they are not optimistic about increasing their influence on key actor&#x2019;s agendas in the short run. Still, CSO`s have moderate expectations to influence new political candidates to take in account the evidence generated by V4CP in the Measurement of perception of population from selected communities on quality of and access to FNS and RE- clean cook stove services. The results of this research will be presented in a workshop to CSO in August and to political candidates in the last quarter of 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-04-2018: &quot;The measurement of the degree of influence in setting the agenda with the private sector was established and it was concluded that it is 0 (both organizations gave an assessment of 0) since only occasional contacts are made with some companies that are related to the work of the organizations: AHDESA and Ecofog&#xF3;n de Honduras.

The effort of the CSOs was concentrated in other links of the chain, especially in the strengthening of relationships within the framework of the platform and not with the private sector. There are few private sector actors in this topic. Some of them have regular contact or business relations for other initiatives.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                     I                                                                                                                                                In the second semester of 2017 contacts with the private sector started in the framework of the program. Some producers of clean stoves in El Salvador were identified and contact established. As one result of these contacts a learning tour to El Salvador took place in December 2017 with the purpose of knowing experiences in the creation and evolution of improved stoves and their regulatory framework. Support organizations that intervened or intervene in the development of this value chain. Role of the central government and local or regional governments. Places visited: San Salvador, Sonsonate know Experience Industrias FALCOM, Santa Tecla Experience Fundaci&#xF3;n Enrique Figueroa. Meetings were also held with technicians from the National Energy Center  
                                                                                                                                 Participated in the tour: Secretaries of State (SAG, ICF, MiAmbiente),  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs expect that by the end of the year there will be more  interrelation and involvement of the private sector in the actions of V4CP and the Interinstitutional Platform to support and participate in the design of the National Strategy and the development of the value chain providing better products and services. However, they do not expect that the plans that include the interests of the CSOs will be elaborated jointly, nor that they may influence their programmatic agendas.
Private sector can contribute to the development of the market and value chain by providing good products and services, and facilitating the M&amp;E of installed stoves.
Private sector is a relevant actor to be consider in the design of the National Strategy.
The Interinstitutional Platform may benefit of attracting and increasing the number of participants form the private sector.                     .

Hermandad de Honduras and Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida are very active in the improved stove market. F. VIDA jointly with the National University and the support of PROFOGONES Project is developing two new designs of improved stoves.
Hermandad de Honduras is designing its marketing strategy with support of V4CP and PROCAMBIO Project.

In August 22, both partner CSOs with support of V4CP will have a talk with agroforestry cooperatives to present the main findings of the Feasibility Study on Provision and Marketing of firewood prototypes as a source of renewable energy for improved stoves. The objective is to motivate them to adopt and offer the firewood prototypes designed for improved stoves to have an alternative to the illegal market of firewood.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: The goal for this indicator is 2. Applying the evaluation rubric jointly the CSOs gave a score of 2, given that the CSOs consider that they have not been able to place in their programmatic agendas, nor is there a commitment to promote the National Strategy - ENAEM, nor the actions carried out under the program.

Despite this, private sector companies related to the issue of improved stoves participate in the meetings of the Platform, have frequent communications. More interaction spaces are being generated, but it has not been easy to fully involve them in the processes and actions that CSOs are carrying out.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A goal   for this indicator will not be set. CSOs will focus their efforts on   long-term results. CSOs consider that the goal should be kept at 2 since they   do not consider it easy to influence the programmatic agendas of the private   sector. But, it is expected that through the programmed actions, their level   of coordination, collaboration, greater interaction, and better involvement   to the actions programmed by CSOs within the framework of the V4CP program   will be maintained.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved accountability mechanisms of Climate Change National Direction (CCND) of MiAmbiente</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level at which the accountability mechanisms of the National Directorate for Climate Change (NDCC) of MiAmbiente are functioning</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. CSOs are not provided with information - about decisions, decision making processes, policies - by government / companies
1. CSOs are provided with information - about decisions, decision making processes, policies - by government / companies
2. Existence of ad-hoc fora for consultation with CSOs.  CSOs are given the opportunity to provide information to decision makers
3. Government /companies are transparent in their decisions and actions. Government / companies provide feedback on demands of CSOs
4. Formal structures / procedures for feedback/consultations with CSOs are established
5. Government/ companies act on the demands of CSOs through changes in rhetoric and changes in policies and practices
6. Government / companies pro-actively engage with CSOs in determining the policy agenda, in seeking information and possible options</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">An analysis was conducted jointly with CSOs and and it was analysed how accountability mechanisms are perceived and it was concluded that CSOs have not been provided with official information on decisions taken in the form of accountability, nor they are reported on the government policies, companies and the platforms related to the theme of RE-Ecostoves. In Honduras, the demands of citizens or organizations are not answered, there is no transparency of decision-making, there is no political will or a mechanism that forces government and companies to justify their decisions and actions, the voice of CSOs is not as heard, although there are positive examples of advocacy work and achievements obtained through it.
Each organization gave its score on the evaluation rubric, agreed on the score and considered it to be 0.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The   target remains at 1, CSOs have no identified actions to develop in this year,   since the program is in its final phase. Given that the National Strategy is   still in its construction phase, it is likely that it will be re-incorporated   into the DNCC 2020 OAP (POA).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: The target for this indicator is 1, the CSOs applied the evaluation rubric and jointly maintain their score of 2.
CSOs do not have identified actions to implement this year, nor is there an opportunity to open spaces on this issue in 2020. The program is in its final phase and focus the effort on long-term results. Despite this, V4CP partner CSOs work jointly with the Interinstitutional Platform and the National Directorate of Climate Change to promote the approval and implementation of the ENAEM.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are no actions in 2018 related to the improvement of accountability mechanisms, so no progress is expected in this year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: No advocate actions on this indicator were planed for 2018, therefore the established target is 0. Applying the evaluation rubric the CSOs gave an average score of 1 since they consider that there have been small progress on it. As an example, General Director of the National Directorate of Climate Change/Mi Ambiente shared information on processes related to improved stoves and the NAMA. They are reporting and sharing information, but these actions are very incipient. There are no report on decisions or decision-making processes related to the RE issue.
In Honduras, one of the difficulties in this area is that there is no information available, there is no transparency in decision making, there is no political will or mechanism that oblige the government, institutions and companies to justify their decisions and actions.
Internally, the accountability of CSOs is differentiated since some make periodic reports to contributing entities, perform internal and external audits, present reports to the Board of Directors and Assembly, report to the Directorate of Registration and Follow-up to Associations Civil (DIRSAC), Revenue Management Service (SAR).
CSOs are also unaware of the mechanisms of accountability that My Environment has, despite everything; There has been some progress and it is that a greater alliance with this government entity is being generated, it is a strong and relevant actor that has the program. Relations are improving, so it is considered that improving them with an institution can induce other institutions for the credibility that can be had on the subject.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are no action in 2017 related to improvement of the accountability mechanisms and so no expected progress on it in 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-04-2018: &quot;An analysis was conducted with CSOs to assess the degree to which progress has been made with accountability mechanisms and the score is 0. There are no actions in the 2017 plan that contribute to this indicator. CSOs do not get information about the decisions made or the decision-making processes, policies or other relevant issues of the NDCC / MiAmbiente.
The communication is mainly done in the interinstitutional platform, there is no direct communication with CSOs. There are  few institutions and organizations that provide information, and their accountability is almost none. The information is provided in some cases when requested, there are no accountability portals and the information is not disaggregated. The government does not have a specific portal  for each Secretary or Program that is available, the little information available is very general information. There are no spaces for social oversight. Just a few dare to ask for information because there is a lack of knowledge of the mechanisms to access it (to whom to go and how to request information).&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A target of 0 is set for 2019 since there are no actions identified for 2019 related to the improvement of accountability mechanisms.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: No target had been defined for this indicator. CSOs gave a jointly score of 1, applying the rubric of evaluation. CSOs consider that they don`t get information on decisions, decision-making processes, or the policies of the DNCC/MiAmbiente, as is indicated in the evaluation rubric. However, in 2019 the DNCC incorporated the National Strategy for the Adoption of Improved Stoves ENAEM in its Annual Operational Plan. The DNCC is committed to keep the support to the ENAEM in 2020.
On the other hand, Mi Ambiente/DNCC started the process of &#x201C;Preparation of a National Appropriate Mitigation Action-NAMA&#x201D; based on efficient stoves. Both instruments are complementary and both aim to improve the quality of life of Honduran families who live in poverty and cook with open fire stoves. The DNCC requested the V4CP Program with the support of the SNV and the Interinstitutional Platform to review the proposal or document of Technical Cooperation with IDB for the preparation of the NAMA where the observations and recommendations were given, and included in the document.

As a result, the DNCC named the Interinstitutional Platform as the governance mechanism that the project will use to present, discuss and agree on any decision related to the concept note of the NAMA allowing with this the participation of a broader group of actors in the process. Likewise, the inclusion of the Presidential Office for Climate Change (Clima Plus) in coordination and consultation processes will be promoted through the Interinstitutional Platform. On the other hand, IDB Representative affirmed in a meeting the relevance of the adjustments proposed by the DNCC with the support of the Interinstitutional Platform. The adjustments rescue the current context on improved stoves in the country; elements that were not present at the time the documents were prepared by the IDB. The adjustments were accepted.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Appropriate budget allocation by the government to promote the development of the market for energy efficient ecostoves, development of AFS for firewood and promotion of adoption at the demand level.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase / decrease (in%) of the annual budget allocation for the development and use of renewable energy (annual comparison of renewable energy budget versus total energy budget)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">(annual comparison)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="92.5%" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Budget allocation for the Development of Renewable Energy in relation to the global Energy budget, Honduras 2015-2017.
The budget allocation for the energy sector in 2015 was 2,733.3 million Lempiras, of which 2,311.3 million were allocated to the sub sector renewable energy that represent 84.6% of energy budget. In 2016 the allocation to renewable energy increased to 92.5% percent. It is this figure that represents our baseline.

[OLD TEXT: 2015: 1,589,036,315 Lempiras http://www.sefin.gob.hn/wp-content/uploads/Presupuesto/2015/aprobado/principal.html                                                                                                              2016: 1,929,687,526 Lempiras  http://www.sefin.gob.hn/wp-content/uploads/Presupuesto/2016/Aprobado/principal.html
It should be noted that one of the biggest problems in Honduras is the reliability of the information, these data were taken from the Integrated Financial Management System - SIAFI, these data reflect an increase in the budget of a 21,44% for RE. It was not possible to identify the budget for ecostoves.]</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There   are no planned activities in 2020 for an appropriate budget allocation and,   therefore, no progress is expected on this indicator.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: No progress on this indicator is reported in 2020 as no activities were scheduled for it in year 2020.
The ENEM does not have an estimated budget. It is the legal framework, the umbrella for the different public and private initiatives such as the NAMA. It is expected that all these initiatives contributes or are aligned to the ENAEM and feed the ENAEM Fund. For example the NAMA has an estimated budget of Euros 27.9 Millions (13.4 from international funding and 14.5 from national (public and private) funding</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="92.5%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are no activities planned in 2017 for an appropriate budget allocation and therefore no progress is expected in 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="94.1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-12-2018: In 2017, allocation increased to 94,1% (2,804,5 million Lempiras) of the total allocation of the energy sector in Honduras. This represents a 1.6% increase from budget allocation to RE in 2016. These data show how the Honduran energy matrix has changed from non-renewable sources to renewable sources. This data was provided by a V4CP external consultant with high experience in the subject.

To measure the annual public expenditure on energy (both budgeted, executed or accrued and other related variables) faces many barriers due to the sources of information. For this reason, a proxy variable (public investment for the generation of energy) was used for the construction of the indicators Global Budget and Annual Expenditure of the Energy Sector. This action was necessary given the fact that this data is not available within the national accounting systm. The data presented for this indicator is based on the following variable: Global Budget Of The Energy Sector is the expenditure of the current Budget of Public Investment for the generation of new projects, as well as that related to the maintenance and repair of the existing projects in the energy sector of Honduras.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="94.1%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are no actions for 2018 that imply an appropriate budgetary allocation by the government to promote the development of the improved stoves market, therefore, no goal is defined for this year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="94.15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: In order to measure the 2017 and 2018 indicators regarding budget allocation and public spending, consultants with well-known experience were hired to collect and analyse the data from governmental sources. There are differences in the values reported in previous years since the analysis was based on just three quarters instead of IV quarters data. In 2018 study, the 2017 data and scores were reviewed to include the whole year data (when the 2017 study was done there was data available just for the first three quarters of the year), hence, in the data presented in the previous reports, values are lower than the current ones. The corrected values are as follow:                                                                                                                                2015 ratio of renewable energy to total energy:  84.56% (2,311.35 / 2,733.27 million lempiras);                 2016  this ratio increased to 92.50% (3,226.68/3,488.47 million lempiras), equivalent to a difference of 7.94% (increase).                                                                                                                                           2017 ratio of renewable energy to total energy: 96.23% (4,333.84/4,503.61 million lempiras);                  2018 this ratio decreased to 94.15% (3,556.98/3,778.12 million lempiras), which is equivalent to a difference of -2.08% (decrease)                                                                                                                      
The decrease is explained by several large project that were completed, especially referents to hydraulic sources. The values presented are estimations, since there are no official data that make precise reference to budget allocation for these topics.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A target of 0 is set for 2019 since there are no actions identified for 2019 that imply an adequate budgetary allocation by the government to promote the development of the improved stove market.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="95.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: To measure the degree of progress in the indicator, a consultant was hired who has been making these measurements, has collected information and analyzed data from government sources. It is important to clarify that there are differences in the values notified in 2018, since the analysis was based on data from only three quarters instead of IV quarters since they were not available at the time of the report. In the 2019 study, the 2018 data and scores were reviewed to include the information for the whole year, so in the data presented in the previous reports the values are lower than the current ones. The corrected values are as follows:

2018 ratio of renewable energy to total energy: 94.15% (3,556.98/3,778.12 million lempiras), the updated data is 97% (L. 3,510.7/L. 3,607.70 million lempiras) which is equivalent to a difference of 2.85% (increase).
For 2019 this proportion decreased by 2% since 95% of the allocation for the energy sector in Honduras corresponded to the renewable energy sub sector, that is, 898.6 of the 946.84 million lempiras allocated for the energy sector, the decrease is propitiated by the significant decrease in the budget allocation for the generation of projects of the National Electric Power Company.
In 2018, the allocation increased to 97% (3,510.7 million lempiras) of the total allocation of the energy sector in Honduras of 3,607.7 million lempiras. In terms of year-on-year growth, both the energy sector and the subsector presented decreases in their annual budget allocations of 20% and 19% respectively. These data show how the energy matrix of Honduras has changed from non-renewable sources to renewable sources. These data were provided by an external V4CP consultant with high experience in the subject. To measure the annual public expenditure on energy (both budgeted, executed or accumulated and other related variables) faces many obstacles because many of the data are not clearly published on official platforms. For t ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">IIncrease / decrease (in%) of the annual budget allocation related to the development of the improved stoves market (improved stoves budget as a percentage of the total budget of the Renewable Energy sector)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecostoves budget as a percentage of the total budget of the Renewable Energy sector</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0.7%" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Budget allocation for the development and use of improved stoves between the years 2015-2017 in relation to the budget of the renewable energy subsector 2015-2017.

The budget allocation for the development of the improved stoves project in 2016 was 2.1 million Lempiras, which in relation to that assigned to renewable energy represents only 0.7%. For the purposes of the information presented, the following variable was used:  Annual budget for the Development and Use of Improved Stoves = Approved in Force budget. For Annual Expenditure for the Development and Use of Improved Stoves: Accrued budget; data contemplated in the budgetary area of the &quot;Project construction of eco-stoves, with accompaniment and installation of improved stoves, stoves fair&quot;, of Public Investment.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There   are no planned activities in 2020 for an appropriate budget allocation and,   therefore, no progress is expected on this indicator.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: No progress on this indicator is reported in 2020 as no activities were scheduled for it in year 2020.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.7%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are no activities planned in 2017 for an appropriate budget allocation and therefore no progress is expected in 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-12-2018: For the specific issue of the development and use of improved stoves in Honduras, the disadvantage was that despite the fact that the project started since 2011, with a closing date to 2017 and with a project extension to 2018, there is data just for 2016 of the study period 2015 - 2017. There are no official figures because many projects are managed under the figure of Public Private Partnership (PPP), who are not obliged to present publicly the registration of their operations (this under the protection of the Law of official secrets and classification of the information). On the other hand, the funds are channeled through trusts, in this case the Vida Major presidential program, who is responsible for the development of the project related to the improved stoves in Honduras, manages its funds through the Commission for the promotion of the public-private alliance COALIANZA, so although the totals are known, the breakdowns of these are not always recorded.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are no actions for 2018 that imply an appropriate budgetary allocation by the government to promote the development of the improved stoves market, therefore, no goal is defined for this year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The official budget allocation for improved stoves is not published, as it is protected under the figure of trust, in which several governmental programs and projects are included. Values reported in previous years were based on the scarce official information consultants had access to. The known information was the government target to deliver 100,000 clean stoves per year. For the 2018 study more information was available such as the average market price for improved stoves (estimated in USD 219), value based on information provided by different actors interviewed in the studies done by the program such as formal or artisanal manufacturers, project technicians, and governmental authorities, among others.
For the above, the following values were recalculated based on the assumptions that 100,000 improved stoves will be delivered per year and that the average market price is USD 219:

2015 ratio improved stoves to renewable energy estimated in 21% (483.96 budget approved improved stoves /2,311.35 budget approved renewable energy);
2016: 16% (503.59 / 3,226.68) resulting in a decrease of -5% compared to 2015.
2017:  the ratio was 12% (517.97 / 4,333.84) 
2018:  15% (527.14/3,556.98) resulting in an increase of 3%, compared to 2017.

It is important to record that the above values are own estimations since official figures are unknown
Although it was said that the extension of the project would be up to 2018, as indicated by the authorities that run the Better Life Program, the life of it could be extended again, depending on the level of acceptance of the project by its beneficiaries.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No target is set for 2019 since there are no actions identified for 2019 that imply an adequate budgetary allocation by the government to promote the development of the improved stove market.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="60.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: &quot;In order to carry out this analysis, the values of improved stoves delivered, which are published by the Ministry of Development and Social Inclusion, are taken as reference; this data was accessed through the transparency portal of this secretariat; we do not have the exact value of the budget allocation for the improved stoves project in Honduras, since these values are not published by official sources, what we have is an estimate based on an average market price of USD 219.00, under the average annual exchange rate. According to the planning of the government project Healthy Housing of the Better Life Program, 100,000 improved stoves would be delivered annually.
For 2018, it is estimated that the budget allocated for the development and distribution of improved stoves in Honduras was 527.14 million lempiras, following the basis of the delivery of 100,000 units annually and in 2019 it is 540.49 million lempiras.When compared to the budget allocated for renewable energy sub sector projects, in 2018 the budget allocation for the improved stoves project is equivalent to 15.02% of the total.
In 2019 this proportion increased, to 60.15% this figure is significant, given the high decrease in the budget of the renewable energy sub sector for this year that is equivalent to 898.60 a decrease of 390.60%, due to the closure and final stages of the mega projects managed and executed by the ENEE and that the allocation trend for MS is assumed in increases for the assumption of 100,000 units delivered annually and that are affected by the average annual exchange rate, from which this calculation starts.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase / decrease (in%) of the allocation of annual expenditure for the development and use of renewable energy (annual comparison of renewable energy expenditure versus total energy expenditure)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">annual comparison</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="93%" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the purposes of the information presented, the following variable were used: Annual Expenditure for the generation of renewable energy, the Accrued Budget for Public Investment for the development of renewable energy, referring to the generation of new projects, as well as the expenditure dedicated to maintenance and repair of existing projects in the renewable energy sector of Honduras.

The ratio of renewable energy expenditure to total spending in the energy sector was 83% in 2015, and 93% in 2016.

[OLD TEXT: It was only possible to determine that in the year 2015 the expenditure in Renewable energy was by the amount of L. 1,743,347,404. Sources: Ministry of Finance SEFIN (316,208.82), National Energy Enterprise, ENEE (25,425,799.43), and National program for Sustainable development PRONADERS (1717,605,395.52).]</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There   are no planned activities in 2020 for an appropriate budget allocation and,   therefore, no progress is expected on this indicator.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: No progress on this indicator is reported in 2020 as no activities were scheduled for it in year 2020.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="93%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is no action in 2017 for an appropriate budget allocation and therefore no progress is expected in 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="93.7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-12-2018: Annual expenditure on the development of Renewable Energy in relation to annual energy expenditure, between the years 2015-2017.
Annual expenditure on renewable energy, a growing trend is identified, of the 1,754.3 million Lempiras presented in 2015, in the first half of 2017 it reached 1,216,5 million.

Although the ratio of renewable energy expenditure to total spending in the energy sector was high in the first two years 83 (2015) and 93% (2016) respectively, in 2017 it was 93,7% which is in line with the growing trend in the budget execution of the renewable energy sector observed in these three years.

For the purposes of the information presented, the following variable were used: Annual Expenditure for the generation of renewable energy, the Accrued Budget for Public Investment for the development of renewable energy, referring to the generation of new projects, as well as the expenditure dedicated to maintenance and repair of existing projects in the renewable energy sector of Honduras.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="93.7%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are no actions for 2018 that imply an appropriate budgetary allocation by the government to promote the development of the improved stoves market, therefore, no goal is defined for this year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="94.01">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: In order to measure the 2017 and 2018 indicators regarding budget allocation and public spending, consultants with well-known experience were hired to collect and analyse the data from governmental sources. There are differences in the values reported in previous years since the analysis was based on just three quarters instead of four quarters data. In 2018 study, the 2017 data and scores were reviewed to include the whole year data (when the 2017 study was done there was data available just for the first three quarters of the year), hence, in the data presented in the previous reports, values are lower than the current ones.
The corrected values are as follow:           
2015: ratio of spending on renewable energy/energy sector 83.08% (1,754.34/2,111.57);
2016: ratio of 93.11% (2,681.20 / 2,879.68), shows an increase of 10.03% compared to 2015.
2017: the ratio of spending on renewable energy/energy sector was 96.04% (3,599.69 / 3,747.96) 

For 2018, data available was for the first three quarters. In order to establish a comparison, a projection of the values of the fourth quarter was made, based on the average of expenditures of the energy sector and renewable energy observed in the period 2015-2017. 
For 2018, 94.01% of the expenditures of the energy sector corresponded to renewable energy projects and programs, equivalent to 2,884.44 million lempiras of 3,067.94 for energy sector, which shows a decrease of -2.03 compared to 2017 values.
These values could change, if the analysis is done based on the complete 2018 official data, when it is available.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No target is set for 2019 since there are no actions identified for 2019 that imply an adequate budgetary allocation by the government to promote the development of the improved stove market.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="96.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: &quot;There are differences in the values notified in 2018, since the analysis was based on data from only three quarters instead of IV quarters since they were not available at the time of the report. So the 2018 data had a variation such as: The ratio of renewable energy expenditure/energy sector was 94.01% (2,884.44/3,067.94 million lempiras), the updated data is 98% (2,084.80/2,136.64 million lempiras) equivalent to a difference of 3.99% (increase).
In 2018, L. 2084.8 million of the executed budget corresponded to renewable type projects, by 2019 it is estimated that L. 26.5 million would have been allocated for energy generation projects based on non-renewable sources, that is, 4% of the executed budget .

For 2019 this proportion decreased by 2% since 98% of the budget of the energy sector executed in 2018 was invested in programs and projects of the renewable energy sub sector, 2019 shows a ratio of 96% of renewable energy in the composition of the energy sector ( 554.50/580.10 million lempiras), with which it can be said that annually the investment and reinvestment in the use of renewable resources for the generation of electricity remains at margins above 95%

For the purposes of the information presented, the following variables were used: annual expenditure for the generation of renewable energy, the accumulated budget of Public Investment for the development of renewable energies, in reference to the generation of new projects, as well as the expenditure dedicated maintenance and repair of existing projects in the renewable energy sector of Honduras.
Until the moment in which the investigation was carried out, the official data available were those of the third quarter of 2019, in order to establish a comparison, a projection of the values of the IV quarter was made, through the average of expenses of the energy and renewable energy sector  observed in the 2015-2018 period, the same was done in the previous study.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase / decrease (in%) of the annual expenditure allocation related to the development of the improved stoves market (cost of improved stoves as a percentage of the total expenditure of the Renewable Energy sector)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">spending on Ecostoves as a percentage of total spending in the Renewable Energy sector</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0.08%" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the information provided by the Ministry of Finance, it was not possible to determine the ecostoves budget, it was stated in visits to several institutions that this information is not available.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There   are no planned activities in 2020 for an appropriate budget allocation and,   therefore, no progress is expected on this indicator.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: No progress on this indicator is reported in 2020 as no activities were scheduled for it in year 2020.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.08%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is no action in 2017 for an appropriate budget allocation and therefore no progress is expected in 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-12-2018: The increase is unknown. There is no official data for 2017. We know that there are governmental programs to promote clean stoves but these investments are managed as &#x201C;public &#x2013; private associations&#x201D;. Under this legal and financial figure, the government is not required to present to the public the data or the register of its operations. So we do not have access to this information</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.08%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are no actions for 2018 that imply an appropriate budgetary allocation by the government to promote the development of the improved stoves market, therefore, no goal is defined for this year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="-4.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: As in the case of budget allocation for improved stoves, before middle 2018, there was no completed data for 2017. What was included in previous reports are estimations based on the scarce official information consultants had access to. The reviewed values are as follow:
2015: ratio of spending on improved stoves compared to renewable energy expenditure is 12% (208.1/1,754.34). (Approximately 43,000 stoves were delivered)
2016: ratio of 13% (355.03 / 2,681.20), that is to say 1% increase compared to 2015.  (Approximately 70,500 stoves were delivered)
2017: ratio of 9% (310.78 / 3,599.69) (60,002 improved stoves were delivered)
2018: ratio of 5% (137.01 / 2,884.40), That represents 4% less than what was observed in 2017. (25,998 improved stoves were delivered)

According to the government&apos;s first year report published at the beginning of 2019, in 2018 a total of 25,998 improved stoves were delivered, that is, 34,004, Improved stoves less than in 2017.
The expenditure of the government project of improved stoves in 2018, decreased to 137.04 million lempiras. 

This decrease is due to several factors, including the level of acceptance of improved stoves. In general, the adoption is slow and the attachment to the traditional stove and similar designs is strong in Honduras. On the other hand, although it is not possible to prove that the project has been used for political purposes, the analysis of the 2015-2018 data shows higher level of expenditure on improved stoves, in years of political campaigns, and lower, not even half of what was planned, in years when there is not political campaigns.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No target is set for 2019 since there are no actions identified for 2019 that imply an adequate budgetary allocation by the government to promote the development of the improved stove market.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: &quot;As in the case of the budget allocation for improved stoves, before mid-2019 there was no complete data for 2018, which generated variations in the data that are detailed below:
2018: proportion of 5% (137.01/2.884.40 and the adjusted value is 6.62% (138.06/2084.80) generating an increase of 1.62%.

On the other hand, an adjustment of 25,998 improved stoves reported in 2018 was also made, official figures indicate that 26,190 were delivered, that is 192 more improved stoves reported.The expense of the government project of improved stoves in 2018, decreased to 137.04 million lempiras, the correct data is 138.06.

For 2018, annual expenditure on improved stoves corresponded to 6.62% of total renewable energy expenditure, in 2019 this value decreased drastically to 0.15% while L. 138.06 million were executed in the improved stoves project in 2018, in the renewable energy sub-sector the budget execution figure corresponded to L. 2,084 million lempiras.
Even with the significant decrease in budget execution in 2019 for renewable energy when establishing the comparison with the IS project, it showed that everything executed for the distribution of improved stoves is only 0.15% of the accrued in renewable energy, since Total IS expenditure was L. 826,956.11 lempiras, contrasted with the estimated 554.5 million executed in the renewable energy sub sector projects.
Most of the current programs focus on the installation of improved kitchens, but not on their adoption, which negatively affects the desired changes. In some cases, improved stoves were not used or are used in a low percentage. A study shows that 16% of households surveyed in twelve communities across the country have an additional stove than the traditional one. Similarly, the analysis of the Perception of the degree of quality and accessibility of services 2018 by V4CP reflects that of 106 people surveyed (28 have a stove, 54 have 2 stoves, 23 have 3 stoves and 1 person had 4 stoves in their h ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capabilities of CSOs strengthened.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs with improved advocacy capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their advocacy capacities guided by a list of advocacy criteria.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="2.5" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: Confidencial</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Average score 2.53
Changes are expected in 2018 given the interventions and actions that the program would carry out in areas of knowledge of the area of RE, including the identification of the main actors, analysis of Policies, strategies, laws and regulations and the studies that will be done. In the same way, the workshops among peers will be carried out by CSOs based on their expertise. &quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The target of 2 CSOs that increase their thematic knowledge capacities was not reached as just one CSO reported increase in this indicator. The scores were as follows: one CSO 2.8 to 3.3, an increase of 0.5; the other CSO maintained its score of 3.5 to 3.5. 

A series of peer to peer capacity building workshops were held among CSOs based on their expertise: Training on political advocacy, Gender and Climate change with emphasis on public policies, generational change and masculinity, Renewable Energy and Improved Stoves, Communication plans, and Decentralization and local public policies. Also workshops promoted from SNV such as: building coalitions, evidence and advocacy, media and communication skills for development; Training of technical and administrative CSOs staff on V4CP, measurement of perceptions on quality and accessibility of services.

CSOs consider that they have strengthened their capacities in different areas due to their participation on the research carried out through expert consultant teams. CSOs participated in the whole process from the preparation of the terms of reference to the presentation of progress and final reports, including their accompaniment of the field work, socialization and validation of knowledge products. They are empowered by their knowledge products and the learning they got from them in topics such as the legal framework of improved stoves in Honduras, Gender approach on the value chain of IS; Impact of  exemption of sale tax and other on IS; Socioeconomic and Environmental issues related to the National Strategy, that will be developed in 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2.5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">no major changes are expected in the target in 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-03-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Changes are expected for 2019 given the effect of the actions to be carried out especially the research to develop knowledge products, processes lead by partner CSOs.

CSOs consider that they need to strengthen: &#x2022; Spokesperson capacities to influence the development, approval and implementation of the National Strategy for the Adoption of Improved Stoves. Practical training.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs with increased thematic knowledge</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their thematic knowledge guided by a list of  criteria.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="2.7" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;average score is 3.13
Changes are expected in 2018 given the interventions and actions that the program would carry out in areas of knowledge of the area of RE, including the identification of the main actors, analysis of Policies, strategies, laws and regulations and the studies that will be done. In the same way for the workshops peer to peer that CSOs will be carrying out based on their expertise.  &quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The target of 2 CSOs that increase their thematic knowledge capacities was not reached as just one CSO reported increase in this indicator. The scores were as follows: one CSO 2.8 to 3.3, an increase of 0.5; the other CSO maintained its score of 3.5 to 3.5. 

A series of peer to peer capacity building workshops were held among CSOs based on their expertise: Training on political advocacy, Gender and Climate change with emphasis on public policies, generational change and masculinity, Renewable Energy and Improved Stoves, Communication plans, and Decentralization and local public policies. Also workshops promoted from SNV such as: building coalitions, evidence and advocacy, media and communication skills for development; Training of technical and administrative CSOs staff on V4CP, measurement of perceptions on quality and accessibility of services.

CSOs consider that they have strengthened their capacities in different areas due to their participation on the research carried out through expert consultant teams. CSOs participated in the whole process from the preparation of the terms of reference to the presentation of progress and final reports, including their accompaniment of the field work, socialization and validation of knowledge products. They are empowered by their knowledge products and the learning they got from them in topics such as the legal framework of improved stoves in Honduras, Gender approach on the value chain of IS; Impact of  exemption of sale tax and other on IS; Socioeconomic and Environmental issues related to the National Strategy, that will be developed in 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2.7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">no major changes are expected</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-03-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that changes will occur in 2019 taking into account the interventions and actions that will be carried out.

CSOs consider that they need to strengthen capacities in:
&#x2022; Implementation of cost accounting.
&#x2022; Implementation and monitoring of a new accounting system.
&#x2022; Creation of an effective communication strategy.
&#x2022; Creation of a salary policy.
&#x2022; Administrative strengthening - processes.

&quot;CSOs highly appreciate the training provided by experts, as has been done in previous years. The training in 2019 will be done by:
1) individual mini workshop (for each CSO based on  demand and resources available)
2) General workshop (for all or a group of CSOs based on demand and resources available).

A small fund has been allocated to hire coachers for short term and specific assignment. It will also be based on demand and resources available.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: Confidential | 27-04-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSO with improved leadership capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their leadership capacities guided by a list of leadership criteria.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="3.1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Average score 3.28
It is considered that CSOs may have some change by 2018 given the effect of the actions of 2017, likewise by 2018 it is planned that each CSO will conduct workshops among peers based on their expertise they will share with other CSOs, example:

It has been considered that there may be a small increase over the value reported at the end of 2017, the same % increase was considered.      
&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The average score was obtained through guided self-evaluations which results were tabulated in google. The consolidation of the data was done and shared by SNV Netherlands.

In 2018 target a small increase was considered compared to the reported value for 2017. The data generated shows that no CSO increased their leadership abilities since their score was maintained from 3.2 to 3.2 and 1 CSO lower its score from 3.3 to 2.5.

This is coincident since the strengthening of capacities was oriented according to the demand of the CSOs. The CSOs prioritized the topics of organizational sustainability, advocacy and thematic knowledge so peer to peer workshops were developed according to the CSO&apos;s expertise.  
Despite the score given, CSOs consider that they made progress in some aspects of leadership such as: Search for the consensus of all those involved in the execution of activities, coordination with key actors and the efficient use of resources. They also feel that they have strengthened their communication skills for a more effective communication of their messages. They also consider that they have been more proactivity and responsible. Improvement of the relationship with various actors, better knowledge of their interests that facilitate the identification of effective routes for the solution of problems, and increase their motivation.
The cause is the rotation of personel assigned to V4CP Program. The surveys were filled as follow:

1 CSO: 2017: Filled by 2 persons          2018: Filled by 1 new person                                                                    .
2 CSO: 2017: Filled by 3 persons    2018: Filled by 2 persons (1 person is new)
 
In our opinion partner CSOs are very self-critical.
CSOs haighly value the expertis of the facilitators and trainers that have developed the training and workshops so far.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">no major changes are expected</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-03-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is not expected an increase in the leadership score given that the actions of the program will be more oriented to advocacy. Even though, the advocacy actions may have a conjectural influence in the leadership score

Capacity building and leadership issues were not prioritized by CSOs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs with increased capacity in organisational sustainability</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs self-assessed their thematic knowledge guided by a list of  criteria.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Average score is 2.7
Changes are expected in 2018 as coaching and counseling services continue for each CSOs.

It should be noted that the international panorama of financial crisis is having a direct impact in the operational logic of CSOs. Each time the budget cuts are more severe. The analysis of the partner CSOs indicated that 80% are directly dependent on external cooperation funds. 20% of them have started with initiatives of financial self-management, but in some cases they cover only 14-20% of the budget and only 50% of it in one CSO. &quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A small change is expected in this indicator in 2019 and also a change in the provision of the service. Short term and punctual-product services will be provided upon demand expressed by the CSOs and available resources.

The needs of the organizations are diverse and differentiated as can be seen in the following topics prioritized by CSOs: &#x2022; Self-sustainability &#x2022; Inclusive Businesses &#x2022; Resource management &#x2022; Formulation of technical proposals based on the information generated. &#x2022; Design of investment projects that contemplate financial sustainability.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: Confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of quality services for the adoption of ecostoves, in order to improve the health of users and reduce the consumption of firewood to levels below 50% of a conventional stove.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">More accessible services for people in conditions of poverty and extreme poverty.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="18.9" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the purpose of being able to determine the improvement in the accessibility of the services in RE, a participatory Methodology for the survey was prepared and 6 focus groups were realized in some areas of the country with people of the communities, 116 women and 18 men participated.

On the same 24-point scale, this indicator averaged 18.9 points, that is, an indicator of 78% of satisfaction with the ease of accessing the service, according to the category score.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There   is no certainty that the target set for previous years have been achieved so   the same target will be set for 2020. 
 

    The main action planned for 2020 is the &#x201C;Perception measurement on the   degree of accessibility and quality of RE-IS services provided by the   government&#x201D;. This final study will be facilitated by the same expert that   facilitated the base line and intermediate measurements. V4CP/SNV team and   partner CSOs play an important role in these studies</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: A target had not been defined for this indicator, so it is unknown to date if there is any improvement in access to services provided by the government in the area of improved stoves.

CSOs were trained for the field survey, interpretation and dissemination of data of the final measurement. However, the field work was postponed due to absolute curfew set by the Government of Honduras since March 16 up to date for Covid pandemic. The absolute curfew is maintained throughout the Honduran territory until August 23. It is expected to start the survey in September, this will depend on whether the measures are maintained, complying with all biosafety protocols. 
A pilot will be developed in the western area through Hermandad de Honduras, given that it is the area with the fewest cases of COVID-19. Consultations will be done applying all the biosecurity measures and by direct interviews to respondents who participated in the baseline and the intermediate measurement done by V4CP and its partners CSOs (meetings are not allowed, as a prevention measure).

The study is being facilitated by the same thematic expert who prepared the baseline and the intermediate measurement; with the accompaniment of SNV and partner CSOs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="19">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that Eco stove services provided by the government will continue in 2017 and that giving that 2017 is a political year more people will have access to them. It will be necessary to allocate enough budget and time to carry out this surveys every two years.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="14.90">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">04-07-2018: &quot;As it was a political year, in 2017 no changes were expected in the quality of services for the adoption of improved stoves provided by the government and the target was the same as the baseline. In the previous report, the preliminary data obtained from the study measuring the perception of the degree of Quality and Accessibility of Renewable Energy-improved stoves services were reported. The study and the verification of data was completed in the second semester. The final report reports data different from the data of the preliminary report.
The survey was conducted with 121 people (111 women 91.74% and 10 men 8.26%), through focus groups and their opinions defined the initial situation in terms of Quality and Access of services. The study covered 5 departments of the country, involving a total of 6 municipalities.  
According to the data gathered, there is more than one tipe of stoves in 120 cases. In those 120 households there are 242 stoves, an average of two stoves per household. In 65% of the cases both stoves are used. The most common stove in the households consulted is the eco-stove Envirofit (87%), followed by the traditional stove (76%). A higher percentage of users of this latter model uses it (77%) compared to the percentage that uses the Envirofit (56%). Much less widespread are the Justa model and the 2 x 3 of Mirador Project. 

On the same scale from zero to 24 points, the Accessibility indicator reached an average of 14.9 points, that is 62% satisfaction with the degree of ease of accessing the service, that is, an &quot;&quot;acceptable&quot;&quot; level.
To assess the accessibility of services, three categories were used: Material limitations 67%, Economic limitations 77% and sociocultural limitations 43%.
In general, the evaluation of the degree of accessibility shows that the level of satisfaction with the service is largely due to sociocultural limitations, given that it was the category with the lowest score, these limitations are related to t ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15.05">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">An increae of 1% in the access to services for clean stoves is expected, taking in account that the government will increase the donation of clean stoves and its services for political reasons in 2018. A significant increase in Vida Mejor governmental program is expected and it has a big line for clean stoves.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="11.30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: An increase of 1% in the accessibility of the service was expected, the target established was 15.05. To measure the perception of people on quality of the services in improved stoves, the participatory methodology used for the baseline was adjusted and an intermediate measurement was made. The intermediate measurement was done in the same 5 districts, as in the baseline, including 6 municipalities in total and neighbors of 28 different communities, compared to the 30 communities of the baseline. The call gathered 106 people instead of the 121 that participated in the baseline (86 women-81% and 20 men-19%), that represents 88% of the sample of the baseline.
To perception on Accessibility of the Service, was measured based on three categories: Material Limitations, Economic Limitations and Sociocultural Limitations. In the same scale from zero to 24 points, the Accessibility indicator reached an average of 11.3 points, equivalent to 47% satisfaction, a significant reduction compared to 14.9 points and 62% satisfaction reported in the baseline.
In conclusion, the degree of perceived access to Envirofit eco-stove services has deteriorated since the baseline survey 19 months ago. All limitations were reduced, but more significantly sociocultural limitations. The sociocultural limitations was also rated as the lowest rated category in the baseline. Its low rating is not due to the number of requirements to access an Envirofit eco-stove, but the selection criteria. 78% of participants consider that not all people can get one; a slightly higher percentage believe that there are reasons why people are not eligible, that is, there are cases of exclusion. Almost the same percentage considers that the distribution that is made of the eco-stoves is not fair or equitable. Only 9 people considered &quot;fair&quot; the distribution of the eco-stoves and at the same time indicated that &quot;there were no reasons to exclude a person.&quot; In contrast, 40 who did not consider it fair, ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improvement in the quality of services provided by the government, private sector or academia (universities).</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="12.9" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the purpose of being able to determine the improvement in the quality of the services in RE, a participatory Methodology for the survey was prepared and 6 focus groups were realized in some areas of the country with people of the communities, 116 women and 18 men participated.
On a scale of zero to twenty-four points this indicator was fixed on average by 12.9 points, that is to say an indicator of 54% of satisfaction with the service, according to the category score.
The report of each focal group and final report is still in process.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There   is no certainty that the target set for previous years have been achieved so   the same target will be set for 2020. 
 

    The main action planned for 2020 is the &#x201C;Perception measurement on the   degree of accessibility and quality of RE-IS services provided by the   government&#x201D;. This final study will be facilitated by the same expert that   facilitated the base line and intermediate measurements. V4CP/SNV team and   partner CSOs play an important role in these studies</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: A target had not been defined for this indicator, so it is unknown to date if there is any improvement in the quality of the services provided by the government in the area of improved stoves.

CSOs were trained for the field survey, interpretation and dissemination of data of the final measurement. However, the field work was postponed due to absolute curfew set by the Government of Honduras since March 16 up to date for Covid pandemic. The absolute curfew is maintained throughout the Honduran territory until August 23. It is expected to start the survey in September, this will depend on whether the measures are maintained, complying with all biosafety protocols. 
A pilot will be developed in the western area through Hermandad de Honduras, given that it is the area with the fewest cases of COVID-19. Consultations will be done applying all the biosecurity measures and by direct interviews to respondents who participated in the baseline and the intermediate measurement done by V4CP and its partners CSOs (meetings are not allowed, as a prevention measure).

The study is being facilitated by the same thematic expert who prepared the baseline and the intermediate measurement; with the accompaniment of SNV and partner CSOs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="11.4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is no certainty that the target established in 2017 has increased so this same score is reflected for 2018.
Given the current situation the country is facing due to the dark process of the president re-election, improvement in the quality of RE  services  is not expected.                                                        there may be a lot of disagreements in local communities about the current situation in the country.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="9.70">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: No significant changes were expected in this indicator, so the established target of 11.4 was maintained in the baseline. To measure the perception of people on quality of the services in improved stoves, the participatory methodology used for the baseline was adjusted and an intermediate measurement was made. The intermediate measurement was done in the same 5 districts, as in the baseline, including 6 municipalities in total and neighbors of 28 different communities, compared to the 30 communities of the baseline. The call gathered 106 people instead of the 121 that participated in the baseline (86 women-81% and 20 men-19%), that represents 88% of the sample of the baseline.
Five categories were used to evaluate the perception on quality of the services: Relevance, Efficiency, Efficacy, Impact and Sustainability. For the intermediate measurement, the Service Quality indicator maintained the perception of a &quot;deficient&quot; level, reaching an average of 9.7 points, equivalent to a degree of satisfaction of 41%, which is lower than the score recorded during the baseline (11.4 points, 47%).
Although the population recognizes the impact that the eco-stove Envirofit has on their homes -the only category that increased its level and ranked in the top third of the scores-, the level of relevance decreased markedly, the service is still considered as &quot; deficient &quot;(less than 50% satisfaction).
In general, the evaluation shows that the low satisfaction of the service is based on low efficiency and low sustainability. They are perceived as having a low level of functionality and a short lifespan, given that it was the category with the lowest score. The perception of the services relevance is reduced considerably that is, the perception of being necessary and demanded services by the population. One possible explanation for this could be the fact that, on average, those consulted have had little more than two years the eco-friendly stoves, which means that when t ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National inclusive enabling Strategy for the installment of improved stoves approved</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress in the development, approval, socialization, adoption and implementation of a new inclusive strategy by government</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We use &#x2018;scoring rubric&#x2019; as method. The below list unpacks the indicator and defines multiple levels of success: 

0. No legislative framework in the form of policies, laws, standards, regulations and/or guidelines exists, or existing/new suggested legislative framework is detrimental to issue
1. A new/adjusted legislative framework is considered 
2. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been drafted
3. A new/adjusted legislative framework has been adopted but not applied or enforced, OR framework detrimental to issue has been prevented
4. New/adjusted legislative framework is applied and/or enforced, but without appropriate means and/or not equally applied (across geographical areas, socio-economic groups, men/women &#x2026;.)
5. New/adjusted legislative framework is effectively and equally applied and/or enforced</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;A new Inclusive Strategy for the adoption of ecostoves is being considered. The draft of the Improved Stoves Regulations (first step towards the elaboration of the Strategy) was discussed until page 25 on September 1st at the HOS headquarters with the participation of the consensus group. 
The evaluation rubric was applied and agreed as 1 as a score.
Actors: 
Public sector: 6 influential decision-makers such as the Standardization Coordinator of the Honduran Organization for Standardization (HOS), Secretary of State in the Natural Resources, Environment, Energy and Mines Offices (MiAmbiente), Director of the Institute of Forest Conservation (ICF), Secretary of State in the Offices of Development and Social Inclusion (SEDIS), Secretary of State in the Office of Health (SESAL), Director of Climate Change in My Environment.
Private sector: Mirador Project, Envirofit and local producers. 
Programs and Projects of international donors and lenders: GiZ, IDB, CIDA, USAID. 
Universities: National University, Forestry University, Zamorano.
Civil society Organizations: Honduran Foundation Environment and Development. (Fundacion Vida), Honduras Brotherhood Hermandad de Honduras (HdH), Honduran Association for the Development of Honduras Asociaci&#xF3;n hondure&#xF1;a para el desarrollo (AHDESA), Foundation for the Integral Development of Honduras (FUNDEIH) Fundacion para el desarrollo integral de Honduras.
The two SCO participating in the program proposed to advocate for a legal and financial framework that facilitate the development of the market and the adoption of ecostoves. The specific elements of this enabling environment to be reflected in the content of the strategy will depend on the results of the consensus process that the 2 CSO will carry on with potential partners and alliances. When the agreements are reached probably new indicators will be added to monitor the content of the national strategy.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The   indicator will remain at 2 given the political context and the instability in   the sector structure. However CSOs will concentrate their efforts on advocacy   to get strong support for the implementation of the ENAEM. Among the main   actions of the CSOs in 2020 are: complete the design of the National Strategy   ENAEM, socialization of the ENAEM with different influential actors to get   support for its approval. In close coordination with DNCC/. Similar process   with the Energy Secretariat for the approval of the sale tax exemption for   improved stoves and their parts.
     Continue the implementation of the communication strategy to disseminate   the main components of the National Strategy ENAEM through reflection and/or   discussion events, knowledge sharing with key actors at national and regional   level. It includes mini-workshops with the Interinstitutional Platform and   events with universities and local governments.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: The target for this indicator remains at 2, the CSOs applied the evaluation rubric and gave the same score in a consensual manner.
Some activities have been modified due to the health emergency related to COVID. However, the main actions of the CSOs in 2020: the National Strategy for the Adoption of Improved Stoves (ENAEM) has been finalized, a series of meetings were held to validate and discuss the relevance of the strategic guidelines of the ENAEM and the structure of the document. Currently, the ENAEM socialization process continues with different actors to influence its approval. An awareness and advocacy campaign is being implemented to promote the adoption of improved stoves, and that the different actors know and support the initiatives proposed by the ENAEM.  A series of communication products were developed: 4 radio spots broadcast nationwide through community radio stations and other local radio stations, and they are also being broadcast on different social networks (brochures, posters, posts and bulletins).

The political context, instability in the structure of the sector and the COVID 19 context may hamper the approval of the ENAEM. However, CSOs jointly with the Interinstitutional Platform continue their advocacy work for its approval and governmental officers such as Allan Mej&#xED;a, Technical Coordinator of the NAMAS in MiAmbiente Secretariat highlighted the relevance of ENAEM: &quot;the impacts caused by the COVID 19 pandemic are not limited to the effect on the health of the population, but have also negative implications on the economy and productivity of different sectors which increases the vulnerability of the population, and the dependence of the rural and peri-urban population on firewood as a source of energy for cooking their food. This highlights the validity of the ENAEM and the need to implement the measures it proposes&quot; Jorge Chi Ham, Biomass Specialist of the Energy Secretariat commented: &quot;The adoption of improved stoves will ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;It is expected for 2018 to present a Proposal of an inclusive strategy for the development of the value chain of improved stoves built with the participation of the members of the platform.
A multidisciplinary team will be defined for the formulation of the strategy within the framework of the inter-institutional platform, taking as a basis the previous studies carried out by V4CP, MiAmbiente, ICF and other members of the platform.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: An analysis was conducted jointly with the CSOs to define the progress of this indicator using the evaluation rubric. Both CSOs agreed to give a score of 1 while the established target was 2. For 2018, it was expected to have a National Strategy proposal for adoption of improved stoves, built with the participation of the members of the platform. However, this was not possible. Currently, the National Enabling Inclusive Strategy for the adoption of improved stoves in Honduras is being considered. The terms of reference for the recruitment of a multidisciplinary team for the formulation of the strategy within the framework of the inter-institutional platform were drawn up, based on the previous studies carried out by V4CP, MiAmbiente, ICF and other members of the platform. TORs were published and 5 technical and financial proposals were received at the end of January 2019. Agreements were made with MiAmbiente to lead the process of the national strategy design in consensus and with the technical support of the Inter-Institutional Platform. The selection and contracting process will be done the first quarter of 2019. It should be noted that the Government has not planned to draft a Strategy.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No major progress is expected in this indicator in 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-03-2018: &quot;No progress has been made in this indicator, the evaluation rubric was assessed and CSOs maintained their scores resulting in 0.5 rounded to 1 (1 CSO gave a score of 1 and 1 CSO gave a score of 0).                                                                                                                                          The proposal of the program is to elaborate a National Strategy, a proposal of content has been made by a consultant financed from the program, but at the level of the decision makers it has not been presented. It was presented and discussed in the interinstitutional Platform, and some interest has been expressed.

One CSO gave a score of one taking in accout that there is a proposal of content discussed at the level of the interinstitutional platform and for the CSO it is a step forward. The other CSO recognized the product and that it raized the interest of the platform but there is no action from the government side to design a national strategy for clean stoves so the score is 0</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that by 2019 the proposal of the National Strategy for the adoption of efficient stoves will be presented to the government, built by a consultant team accompanied by the Inter Institutional Platform.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: The target for this indicator was 2, applying the rubric of evaluation the CSOs gave a score of 2 in a consensual way in view of the elaboration of the first draft of the National Strategy for the Adoption of improved stoves, in close coordination with the Interinstitutional Platform and the National Directorate of Climate Change. The initiative was officially launched on October 10, 2019 in the event &#x201C;Challenges in the Access to Energy Event and its implications for Food and Nutrition Security&#x201D;, which was attended by representatives of the State Secretariats, the private sector, universities, agroforestry cooperatives, national and international programs related to the subject, among other relevant actors. The University El Zamorano was hired to provide technical support in the design of the National Strategy ENAEM.

From the perspective of CSOs, the structure of the government is not clear and incorporates new actors every year as in 2018 created the Energy Secretariat with a mandate to regulate electricity, hydrocarbons and renewable energy. At the end of 2019 started the creation of a new Presidential Office to Manage Green Financing. If approved, it will debilitate even more the fragile structure and governance system, concentrated in the presidential house. These new entities come to add existing institutions such as Mi Ambiente, ICF and Clima Plus with the mandate in the field of renewable energy and support for the development of technologies. This makes coordination of actions more difficult and increases uncertainty about the interests of current authorities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusive businesses and greater investments in the development of ecostoves with efficiency of not less than 50%.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of local manufacturers and / or certified small and medium scale ecostoves businesses.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="46" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;In meetings held with staff of the Central American Fund for Access to Energy and Poverty Reduction (FOCAEP) and with the ENDEV Central America program, who commented that these local manufacturers and businesses are not certified, most are individual persons, however, they have their respective billing as required by the Income Management Service of Honduras. These small manufacturers have received trainings from their counterparts on quality, preventive measures, and specifications, among others.

Within this number there is only one medium-sized company: Eco stove of Honduras part of the NGO AHDESA. The rest (45) are individuals or local enterprises that supply all or part of the ecostoves (tinsmiths, metal sheets. Rocket Ceramic Slab, among others).

These are local producers that are not certified yet. As a product of advocacy and others it is expected that they go into a process of certification in the next 3 or 4 years.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A   target for this indicator will not be defined as the CSOs will focus their   actions on the last year of the program in completing the National Strategy,   its approval and future implementation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: No action was considered for this indicator given that the program is in its final phase and the actions were prioritized to complete the ENAEM and influence its approval, and in the exemption of sales tax on improved stoves and their parts.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are no actions for 2018, nor are there currently programs, projects or institutions that certify local manufacturers, it is expected that in the future with the approval of the National Strategy it will be possible to carry it out, that is what the project is aiming for.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: No advocate actions on this indicator were planned for 2018, and there is no established target either. On the other hand, there are not currently programs, projects or institutions that certify local manufacturers. It is expected that in the future with the approval of the National Strategy it will be possible to have this service. There is no obligation for manufacturers to be certified so small and large scale companies are not doing so.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is no action in 2017 on the topic of inclusive business and therefore no progress is expected in it in 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-03-2018: &quot;There was no target for this indicator. In meetings held with the staff of the Central American Fund for Access to Energy and Poverty Reduction (FOCAEP) and with the ENDEV Central America program, they commented that the number of 46 individuals or local companies that supply all or part of the stoves such as: sheet metal, Rocket Ceramic Slab, among others, that was presented in the baseline year 2016 remains.

Currently, there are no programs, projects or institutions that certify local manufacturers, basically the projects are oriented to training processes.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target for this indicator will be determined in the first semester of 2019 based on information gattered on what the certification of stoves means and requires. Also information on other countries experience on certification. Number of stoves evaluated by Zamorano, the standards and tests to apply and their costs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: There was no defined target for this indicator. There are currently no programs, projects or institutions that certify local manufacturers. Only the University El Zamorano evaluates the improved stoves in the country, they have an Evaluation Center.
An interview was conducted with Director of the Stove Evaluation Center and she told us that the Zamorano has evaluated 7 stoves and 1 gasifier in the period 2018 - 2019. (2018: 2 Profogones Project; 2019: 4 Profogones Project, 1 Ecoestufa is the model (specialized manufacturing), 1 International Development Enterprises (IDE) gasifier.
The standards, tests that are applied in the Evaluation Center: What is defined in the OHN 97001: 2017 Standard &quot;Improved Stoves-Requirements and test methods for classification and categorization&quot; is being applied. The water boiling test, fuel consumption, energy transfer, total emissions captured, intra-residential emissions are applied. The safety protocol is applied, the stove is characterized and a report of the results is delivered.
The cost of evaluating the stove depends on what the customer requests. As for example, when it is a complete evaluation test when 3 stoves of the same batch are ordered, the water boiling test costs approximately $ 2,000.00. When it is a verification or preliminary test, it costs $ 1,000.00, only one stove is evaluated in both tests, carbon dioxide and carbon monoxide are measured, intra-household emissions, fuelwood consumption and energy efficiency are quantified.
In Latin America there is no place where you can certify improved stoves such as the International Organization for Standardization (ISO) in the case of Zamorano and the National Autonomous University of Mexico (UNAM) have laboratories and make evaluations. There are also other institutions in other countries, such as Peru and Bolivia.
The Zamorano is not a certification body because they are not accredited under an official accreditation system. To be an accredited body you  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of small-scale local manufacturers that have new or improved supply agreements with businesses, local governments and other medium-scale applicants.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;These manufacturers have agreements with cooperators and organizations that are developing programs and projects on eco stoves themes such as: USAID &#x2013; Proparque (Pro-park) - FINTRAC, German Development Cooperation (GIZ), Environment and Development Foundation; Who grant funds to organizations such as: Hermandad de Honduras (Honduras Brotherhood), Fundaci&#xF3;n Prolancho ( Prolancho Foundation), Cooperative de mujeres (Women Cooperative) COOMUL, among others, however, a market for eco stoves has not been developed as such. There are few cases of manufacturers that sell to the general public.

It should be noted that the government of Honduras currently has a social program called &quot;&quot;Better Life&quot;&quot; where eco stoves are installed for free and it has agreements with a factory to build them.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A   target of 0 is set for 2020, as the monitoring and measurement of this   indicator is beyond the capabilities of CSOs to have access to this kind of   information.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: No progress on this indicator is reported in 2020 as the access to the kind of information required to monitor and measure this indicator is beyond the capabilities of CSOs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are no actions for the year 2018, on this indicator.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: There is no established target for this indicator. Since there is no a market developed for improved stoves, there are currently few cases of manufacturers that sell improved stoves for the general public. These manufacturers have agreements with institutions that are developing programs and projects that include improved stoves, such as: USAID - Proparque- FINTRAC, German Cooperation for Development (GIZ), Hermandad de Honduras, USAID - GEMA, Honduras Social Investment Fund - FHIS POWER, Sustainable Rural Development Program for the Southern Region - EMPRENDESUR. It is unknown how many of the manufacturers have agreements with companies, governments or others.

In spite of this, in the case of Hermandad de Honduras through the actions that are being developed with V4CP, it is promoting inclusive business and has signed in the year 2018, 4 contracts with manufacturers and signed a cooperation agreement with a private company, as it is describe below:

1) Contract for manufacturing services of 22 metal bases for portable containers of improved wood stoves. Contract signed with Welder Jerson Francisco M&#xE9;ndez Garc&#xED;a, March 2018. 

2) Contract for manufacture and assembly of 300 metal sheets. Contract signed with Mr. Roling Adhonhay Fern&#xE1;ndez, May 2018.

3) Contract for manufacture of 500 combustion chambers. Contract signed with Mr. Jorge Alberto Rivera Garc&#xED;a, May 2018.

4) Contract for manufacture and assembly of 200 metal plates, 500 chimney sweeps. Contract signed with Mr. Olfino Manc&#xED;a Sorianin, May 2018.

5) Cooperation agreement  for the construction of 60 stoves (model Justa 16x24) for families in Colonia Richard Washburn and Campamento Uluita, from San Alejo, Tela, Atlantida. Agreement signed with private company (Jaremar Group), as part of their Corporate Social Responsibility actions, November 2018.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is no action in 2017 on the topic of inclusive business and therefore no progress is expected in it in 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-03-2018: &quot;There was no target set for this indicator.
Based on the interview to FOCAEP and ENDEV personnel, these manufacturers have agreements with institutions that are developing programs and projects that include improved stoves such as: USAID - Proparque- FINTRAC, German Cooperation for Development (GIZ), Hermandad de  Honduras, USAID - GEMA, Honduran Investment Social Fund - FHIS PODER, Sustainable Rural Development Program for the Southern Region - EMPRENDESUR. There is not a developed market for improved stoves. There are few cases of manufacturers that sell improved stoves to the general public.
It is unknown how many of the manufacturers have agreements with companies, governments or others.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A target of 0 is set for 2019 since there are no actions identified for 2019 that imply an adequate budgetary allocation by the government to promote the development of the improved stove market. On the other hand, it is expected that the promotion of improved stoves through the work of the platform and more cooperation with private sector will lead to more business in terms of more manufacturers or more contracts but it is uncertain the access of the program to this kind of information to measure this progress.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: A target of 0 was set for 2019, as the monitoring and measurement of this indicator is beyond the capabilities of CSOs to have access to this kind of information.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategies and advocacy plan of CSOs elaborated and being implemented</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of activity plans that organizations develop versus the number of CSOs involved</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="100%" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;The 2016 Activity Plan was formulated jointly with CSOs through workshops and face-to-face meetings, with the support of a consultant and SNV. Plans of activities for the year 2017 of both organizations are being prepared.
The activities plans for this year are focused on the Outcome A.  Some examples of actions to be carried out: socialization days of the program in strategic areas of the country and meetings to incorporate the program into its Institutional Plan.
The percentage 100% is the result of dividing the 2 plans of activities between the 2 organizations that participate in this topic = 2/2 = 1 * 100%&quot;</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="No">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">V4CP   Program will end in year 2020, so it is not expected to develop any action   plans for the coming year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: V4CP Program will end in year 2020, so it is not expected to develop any advocate plan for the coming year. CSOs are currently implementing their 2020 Action Plan.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the fourth quarter of 2018, the action plan for the year 2018 will be formulated jointly with CSOs. Through various workshops and face-to-face meetings with each member of CSOs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The 2019 Action Plans were formulated jointly with HdH and F. VIDA in face-to-face meetings and workshops with the support of SNV and the consultant that supported the process the previous years.
Some examples of actions that will be carried out in 2019 are: + Participate in the development of the proposal of a National Strategy for the adoption of improved stoves. + Develop actions of advocacy, lobbying and negotiation with decision makers for the approval of the National Strategy. + Lead, support and monitor the consulting teams in the development of the studies. + Promote and participate in actions that contribute to the consolidation of the inter-institutional platform for the value chain of improved stoves. + Develop actions to improve the relationship and collaboration with private, governmental actors and academics related to the implementation of improved stoves policies and strategies. + Participate in bilateral meetings with diverse actors such as CSOs, academic institutions, the public sector, the private sector and others, who identify themselves as possible allies to advocate for a National Strategy on Improved Stoves. Among these: manufacturers and suppliers of for improved stoves, academia: National Autonomous University of Honduras (UNAH), ZAMORANO, relevant actors such as the Global Alliance of Clean Cookstoves, SICA/CCAD, IDECOAS, GEMA, FHIS-Poder, PAHO, or other relevant actors. Join efforts with universities to hold forums on renewable energy and improved stoves.
The percentage of 100% is the result of dividing the 2 action plans between the 2 organizations that participate in this topic = 2/2 = 1 * 100%</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the third quarter of 2017, the plan of activities for the year 2018 would be formulated jointly with the CSOs. Through workshops and meetings with each of the CSOs members of the program to agree on actions.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-03-2018: &quot;The 2018 Action Plan was formulated jointly with CSOs through workshops and face-to-face meetings, with the support of a Consultant and SNV team.
The activities for this year will focus on lobbying and negotiating a consensual proposal among the stakeholders to achieve the approval of the strategy. This includes actions for the design and socialization of the proposal, national forums, lobbying activities, meetings with decision makers and other related activities. Once the National Strategy is approved, measures will be taken to guarantee its implementation and broad socialization through different means.

The percentage of 100% is the result of dividing the 2 action plans between the 2 organizations that participate in this topic = 2/2 = 1 * 100%&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the third and fourth quarter of 2019, CSOs are expected to drawn up their action plans, accompanied by a consultant and the SNV team. To define actions and allocate budget, a serie of mini workshops and individual meetings with each organization will take place.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: In the last quarter of 2019, the action plan of each CSO was formulated, taking into account the inputs of the Learning Event, V4CP 2020 Annual Plan and the 2020 Advocacy Plan. Meetings were held with each of the CSOs to define the actions that each of them would develop in 2020.
The action plan of each CSO was developed jointly between the CSOs, the SNV and an individual consultant who is an expert on RE-IS issue and has been leading this process since the program began. The main activities that CSOs will develop in 2020 are: Strengthen (institutionalization) the interinstitutional platform, Complete the National strategy for the adoption of improved stoves (ENAEM), Advocate for the approval of the national strategy ENAEM and influence the design of the action plan for the implementation of the ENAEM, Develop Regional events to present the ENAEM to local authorities and other relevant actors, Implement the communication strategy to disseminate evidences, sensitize main actors, general public to promote the adoption of improved stoves, and Develop the final measurement of community perception on access and quality of services provided by the government in the renewable energy and improve stove sector.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual advocacy plan formulated.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="yes" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;The advocacy plan was formulated jointly with the CSOs;  workshops were carried out for the formulation of it and the SNV with the support of a consultant fine-tuned the activities and finished the document that was sent to SNV Netherlands, in which the description of the problem is contemplated, also goal, context analysis, Theory of change, monitoring and evaluation, commitment strategy and activities and resources for 2017, outlook activities for 2018, assumptions, risks and mitigation.
The Advocacy Plan of Activities is based on each of the products and results that the program hopes to achieve, in an excel template that was elaborated and it contemplates the sub activities that are related to the activities set  in the word document of the RE Advocacy Plan. For 2017 it is expected to perform 17 major activities for Products: A, B and C and for Results: D, E, F.&quot;</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="No">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">V4CP Program will end in year 2020, so it is not expected to develop any   advocate plan for the coming year. However, advocacy efforts will focus on   monitoring an appropriate budget allocation and relocation from the   government to promote the development of an improved stove market. CSOs will   continue the advocacy on Energy and General Coordination Secretariats for the   approval of the Presidencial Decree for the sale tax exemption on improved   stoves, and also for the approval of the National Strategy ENAEM. Workshops   and meetings to strengthen the Interinstitutional Platform will continue as   well as the strengthening of links with Latin American networks.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: Given that the program is in its final phase, no annual advocacy plans will be drawn up for 2021. The 2020 plan is currently being executed. Efforts are focused on the socialization of ENAEM and advocacy actions for its approval. Systematization of experiences in both CSOs highlighting the process and learnings on evidence creation and use for advocacy in public policies as well as the institutional advocacy from the local to the national level. Promotion and communication campaign of the V4CP contributions to RE-IS sector. Advocacy to achieve tax exemption on improved stoves, for which an Ad hoc committee has been formed. A series of workshops are being held to strengthen the Interinstitutional Platform (IP) to work together on governance, internal regulations and action plan 2020-2021 as part of the actions for its sustainability. In the same sense, the CSOs formed a consortium and are jointly developing a Regional project proposal that seeks to continue with advocacy actions on public policies, based on evidence, scaling up V4CP to other countries (El Salvador and Guatemala, and adding other themes such as climate chang</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="yes">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;By the end of 2018, it is expected to draw up the 2019 advocacy plan jointly with  CSOs to send it to SNV Netherlands for review and approval.
Through workshops and meetings with each member of CSOs of the program to agree on actions.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The advocacy plan for 2019 was developed jointly with the CSOs taking in account CSOs inputs gathered in the  learning event and a serie of mini workshops. The process was facilitated by an individual consultant, who has been in the whole process since the program began. The document presents the 2019 main activities and their contributions to the products and outcomes stated in the RE- IS theory of change. The 2019 dvocacy plan focusses on:                                                                                                                      &#x2022; Strengthening the inter-institutional platform by attracting more relevant actors for advocacy.                                                                                            
&#x2022; Strengthening the capabilities (skills and knowledge) of partner CSOs to improve their influence in the inter-institutional platform. 
&#x2022; Links, alliances and coalitions at different levels with relevant actors (CSOs, academia, the private sector, research institutes, international entities) of the topic of improved stoves. 
&#x2022; Knowledge and exchange of good practices with other actors or processes.
&#x2022; The creation of consensus/conflict management and harmonization of the different interests in relation to the improved Stoves/for advocacy actions.                                          
&#x2022; Dissemination of evidence to enable partners to implement common strategies and approaches in the promotion of the adoption of improved stoves                                           
&#x2022; Planned, systematic and phased advocacy actions, based on public policy and strategy proposals. 
&#x2022; Carry out awareness-raising activities with messages on social networks, banners, threefoils, stickers, or other types of printed materials to be used in exchanges of experiences events with relevant actors.
The advocacy will focus on the following public stakeholders Forest Conservation Institute (ICF), MiAmbiente, Clima Plus, municipalities,  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="yes">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the middle of 2017, the advocacy plan for 2018 would be prepared in conjunction with the CSOs to be sent to SNV Netherlands for review and approval.
Through workshops and meetings with each of the CSOs members of the program to agree on actions.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-03-2018: &quot;Advocacy plan was formulated jointly with CSOs. Training workshops were held with the support of a consultant and SNV team. Learning workshop was relevant to analyze how we are and where we want to go, and adjust the activities according to the results of the analysis. The plan was completed in October and was sent to SNV Netherlands. The document includes summary of context analysis, contextualized theory of change, monitoring and evaluation, commitment strategy, plan of activities and resources for 2018, main actions planned for 2019, assumptions, risks and mitigation measures.
Advocacy Plan is based on products and results that the program expects to achieve in 201: 23 main activities focus on Products A, B and C and for Outcomes D, E, F, H, I and L.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="yes">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">By mid-2019, the 2020 advocacy plan will be prepared through workshops and meetings with CSOs, to be  submitted to SNV Netherlands for review and approval.

It is foreseen that by 2020 the actions of the advocacy plan will focus on the socialization and monitoring of the implementation of the national strategy in consensus with the CSOs interested in reducing the environmental health impacts caused by the use of the traditional stove, as well as contributing to mitigate the impacts of climate change. The development of awareness activities with messages on social networks, printed information such as banners, theefoils, stickers and others. Forums and training workshops on improved stoves, biomass and others.   as well as the measurement of the perception of quality and access to the RE services provided by the state.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: Based on inputs provided by the CSOs in the learning event and the meetings with each one of partner CSOs, the 2020 advocacy plan was formulated. The process was facilitated by SNV and an individual consultant, who has been accompanying these processes since the beginning of the program. The plan focus on the mid and long term outcomes of the ToC. The main actions are:

&#x2022; Strengthen (institutionalization) the interinstitutional platform:
&#x2022; Complete the National strategy for the adoption of improved stoves (ENAEM)
&#x2022; Advocate for the approval of the national strategy ENAEM and influence the design of the action plan for the implementation of the ENAEM
&#x2022; Develop Regional events to present the ENAEM to local authorities and other relevant actors
&#x2022; Implement the communication strategy to disseminate evidences, sensitize main actors, general public to promote the adoption of improved stoves

Advocacy will focus on the following Secretariats: Development and social inclusion SEDIS, Health SESAL, and Energy SEN. Also on the Forestry Conservancy Institute ICF, the Association of municipalities AMHON to provide support to the Environment Secretariat MiAmbiente for the approval of the ENAEM.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased participation of CSOs in the NAMA National Table of efficient stoves, the Honduran Organization for Standardization (HOS), El Zamorano Stoves Evaluation Center, UNAH or other coordination platforms and alliances with the public and private sector).</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of evidence based in knowledge / research products shared by CSOs with stakeholders.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the framework of the Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida program, it was shared the document Context Analysis on Renewable Energy through email to Fausto L&#xF3;pez / Senior Associated MIF - Inter-American Development Bank (IDB) on September 28, 2016.
To determine the 0.5 was counted the number of documents shared between the number of CSOs participating in the topic; this equals: 1/2</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that during the first semester 2 knowledge products will be developed that will be shared with various national actors: 1) Summary of the main conclusions of the studies as evidence to support CSO advocacy actions. 2) Final document of the National Strategy for Adoption of Improved Stoves.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: The target for the period was two research/knowledge products developed and shared with interested parties and three knowledge products were developed and shared;
1)	Final document of the National Strategy for the Adoption of Improved Stoves of Honduras (ENAEM) was completed, presented and socialized with the Interinstitutional Platform and the accompaniment of the Interinstitutional Technical Committee on Climate Change, and the National Mitigation Committee of Honduras. The following institutions participated: The National Directorate of Climate Change (DNCC) -MiAmbiente, Legal Department-MiAmbiente, Center for Studies and Control of Pollutants (CESSCO) -MiAmbiente, Forest Conservation Institute (ICF), Energy Secretariat (SEN), Fundaci&#xF3;n para el Desarrollo de la zona Sur (FUNDESUR), Ecofog&#xF3;n Honduras, Mirador Project, Global Brigades, Deutsche Gesellschaft f&#xFC;r Internationale Zusammenarbeit (GIZ), Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida, Hermandad de Honduras (HDH), Universidad Tecnol&#xF3;gica Centroamericana (UNITEC), Escuela Agricola Panamericana El Zamorano, United Nations (UN)/Environment, SNV, Independent Consultants.

A promotion and advocacy campaign in support of the approval and implementation of the ENAEM is being developed through social networks, videos, posters, brochures, and radio spots broadcast on community radio stations nationwide. Representatives of Environment, Health, and Energy Secretariats expressed their support to the ENAEM and to the advocacy campaign to get the approval of the ENAEM by the Interinstitutional Committee for Climate Change (ICCC),  

2)	An article on the launch of the ENAEM was published on the &#x201C;Clean Energy for All&#x201D; web page, a site dedicated to creating alliances for the promotion of renewable energy in Latin America and the Caribbean  https://energialimpiaparatodos.com/2020/06/16/presentan-estrategia-nacional-de-adopcion-de-estufas-mejoradas-en-honduras/                                                                               I ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the second semester two knowledge products will be elaborated, validated and shared with local and national actors with the support and accompaniment of expert consultants, CSOs and SNV:
1) Proposal of an Inclusive National Strategy for the Development of the Value Chain of Improved Stoves.
2) Socioeconomic Environmental analysis for a National Strategy for the Adoption of Improved Wood Stoves in Honduras.
 It is expected to continue the socialization of the results of the three studies generated in the first semester 2018.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The target established for this second semester of 2018 was to share 2 knowledge products and the result achieved is 5. The products and events that were carried out to share them are:
1) Educational series: Gender Focus in the value chain of improved stoves. Validation workshop in the southern area with community radio stations: Los Prados Nr. 2, Cadenas Network, Stereo Namasigue, Stereo Pespire, Radio Voces Aramecina, Radio Chulula, P.San  Juancito
2) Study Gender approach in the value chain of improved stoves. Event of the Inter-American Day of Air Quality, students of social and environmental sciences of the National Pedagogical University and other actors participated: PAHO, CESCCO, AIDIS, SESAL and MiAmbiente.
3) Measurement of the perception of the degree of Quality and Accessibility of Renewable Energy services - Improved stoves Honduras. Focus group workshops held in Yamaranguila, Intibuc&#xE1; - Namasigue, Choluteca - Aguanqueterique, La Paz. Community representatives and population from the communities of Cofrad&#xED;a, Las Lajas, Semane, Rinconada, Bonanza, El Chaguit&#xF3;n, El Obraje, Yorol&#xE1;n, Aguanqueterique, El Paque, Las Anonas, Llanos de Guarina, San Jos&#xE9;, El Guapinol, Pie la cuesta, La Calera, San Jose and Monte Crudo, El Bosque, El Carrizal and Las Lomitas, Nuevo Cedro, Poza Verde, Rancho Obispo, Bellavista, Casco Urbano, La Majada, Las Mesitas, Los Llanitos.
4) Educational series: Analysis of the Legal Framework of the Improved Stoves in Honduras. Inter-institutional Platform Meeting, with the participation of: UNAH, GIZ, consultants, Ecofog&#xF3;n de Honduras, CESSCO/Mi Ambiente, Energy and Health Secretariats, Mirador Project.
5) Social and Environmental study for a national strategy for the adoption of improved stoves in Honduras. Meetings with the Interinstitutional Platform, participated: Governmental Secretariats of: Health (SESAL), Energy (E), Agriculture (SAG/DICTA), and Environment (MiAmbiente/DNCC-CESCCO- ICF), CLIMA Plus. Universities: U ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the second semester two knowledge products will be elaborated, validated and shared with local and national actors with the support and accompaniment of expert consultants, CSO and SNV:
1) Intermediate measurement of the perception of the degree of Quality and Accessibility of Renewable Energy services - Ecostoves and Improved Stoves in Honduras. 
2) Feasibility of provision and commercialization of firewood prototypes as a source of renewable energy for improved stoves.
It is expected that the socialization of knowledge products developed in 2018 will continue. The main audiences for advocacy based on these reports are the authorities of DNCC/Mi Ambiente and Forestry Conservancy Institute ICF, as well as congressmen at national level, and local authorities. The secondary audience are the media, universities and regional authorities, and private sector. To reach them two regional symposiums will be developed, one in the north cost and the other in the central region where main finding of the research will be presented. Visits to high level authorities will take place and material will key messages will be distributed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The target planned for this first semester was 2 knowledge products shared with relevant stakeholders but partner CSOs shared 7 knowledge products in different events; lectures were made on some of the studies carried out by V4CP, such as:
1) Fiscal study: Impact on the exemption of sales tax on improved stoves and the import tax on sheets and other imported parts. Paper presented at the 3rd Forum of the Latin American and Caribbean Network of Clean Stoves (RLCCL). The advocacy has begun at the level of national authorities for the treatment of the tax issue such as: Visit to the Energy Secretariat to present the need for exemption from sales tax on the improved stoves, based on the main findings of the study. The Energy Secretariat is interested in the issue and indicated that it will review the energy policy and other legal instruments that they have to date to see if it is possible to annex the issue; otherwise they will analyse and identify the appropriate form to prepare the opinion for the exemption of the ISR. A meeting with the Presidential Officer for CLIMA Plus was also held in order to raise awareness about the issue. This study was also mentioned as relevant evidence to promote a regional fiscal policy initiative for improved stoves.
2) Socioeconomic &amp; Environmental Study for a National Strategy for Improved Stoves. Main findings of this study was presented at the 3rd Forum of the Latin American and Caribbean Network of Clean Stoves (RLCCL). It is also an important reference for the National Strategy for the Adoption of Improved Stoves ENAEM.
3) Cost-Benefit Analysis for the implementation of the ENAEM. Meeting with the Interinstitutional Platform to socialize progress of the consultancy. Meeting with the Director of the NDCC and two collaborators, in this meeting the leadership of the NDCC was agreed on the design of the ENAEM in coordination and with the support of the V4CP and the Interinstitutional Platform.
4) Gender Approach in the ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that by 2017 (4) knowledge/research products will be developed. The bi-annual target is (1) for the first semester and (3) for the second semester</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018: For the reporting period the target was set in one knowledge products to be share with two actors. In this case, one knowledge products was shared with four actors (4/2=2). 
Two workshops were developed to review and provide feedback to the legal framework study. The final version includes the feedback received and the doc was shared with national university UNAH, Zamorano, UNITEC; and Program for energy access - ENDEV/GIZ)
The second semester 2017, a pp presentation will be made to present the main findings of the study to local actors interested in the theme. The doc will be post in the V4CP webpage.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that in the first semester with the support of consultants, together with CSOs and the accompaniment of SNV, two knowledge products will be developed and shared with local and national actors:
1) The study on the Effect of the reduction / elimination of taxes on imports of metals and other imported parts used in clean kitchens.
2) The Gender Approach study in the Value Chain of Improved Stoves.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-11-2018: &quot;The target set for this first semester of 2018 was 2 knowledge products and the result reached is 3 studies which have been validated and socialized. The studies and the events that were carried out to share them are:
1) Study of the gender approach in the value chain of improved stoves, two events were carried out:
a) Workshop to validate the results of the gender focus study in the EM value chain. Hotel Plaza del General, Tegucigalpa; there were representatives of the private sector, government institutions, base community representatives/civil society such as: Ecofog&#xF3;n de Honduras, SESAL, Governance in Ecosystems, livelihoods and water -ERyP + L, National Directorate of Climate Change-DNCC/Mi Ambiente, patronages, women&apos;s network, Mirador Project, CESCO/My environment, SEDIS.
The presentation of the main findings of the study was made and participants reviewed and provided feedback on main findings such as adoption of stoves, What do women think?, links in the value chain and How is the participation of women?, Identify key messages for communication, Define Actions to promote gender focus in the field of improved stoves, and Define actions to promote gender focus in national strategy of improved stoves.
b) Interinstitutional platform meeting of the value chain of improved stoves. Participated institutes of knowledge, international cooperation, government institution, UNAH, GIZ, My Environment, UNACIFOR. The progress of the gender focus study was socialized and relevant contributions were received which have been incorporated into the document.
2) Popular version of the Legal Framework, evidence and content proposal of a National Strategy for the adoption of improved stoves.
a) Inter-institutional platform meeting of the value chain of improved stoves with participation of representatives of knowledge institutes, international cooperation, government institution, representatives of the UNAH, GIZ, My Environment, UNACIFOR. The popular version of  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the second semester 2017, two knowledge products will be shared by partner CSOs with four relevant actors.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-03-2018: &quot;The target set for reporting in the second semester was 4 knowledge products shared with local and national actors. Five knowledge products were shared in total, in the following events:
a) Technical meeting of the Environmental Unit and Municipal Office of Women, San Marcos, Ocotepeque;
b) Meetings with liders and technical specialists of the Liberal and National parties. Relevant information on FNS and RE was presented.
c)Talks on &quot;&quot;Challenges of FNS and RE in Honduras&quot;&quot;, with technical personnel, congress and presidential candidatel Christian Democratic Party-PDC, Liberal Party, Alliance Party, National Party, Tegucigalpa.
d) Meetings with representatives of political parties at regional and local level;
e) Meeting Members of the territorial table of Climate Change, La Labor Ocotepeque 
f) Workshop with representatives of Organizations that work on RE and FNS in Cop&#xE1;n, Lempira and Ocotepeque departments;
g) Meeting with representatives of rural savings Union of San Marcos Ocotepeque, UNIOSAM.

Interactive presentations were made, the information was highly appreciated by national, regional and local actors.
The knowledge products shared were:
1) Presentation on Renewable Energy Emphasis on Improved Stoves for the Fight against Poverty. CSO`s were in charged of the presentation. SNV provided support.
2) Measurement of the perception of the degree of Quality and Accessibility of Renewable Energy services - Improved stoves Honduras, a consultant was hired for its preparation with the support of CSOs and SNV. Result of the study presented by CSOs with support of SNV.
3) Analysis of the Legal Framework, Evidence and Content Proposal of a National Strategy for Ecostoves, a consultant was hired to prepare it with the support of CSOs and SNV.       
4) Report &quot;&quot;Analysis of three relevant documents for improved stoves NAMA&quot;&quot; requested by and presented to NDCC (National Directorate of Climate Chage) MiAmbiente. A consultant (Mirza Castro) was hired by HDH ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;The second semester of 2019, efforts of the program will focus on the participative design of the National Strategy, lobbying and advocacy actions for its approval. Progress in its development will be socialized in different events such as the Symposium that will be held in Tegucigalpa with decision makers.


CSOs will share the second semester the following knowledge products: 

1) National Strategy for the Adoption of Improved Stoves ENAEM in Honduras.
2) Feasibility Study on Provision and Marketing of firewood prototypes as a source of renewable energy for improved stoves.
3) Cost-Benefit Analysis for the implementation of the ENAEM in Honduras.
4) Measurement of the perception of quality and access to improved stoves services.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: The target for this indicator was to share 4 knowledge products and CSO shared 4 with different actors, and in different events:
1) &#x201C;Feasibility study on provision and marketing of firewood prototypes as a renewable energy source for improved stoves&#x201D;. i) Interinstitutional Platform meetings to socialize, get feedback and validate the results of the study, ii) Workshop with municipalities and the private sector, especially agroforestry cooperatives in which the study &#x201C;Feasibility of provision and marketing of firewood prototypes as a renewable energy source for improved stoves&#x201D; was presented. The main findings of the study are important reference/ inputs for the National Strategy-ENAEM.
2) &#x201C;First draft of the proposal National Strategy for the Adoption of Improved Stoves in Honduras ENAEM. i) Event &#x201C;Challenges of access to energy and its implications for food security. ii) Workshop with the Interinstitutional Platform to present the Draft of the ENAEM. It captured the interest of some actors to accompany and get involved in the process of elaboration of the ENAEM. The Director of Renewable energy of the Energy Secretariat SEN Said that the information shared can be included in the Secretariat information system that is being designed. The Coordinator of the area of risk management-Health Secretariat said that the studies supply reliable information, than can be useful for the Secretariat especially that the health issue is not perceive at first glance by users of firewood stoves. She is interested in getting more information about the variables and the questions used to compare with the tools they use to collect data, to improve the tools.
3) Cost-benefit analysis for the implementation of a National Strategy for the adoption of improved stoves. Interinstitutional Platform meetings to socialize, get feedback and validate the results of the study. Part of the data of this study was used in the analysis of the roadmap and scenarios of the proposal for  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of verbal interventions by CSOs at relevant meetings.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;In the same interventions mentioned above, Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida requested at the meeting of NAMA Coordination Table of Efficient Stoves for Hermandad de Honduras to be part of this coordination table, in turn Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida intervened to indicate improvements in the content of the normative.In the case of Hermandad de Honduras, it has not had verbal interventions in relevant meetings.
Only one CSO participated in 2 verbal interventions / 2 OSC =1</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organizations   will focus their efforts on long-term results. CSOs will continue their   verbal interventions, and expressing their opinions In the Interinstitutional   Platform and with other relevant actors. The advocacy efforts will focus on   the National Strategy ENAEM, completing, socializing the document and   influencing the political will of decision makers for the approval of the   ENAEM. There will be events of reflection and/or discussion and exchange of   knowledge with the key actors at national, regional and local levels. As part   of the closing actions of the program, a National Forum will be organized by   the CSOs to present the main contributions of V4CP to the energy sector in   Honduras and launch the Interinstitutional Platform as an advocacy spearhead   for the correct application of the National Strategy.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="10.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: A target of 5 verbal interventions by CSOs in relevant meetings was set. CSOs had 10 interventions in different events related to:
* Participation in workshops for the construction of the NAMA Concept Note of Improved Stoves. A series of contributions have been given on the subject of gap analysis, key factors of the NAMA of improved stoves-IS, climate change, gender and youth. Key elements to be considered by the NAMA to boost supply from IS. Installed capacity of the supply of improved stoves and established target and adoption rates. Discussions about technological innovation processes on the topic of IS. Key elements that the NAMA should consider driving the adoption of IS. Discussions on the role of financing for IS value chain development and key elements for the IS NAMA. Similarly, a series of contributions have been made to the documents generated by V4CP. Allan Mej&#xED;a, Representative of MiAmbiente Secretariat expressed: the national strategy ENAEM will be the umbrella where the NAMA of Improved Stoves will fit as it will regulate and coordinate the different actors of the sector such as academia, manufacturers, NGOs and others linked to the ENAEM, being the Natural Resources and Environment Secretariat responsible for registering NAMA initiatives in Honduras.
* Contributions made on different meetings held to complete the national strategy ENAEM proposal, promoted by V4CP program and led by the NDCC with technical support of the Interinstitutional Platform. In February, a workshop was held to validate and discuss the relevance of the ENAEM strategic guidelines. Meetings have been held with the consultancy coordination and monitoring committee made up of SNV, FV, NDCC/MiAmbiente, HDH and thematic specialists of IP, where the ENAEM document has been reviewed. The comments were sent to the consulting team and later virtual meetings were held to expand them.
* Webinar Ecological Stoves with members of the College of Environmental Engineers of Ho ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs in the second semester are expected to have greater intervention, since a series of actions have been established at the local and national levels. CSOs will work on building alliances at the local, regional and national levels. It is planned to carry out regional events and validation and advocacy events for the elaboration of the Improved Stoves Strategy; it is planned to implement actions from the dissemination and advocacy plan.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="12.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: A target of 10 verbal interventions was set, the CSOs together with the SNV had 12 interventions in different workshops and meetings with key actors. Presentations were made to promote and advocate for an inclusive National Strategy, the positioning of the topic of improved stoves and biomass, Gender focus in the value chain, Environmental Social Study. Knowledge was exchanged and issues related to the performance of the stoves and the use of biomass as fuel in a sustainable manner were discussed. A CSO was invited to make a presentation of the study &quot;Gender Approach in the Value Chain of Improved Stoves&quot; at the National Pedagogical University Francisco Moraz&#xE1;n (UPNFM). The presentation was part of the agenda to celebrate the Inter-American Air Quality Day to raise awareness among students and other stakeholders that participated such as: Pan American Health Organization (PAHO), CESCCO, Inter-American Association of Sanitary and Environmental Engineering (AIDIS), Secretariat of Health and My Environment.

The diverse relevant actors that have participated in the events are: Governmental Secretariats of: Health (SESAL), Energy (E), Agriculture (SAG/DICTA), and Environment (MiAmbiente/DNCC-CESCCO- ICF), CLIMA Plus. Universities: UNAH, Zamorano and UPNFM.  Programs and projects: GIZ/Procambio, ENDEV/GIZ, GEMA/DAI/USAID, Private sector: Hojalater&#xED;a Valle, ENVIROFIT, Mirador Project, Ecofog&#xF3;n de Honduras, E&#xB4;Copan. ONGs: National Organization for Rural Urban and Ecological Development -ORNADER, AHDESA, Caja Rural, and Community Radios.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the first semester, it is expected to launch the communication action plan to raise awareness, influence and position the issue of improved stoves and the importance of an Inclusive National Strategy. It is planned to have regional events to promote participation in the development of the National Strategy. Forums, Symposium on improved stove, biomass and other related issues. Focused on universities, government institutions, private sector and others. We will continue with the monitoring and validation of the studies that are necessary for the construction of the National Strategy, among other actions of lobbying and advocacy with targeted key actors and decision makers.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="10.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: The target for the first semester of the year 2019 is 5 interventions. CSOs managed to have 10 interventions in meetings with the Interinstitutional Platform, workshop with journalists and communicators, forums related to improved stoves, symposium, fair and tour. The interventions were focused on presentations made in the 3rd Forum of the Latin American and Caribbean Network of Clean Kitchens, where the presentation of the studies carried out by V4CP program was made. 1) Socioeconomic &amp; Environmental Study for a National Strategy for Improved Stoves. SNV, 2) Interinstitutional platform for the development of the value chain of EM-Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida. 3) Fiscal study: Impact on the exemption of sales tax on improved stoves and the import tax on sheets and other imported parts-Hermandad de Honduras. Participation in the closing panel, SNV. Presentations caught the interest of participants especially the fiscal study on impact of the exemption of sales taxes.

Other interventions were made on the viability of the institutionalization of the Interinstitutional Platform (IP). Participants commented on the important role the IP plays in the process of evidence generation, free discussion of different topics related to improved stoves, creating consensus and others. For most the IP should not have a legal status to perform these tasks and participation should be voluntary.
There was also a presentation, guided reading and training for the use of popular booklets on a) Gender Approach in the Value Chain of Improved Stoves and b) Legal Framework of Improved Stoves. An exhibition on different models of improved stoves was made, where benefits of adopting improved stove at homes were put upfront. Other interventions were made at the Symposium on improved stoves and biomass, key binomial to promote inclusive business in Honduras.

The participation in the Experts meeting of SICA countries, brought the IP and CSOs interventions to new scenarios, the Central American ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are expected to have 2 verbal interventions each in 2017. The bi-annual target will be that each CSO have (1) intervention during the first semester and (1) during the second semester of 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2018:  The target set for the first semester 2017 is 1 intervention per CSO and the achieved score is 6 (12 interventions/2 CSO). Partner CSOs and SNV officials had relevant interventions at different meetings in which V4CP and progress has been introduced, lobbing to establish liaison with relevant organizations has been done.
The interventions have been well received by local actors who expressed that find the V4CP relevant. As a result, an inter institutional platform to support the development of the clean cook stove value chain was created with the participation of seven organizations: Universities (national university UNAH, Zamorano, UNITEC), Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida, Hermandad de Honduras, program for energy access - GIZ (ENDEV/GIZ), and SNV.
Some of the organizations that have been represented in the events, where those interventions took place, are: Governmental national authorities (minister of MiAmbiente, vice minister of energy, director of climate change national office, presidential designated for climate change); Universities (national university UNAH, Zamorano, UNITEC); other international organizations and projects of interest (Global Alliance for Clean Cook stoves, Program for energy access - ENDEV/GIZ); municipal and regional authorities (municipal board and local leaders of Mercedes, Guisayote commonwealth); Dutch Embassy in Costa Rica (Desiree Hagenaars, first secretary).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs are expected to have greater intervention, since a series of actions have been established at the local and national levels.
We will work in the construction of alliances at municipal, regional and national level with the new actors of the renewable energy sector with emphasis on improved stoves.

The advocacy will focus on the following public stakeholders Forest Conservation Institute-ICF, MiAmbiente, Clima Plus, municipalities, Ministry of Agriculture and Livestock SAG / Dicta, Association of Municipalities of Honduras AMHON; and in private actors such as Foundation for Rural Business Development FUNDER, Honduran Association for the Development of Honduras -AHDESA, Foundation for the Development of the South- FUNDESUR, Foundation for the Integral Development of Honduras-FUNDEIH, Ecofog&#xF3;n Honduras.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="12.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-11-2018: The target set for the first semester was 6 verbal interventions, CSOs jointly with the SNV had 12 verbal interventions in different workshops, forum, field visits, and meetings with key actors. The interventions were aimed at generating opportunities for coordination and partnership with organizations/institutions working on the topic of Renewable Energy with emphasis on improved stoves. Presentations were made to promote and advocate for an inclusive National Strategy for Stoves, positioning the topics of improved stoves, gender focus in the value chain, promoting models of improved stoves, exchange knowledge and discuss issues related to the performance of stoves and the use of biomass as fuel in a sustainable manner. The national market for improved stoves and the Honduran regulation OHN 97001 have been encouraged. Important profile analyses have been carried out for the Improved Stoves Strategy and other documents and roadmap update.
Among the relevant actors that participated in the different events are: public sector (National Directorate of Climate Change/My Environment, Ministry of Health, Pollution Control and Study Center - CESCO/My environment, Secretariat of Social Inclusion - SEDIS, Municipal Technical Unit -UTI, National Electric Energy Company-ENEE, National Institute of Statistics INE); Private sector (Ecofog&#xF3;n de Honduras, Proyecto Mirador, small scale local producers of clean stoves), Civil Society (patronages, women&apos;s networks, COMUPUCA Foundation, Territorial Table of Climate Change, community representatives), programs and projects (Governance in Ecosystems, livelihoods and water -ER and P + L ), academy/knowledge institutes (National Autonomous University of Honduras-UNAH, National University of Forestry Sciences-UNACIFOR, El Zamorano), cooperation agencies (ENDEV-GIZ, Strategic Honduras-INVEST-H, CARE, World Vision, Creative Associates International, World Health Organization-WHO/Pan-American Health Organization-PAHO, Adventi ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The score for the reporting period is higher than the set target. For the second semester similar trend is expected giving the different meetings that will take place at local and national level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="12.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-03-2018: &quot;The target set for reporting in the second semester was 8. CSOs together with SNV had in the period 12 relevant verbal interventions in forums, meetings, talks to socialize the V4C program, raise awareness about the context, challenges, recent progress and proposals of alternative solutions in the topic of Renewable Energy focused on Improved Stoves, to influence the agenda of relevant actors. Presentation of the Legal Framework and Content Proposal Strategy for Improved Stoves. On Workshops and meetings on analysis and participatory construction of the Profile of the National Appropriate Mitigation Action (NAMA) of Improved Wood Stoves in Honduras.

A series of events had been established to generate awareness and establish relationships with relevant local actors. Processes of dialogue and consensus have been carried out with local actors to develop joint actions to advocate for a National Strategy for the Development of the Value Chain that massifies the adoption of improved stoves, biogas and others RE sources.

The meetings where the CSOs had interventions were the following:
a.   Discussion on improved stoves: The problem in the subject of RE was analyzed jointly with El Zamorano, ENDEV, SNV, Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida and Universidad nacional Aut&#xF3;noma de Ho  nduras UNAH.
b.  Tour of exchange of experiences in Nicaragua, the impact of biogas on the agricultural sector and the reduction of polluting emissions was announced, as well as the experience of &quot;&quot;prole&#xF1;a&quot;&quot; in the reforestation; stakeholders: Universidad Nacional Aut&#xF3;noma de Honduras - UNAH, Mi Ambiente, Instituto de Conservaci&#xF3;n Forestal (ICF), Secretar&#xED;a de Agricultura y Ganader&#xED;a (SAG), Federaci&#xF3;n Nacional de Agricultores y Ganaderos de Honduras (FENAGH).
c.   Follow-up Workshop on Agreements of the Exchange Tour to Nicaragua, Tegucigalpa, organized and developed by Mi Ambiente, Honduras: CSOs provided input for the generation of basic guidelines to prepare the profile of a potential National Bi ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Second semester CSOs are expected to continue expressing their opinions and statements on improved stoves in the Interinstitutional Platform and with other relevant actors in meetings and other actions to advocate for the participative design and validation of the National Strategy for the Adoption of Improved Stoves ENAEM. Greater emphasis will be placed on this process. As part of the implementation of the communication plan, a symposium that target decision makers to generate the political will for the approval of the ENAEM will be developed in the capital city.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="11.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: The target for the second semester was 9 interventions. The CSOs managed to have 11 interventions in meetings with the Interinstitutional Platform, World Bank, UN Environment, DNCC, and University El Zamorano. The interventions were related to:
&#x2022; Meetings with the World Bank (WB) mission to analyze the context and get agreements on the process of review of the Nationally Determined Contribution (NDC), especially the one related to the reduction of firewood consumption by 39% as one of the commitments assumed by Honduras. The close relationship of this NDC with other initiatives in the country such as the National Strategy ENAEM and The NAMA for efficient stoves which concept note is being develop by SNV/DNCC, was stated by V4CP. As a result, the 3 main parties (WB-UN Environment-V4CP/SNV) agreed to work these topics in close coordination with the Interinstitutional Platform (IP). They also agreed to have joint workshops for the development of the thee processes: ENAEM, Concept Note of the NAMA-Nationally Appropriate Mitigation Action and the NDCs.
&#x2022; Meetings with the Interinstitutional Platform (IP) where the roadmap that ECLAC socialized at the Expert Meeting on universal access to modern fuels for cooking food in the ECLAC countries was presented: Proposed of Action Plan for Guatemala, Honduras and Nicaragua. For the ECLAC event, CSOs/V4CP provided the technical assistant and accompaniment to government entities such as Health and Energy Secretariats, and to ICF in preparing the Honduras presentation. Analysis of the roadmap and country scenario presented by the Central American Integration System ECLAC in their proposal &#x201C;transition from the use of traditional stoves to LPG gas stoves&#x201D;, inputs from the Cost-Benefit Analysis and other V4CP studies were used to support the arguments in favor of the adjustment proposed especially for the Honduran scenario. The document was presented to the Energy Secretariat as formal channel to ECLAC.
&#x2022; Meeting with ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of formal and informal CSO meetings with government and / or private sector, international scenarios, academia (universities), clean kitchen alliances and platforms.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="3" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;The most relevant meetings that one CSO has participated in this year have been: First meeting of NAMA Coordination Table of Efficient Stoves, Second Meeting of NAMA Coordinating Table of Efficient Stoves, Review and discussion of draft Standard For Improved Stoves. In the case of the other CSO, has indicated that in this topic it has not had participation in any relevant meeting.
The main stakeholders represented in the meetings were: Climate Change and Environment Division, Honduran Standardization Agency, public sector institutions such as: Ministry of Agriculture and Livestock, academy such as: Agricultural School Zamorano, Civil Society Organizations and International cooperation.
Only one CSO participated in 3 meetings / 2 CSOs participating = 1.5&quot;</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A   series of workshops and meetings to complete and validate the proposal of   National Strategy for the adoption of improved stoves (ENAEM).   Interinstitutional Platform meetings and other advocacy actions in support of   the ENAEM. The partner CSOs will continue the implementation of the   Communication Plan to raise awareness through different media; lobbying and   advocacy meetings with government entities, especially with the Ministry of   Energy to follow up on the issue of tax exemption for improved stoves and   with the DNCC for the approval of the ENAEM; Regional events to present the   ENAEM to local authorities and other relevant actors.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="17.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: The target of this indicator was 10 events. CSOs organized and participated in 17 formal and informal meetings related to improved stoves. Some of the events are detailed:
* Sector Evaluation and Gap Analysis of the Improved Stoves sector in view of the design of the Concept Note of the NAMA for Honduras. Representatives from the public and private sectors, NGOs and international cooperation participated.
* Virtual meetings for the construction of the Concept Note for improved stoves (IS). Introduction to the NAMA concept note. Basic information, goals and co-benefits of the NAMA. Review of the IS Offer/IS NAMA. IS Technology/NAMA Review. IS/NAMA demand review. Review of the financing component.
* Bilateral meeting to review and estimate the target or volume of improved stoves to be adopted under the NAMA, based on previous experiences. Participation of FV, SNV and Mirador Project.
* Presentation and Socialization of the National Strategy for the Adoption of Improved Stoves (virtual), an event jointly organized by Hermandad de Honduras (HDH), SNV, Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida (FV), National Directorate of Climate Change (DNCC/MiAmbiente), Interinstitutional Technical Committee on Climate Change and the National Mitigation Committee of Honduras. The welcome was made by the Director of the National Directorate of Climate Change (DNCC/MiAmbiente) in representation of the MiAmbiente Secretariat Minister. 44 participants representing public and private sector, NGOs, Knowledge Institutes, international cooperation, independent specialists and civil society participated.
* Meetings to complete the National Strategy ENAEM and preparatory meeting with the Director and technical staff of the NDCC to coordinate bilateral support for the presentation and socialization of the ENAEM. Participants from Hermandad de Honduras (HDH), SNV, Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida (FV), National Directorate of Climate Change (DNCC/MiAmbiente), and El Zamorano.
* Ecological Stoves Webinar facilitated by the C ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="18">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the second semester actions will be carried out by the CSOs to continue the strengthening of the Inter-institutional Platform to improve coordination and collaboration and its level of influence. It is also expected to have greater communication and influence with the public and private sectors as advocacy actions will be developed with key actors, and workshops for the participative construction of a National Strategy Proposal for Improved Stoves will be developed. Promotion of the National Strategy in different spaces and media.
Socialize and share the studies with key and relevant actors and execute a communication strategy to position the agenda of the program in
different spaces and media.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="20.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: A target of 18 events was established for this indicator. During the second semester a total of 20 was reached. Meetings, field visits and workshops were held to position the theme of RE- Improved Stoves in the agendas of different actors, as well as lobbying actions to build strategic alliances and consensus on the importance of a National Strategy and its table of contend. Some of the events are described below:
* Meetings with the Interinstitutional Platform to socialize and validate the Fiscal Study and the Educational series: Analysis of the legal framework for improved stoves in Honduras. Presentation of progress reports of the social and environmental study. Among the participants were: Governmental Secretariats of: Health (SESAL), Energy (E), Agriculture (SAG/DICTA), and Environment (MiAmbiente/DNCC-CESCCO- ICF). Universities: UNAH, Zamorano and UPNFM.   Programs and projects: GIZ/Procambio, ENDEV/GIZ, GEMA/DAI/USAID, Private sector: Hojalater&#xED;a Valle, ENVIROFIT, Mirador Project, Ecofog&#xF3;n de Honduras. ONGs: National Organization for Rural Urban and Ecological Development  -ORNADER, AHDESA, Caja Rural.
* Workshops were held to collect information and validate the studies. Among the participants were: Clima plus, Envirofit, E&apos;Copan, Mirador Project, Hojalateria Valle, FUNDER, ICF and UNAH.
* Field tour of a CSO to learn about new models of improved stoves and analyse the possibility of an alliance and future business relationships; Sonsonate, El Salvador and socialization meeting of initiatives with improved stoves to promote the stove market with the support of the V4CP program to Grupo Jaremar staff in San Alejo Community, Tela.
* Workshop for the validation of educational series of the study Focusing on Gender. Done in the south region with the participation of community radios: Los Prados Nr. 2, Cadenas Network, Stereo Namasigue, Stereo Pespire, Radio Voces Aramecina, Radio Chulula, P.San  Juancito.
* Participation in the event to celebrat ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the first semester, it is expected that a series of actions will be done to continue with the strengthening of the Inter-institutional Platform, attracting more relevant actors for the advocacy. Consensus building/Conflict management and harmonization of different interests in relation to improved stoves. The National Strategy will be promoted by different means. Implementation of the communication plan which includes the socialization of main findings of the studies with key and relevant stakeholders; key messages in social networks, printed information such as banners, threfoils, stickers, or other types to raise awareness on the subject. Meetings, exchanges of experiences and Symposium/forums/workshops with relevant actors.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="17.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: &quot;The target for the first semester of the year 2019 is 10 meetings. CSOs managed to organize and participate in 17 formal and informal meetings to present progress made in the topic of improved stoves and biomass at national and international level, some of the events are described:
1) 3rd Forum of the Latin American and Caribbean Network of Clean Kitchens. 2) Reflection with the interinstitutional Platform on current role of the platform and its future. 3) Meeting of the Interinstitutional Platform to present and analyse draft reports on V4CP consultancy services. 4) Media Training in the Western region of Honduras. Influencers / generators of opinion were trained on the use of knowledge products generated by V4CP Program. Participants were journalists and representatives of local radio stations such as: National Television Authority-ATN TV, San Marcos TV, Radio LEMPIRA, Mundovisi&#xF3;n and H&#xE1;bitat para la Humanidad. 5) San Marcos de Ocotepeque gastronomic fair, with the participation of local governments, micro-enterprises, users of improved stoves. 6) Symposium on improved stoves and biomass, key binomial to promote inclusive business in Honduras. V4CP joined efforts for this strategic action with the Atlantic Coast Centre of the National University (CURLA-UNAH) and the Ceibe&#xF1;a Cooperative. Local authorities, private sector, NGO`s and 50 students participated. 7) Interinstitutional Platform Meeting to define its position before the World Health Organization (WHO) initiative for a regional clean stove evaluation standard and a fiscal policy, as well as LPG promotion. 8) Visit of partner CSO Hermandad de Honduras (HDH) to &quot;&quot;Perfection Group&quot;&quot; a producer of clean stoves in Costa Rica, to explore the possibility to increase the supply of models of cooking technologies in HDH, by mean of an alliance based on inclusive business approach, as part of the sustainability strategy of HDH.  It was accompanied by PROCAMBIO/GIZ. 9) Meeting with Director of the Sec ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the first quarter it is expected to have meetings with the new national and municipal authorities in partner CSO`s regions. Meetings with the inter-institutional Platform to search for synergies and joint work.

National forums, lobbying activities, meetings with decision makers and other related activities have been scheduled; with the purpose of lobbying and negotiating a consensual proposal among the interested parties to achieve the approval of the strategy. This includes actions for the design and socialization of it.

For the second semester, it is expected to continue with several meetings with key actors to strenghten  relationships and to search for synergies and construction of political agendas.                        Products or reserch will be shared with key actors and target audience.
.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="23.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-11-2018: The target set for this first semester of 2018 was 12 events and the result reached is 23 events. Result higher than expected due to a series of meetings, discussions, fairs, field visits, and workshops to position the subject of RE in the agendas of different actors, advocacy and lobby to build strategic alliances and consensus on a proposal for a National Strategy for Adoption of Improved Stoves. Events for validation and monitoring of the studies generated by the program were organized such as: Gender Approach Study, Study of the Impact of the Exoneration of the Tax on Sale and a popular version of the Legal Framework; revision of evidence needed for the content of the National Strategy for the adoption of stoves. Additionally, a series of events were held to strengthen the capacity of CSOs, such as: Induction Workshop for the new CSO`s technical liaisons and administrative staff. As part of 2018 operative strategy, the figure of CSO technical liaison was introduced in each partner CSO (paid by the program) to support the executive directors to implement the action and advocacy plans. Peer-to-peer workshops were initiated for CSOs to strengthen the capacities of other CSOs in their thematic areas of expertise, the workshop was on: Climate Change. A workshop to prioritize the communication products for 2018 and define the role of the new CSO`s technical liaisons in the communication strategy was held in April.
All the events have been formal. The most relevant are described below:
* Workshops to validate the results of the studies with representatives of public and private sector, civil society, related projects and programs such as: Ministry of Health - SESAL, National Directorate of Climate Change-DNCC / Mi Ambiente, Pollutant Control and Study Center - CESCO/My environment, Secretariat of Social Inclusion &#x2013; SEDIS; Ecofog&#xF3;n de Honduras, Mirador Project, and small scale  local producers of clean stoves; grassroots organizations (patronatos water  ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is expected that by 2017 CSOs can participate in at least 4 meetings, forums or meetings each. The bi-annual target will be that each CSO participate in 2 meetings during the first semester and in 2 during the second semester of 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="15.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-03-2018: The target set for the first semester 2017 is 2 and the achieved score is 7.5 (15 meetings/2 CSO). Contrary to expectations, the electoral process to elect municipal and national authorities has awakened the interest on CSO and V4CP themes. On the other hand, V4CP has organized a series of workshops and meetings with RE authorities and other actors of interest, given the increased interest of CSO to participate in those events.
All events have been formal meetings and workshops. The main events are listed below:
1. Workshops to review and provide feedback to the study on Legal framework analysis and outline for a national strategy for clean cook stoves.
2. Meetings with authorities of the Secretary MiAmbiente: Minister of MiAmbiente, Vice minister of Energy, and General Director of National office for climate change DNCC. 
3. Meetings with representatives of the National University UNAH; Zamorano University, Fundaci&#xF3;n Vida board; Program for energy access - GIZ (ENDEV/GIZ), Hermandad de Honduras board.
4.  Participation in forum: Launch of OHN 97001: 2017 normative &#x201C;Improved cook stoves- requirements and test methods for classification and categorization.
5. Meeting with the Presidential Designated for climate change, Marlon Escoto, to inform about the V4CP and explore opportunities for coordination and collaboration in both themes: FNS and RE.
6. First meeting of the inter institutional platform to support the development of the clean cook stove value chain. With the participation of Richard Grinnell from the Global Alliance for Clean Cook stoves (GACC)
7. Meeting of partner CSO with representatives of Guisayote commonwealth to introduce V4CP and progress
8. Meeting with municipal board and local leaders of Mercedes
9. Meetings to exchange experiences between a partner CSO, National University and Micro finance organization
10. Meetings between partner CSOs to exchange information and knowledge.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the second semester of 2017, the CSOs will be lobbing to have meetings with representatives of main political parties at municipal and national level to advocate for the FNS and RE themes to be included in their proposals for national agendas. 
Meetings to follow up main actors reached in the first semester and workshops to share knowledge products, information and leanings will also take place in the second semester 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="22.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-03-2018: &quot;The target established for the second semester of 2017 was 12 events and the reached result is 22 events. This score results from the adjustment of the measurement method made by SNV Netherlands.
The result achieved is higher than expected due to the political election year and strategy define by the V4CP. A series of meetings, forums and discussions were held to position FSN and RE issue in agendas of candidates for popular election. V4CP also organized a series of consultation days, workshops and meetings with the authorities related to the subject and other stakeholders. All events have been formal, described below:
1) Meetings with the representatives of the main political parties at the municipal and national levels, Liberal Party (Liberal), Innovation and Unity Party (PINU), Christian Democratic Party (DC), Freedom and Refoundation Party (LIBRE) and National Party (Nacional) to advocate for the inclusion of FSN and RE issues as a priority in their national agendas.
2)Talks and Political Forums at the municipal and national level &quot;&quot;Challenges of FSN and RE in Honduras&quot;&quot; with technical personnel, congressmen and mayor candidates and also at the presidential level.
3) Interinstitutional Platform of Improved Stoves with participation: Secretaries of State (Secretary of Agriculture and Livestock-SAG, Institute of Forest Conservation-ICF, Environment -MiAmbiente), Universities (Pan-American Agricultural School El Zamorano, National Autonomous University of Honduras UNAH, Technological Central American University-UNITEC, National University of Forestry Sciences -UNACIFOR), Civil society organizations (HDH, F. VIDA), support agencies, programs and projects (SNV, Energy Access Program - GIZ (ENDEV / GIZ)
4) Exchange tours Nicaragua and El Salvador members of the Interinstitutional Platform for Improved Stoves.
5) Meetings of the Interinstitutional Platform for Improved Stoves for participatory analysis and design of the NAMA pofile (National Appropria ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;For the second semester of 2019, CSOs are expected to participate in different workshops for the participative design, socialization and validation of the National Strategy for the Adoption of Improved Stoves  (ENAEM). In addition, the Interinstitutional Platform will have meetings and develop other support actions for the National Strategy (ENAEM).
V4CP Partner CSOs will continue implementing the Communication Plan for the promotion of the participative design of the National Strategy; lobby meetings and advocacy with government entities, especially with the Energy Secretariat to follow up the issue of tax exemption for improved stoves; exchanges of experiences and Symposium / forums / workshops with relevant actors and bilateral meetings with potential partners for the implementation of a National Strategy.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="21.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: The target for this indicator is 20, CSOs organized and participated in 21 formal and informal events. Some of the events are listed below:
&#x2022; Meetings with the Interinstitutional Platform: for validation of the cost-benefit study; presentation of the methodology for the design of the proposal of the National Strategy ENAEM; analysis of the roadmap and country scenario presented by the Central American Integration System ECLAC in their proposal &#x201C;transition from the use of traditional stoves to LPG gas stoves&#x201D;. In those meetings participated representatives of the National Directorate of Climate Change (DNCC), Energizing Development (EnDev)/Deutsche Gesellschaft f&#xFC;r Internationale Zusammenarbeit (GIZ), Pan American Health Organization (PAHO), University Zamorano, Secretariat of Health, Forest Conservation Institute (ICF),  Enterprise Honduras Eco Stove and the Secretariat of Energy, among others.
&#x2022; Central American and Caribbean Events: Honduras presentation at the meeting of experts-Universalization of access to fuels Food cooking systems in ECLAC countries. Antigua, Guatemala June 20-21, 2019
&#x2022; Meetings with the Ministry of Energy (SEN) to socialize what was discussed and analysed with the members of the interinstitutional Platform on the ECLAC roadmap and countries scenarios.  Adjustments to the proposal were made and sent to consideration of the Energy Secretariat which accepted and included part of them to its official comments to the proposal sent to ECLAC on &#x201C;transition from the use of traditional stoves to LPG Gas stoves&#x201D; proposal.
&#x2022; Meetings with representatives of the World Bank to review and analyse possible adjustment to the Nationally Determined Contribution (NDC) assumed by the state of Honduras, especially those related to the reduction of firewood consumption by 39% by using efficient stoves. Those meetings were facilitated by the international consultant hired by WB and PNUD. Participation of DNCC, UN Environment, University Zamorano, ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="tbc"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased commitment and willingness to develop an enabling and inclusive strategy for the installment of improved stoves.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of politicians/decision-makers that show higher support to the development of an inclusive strategy.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The   advocacy efforts will focus on the Government Secretariats such as   Development and Social Inclusion (SEDIS), Energy (SEN), and Health (SESAL)   and the Forest Conservation Institute to support the Secretariat of My   Environment in the development and approval of the National Strategy. It is   expected that despite the constant turnover of personnel that are frequent in   the state authorities, the evaluated actors that have shown interest and have   made commitments continue in their functions and continue as allies promoting   the approval and implementation of the ENAEM.
     In addition, it is expected to have a higher level of commitment from   private sector actors so that they also promote the development, approval and   implementation and sustainability of the ENAEM.
 

    Individual meetings (breakfasts, lunches, among others) will be held with   relevant decision-making actors, also at meetings of the Platform and other   related spaces, to raise awareness among decision makers, the private sector,   government sector and universities on approval and implementation of the   ENAEM.
 

    CSOs will continue the strategy of approaching high level officers of   related Secretariats. They set as a target the Ministers of different   Secretariat of State as they are part of the Council of Ministers that   approves the PCM executive decrees to obtain the approval of the ENAEM and   the Sale Tax Exception for improved stoves and their parts.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-11-2020: The target for this indicator is 1, the CSOs identified and evaluated 2 political leaders and/or decision makers who have demonstrated support for the V4CP program and the actions that have been carried out on the issue of improved stoves.

The CSOs evaluated NDCC/Mi Ambiente they consider that he is a supportive person. He has participated in different meetings for the National Strategy and expressed that &quot;the construction of the ENAEM is a reflection of the necessary interinstitutional coordination in the country and it will be the umbrella of the NAMA of improved stoves that will fit, complying with the commitments that the country has in the climate agenda. NDCC and MiAmbiente Secretariat join the process of design of the ENAEM and invite each key actor to join the effort and to support the national strategy&quot;. He is an extremely influential person and has been evaluated as a trustworthy person since he has clearly shown support for the approval of the ENAEM, agreements have been reached that are fulfilled at predefined times and he has accompanied the process from the beginning.
Energy Secretary, evaluated as a supportive person, has assigned a person to follow up on the construction of the ENAEM, she remains informed and willing to support its approval. She reiterates his commitment in events, also communicated it to V4CP program &quot;it is of special satisfaction for the SEN to be part of such relevant initiatives as the Interinstitutional Platform that with the support of the SNV, is developing the concept note of the NAMA and with the support of the V4CP program has managed to culminate the participatory development process of ENAEM&quot; as SEN, we agree on the appreciation of the IP, the exemption of 15% of Sales Tax on improved stoves would expand access and adoption by families , especially of families living in poverty, thereby contributing to the improvement of health, quality of life and family economy. It would also contribute to the fulfilme ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">07-10-2019: In 2018, the target of 1 set for this indicator was achieved. General Director of the National Directorate of Climate Change/MiAmbiente is identified as a person who has demonstrated support to V4CP initiatives, especially at the end of 2018.
The CSOs valued this actor as a supportive actor since: he facilitated processes, helped to open doors in other governmental entities and other areas of MiAmbiente. He reacted and accompanied when he had been asked for support. He has shown support because he talks about the subject and has been encouraging and supporting the theme. He has defended and recognized to others the work that is being done by V4CP, especially in the Inter-institutional Platform. He has relied on the platform to analyse reports related to the governmental NAMA done by international organizations, and has also relied on the information generated by V4CP. He supported the platform initiative and registered in the NAMA Facility the profile of the National Strategy for Efficient Stoves. He made phone calls to reach other stakeholders and has expressed interest in the national strategy through emails and talks. There are exchanges of information because he trust the professionalism of the actors involved. He has also informed the Minister about the actions of the platform and the V4CP program.
He is an influential person because he has a domain or thematic management related to the topic of improved stoves, he is a member of a key committee/work group, and has a relevant position in the structure.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-03-2018: confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">confidential</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">27-04-2020: The target for this indicator is 1. CSOs identified and evaluated 3 influential actors who have supported the actions of the program: Director of the National Directorate of Climate Change/My Environment, Director of Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency/Energy Secretariat (SEN), Coordinator of the Risk Management area/Health Secretariat.

The evaluation conducted by CSOs applying the Policy Creation Qualification Tool have the following results: Person 1 the CSOs consider that he is a supportive person who is interested in continue the promotion of the ENAEM and its connection with the NAMA of Efficient Stoves. He requested information on the ENAEM progress to be able to share it at the UN Conference on Climate Change, COP25 held in Madrid in the month of December 2019. He is an influential person. Learnt about the subject, has accompanied the actions of the program and has participated actively in the Interinstitutional Platform and accompanied from the beginning the construction of the ENAEM. He has been valued as a reliable person since his career is known, he has maintained a high level of communication and cooperation with the V4CP program.
Person 2 is evaluated as a person not very supportive. Only in the meetings of the Interinstitutional Platform has expressed the interest of the to support and promote the ENAEM. However, she has not assumed a formal commitment to lead or accompany the approval process. Is considered part of the Platform and with the interest of continuing to promote the ENAEM, they have invited the Platform to be part of thematic discussions and has opened up that the positioning of the Platform regarding the Roadmap prepared by SICA is presented; The information was received, but the decisions taken by the Secretariat regarding this topic has not been communicated officially. V4CP had access to a new version of the draft document and it shows that the main part of the statement was included that is the part related to pr ...</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
