<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12745A0301-COL-31320</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National -Lund-KTH Univ -Sust fishing in Colombia Open Innovation- 2020-2023</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">National -Lund-KTH Univ-H&#xE5;llbart fiske genom &#xD6;ppen Innovation Colombia 2020-2023</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The general objective of the contribution is &#x201C;to strength and develop communitarian ecosystem capabilities and self-efficacy by designing a sustainable fishing model under open innovation and co-creation methodologies that contributes to reducing the environmental and economic impact generated by the current fossil fuel system&#x201D;.
It is expected that through the development of this project, a more dynamic economy and greater investment from the private and public sectors will lead, in the long term, to an improvement in the quality of life for people living in the municipality of Guapi. It is also expected to stimulate other related initiatives that contribute to the development of artisanal fishing in sustainable terms, such as&#xA0;tourism.
The specific proposed outputs are
-To develop a sustainable model associated with to the artisanal fishing value chain in Guapi through identifying socioeconomic and environmental factors of the ecosystem.
-To design and build a boat powered by renewable and hybrid energies in coordination with the designed sustainable fishing model.
-&#xA0;To propose a business plan in coordination with social entrepreneurships, strengthening the proposed sustainable fishing model.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsens &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att &quot;st&#xE4;rka och utveckla lokalsamh&#xE4;llets gemensamma kapacitet och egenf&#xF6;rm&#xE5;ga f&#xF6;r ekosystem genom utformningen av en h&#xE5;llbar fiskerimodell, med st&#xF6;d av innovation och medskapande metoder f&#xF6;r minskning av milj&#xF6;- och ekonomisk p&#xE5;verkan som det nuvarande systemet f&#xF6;r fossila br&#xE4;nslen ger upphov till&quot;. Det svenska bidraget p&#xE5; 6 110 000 SEK delas upp enligt f&#xF6;ljande: 5 600 000 SEK till Colombias nationella universitet (UNAL), 270 000 SEK till Lunds universitet och 240 000 SEK till KTH, Kungliga Tekniska H&#xF6;gskolan.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The general objective of the contribution is &#x201C;to strengthen and develop communitarian ecosystem capabilities and self-efficacy by designing a sustainable fishing model under open innovation and co-creation methodologies that contributes to reducing the environmental and economic impact generated by the current fossil fuel system&#x201D;.  The Swedish contribution of 6,110,000 SEK will be divided as follows: 5,600,000 SEK for the National University of Colombia (UNAL), 270,000 SEK for Lund University and 240,000 SEK for KTH, the Royal Institute of Technology.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KTH/Kungliga Tekniska H&#xF6;gskolan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KTH/Kungliga Tekniska H&#xF6;gskolan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="31320" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fishery development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="313" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fishing</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="14.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">14.4 - By 2020, effectively regulate harvesting and end overfishing, illegal, unreported and unregulated fishing and destructive fishing practices and implement science-based management plans, in order to restore fish stocks in the shortest time feasible, at least to levels that can produce maximum sustainable yield as determined by their biological characteristics.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">14.4 - Senast 2020 inf&#xF6;ra en effektiv f&#xE5;ngstreglering och stoppa &#xF6;verfiske, olagligt, orapporterat och oreglerat fiske liksom destruktiva fiskemetoder samt genomf&#xF6;ra vetenskapligt baserade f&#xF6;rvaltningsplaner i syfte att &#xE5;terst&#xE4;lla fiskbest&#xE5;nden s&#xE5; snabbt som m&#xF6;jligt, &#xE5;tminstone till de niv&#xE5;er som kan producera maximalt h&#xE5;llbart uttag, fastst&#xE4;llt utifr&#xE5;n deras biologiska egenskaper.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="7.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">7.a - By 2030, enhance international cooperation to facilitate access to clean energy research and technology, including renewable energy, energy efficiency and advanced and cleaner fossil-fuel technology, and promote investment in energy infrastructure and clean energy technology.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">7.a - Till 2030 st&#xE4;rka det internationella samarbetet f&#xF6;r att underl&#xE4;tta tillg&#xE5;ng till forskning och teknik inom ren energi, inklusive f&#xF6;rnybar energi, energieffektivitet samt avancerad och renare fossilbr&#xE4;nslebaserad teknik, samt fr&#xE4;mja investeringar i energiinfrastruktur och ren energiteknik.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">13029.7403824229</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">13029.7403824229</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-01">13029.740382</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">13029.7403824229</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/12745_SIDA-KTH-signedbothparties.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreeement KTH - PPDP Sustainable fishing through open innovation</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/12745_SignedagreementULund.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreeement Lund University- PPDP Sustainable fishing through open innovation</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/12745_SignedGrantagreementUN.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement- PPDP Sustainable fishing through open innovation</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/12745_SignedDecisiononContribution&amp;appraisalofintervention(12745).pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution- 12745-  PPDP Sustainable fishing through open innovation</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2021 the whole academic team was hired and three field trips were undertaken to develop the first outcome of developing a sustainable model linked to the artisanal fishing value chain in Guapi. The main activities in partnership with the participants fishing organizations for diagnosis of the socioeconomic and biological condition of fishing activity in Guapi and the analysis of the fishing value chain were developed. The social team conducted a gender analysis, to understand the role of women in the artisanal fishing activities.

For the second outcome of designing and building a boat powered by renewable and hybrid energies linked to the designed sustainable fishing model UNAL could only complete the workshop that focused on design thinking. The design team has, in cooperation with the communities and based on social cartography, created a logotype of the project that could also be used by the associations in the future. The engineering team prepared a complete report on the energy generation alternatives for the boat, hybrid solutions and proposed preliminary social, economic and technical criteria for choosing the best solution.
None of the activities for the third outcome of proposing a business plan linked to social entrepreneurships were implemented during the first year but the plan is to develop them in the second half of 2022.

In addition, as part of the Bogota International Bookfair, where Sweden was the guest of honour, this project was presented in a virtual event on August the 20th, 2021. Catalina Hoyos from the Embassy moderated the panel discussion where Professors Katarina Larssen from KTH, Marie L&#xF6;wegren from Lund University, Diana Lopez from the National University (UNAL), and Sebastian Loango, Representative of the Renacer Guapire&#xF1;o Association presented the projects goals, results, challenges and their different roles as a good example of triple helix and open innovation. Here is a link to the published material from KTH: https://www.kth.se/philhist/historia/kalender/webinar-co-creation-in-t

The Embassy&apos;s assessment is that use of the participatory approach was an important element of the open innovation and co-creation perspectives, as well as the promotion of participant communities and the academic teams ownership. The design team included didactic communication elements for the common understanding of the project objectives that emphasized the teamwork, creativity, common learning process and common leadership. During the second half of the year, the Embassy also participated in 8 virtual meetings where the different academic teams presented their progress on: gender issues; ethnography; oceanography and the environment; design; value chain; and design and power system of the boat. Hence, the first year has been useful to
consolidate the team with common recognition of the contributions from different disciplines as well as from the traditional fishing practices.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12745" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1050203" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1176000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Colombia 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Colombia 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
