<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-14405A0101-COL-72010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam GB - HUM 2021-2025</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Oxfam GB - HUM 2021-2025</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen &#xE4;r en del av ett strategiskt partnerskap som str&#xE4;cker sig mellan 2021 och 2025 mellan Oxfam och Sidas humanit&#xE4;ra enhet. Insatsen f&#xF6;r 2022 uppg&#xE5;r till 107 800 000 SEK och f&#xF6;rdelas till projekt i 6 kriser, ger Oxfam m&#xF6;jlighet att s&#xF6;ka om st&#xF6;d genom Sidas Rapid Response Mechanism samt tv&#xE5; metod och kapacitetsst&#xF6;d. 

M&#xE5;let med insatsen &#xE4;r att skyndsamt kunna n&#xE5; m&#xE4;nniskor med humanit&#xE4;rt st&#xF6;d i akuta kriser samt att bidra till att st&#xE4;rka kapaciteten i det humanit&#xE4;ra systemet. Samtliga f&#xF6;reslagna insatser v&#xE4;gleds av Oxfams k&#xE4;rnmandat, vilket &#xE4;r att arbeta med samh&#xE4;llen innan, under och efter kriser f&#xF6;r att bygga upp deras motst&#xE5;ndskraft, r&#xE4;dda liv och tillsammans angripa orsakerna till konflikt och andra katastrofer.

Oxfam &#xE4;r en global hj&#xE4;lporganisation som arbetar med m&#xE4;nniskor mot fattigdom &#xF6;ver hela v&#xE4;rlden. Oxfam:s vision &#xE4;r en r&#xE4;ttvis v&#xE4;rld utan fattigdom, d&#xE4;r alla v&#xE4;rderas och behandlas lika, har samma r&#xE4;ttigheter och kan p&#xE5;verka sin egen framtid. Oxfam arbetar p&#xE5; flera niv&#xE5;er, genom livr&#xE4;ddande katastrofinsatser, l&#xE5;ngsiktiga projekt som ger m&#xE4;nniskor m&#xF6;jlighet att lyfta sig ur fattigdom och politisk p&#xE5;verkan lindrar vi de akuta symptomen.  Oxfam GB &#xE4;r ett av 20 medlemmar som utg&#xF6;r konfederationen Oxfam International.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The contribution for 2022 includes humanitarian support to Oxfam&apos;s annual projects in six crises, Oxfam&apos;s projects applied through Sida&apos;s rapid response mechanism (RRM) and for method and capacity support. 

The contribution is the second year of a strategic partnership that extends between 2021 and 2025 between Oxfam and Sida&apos;s Humanitarian Unit. The aim of the contribution is to reach people affected by crisis with humanitarian assistance and protection and to contribute to strengthening the capacity of the humanitarian system. All proposed efforts are guided by Oxfam&apos;s core mandate, which is to work with communities before, during and after crises to build their resilience, save lives and tackle the causes of conflict and other disasters.

Oxfam is a global movement of people who are fighting inequality to end poverty and injustice.  Oxfam works in about 70 countries, with partners, and allies. Oxfam GB is one of 20 affiliates that make up the confederation Oxfam International.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This contribution is aimed at supporting Oxfam in selected humanitarian crisis where Oxfam will implement specific projects and where the organisation has a clear added value to provide humanitarian assistance and protection to crisis affected populations.

In 2020 Oxfam launched its new Global Strategic Framework 2020-2030. It sets out the overall direction that Oxfam will take in the years to 2030. According to Oxfam, implementation of the framework will be supported by global horizon plans that will set out specific objectives, systemic interventions, and actions. These plans will serve as a roadmaps for measuring progress towards Oxfam&apos;s collective ambition. A combination of six approaches is presented in the framework and will constitute Oxfam&apos;s overarching theory of change. These include:
A feminist approach- To end all forms of discrimination, injustices and violations of rights suffered by women and gender non-conforming people
People power  Amplify the voices and actions of people that experience poverty and injustice and work with those who fight for their causes
Thinking globally and acting locally- Build a coalition within and between regions and from the local to the global
Enhanced humanitarian action- remain committed to delivering life-saving assistance and protection in times of conflict and disaster
Digital rights and space- to engage with and leverage the power and influence of digital technology
Systematic change  Mobilize to transform the systems that perpetuate poverty and injustice.
The strategy also outlines Oxfams approach to enhance its humanitarian actions which involves 1) deliveing life-saving support and assistance to communities affected by conflict and disaster, including people on the move; 2) transforming the systems that contribute to fragility and humanitarian crises;3) helping people and communities develop core competencies to strengthen their resilience; 4) continue to reorient the humanitarian system towards local leadership, and; 5) expanding opportunities for those impacted by protracted conflict and recurring crises to lead on sustainable solutions.
At the operational level the global strategic framework reaffirms Oxfams commitment to humanitarian assistance in the technical areas of WASH, Economic Inclusion, Cash and social protection based approaches, Gender, Community based protection and safe programming, and finally advocacy work to complement programmes in particular on women in conflict.
In&#xA0;all the technical areas there are four pillars that will inform the humanitarian approach including 1) Community Engagement; 2) Safe Programming; 3) Partnership and Leadership, 4) Feminist approach. Oxfam has developed Horizon Plan for humanitarian action, which give practical and pragmatic guidance on expectations for Oxfam countries on its humanitarian ambition, how it is changing in approach and alignment of appropriate support.&#xA0;&#xA0;

Sida&apos;s Humanitarian Assistance to Oxfam GB 2022

Oxfam GB is assessed to be well placed to respond to the increased global humanitarian needs in 2022. Oxfams broad global presence at national and regional level means that existing offices and personnel on the ground can immediately respond to rapid onset crises. In addition, Oxfam has a team of humanitarian support personnel in all sectors that are on stand-by to be deployed to support the upscale of a humanitarian response.

Sida considers Oxfam GB to be a partner that through its humanitarian interventions and own Strategic Framework makes a significant contribution in meeting the objectives of the Strategy for Swedens humanitarian aid provided through the Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency (Sida) 2021-2025.

Based on Sida&apos;s humanitarian needs-based allocation process that took place in late 2021, and which is grounded in the 4 humanitarian principles, additional funds is prepared to be allocated to Oxfam in 2022.

For 2022, the following support is proposed for Oxfam:

- Annual Projects/Programmes in Algeria, CAR, Colombia, Syria, Yemen and Chad in line with Humanitarian Response Plans  or Refugee Response Plans  64 MSEK

- Rapid Response Mechanism  35 MSEK

- Method Development and Capacity-Building  6,8 MSEK

- Programme management support  2 MSEK

This means that the total initial contribution to Oxfam GB in 2022 amounts to 107,8 MSEK.

Sida proposes to support multi-year funding for Method Development and Capacity-Building between 2022 and 2024 at a total of 18 MSEK, this includes 6,2 MSEK in 2023 and 5 MSEK in 2024.

Annual Projects (64 MSEK)

Algeria (10 MSEK)

The proposed project will contribute to the larger objective of improving Sahrawi refugees access to essential services in WASH and food security to meet their basic needs in the Boujdour camp. The project aims to reach 16,400 refugees with WASH services and 138,421 refugees with food security and livelihoods assistance. This in turn will help to prevent health issues associated with the inadequate provision and storage of water, including diarrhoea and water borne diseases. Improving access to potable water will also bring about multi-sectoral improvements, as water access has implications for camp-based health and education facilities, agriculture and livestock initiatives.

CAR (15 MSEK)

Focus areas of the intervention are WASH, food security and livelihoods as well as protection, with a strong orientation towards enabling the affected community and resilience/sustainability. The project will use the same community focused approach as in the previously conducted multiyear project, but in new areas of CAR, focusing on Ouham and Haute-Kotto.

The project aims to reach 75,995 people and aims to strengthen the self-protection capacity of the women, girls, boys and men most exposed to protection threats as well as their access to community protection services in the intervention areas in Bria and Batangafo. To restore the livelihoods of 300 households in Batangafo and 500 households in Bria through cash transfers and/or vouchers, early recovery activities through community engagement, maintenance of surveillance capacity and the establishment of an emergency fund. To improve access to water and sanitation infrastructure to reduce public health risks through hygiene promotion actions and the community engagement approach for the displaced, returnee and host populations at the displacement sites and in returnee districts in Bria centre, Batangafo centre and the surrounding areas.

The Regional Venezuela Crisis - Colombia (8 MSEK)

The proposed intervention by Oxfam GB will increase the protection of the lives and dignity of 5,200 migrant women from Venezuela who intend to settle permanently, host communities, and their families, through direct humanitarian assistance in the municipalities of Arauca, Arauquita, Tame, Fortul and Saravena, in the Department of Arauca, Colombia. Oxfam will work together with a local organisation named Apoyar and seek to enable women and their families to: identify risks and (self-) protection actions that they can develop; receive psychological first aid; access sexual and reproductive rights, and short-term contraceptive methods; and, in extreme cases, identify protection risks related to threats of recruitment, violence and gender-based sexual violence.

Syria (10 MSEK)

The project aims to support the conflict-affected communities in Sheikh Maqsoud and Handarat through a conflict-sensitive EFSVL and WASH response with Gender and Protection mainstreaming to meet their basic food needs and access safe water. The project aims to contribute towards the prevention of negative coping strategies of 18,950 conflict-affected returnees and host communities in Aleppo, Syria.

Yemen (10 MSEK)

The project objective is to save lives, reduce suffering and contribute towards prevention of negative coping strategies of 21,371 people from the most vulnerable households affected by the ongoing conflict and displacement in Marib and Alwadi district of Marib Governorate, Yemen. Oxfam will implement inclusive, need-based, and gender-focused interventions under food security, livelihoods, WASH, and protection sectors through a participatory and integrated approach.

Chad (11 MSEK)

Oxfams work in Chad is multi-sectoral focused on WASH, food security and protection and primarily focused in the Lake District. The project will reach 53,200 people, including 11,278 women, 10,002 men, 16,918 girls and 15,002 boys across all intervention zones, equal to 13% of the population (401,511) affected by the crisis over this time. The project will aim to reduce the level of vulnerability in relation to access to food, improve protection mechanisms, and access to adequate water, sanitation and hygiene for the displaced persons and host communities affected by the crises in the Bagasola, Daboua and Liwa intervention areas in Chads Lac province.

Rapid Response Mechanism (35 MSEK)

Part of the annual humanitarian budget is set aside for sudden humanitarian crises and deteriorations of major ongoing crises. For these situations Sida has a Rapid Response Mechanism (RRM) with partner organizations that makes it possible to fund lifesaving responses worldwide within 24 hours. Oxfam has been assessed by the Sida humanitarian unit to have strong capacity to respond to sudden onset crises in complex humanitarian contexts. Oxfams broad global presence at national and regional level means that existing offices and personnel (development and humanitarian) on the ground can immediately respond to a rapid onset emergency.

Across the entire second Humanitarian Partnership Agreement between Oxfam and Sida, spanning the 3 financial years between April 2018  March, 2021 a total of 27 RRM projects were implemented. More than 1,000,000 people were reached through the RRM mechanism with WASH, EFSVL and protection assistance. Sida supported Oxfam-led RRMs in Afghanistan (x2), Algeria, Bangladesh, Burkina Faso, CAR (x2), Chad (x3), Colombia, Guatemala, Honduras, Iraq, Kenya (x3), Malawi, Mauritania, Mozambique, Niger, Senegal, Somaliland, South Sudan (x2) and Syria. Oxfam has shifted towards responses to natural disaster in the second HPA as Oxfam has used nearly 80% of the RRM projects to respond to natural disasters such as: floods, cyclones, locust infestations, droughts and the COVID-19 pandemic. 2 RRM projects responded to political crises: the Venezuela migrant crisis in Colombia and the closure of refugee camps in Iraq. 5 RRM responses were conflict related (Syria, CAR (X2), Niger and Burkina Faso). More than half of the RRM projects (16), Oxfam implemented together with local humanitarian partners in alignment with our Grand Bargain and Charter for Change Commitments to localisation.

In 2020, 8 RRM projects reached a total of 363,546 people, including 132,859 people with WASH services, 175,780 with livelihood support/cash, 42,529 with protection services and 12,378 with non-food items, in 7 countries. These countries were Algeria, Afghanistan, Iraq, Chad, South Sudan, Honduras and Guatemala. 7 out of 8 RRMs responded to natural disasters and/or the COVID-19 pandemic.

Around half of the RRM responses involved partners and 2 were partner led (in Honduras and Guatemala). NCEs were granted to 62% of year 3 projects in the second humanitarian partnership agreement between Oxfam and Sida. This rise can be partly explained by the impact of the global pandemic, but also by the short duration of most projects, the difficult conditions in mostly hard to reach areas and on rare occasions, internal operational challenges.

The contexts in which Oxfam GB has implemented the RRM responses in the previous agreement period in 2021 are diverse and include amongst others support to conflict-affected populations in CAR, Ethiopia, Yemen and Occupied Palestinian Territories, and to drought-affected populations in Kenya and Somalia.

Oxfam has proven to be well positioned at country level to monitor crises, ensure quick access, good coordination and effective implementation.

In alignment with Oxfams new 10-year global strategic framework until 2030 and Oxfams new humanitarian approach, RRM projects in the next financial year will continue to focus on integrated response work in the following areas: community-based protection and safe programming; WASH; economic inclusion, which will encompass EFSVL, Cash and social protection-based approaches; gender mainstreaming across all sectors and gender stand-alone programming; a feminist approach in all Oxfams work and whenever possible, facilitate local humanitarian leadership and work with local Womens Rights Organisations; and finally, wherever possible, advocacy work to complement Oxfams programme, particularly on women in conflict through the #I Matter campaign.

Sida assesses that Oxfam is well-placed in order to respond quickly to sudden onset crises through the RRM. Despite previous dialogue issues linked to Oxfam being somewhat delayed in their requests for RRM funding and often sought pre-approval before starting to work on an RRM application, Sida assesses that Oxfam has proven to be well-placed and able to respond quickly and effectively. Therefore Sida will increase the allocation of RRM funding to Oxfam by 5 MSEK in 2022 compared to 2021.

In 2022, 35 MSEK will be added to the agreement with Oxfam GB to support the organization through the modality of RRM support.

Method- and capacity-building support (18 MSEK)

CaLP (2022: 5 MSEK  2023: 5 MSEK  2024: 5 MSEK)

Sida will in 2022 continue its support to the Cash Learning Partnership (CaLP), a network based on learning, knowledge sharing, networking and coordination around the appropriate and timely use of cash transfer programming (CTP) in humanitarian response. As CaLP is not a legal body and is hosted by the Humanitarian Department of Oxfam House, it was decided to include the support to CaLP in the agreement between Oxfam GB and Sida. Sida will in 2022 continue to support CaLP with 5 MSEK. In addition Sida proposes to support CaLP through multi-year support between 2022-2024 with 5 MSEK each year.

The disbursement of the support to Calp for 2023-24 and 2024-2025 &#xE1; 5 MSEK each year is conditioned on the receipt of an updated workplan and budget and subject to parliamentary appropriation of funds.

WASH Tweaks (2022: 1,8 MSEK  2023: 1,2 MSEK)

In 2022, Sida will support Oxfam GBs method and capacity building project called WASH Tweaks with 1,8 MSEK.

WASH Tweaks seeks to promote the centrality of protection across the WASH sector by ensuring that emergency infrastructure is safe and used by the communities it is intended for.

This will be achieved by systematically increasing awareness of and capacity for improved consultation, action on feedback, and dialogue with affected populations on the design and implementation of WASH facilities in the global WASH sector. The project will focus on vulnerable populations, including women, girls, elderly, disabled and marginalised groups, by supporting behaviour change in WASH practitioners to adopt effective consultation more widely throughout the WASH project cycle.

The WASH Tweaks will include learnings from Oxfam&apos;s developed Sani Tweaks approach and through highly interactive workshops and tools and guidance designed to support WASH practitioners to put themselves in the shoes of the people that they work with.

The project will aim to increase the use of water and sanitation facilities in emergencies through improved consultation brought about by a sector-wide change and will be jointly implemented between Oxfam and the London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine. The project will be implemented globally including a research study in Ethiopia or Bangladesh and project work in up to 10 countries depending on funds available, including Bangladesh, Burkina Faso, CAR, DRC, Iraq, Myanmar, Nigeria, South Sudan, Syria and Yemen.

The disbursement of the support to WASH Tweaks for 2023 &#xE1; 1,2 MSEK is conditioned on the receipt of an updated workplan and budget and subject to parliamentary appropriation of funds.

Programme Management costs (2 MSEK)

It is also suggested that Oxfam GB receive funding for programme management costs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21501" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21501" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2026-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="720" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.1 - Avsev&#xE4;rt minska alla former av v&#xE5;ld och d&#xF6;dligt v&#xE5;ld &#xF6;verallt.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.1 - Significantly reduce all forms of violence and related death rates everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.2 - Eliminera &#xF6;vergrepp, utnyttjande, m&#xE4;nniskohandel och alla former av v&#xE5;ld eller tortyr mot barn.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.2 - End abuse, exploitation, trafficking and all forms of violence against and torture of children.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1049330.1775699845</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">932737.9358322937</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">53645.410038592</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2024-01-01">43262.4274504774</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1049330.1775699845</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">932737.9358322937</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">53645.410038592</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2024-01-01">43262.4274504774</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-01">2078975.950891</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-28">1049330.1775699845</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-28">932737.9358322937</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/hum/14405_Amendmentno.1totheAgreement,HumanitarianPartnershipAgreement2021-2026,betweenTheSwedishInternationalDevelopmentCooperationAgency,SidaandOxfamGB.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment no. 1 to the Agreement &apos;&apos;Humanitarian Partnership Agreement 2021 -2026&apos;&apos; between The Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency, Sida and Oxfam GB</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/hum/14405_009523-21Beslutominsats,OxfamGBHUM2021-2025(14405)2887515_1_1.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats 2021-000503,Oxfam GB HUM 2021-2025</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/hum/14405_Beslutomstorreandringavinsats,OxfamGB-HUM2021-2025-2022-000575.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om st&#xF6;rre &#xE4;ndring av insats, 2022-000575, Oxfam GB - HUM 2021-2025</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="14405" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1010104" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0" strategy-end-date="2025-12-31" strategy-start-date="2021-01-01">
    <sida:title>Humanitarian aid 2021-2025</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Humanit&#xE4;rt bist&#xE5;nd 2021-2025</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
