<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5519000003-COL-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">V&#xE4;rldsbankens-Colombia- samfinansieringsfond f&#xF6;r fred  2014-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Bank -Colombia- Trust Fund for Peace 2014-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To improve the Government of Colombia timely access to global expertise and financing for peace consolidation and the implementation of peace agreements.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Bank has applied to Sida for funding of 19.5 million SEK to the &#x201C;Multi-Donor Trust Fund (MDTF) for Peace and Post-Conflict Support to Colombia&#x201D; in Colombia during the period 2014-2016. 

The MDTF aims at supporting peace-building interventions, leverage funds for the implementation of a possible peace agreement and contribute to ensuring an enduring peace in an eventual post-conflict scenario in Colombia. The objective of the fund is &#x201C;to improve Government of Colombia timely access to global expertise and financing for peace consolidation and the implementation of peace agreements&#x201D;. Interventions granted funds through the MDTF shall strengthen public institutions on a national, regional and local level.

The MDTF&#x2019;s total budget will initially be 45.5 million SEK (7 million USD), of which the World Bank&#x2019;s contribution amounts to 26 million SEK (4 million USD) and the Swedish contribution amounts to 19.5 million SEK (3 million USD). Sweden constitutes the MDTF&#x2019;s first donor, and the Swedish contribution will be directed to the Colombian Unit for Attention and Reparation of Victims (Victims Unit). The Victims Unit plans and implements individual and collective victims reparation and the contribution will focus on collective reparation plans and community-driven development.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">V&#xE4;rldsbanken har ans&#xF6;kt till Sida om finansiering p&#xE5; 19,5 miljoner SEK till samfinansieringsfonden &#x201D;Multi-Donor Trust Fund for Peace and Post-Conflict Support to Colombia&#x201D; i Colombia under perioden 2014-2016.

Samfinansieringsfonden avser st&#xF6;dja fredsbyggande insatser, ut&#xF6;ka medel f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;rande av fredsavtal samt bidra till s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;llande av en h&#xE5;llbar fred i en potentiell post-konfliktsituation i Colombia. Fonden syftar till att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra och p&#xE5;skynda den colombianska regeringens f&#xF6;rfogande av internationell expertis och finansiering till f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;n f&#xF6;r konsolidering av fred och genomf&#xF6;rande av fredsavtal. Insatser som godk&#xE4;nns genom fonden skall st&#xE4;rka offentliga institutioner p&#xE5; nationell, regional och lokal niv&#xE5;. 

Samfinansieringsfonden kommer initialt att ha en budget p&#xE5; 45,5 miljoner SEK (7 miljoner USD), d&#xE4;r V&#xE4;rldsbankens bidrag uppg&#xE5;r till 26 miljoner SEK (4 miljoner USD) och det svenska bidraget till 19,5 miljoner SEK (3 miljoner USD). Sverige utg&#xF6;r fondens f&#xF6;rsta givare och det svenska st&#xF6;det kommer g&#xE5; till den colombianska myndigheten f&#xF6;r uppr&#xE4;ttelse av konfliktens offer (Victims Unit). Victims Unit arbetar med individuell och kollektiv uppr&#xE4;ttelse f&#xF6;r konfliktens offer och insatsen kommer att fokusera p&#xE5; kollektiva uppr&#xE4;ttelseplaner och samh&#xE4;llsdriven utveckling (community-driven development).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B04" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">-116592.2419522205</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/55190000_SignedamendementtotheagreementDec52017.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1st Amendment - 55190000- World Bank MDTF for peace and post conflict</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/55190000_signedsecondamendmentBM.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2nd Amendment - 55190000- World Bank MDTF for peace and post conflict</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/55190000_ThirdamendmenttotheagreementsignedGoran-Nov2020.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3rd Amendment - 55190000- World Bank MDTF for peace and post conflict</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/55190000_GrantagreementWBsigned31102014.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement- 55190000- World Bank MDTF for peace and post conflict 2014 -2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/55190000_55190000-Decisiononmajoramendment.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on amendment 55190000- World Bank MDTF for peace and post conflict</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/55190000_55190000-Decisionconcontribution.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution 55190000- World Bank MDTF for peace and post conflict</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On December the 1st, 2020 a first draft of the narrative report was delivered by the WB. &#xA0;After the receipt of comments and questions, a final version of the report was delivered on March the 12th, 2021 and is the basis for this statement. &#xA0;This narrative report was also shared with the Steering Committee formed by the National Planning Department (DNP) and the Colombian Presidential Agency for international Cooperation (APC) with a request for a fourth amendment to extend the activity period until September 2022.
The MDTF was initially set up for a period of five years with an expected closure on December the 31st, 2018. However, the members of the Steering Committee agreed to extend the funding in order to adjust the MDTF, in line with a request from the Government of Colombia, and to ensure that the objectives of the MDTF are achieved. On December the 5th, 2017 an amendment was signed to extend the period of activities until December the 30th, 2019. This was followed on August the 26th, 2019 by the signing of a second extension until September the 30th, 2020 and by the signing of a third amendment which has extended activities until September the 30th, 2021.
During the last reporting period (September 2019 to September 2020) the fund focused on two components: 1. Technical Assistance (TA) to strengthen the Government of Colombia&#x2019;s (GoC) capacity to implement the multipurpose cadastral Policy in selected municipalities; 2. Technical Assistance program to strengthen the capacity of communities to participate in the formulation and implementation of a Territorially Focused Development Plan ( Spanish acronym is PDETs) , called ComuniPaz.
Despite the problems caused by the COVID-19 pandemic, the first component made significant progress due to the leading role played by the High Counsellor for Management and Compliance (under the Colombian Presidency) and the boost given by &#xA0;the loan of US$100 million that was agreed between the WB Board and the Colombian government in 2019. &#xA0;Last year the WB provided more assistance, requested by the GoC to further define and implement the recommendations from the first TA program and to improve operations and streamline processes and procedures for the formalization of cadastral surveys and land tenure.
This second TA continued to provide support in the following areas:
1. Strategic and technical coordination of the Multipurpose Cadastral Project;
2. Cartography production and geodetic network for the Agust&#xED;n Codazzi Geographic Institute (Spanish Acronym is IGAC);
3. Streamlined land tenure formalization procedures for the Ministry of Agriculture and National Land Agency (Spanish acronym is ANT);
4. Strengthening of ICT systems and concepts for the IGAC and Superintendency of Registries and Notaries (Spanish Acronym is SNR);
5. Alternative Dispute Resolution Mechanisms (Spanish acronym is MASC) in land-related matters in post-conflict municipalities.
&#xA0;
In addition, last year the TA included $50,000 US dollars for consultants that supported the multipurpose cadastral system in environmentally protected areas which was aimed at preventing deforestation and the transformation of natural ecosystems.&#xA0; The consultants developed three specific products: an operational manual; an interinstitutional framework agreement; and a proposal for a procurement strategy and plan. These defined products were a prerequisite to develop the whole environmental cadastral system in 40 municipalities in the Departments of Caquet&#xE1;, Guaviare, Putumayo, Meta, Arauca, Antioquia, Choc&#xF3;, Cordoba and Bolivar that will be partly financed by a contribution of &#xA0;&#xA3;40 million pounds from the UK.
The Embassy&#x2019;s assessment is that this TA has contributed to effective coordination between different relevant public institutions such as the National Planning Department &#xA0;(Spanish Acronym is DNP), IGAC, SNR and ANT with a common action plan and support to modify the legal framework when any bottlenecks were identified. The TA program has resulted in a close dialogue between the WB experts and the leading institution that has been highly appreciated and that has also achieved concrete results.
In addition to the technical issues of cartography, ICT systems and simplified methodology for formalization process, the TA in 2020 included MASC virtual training in land issues.&#xA0; Small conflicts about land property rights can create bottlenecks for updating the cadastral system as well as for land formalization processes that could be easily solved using existing conciliation resources provided by the Ombudsman&#x2019;s office of Colombia (&#x201C;Defensoria del Pueblo&#x201D;), the Chamber of Commerce or the police inspection offices. However, an integration process between judicial and land issues was necessary. The WB therefore provided training, guidance and orientation to 363 people. The Embassy participated in one of these virtual training sessions given to the Chamber of Commerce and the Ministry of Justice in May 2020 and our assessment is that the quality of consultants was high, the content was relevant, and the participants responded positively.&#xA0; The challenge is still to bring this whole MASC process to rural areas and in the massif process of formalization, so these are part of the recommendations presented by WB to the GoC.
The second output (the implementation of the technical assistance to ComuniPaz) has been delayed due to the COVID 19 pandemic and because of internal changes that have taken place in the Territory Renewal Agency (Spanish acronym is ART). This has all contributed to delays in undertaking the preparatory field work. &#xA0;&#xA0;As mentioned in the previous conclusion on performance, the consultancy for creating infrastructure projects in the two PDET regions of Choc&#xF3; and Catatumbo was assessed as relevant as the main bottleneck to implementing the PDETs is the technical structuring of the investment projects. By the end of 2019, the agreement between the WB, the ART and the Stabilisation Counsellor, was to use the remaining resources in the fund for specialist consultants that could formulate the projects in consultation with the various communities.&#xA0; This consultancy was planned to be complementary to a loan from the WB of 400 million US Dollars to implement ComuniPaz in 4 PDET regions. However, with the arrival of the COVID-19 pandemic, the GoC changed its priorities and so did not pursue this loan request. In conclusion, the consultancy proposal could not be developed in 2020 but is ready for implementation in 2021.
&#xA0;
The Embassy&#x2019;s assessment is that last year, the only progress made was in the cadastral component where leadership and wiliness from the GoC has been very evident and the WB has demonstrated its consistent capacity over the last 7 years.&#xA0; The contribution given by Sweden has supported the implementation of the whole multipurpose cadaster policy that has been financed with the 100 million US Dollar loan provided by the WB to the Colombian Government and by other donors such as UK. This is a complementary and additional way of working to fill gaps in strategic areas prioritized in the peace agreement.&#xA0;
In contrast, the PDET implementation has been slow and the many changes in the ART has also demonstrated the lack of interest in this issue. The onset of the COVID-19 pandemic forced the GoC to change its priorities thereby further reducing the possibility of implementing these plans.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55190000" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
