<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5206005902-COL-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNDP Fond f&#xF6;r &#xF6;verg&#xE5;ngsr&#xE4;ttvisa</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP Fund for Transitional Justice</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Fonden f&#xF6;r &#xF6;verg&#xE5;ngsr&#xE4;ttvisa &#xE4;r en givargemensam fond hanterad av     UNDP med det &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let att st&#xE4;rka institutionell kapacitet   p&#xE5; nationell och regional niv&#xE5; f&#xF6;r fredsbyggande, f&#xF6;rsoning och       fredlig samlevnad med fokus p&#xE5; m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter, r&#xE4;ttigheter f&#xF6;r konfliktens offer och st&#xF6;d till det colombianska r&#xE4;ttssystemet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Fund for Transitional Justice is a multi-donor fund managed by    UNDP aiming to strengthen institutional, national and regional        capacities for peace building, promotion of coexistence and           reconciliation via the recognition of human rights, victim&apos;s rights   and support to the colombian justice system.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2015Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: 1. Strengthening of victim&#xB4;s organizations  - 2.149 leaders of victims&#xB4;organizations have strenghtened their knowledge on HUman Rights, Democracy, Rule of Law, Transitional Justice, Reconciliation, Reintegration, enforced disappearance and accountability.   - The exchange of knowledge and experience  of organizations in the territorial networks for the promotion of the rights of the victims was promoted thorugh the development of 4 national meetings with the participation of 450 victims&amp;apos; representatives in 22 territories.     2. Access to Truth and Justice  - 21,451 victims of armed conflict have been able to access integral reparation measures including the right to the truth based on their active participation in hearings of integral reparation and identification of the affectations caused. The active and effective participation of the victims in the hearings, has changed the passive role that they had.  Now, they became the center of the hearing and manage to expose their affectations before the Justice and Peace Court. This fact makes the truth of the victims have a real opportunity to become a judicial truth and be taken into account in judicial decisions.  - Gender violence: 1,061 victims of of sexual violence were supported in the accession to Justice and Reparation. Likewise, 1,650 victims of sexual violence received support in their process of emotional recovery and empowerment of rights, through the strategy &amp;quot;accompaniment circles&amp;quot; carried out in 70 municipalities of 12 departments.   - Systematization and transfer of the &amp;quot;Justice and Peace&amp;quot; Law: A qualitative and quantitative study of all sentences of &amp;quot;justice and Peace&amp;quot; was made. This analysis presents objective evidence and verificial findings of the scope and limits of Law 975 of Justice and Peace, as a legal mechanism of criminal prosecution within the framework of Transitional Justice in Colombia.  - Support to Human Rights Public Policy: Together with the National Center for Historical Memory (CNMH for its acronym in spanish), the proposal for a public policy of archives on Human Rights, Historical Memory and Conflict was prepared. In addition, a joint work route was set up between the CNMH and the General Archive of the Nation aimed at the construction of the Document Management Protocol for the Archives of Human Rights, historical memory and conflict.The fund also contributed to the creation of an alliance between the judicial branch and the CNMH.Through several sessions of joint work,  an agreement for the diagnosis and transfer of judicial archives in matters of Human Rights and International Humanitarian Law was reached.     3. Reintegration and reconciliation   - Together with the Ministry of Justice, the Colombian Agency for Reintegration, the Victims Unit, the Ombudsman&amp;apos;s Office and the National Center for Historical Memory, the fund supported community reintegration and reconciliation initiatives in 5 municipalities (Popay&#xE1;n, Turbo, Soledad, Barranquilla, Bello). In these places, 7,348 victims of the armed conflict and 563 people in reintegration process, were included into spaces for the promotion of coexistence and the reconstruction of the social tissue based on artistic, cultural, sporting and recreational strategies.  - At the institutional level, the fund worked with 5 institutions (Vicitm&#xB4;s Unit, Colombian Agency for Reintegration, Ombudnsman&#xB4;s Office, Ministry of Justice and National Center for Historical Memory) in the construction of a model of &amp;quot;methodological articulation&amp;quot; aimed at mapping each of the institutional reintegration and reconciliation methodologies and identifying articulation points between the institutions.     4. Institutional strengthening for the implementation of Transitional Justice mechanisms    A. Implementation of Victim&#xB4;s and land restitution Law:   .  The National Center for Historical Memory  advanced in the systematization and visibility of historical memory investigations (approximately 90,000 archives), which improved efficiency in the management of institutional knowledge and access to information; both fundamental to define the actions in terms of orientation, attention and reparation to the victims.  - It is also worth mentioning the formulation and appropriation by the Ministry of Justice and Law, the Ombudsman&amp;apos;s Office and the Victims Unit of the &amp;quot;victim assistance protocol&amp;quot; that was developed with the support of the Fund. This protocol is one of the main tools of consultation and analysis by the public officials to improve the efficiency and effectiveness in the processes of orientation and attention to the victims in the country. 2,000 physical copies and 3,000 digital copies were produced and distributed nationwide.  - In articulated work with the Attorney General&amp;apos;s Office, the Ombudsman&amp;apos;s Office, the Vitim&#xB4;s Unit, the Land Restitution Unit, and the Federation of local Ombudsman (FENALPER), the &amp;quot;Official Training Program for Personnel on Vicitm&#xB4;s Law and supplementary rules&amp;quot; was formulated and implemented. This joint effort made it possible to strengthen the capacities and knowledge of 750 public officials (mostly staff members and regional prosecutors) in matters of care, assistance,  integral reparation to victims and land restitution processes.  - Along with the National Commission of the Public Ministry for Transitional Justice, access to the route of comprehensive care and reparation of 3,096 new victims was promoted through 6 days of declaration taking in the departments of Antioquia (Uraba) And Sucre.  - Promotion of the role of the Public Prosecutor&amp;apos;s Office as head of the technical secretariat of the victim participation tables. In this sense, The Fund and FENALPER gave support to 7 municipalities (Cali, Buenaventura-Valle, Carepa-Antioquia, Tib&#xFA;-Norte de Santander, Santa Marta-Magdalena, Rosario-Nari&#xF1;o and Santa Rosa del Sur-Magdalena Medio) whici translated in the improvement of their ability to respond to the responsibilities imposed by the Victim&#xB4;s Law.   -3096 victims have accessed the integral reparation route, through declaration taking workshops in Antioquia and Sucre    B Support to Victim&#xB4;s protection   - Fund was able to strengthen appropriation of tools for self-security and self-care of 200 leaders and leaders of social organizations and public servnts in 4 regions of the country. This work was done by supporting the National Protection Unit in the design and dissemination of a self-protection booklet developed with  inputs from leaders of victims&amp;apos; organizations, land claimants, women, journalists, trade unionists and ethnic groups.   - 135 victims who requested protection measures in 2015 were trained in self-protection measures. It is worth noting that  50% of the victims are leaders of organizations, so a multiplier effect is expected from the application of self-protection measures to the victims who are part of these organizations.      5. Support to comprehensive reparation measures   - In 2015, with support from the Presidential Cooperation Agency (APC), the design of  collective reparation plans for 7 communities prioritized by the Victim&#xB4;s Unit was achieved. It is important to mention that this strategy included a gender approach from its design, supporting women&amp;apos;s organizations in the implementation of their repair plan.   - The process of reparation and restitution of lands of more than 45 thousand people of 86 ethnic communities was promoted.  - Issuing of several restitution judgments, including the first sentence of restitution to ethnic communities (55 thousand hectares in Alto And&#xE1;gueda).   -</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52060059" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
