<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10773A0101-COL-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme for the Support of the Peace Agreement&#xB4;s transitional justice system</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Programme for the Support of the Peace Agreement&#xB4;s transitional justice system</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">IOM har ans&#xF6;kt till Sida om 24 miljoner SEK f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra &#x201D;Programmet f&#xF6;r st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r Fredsavtalets system f&#xF6;r &#xD6;verg&#xE5;ngsr&#xE4;ttvisa &#x201D;under perioden 2018 till 2022. Programmets m&#xE5;ls&#xE4;ttning &#xE4;r att st&#xF6;dja systemet f&#xF6;r &#xF6;verg&#xE5;ngsr&#xE4;ttvisa (SIVJRNR f&#xF6;r dess akronym p&#xE5; spanska), skapat genom fredsavtalet mellan den colombianska regeringen och gerillagruppen FARC. Syftet &#xE4;r &#xE4;ven att fr&#xE4;mja offers och civilsamh&#xE4;llets deltagande i systemet. I syfte att fullf&#xF6;ra dessa m&#xE5;l kommer programmet att agera som en fond som st&#xF6;djer projekt med inriktning p&#xE5;: (i) att st&#xE4;rka institutioner och mekanismer relaterade till &#xF6;verg&#xE5;ngsr&#xE4;ttvisa inom SIVJRNR; (ii) fr&#xE4;mja offers och det civila samh&#xE4;llets deltagande inom SIVJRNR; och (iii) st&#xF6;dja f&#xF6;rtroendeskapande &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder mellan regeringen, FARC och civilsamh&#xE4;llet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM has applied to Sida for funding 24 MSEK for the implementation of the &#x201C;Programme for the support of the Peace Agreement&#x2019;s Transitional Justice System&#x201D; during the period 2018-2022. The Programme&#x2019;s purpose is to support the Transitional Justice System (SIVJRNR for its acronym in Spanish) created through the Peace Accords between the Colombian government and the Farc guerilla as well as to promote the participation of victims and civil society within the system. In order to fulfill its goal, the Programme will act as a fund that supports projects oriented towards: (i) strengthening the transitional justice institutions and mechanisms within the SIVJRNR; (ii) promoting the participation of civil society and victims in the SIVJRNR; and (iii) supporting trust-building measures between the Government, the Farc and civil society.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="47066" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM/International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47066" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM/International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">575347.5098959771</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">423016.3178544613</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">760068.188974668</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">582961.2097611025</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">575347.509895977</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">423016.3178544613</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">760068.1889746679</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">582961.2097611025</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-01">2416459.541563</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-28">575347.5098959771</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-28">423016.3178544613</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-28">325743.509560572</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-28">434324.679414096</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-28">582961.2097611025</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/10773_SignedAgreementIOM-SwedenProgrammefortheSupportoftheTransitionalJusticeSystem(1).pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Signed Agreement IOM</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/10773_SignedFirstAgreementAmendment(1).pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Signed I Agreement Amendment IOM</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/10773_SignedDecisiononAgreementIOM-SwedenProgrammeforteSupportoftheTransitionalJusticeSystem(1).pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Signed Decision on Agreement IOM</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/10773_SigneddecisionFirstAgreementAmendmentContribution10773.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Signed Decision on First Agreement Amendment IOM</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/10773_SigneddecisionFirstAgreementAmendmentContribution10773(1).pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Signed Decision on I Agreement Amendment IOM</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since 2018, the Program has supported 20 projects to strengthen the transitional justice system created in the Peace Agreement. Eleven of these projects have been operated by IOM in coordination with key stakeholders -Special Jurisdiction for Peace (SJP), Truth Commission, Search Unit and victim&#x2019;s organizations-, while nine are carried out through forwarding of funds to third parties: Solidaridad Jur&#xED;dica (2), Corporate Education Center International-CEC, Casa de la Mujer, Ruta Pac&#xED;fica de las Mujeres, Instituto de Ciencia Pol&#xED;tica -ICP and JA&amp;A.&#xA0;
Out of these initiatives, ten were completed in 2019-2020, nine are under implementation and one is a preparation stage. The contribution is highly valued by the diversity of stakeholders it supports, its flexibility, and needs-based approach, which have been commended by public officials and civil society representatives.
Examples of achieved results as of April 2021, are described below under each program output.
Output 1: Entities and mechanisms of the SIVJRNR have technical and financial capacity to perform their duties. 
The Program has supported four projects that aim at strengthening technical and operational capacities of the SJP in relation to macro-cases 001 (Illegal retentions by FARC-EP), 003 (Deaths illegitimately presented as casualties in combat by State agents) and 006 (Victimization of members of the Patriotic Union Party -UP- by State agents), as well as a search engine to facilitate access to jurisprudence of the SJP. These initiatives have been instrumental in the issuing of the first judicial decisions by the SJP on macro cases 001 and 003.
In a meeting held on April 2021 with Embassy&#x2019;s representatives, the Magistrate in charge of macro case 001 acknowledge the added value of these projects for the SJP, allowing them to gather and analyze meaningful information about the expectations and comments of more than 1.000 victims accredited in the case, as well as the actions undertaken by the &#x201C;victimizers&#x201D; to acknowledge and repair the damage caused. The methodology developed in this macro case has been recognized as a good practice that could be replicated in other macro cases. &#xA0;
Expert civil society organization IFIT received support from 2018 to 2020 (first agreement) and for the period 2021 to 2022 (second agreement) to provide technical assistance and specialized advice to institutions of the Transitional Justice System on topics such as restorative justice and sanctions, conditionality regime, reparation, non-repetition measures, social dialogue, communication and interinstitutional coordination.
Output 2: Civil society and victims have capacity and information for their participation in the SIVJRNR 
&#xA0;The Program supports victims and former FARC combatants to meaningfully participate in and contribute to transitional justice mechanisms through various initiatives. In the case of victims, IOM fostered the organizational strengthening of Fundaci&#xF3;n MAFAPO (Madres V&#xED;ctimas de los Falsos Positivos de Soacha y Bogot&#xE1;), an association formed by the mothers of extrajudicial execution victims. The project contributed to the formulation and presentation to the SJP of a report systematizing victims&#x2019; statements to contribute to macro-case 003. The Swedish Ambassador participated in the virtual event where the report was presented to SJP magistrates, as well as representatives of the Truth Commission and the Search Unit.
The Program fostered women&#x2019;s participation in the Transitional Justice System with two projects: one with Ruta Pac&#xED;fica de las Mujeres, which contributed to the transcription and submission of 1.456 testimonies of women affected by the armed conflict to the Truth Commission; and another with Casa de la Mujer that develops a psychosocial care strategy for women participating in Transitional Justice mechanisms in Cundinamarca and C&#xF3;rdoba.
In 2020, two civil society initiatives received support to draft reports to the Truth Commission on the topics of victimization and forced displacement of militaries and their families, and the incidence of drug-trafficking in armed conflict dynamics with a specific focus on the case of the explosion of the Avianca plane in 1989. Both reports were published and presented in public events, with participation of the Embassy, contributing to inform the ongoing investigations of the Truth Commission on these issues.
In terms of assistance to former combatants, two projects have been supported through Corporaci&#xF3;n Solidaridad Jur&#xED;dica: the first one, allowed former FARC members to conduct 116 interviews in 7 regions and presents reports and documentaries that were submitted to the Truth Commission; and the second one, contributed to collect and submit information on 38 new cases of missing persons during the armed conflict by former FARC members to the Unit for the Search of Missing Persons. As an added value, these initiatives facilitated the dissemination of information on transitional justice mechanisms in territories and fostered an improved coordination between FARC, the Truth Commission, and the Search Unit at the national and local levels.
The Program promoted trust-building and reconciliation strategies developed by the Truth Commission, supporting Reconectando for conducting 5 regional Truth Laboratories, in partnership with USAID. Truth Laboratories are five-day encounters between 17 participants that come from antagonistic sectors of society and that have been affected by the armed conflict, in which dialogue is promoted through methods of the Deep Ecology, Social Theater and Ritual. Additional support to civil society and community-based organizations for participating in transitional justice mechanisms was channeled through IFIT and CEC International.
Output 3: The Government and Civil Society have capacities for the formulation and development of trust building actions within the implementation of the Peace Agreement.
This Output was oriented towards supporting Acts of Acknowledgement of Responsibility and trust-building between victims and FARC, before transitional justice mechanisms were fully operational. In 2019, IOM and the Embassy agreed to limit this Output due to difficulties in the implementation of Acts of Acknowledgement and the new role of the Truth Commission in the promotion of trust and reconciliation (see UM2018/05166-33 and UM2018/05166-41).
Nonetheless, the Program supported collective reparation measures for the victims of the case of the 9 councilors of Rivera (Huila) assassinated by FARC. In 2019 a documentary was produced with participation of victims&#x2019; families and the Truth Commission to contribute to the symbolical reparation of victims and constitutes a key communication product to preserve and disseminate the memory of the events.
The documentary was presented publicly in February 2020 in an event in Neiva with participation of the Truth Commission, the National Center for Historical Memory, the Embassy, and the families of the victims. The documentary was also screened in the central park of Rivera on the date of commemoration of the killings, as a symbolic measure to preserve the collective memory of conflict in the municipality.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10773" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1050203" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1176000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Colombia 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Colombia 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
