<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10303A0101-COL-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Resident Coordinators Office 2016-21</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UN Resident Coordinators Office 2016-21</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d till kontoret f&#xF6;r FN-systemets gemensamma land-koordinator, UN Resident Coordinator&#x2019;s Office (RCO), i Colombia. 
FN har en omfattande n&#xE4;rvaro i landet. Samordning och samarbete, internt och externt, &#xE4;r viktigt men kr&#xE4;vande och ett starkt RCO &#xE4;r avg&#xF6;rande f&#xF6;r FN:s fortsatta roll i Colombia. Insatsen &#xE4;mnar d&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r st&#xE4;rka RCO, i linje med FN-reformen, och d&#xE4;rigenom FN:s roll i fredsbyggandet i Colombia, genom &#xF6;kad kapacitet f&#xF6;r gemensam analys, planering, informationshantering och kommunikation. 
Sida st&#xF6;djer tv&#xE5; strategiska positioner vid RCO i Colombia, varav en svensk och en lokalanst&#xE4;lld, och bidrar &#xE4;ven med finansiering till snabba strategiska och katalytiska aktiviteter av vikt f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;randet av fredsavtalet mellan regeringen och FARC, samt f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningarna f&#xF6;r en fullst&#xE4;ndig fred.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for the Office of the UN Resident Coordinator, RCO, in Colombia.
The UN has an extensive presence in the country. Coordination and cooperation, internally and externally, is important but demanding and a strong RCO is crucial for the UN&apos;s continued role in Colombia. The effort therefore aims to strengthen the RCO, in line with the UN reform, and thereby the UN&apos;s role in peacebuilding in Colombia, through increased capacity for joint analysis, planning, information management and communication.
Sida supports two strategic positions at RCO in Colombia, of which one is Swedish and one is local, and also contributes funding to rapid strategic and catalytic activities of importance for the implementation of the peace agreement between the government and the FARC, as well as the conditions for a complete peace.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">350610.6468766435</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">350610.6468766435</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-01">350610.646876</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-28">350610.6468766435</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/10303_UM2016_16363-12Amendment1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement Strengthening Resident Coordinators Office in Colombia - amendment 1</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/10303_UM2016_16363-14Amendment2UNRCOsigned20184608397_2_1(1).pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement Strengthening Resident Coordinators Office in Colombia - amendment 2</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/10303_201120LetterofapprovalAmendment3OCR.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement Strengthening Resident Coordinators Office in Colombia - amendment 3</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/10303_UM2016_16363-12Agreement93830UNDPStrengtheningDonorCoordinatorOffice4608380_2_1(1).pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement Strengthening Resident Coordinators Office in Colombia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/10303_Tillaggsbeslut2017-11-09.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision Strengthening Resident Coordinators Office in Colombia - amendement 1</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/10303_Tillaggsbeslut2018-11-20.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision Strengthening Resident Coordinators Office in Colombia - amendment 2</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/10303_Beslut2016-10-03.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision Strengthening Resident Coordinators Office in Colombia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The contribution has two main results or &#x201C;Outputs&#x201D;. The first one is to strengthen the capacity of the UN Resident Coordinator&#x2019;s Office in Colombia through additional staff-members within the Office: One P5-level Head of Office and one G6-level Associate Officer, with responsibility for the administration of the Swedish contribution. The second is to strengthen its capacity to lead and coordinate the UN-system in Colombia by engaging the UN in strategic and catalytic activities for peacebuilding and sustainable development. With regards to the former, the head of the resident coordinator&#x2019;s office has direct responsibility for carrying out the entire mandate of the office, including the delivery of the expected results of the contribution. The progress on all indicators for Output 1 are significant and Sida concludes that this aspect of the intervention has significantly contributed to strengthening the RCO&#x2019;s capacity. Among other results, the overall progress of implementation of the UNDAF is estimated at over 80%, in comparison to the target at 50%, and the new generation UNDAF for 2020-2024 was negotiated with the government and Colombia under the leadership of the RCO, and was signed in 2020. This new framework, the UNSDCF, responds to shared priorities and allows key UN-agencies and programmes to continue carrying out their mandates in Colombian in support of the peace-process and the sustainable development goals, SDGs. The RCO also plays an important role in the UN Multi-Partner Trust Fund (UN-MPTF) for support to peacebuilding in Colombia. The fund is considered successful, both in terms of the important results achieved and the amount of funding it attracts from international donors and channels to strategic peacebuilding activities. The first phase of the MPTF concluded in 2019 and the RCO led the negotiations between the (then recently elected) Colombian government, international donors and the UN-agencies regarding an extension of the fund&#x2019;s existence that resulted in an agreement on the second phase, which aligns both with government priorities and the main concerns of the international community, and emphasizes the gender equality, environmental sustainability and active participation by victims of the conflict and civil society organizations. Under the second Output of the contribution, a total of 17 strategic initiatives were supported by the RCO during the period, ranging from support to local peacebuilding initiatives by Colombian civil society organizations to support for the national government&#x2019;s office for coordination of the Covid-19 response, to improved information management within the UN-system. Sida assesses the initiatives to be strategic and relevant, and the results to be satisfactory. The following activities and results are only a small sample, considered worth highlighting as they exemplify both the progress and the challenges in a wide range of different activities within the mandate of the RCO: The RCO&#x2019;s support to UNDP for reintegration of former FARC-combatants is just one of several contributions to the UNDP&#x2019;s larger reintegration portfolio. However, it&#x2019;s focus on gender equality supports adequate integration of the gender perspective in all reintegration activities supported by the UNDP. In this way it has allowed the UNDP to access funding from other sources, most notably the UN Peace Building Fund (PBF). The Swedish contribution focuses to a large extent on developing day-care centres and other infrastructure to strengthen women&#x2019;s participation and empowerment. These activities were unfortunately halted during a large part of the year due to the pandemic, but the activities will continue during 2021. The support to the Mayor of Bogota&#x2019;s office for peacebuilding and reconciliation is of particular interest and relevance. In comparison with other Colombian municipalities, Bogota has large economic resources of its own and is not in particular need of international aid. However, it has not been prioritised by the national government, despite having by far the largest population of both victims and ex-combatants of the internal armed conflict. Initiatives and policies adopted by Bogota are often replicated by other municipalities around the country. To support Bogota in establishing and implementing its own policy for peacebuilding and reconciliation is therefore seen not only as support to the many victims of the conflict living in the city, but also as a way of encouraging other municipalities to develop and implement their own peacebuilding efforts, as a complement to the policies of the national government. Unfortunately, these activities have been significantly delayed due to the pandemic, and the results to date are limited to strengthening local victims&#x2019; organizations and the economic reintegration of ex-combatants in Bogota. However, the Swedish contribution has also allowed the RCO to coordinate UN inter-agency support for the Mayor&#x2019;s Office, including in the design of a special development plan (PDET) for the rural district of Sumapaz, in Bogota, with a special emphasis on citizen participation and environmental sustainability. The district of Sumapaz holds the words largest &#x201C;paramo&#x201D; ecosystem and is the most important fresh-water source for the city of Bogota and its surroundings. The Swedish contribution also allowed the RCO to engage with and support the Colombian chapter of the international youth movement SOLE. With occasion of the 75th anniversary of the UN and co-funded by the UN Secretary General&#x2019;s office, SOLE carried out an initiative to engage youth in a nation-wide dialogue regarding their future and created a network of &#x201C;ambassadors&#x201D; to facilitate continued dialogue and exchange of ideas. The full experience was documented and is available at http://www.solecolombia.org/narrando-la-conversacion-mas-grande-del-mundo/. It will no doubt serve as inspiration and as an important roadmap to strengthen the UN-system&#x2019;s engagement and work with Colombian youth, and to advance implementation of the Youth, Peace and Security agenda in the country. The RCO continued supporting the Pastoral Social of the Diocese of Quibd&#xF3; to promote a humanitarian agreement between the different armed groups in the region of Choc&#xF3;. The support commits the local coordination team to the process, otherwise genuinely a civil society initiative. However, the various social platforms in the territory did not reach consensus on the actions to be carried out within the framework of the grant and the arrival of Covid-19 imposed other urgent priorities on the local afro-Colombian and indigenous communities. Therefore, the grant was redirected to support the Pastoral Social in its activities to prevent the spread of Covid-19. This has contributed to the overall Covid-response and at the same time strengthened trust in the Pastoral Social as a humanitarian actor and broker of humanitarian access to conflict affected territories. In the early phase of the pandemic, the RCO also stepped in and supported the office of Covid-19 response coordination, within the national government. This support not only allowed the government to strengthen its efforts to coordinate the response in the different regions of the country but also ensured a direct line of communication with the UN-system, including the WHO / PAHO and other humanitarian organizations in the country. Thanks to the Swedish contribution, the RCO also supported the indigenous organizations OPIAC and ONIC, to maintain self-protection mechanisms for their communities. Indigenous people have not only been disproportionally affected by the armed conflict in Colombia, but also by the pandemic. They have their own security forces, the &#x201C;indigenous guard&#x201D; that exercise public authority in their territories. To allow the indigenous guards to continue their work to ensure protection and rule of law in their communities during the pandemic, they were supported with bio-security kits and a screening-systems for Covid-19.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10303" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
