<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13726A0102-COL-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recon: Social entrepeneurship for sustainable development and peace building</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Recon: Social entrepeneurship for sustainable development and peace building</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion RECON (RECON) is a is Colombian NGO that works with vulnerable communities in Colombia searching, supporting and strengthening social entrepreneurships that may generate sustainable economic alternatives to poor populations affected by conflict.
The general objective of this contribution is directed to consolidate RECON as the leading organization of social entrepreneurship in Colombia, with the purpose of identifying, inspiring, connecting and strengthening entrepreneurship initiatives and social innovation projects that generate economic and social transformations and environmental sustainability, in vulnerable communities.
This general objective is expected to be achieved by three specific objectives:
1. To consolidate the technical and institutional capacity of RECON, to benefit and facilitate the participation of civil society in construction processes of peace and territorial development through social entrepreneurship initiatives.
2. To promote actions that contribute to strengthening the identification processes and promotion of entrepreneurship and social innovation projects aligned with the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).
3. To develop organizational strategies to strengthen projects of social entrepreneurship, in order to contribute to the consolidation of sustainability and territorial impact.
By the end of this intervention (which is initially planned for four years), RECON is expected to be the leading organisation in the country that groups and strengthens small civil society organisations and supports and accompanies social entrepreneurship projects conceived by vulnerable populations affected by conflict (women, ex-combatants, LGTBI, poor, indigenous and afro-Colombians, among others) with the purpose of generating sustainable economic income and thus contributing to peace-building in the targeted territories.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Fundacion RECON har ans&#xF6;kt om finansiering p&#xE5; 7 500 000 SEK hos Sveriges ambassad i Colombia f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra projektet &#x201C;Project for the consolidation of the system of social entrepreneurship in Colombia as a tool for sustainable development and peace building&#x201D; i Colombia under perioden 2020-2023.

Insatsen syftar till att konsolidera RECON som den ledande organisationen f&#xF6;r socialt entrepren&#xF6;rskap i landet, i syfte att identifiera, inspirera, sammankoppla och st&#xE4;rka entrepren&#xF6;rskap och initiativ f&#xF6;r social innovation som genererar ekonomiska och sociala f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar och milj&#xF6;m&#xE4;ssig h&#xE5;llbarhet i utsatta samh&#xE4;llen genom att 1) konsolidera RECON:s tekniska och institutionella kapacitet, 2) fr&#xE4;mja &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder som bidrar till identifiering och fr&#xE4;mjande av entrepren&#xF6;rskap och 3) utveckla organisatoriska strategier som st&#xE4;rker sociala entrepren&#xF6;rskap som bidrar till konsolidering av h&#xE5;llbarhet och som har territoriell effekt.

Insatsens totala budget &#xE4;r 7 500 000 SEK.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion RECON has applied to the embassy of Sweden in Colombia for funding of 7 500 000 SEK to carry out the &#x201C;Project for the consolidation of the system of social entrepreneurship in Colombia as a tool for sustainable development and peace building&#x201D; in Colombia during the period 2020-2023.

The intervention aims at consolidating RECON as the leading organisation of social entrepreneurship in the country, with the purpose of identifying, inspiring, connecting and strengthening entrepreneurships and social innovation initiatives that generate economic and social transformations and environmental sustainability in vulnerable communities by 1) consolidating RECON&#x2019;s technical and institutional capacities, 2) promoting actions that contribute to the identification and promotion processes of entrepreneurships and 3) developing organisational strategies that strengthen  social entrepreneurships that contribute to the consolidation of sustainability and have territorial impact. 

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 7 500 000 SEK.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion Recon</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion Recon</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">233184.483904441</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">209866.0355139969</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">233184.483904441</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">209866.0355139969</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-10">412608.445443</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/13726_ReconDecisiononContribution11_06_2020.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recon: Social entrepreneurship for sustainable development and peace building - Decision on Contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PERIOD 1 (06/2020 - 12/2020):

The year 2020 was a year of changes, transformations and opportunities derived from the global Covid-19 pandemic that required RECON to generate an innovative action plan that responded to the reality of the context. Colombia was affected by countless social issues requiring innovative solutions, and social entrepreneurship became a tool to counteract the social, economic and environmental effects arising from the Covid-19 pandemic.

Challenges were related mainly to the impossibility of traveling to the regions and connecting physically with social entrepreneurships and allies. Faced with this challenge, the RECON platform was strengthened to become the space to promote the mobilization of resources for the sustainability of social entrepreneurships through crowdfunding campaigns and visualizing inspiring stories that were then connected with donors, sponsors, philanthropists, allies, and the media.

Examples of results achieved: 
* Digital platform to strengthen Social Entrepreneurship: The strengthening and transformation of the digital platform continued within the framework of the project, creating new digital innovation strategies to generate dissemination and visibility channels whose main objective was to promote the sustainability of social entrepreneurships during the pandemic through Crowdfunding and connections with allies from the public, private and civil society sectors.
* Digital expansion: RECON migrated the face-to-face format and content from Regional Forums to digital dialogues (webinars), which permitted the participation of more social entrepreneurships from different regions of Colombia in the same digital scenario. Likewise, the organization was able to expand its connection and participation capacity, which allowed the entrepreneurs to reach more strategic allies to strengthen their businesses through dialogue and the construction of ideas.
* Virtual training: Digital workshops were put in place to provide training for the strengthening of the social entrepreneurships business model. This action allowed the consolidation of 100% virtual academic processes to accompany social entrepreneurships on their path towards learning and sustainability.
* National call (100% digital): RECON implemented the methodology of the RECON call in a 100% digital model, focused on a national environmental call that allowed the identification of undertakings in 88% of the departments.
* Public Incidence: Given the opportunity offered by virtuality to connect and work with various actors of the Social Entrepreneurship System at the local, national and global levels, RECON worked on the strengthening of the social business model in the country. The results from this exercise were important inputs for the National Entrepreneurship Law.
In addition, the platform connected the needs of vulnerable communities in the territories with the solutions offered by social entrepreneurships to make them beneficiaries and part of the social value chain that guaranteed access to food safety, biosafety and hygiene, education, and human rights.

At the national level, two public calls were developed during the second semester of 2021. The First call, called Colombia Soluciona, was focused on identifying innovative social entrepreneurships that solved problems derived from the Covid-19 Pandemic. The Second was an environmental call, designed to identify solutions to the pollution problems derived from plastic use and promote alternatives to reduce, eliminate and reuse this material.

The National Summit on Social Entrepreneurship was also carried out during this period; it allowed 58.8% of the attendees to make connections and strategic alliances with other actors such as other social entrepreneurships, public entities, private companies, academia and NGOs. This Summit also resulted in a specific commitment of the National Government through the High Presidential Counselor for Innovation and Digital Transformation, the Ministry of Industry, Tourism and Commerce, the Office of the First Lady of the Nation and the Director of INNpulsa Colombia to promote and strengthen a public policy of social entrepreneurship from the territories, with a focus on vulnerable communities.

Another result during this semester was the structuring of RECONs first social incubation model designed to create, strengthen and enhance social entrepreneurships that are generating impacts and transformations in peacebuilding and sustainable development in vulnerable communities in the country, especially conflict-affected municipalities. This model, structured with a duration of 10 months, focused on three training programs that offer accompaniment, individual tutoring, and connection with strategic actors for financing.

At the organizational level, Swedens support to RECON has allowed the implementation of the COSO ERM 17 control system (Committee of Sponsoring Organizations of the Treadway Commission), as well as improvements in the processes through specialized software. As a result of the external audit carried out by Sida/BDO LLP in 2020, different committees for Internal Control and Financial and Administrative follow-up have been created and are carried out periodically to evaluate and determine corrective and improvement actions that must be applied in a timely manner. RECON has created and applied a series of manuals and policies that guide the implementation of the project as well as the organizational development of internal processes; it has also strengthened its technological tools for the optimization of digital processes.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13726" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
