<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11586A0101-COL-16080</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">NIR - Social Dialog</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIR - Social Dialogue</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the Colombian economy to grow sustainably and to break the inequality of today&#x2019;s system, to meet the challenges of tomorrow&#x2019;s labour market and overcome decades of conflict that has deeply fragmented the society, changes at the labour market are necessary. Such developments are strongly dependent on a shift in culture and perception not just in the dialogue between the employers and the trade unions, but within these groups and bodies themselves. The project  &#x201C;Private Sector contribution to Social Dialogue in Colombia&quot;,  NIR (International Council of Swedish Industry) intends to strengthen the dialogue through building trust and providing access to tools among actors at different levels at the labour market.

This two and half year project further intends to support Colombia&#x2019;s OECD implementation process by addressing needs identified in the recent OECD assessments of the labour market. The project focuses on three components; to create a labour market dialogue initiative, to develop the mediation mechanism for the labour market at firm level as well as to design local social dialogue workplace programs - all activities with a shared long-term outcome; to achieve an improved capacity for a sustainable social dialogue. The project starts with an initial phase of six months, to ensure that the specific plans are developed and modified in close cooperation with local stakeholders.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">F&#xF6;r att den colombianska ekonomin ska v&#xE4;xa h&#xE5;llbart och bryta oj&#xE4;mlikheterna i dagens system, m&#xF6;ta utmaningarna p&#xE5; morgondagens arbetsmarknad samt &#xF6;vervinna &#xE5;rtionden av konflikter som har splittrat samh&#xE4;llet, &#xE4;r f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar p&#xE5; arbetsmarknaden n&#xF6;dv&#xE4;ndiga. S&#xE5;dan utveckling &#xE4;r starkt beroende av en f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndring av kultur och uppfattningar, inte bara i dialogen mellan arbetsgivare och fackf&#xF6;reningar, utan inom dessa grupper och organisationer sj&#xE4;lva. Under projektet  &#x201C;Private Sector contribution to Social Dialogue in Colombia&quot;, avser NIR att st&#xE4;rka denna dialogen genom att bygga f&#xF6;rtroende och ge tillg&#xE5;ng till verktyg bland akt&#xF6;rer p&#xE5; olika niv&#xE5;er p&#xE5; arbetsmarknaden.

Detta tv&#xE5; och ett halv&#xE5;rsprojekt avser vidare att st&#xF6;dja Colombias genomf&#xF6;randeprocessen av Colombias nyligen godk&#xE4;nda OECD medlemskap genom att addressera de behov som identifierats i de senaste OECD-bed&#xF6;mningarna betr&#xE4;ffande Colombias arbetsmarknad. 

Projektet fokuserar p&#xE5; tre komponenter; att skapa ett arbetsmarknadsdialoginitiativ, att utveckla medlingsmekanismen p&#xE5; arbetsmarknaden samt att utforma ett arbetsplatsprogram f&#xF6;r sociala dialog p&#xE5; arbetsmarknadens  - alla aktiviteter delar ett l&#xE5;ngsiktigt m&#xE5;l, att uppn&#xE5; en b&#xE4;ttre kapacitet f&#xF6;r en h&#xE5;llbar social dialog. Projektet b&#xF6;rjar med en f&#xF6;rsta fas p&#xE5; sex m&#xE5;nader f&#xF6;r att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att de specifika aktiviteterna utvecklas i n&#xE4;ra samarbete med lokala intressenter.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of the programme Private Sector contribution to Social Dialogue in Colombia is to provide improved conditions for a Sustainable Social Dialogue. The program targets social dialogue on three levels; social dialogue among the labour market parties at 1) central, regional and sectorial level 2) the company and firm level and 3) the workplace level. The combination of these tracks is intended to be mutually reinforcing, and to provide several avenues to reach results. Thus,&#xA0;strengthen the dialogue through building trust and providing access to tools among actors at different levels at the labour market.
Hence, the project focuses on three components; to create a labour market dialogue initiative, to develop the mediation mechanism for the labour market at firm level as well as to design local social dialogue workplace programs - all activities with a shared long-term outcome; to achieve an improved capacity for a sustainable social dialogue.&#xA0;
This two and half year project further intends to support Colombia&#x2019;s OECD accession process by addressing needs identified in the recent OECD assessments of the labour market.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donor country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIR/N&#xE4;ringslivets Internationella R&#xE5;d</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16080" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Dialogue</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">172604.2529687932</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">211508.1589272306</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">157442.6962876098</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">172604.2529687931</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">211508.1589272306</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">157442.6962876098</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">569594.034797</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-28">172604.2529687932</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">211508.1589272306</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-28">157442.6962876098</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/colombia/11586_11589-SignedAgreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement- NIR Social dialogue</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/colombia/11586_11586-Decisiononcontribution.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution 11586-NIR Social dialogue</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During 2019, the NIR team from Stockholm visited Colombia five times and two Coordinators were hired. The Embassy had monitoring meetings with the NIR them and participated in some of the organized events. In February the NIR team were accompanied by the international secretariat from IF METAL. They had meetings with the Nacional Enterprise Association-ANDI, the three main Trade Unions (CUT, CTC, CGT) and Swedish companies presenting the workplace program. These meetings were followed by a visit in October when the program was once again presented to Swedish companies that form part of the Corporate Social Responsibility-CSR Network. In May the Embassy supported NIR organizing a coordination meeting with other donors such as Holland, Denmark, USAID and the International Labour Organization- ILO. The conclusion was that NIR should take into consideration the experiences and the final recommendations from the social dialogue project supported by Denmark as well as the CETCOIT, a mediation mechanism supported by the ILO. In November the Embassy accompanied NIR&#x2019;s Director General and the Director General of the Swedish Mediation Institute to seminars with the Javeriana and Rosario universities. Finally, in December, the Embassy facilitated a dialogue between NIR and Union to Union that also receives support from Sida and who provide support the Trade Unions in Colombia. The aim was to promote greater coordination of activities in Colombia. As regards of the first output, the former Colombian Ambassador to the OECD, Catalina Crane, was hired as Coordinator with the aim of putting in place an operational structure for future dialogue between government, the three main national Trade Unions and employers (represented by ANDI) as part of the OECD agenda. Catalina Crane had both individual and joint meetings, as part of the parallel dialogue apart from with the Commission for Labour Concertation which is an official tri partite forum. Her experience and general recognition among the parties facilitated dialogue and the Trade Unions and ANDI finally agreed to table&#x201D; informality and its relation to both productivity and job stability&#x201D; as the topic to discuss during the year. The objective was to present a joint position with recommendations to the government. However, by the end of the year this bilateral dialogue was suspended because of the different perspectives of ANDI and the Unions regarding Colombian Governmental reforms to the pension system and labour legislation. The Unions supported massive citizen&#x2019; protests in November that continued into December focusing on the annual discussion to set the national minimum wage. In addition, the contacts and interest raised with the Vice-Minister of labour in 2019, will need to be re-started again as a new person was appointed early 2020. Despite the different parties having confirmed the relevance of additional bilateral dialogue, separated from the normal official channels, as well as having confirmed the importance of continuing to jointly analyse the challenges of informality, the actual polarized context on the ground made it difficult to reach any concrete results during the year. The second output, that aim at reactivating a resource pool of mediators has slightly changed for previous steps and contacts with universities. The mediation mechanism to handle labour conflicts outside the judicial system, is another recommendation made to Colombia for the OECD accession process. However, before reactivating the network of mediators, it was necessary to raise awareness among companies and Trade Unions about the relevance of the mediation tool and to coordinate with other donors as mentioned above. Therefore, during 2019 Carlos Guarnizo, a Colombian lawyer specialized in labour law and with previous experience working with NIR from 2008 to 2012, was hired as the Coordinator for this component. He contacted the law schools of private universities (Javeriana and Rosario) that had conducted research on the existing legal framework for labour mediation, as well as on the costs for companies due to the lack of mediation systems. As already mentioned, on the 7th of November 2019 the Director General of the Swedish Mediation Institute, together with representatives from the US Federal Mediation &amp;amp; Conciliation Services and the ILO, participated in seminars with both aforementioned universities in Bogota. The Embassy of Sweden was also participant and our assessment was that despite the huge effort to bring international experiences, it did not have the expected impact as the audience was disappointingly small. In April 2019 the third component, that aim at developing and implementing a framework model for a workplace program, was moved to a NIR global program financed by Sida. The budget for this component was therefore redistributed to the other two components. In addition to making synergies with a global program, this change has the advantage to have a longer timeframe, beyond 2020, to develop the workplace program in Colombia. The report covers the two general meetings held in February and October that presented the program to ANDI and the CSR network of Swedish companies. The Embassy&#x2019;s assessment is that there is a lot of interest among various Swedish companies (including Securitas, Epirok, Atlas Copco and Assa Abloy) and with the new coordinator being hired in May 2020, this will result in the start of tailor-made support. The narrative report presents general conclusions on results throughout the year, without providing detail about the five visits to Colombia, conducted by the NIR team. Based on the report and the various monitoring meetings and events, the Embassy&#xB4;s general assessment is that the impact of the project has unfortunately been lower than expected. The Embassy is aware of the challenges presented by the existing polarized context and the difficulties in making progress on social dialogue issues. However, despite having local Coordinators, it is more difficult to make progress in between each mission to Colombia when the implementing partner is based in Sweden.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="11586" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1050203" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1176000000.0" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <title>Colombia 2016-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Colombia 2016-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
