<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10338A0101-COL-31164</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lantm&#xE4;teriet- Col Cadaster 2018</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Lantm&#xE4;teriet- Col Cadaster 2018</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Denna insats syftar till att st&#xE4;rka den colombianska landadministrationen genom internationell expertis fr&#xE5;n Lantm&#xE4;teriet. Bidraget baseras p&#xE5; ramavtalet mellan Sida och Lantm&#xE4;teriet och p&#xE5; Colombias regeringens beg&#xE4;ran om att st&#xE4;rka r&#xE5;dgivande kommitt&#xE9;n f&#xF6;r pilot projekt inom landadministrationen. Den svenska experten kommer att under 2018 deltaga i 5-7 uppdrag i Colombia. Experten kommer att tillhandah&#xE5;lla teknisk r&#xE5;dgivning f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;randet av &quot;multipurpose cadastral-piloter&quot; (Ett integrerad markinformationssystem som inneh&#xE5;ller: juridisk (t.ex &#xE4;gander&#xE4;tt), fysisk (t.ex topografi) och kulturell (t.ex markanv&#xE4;ndning) information i en gemensam referensram).</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This contribution aims at strengthening the Colombian multi-purpose cadaster policy through international expertise from the Swedish mapping, cadastral and land registration authority (Lantm&#xE4;teriet). The contribution is based on the framework agreement between Sida and Lantm&#xE4;teriet and on Colombian&#x2019;s government request to strengthen the advisory committee for multi-purpose cadaster pilots. The Swedish expert will participate, during 2018, in 5 missions to Colombia and will provide technical advice for the implementation of the multipurpose cadastral pilots.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This contribution aims at strengthening the Colombian multi-purpose cadaster policy through international expertise from the Swedish mapping, cadastral and land registration authority (Lantm&#xE4;teriet). The contribution is based on the framework agreement between Sida and Lantm&#xE4;teriet and on Colombian&#x2019;s government request to strengthen the advisory committee for multi-purpose cadaster pilots. The Swedish expert will participate, during 2018, in 5-7 missions to Colombia and will provide technical advice for the implementation of the multipurpose cadastral pilots.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11004" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lantm&#xE4;teriet</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="11004" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lantm&#xE4;teriet</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="31164" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agrarian reform</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="311" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">62965.3410660039</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">62965.3410660038</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-31">62965.341066</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-28">44892.9853631593</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">18072.3557028445</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The peace agreement between the Government of Colombia (GoC) and the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC), signed in November, 2016, stresses the need for integral rural development in the territory, including updated cadastral information. &#xA0;The GOC has approved the multi-purpose cadaster policy (CONPES 3859 of June 13, 2016) which specifies the action plan, tentative budget and the new institutional arrangements to implement the new policy. The policy implementation started with pilot projects developed during 2017 and 2018 and in parallel, the GOC has requested global expertise to review every step of the process of the cadaster pilots to the World Bank. The external advisory committee formed by 8 national and international experts started working in 2017 and the Swedish expert from Lantm&#xE4;teriet joined the group in January 2018.
The contribution Lantm&#xE4;teriet &#x2013; Consultancy for Multipurpose Colombian Cadaster served therefore to aid the Colombian cadaster process. Specifically, it contributed with an expert from Swedish Lantm&#xE4;teriet on the external Advisory Committee (AC), technically supervised and managed by the World Bank through the Sida&#x2019;s contribution WB Multidonor Trust Fund for peace and Post conflict (55190000).
The new GoC headed by President Duque (elected in 2018) proposed a new cadaster policy (CONPES 3958, March 19, 2019). The new policy updates the previous CONPES from 2016, based on lessons learned from the pilot projects and recommendations and inputs from the AC. Several recommendations made by the AC were incorporated in the new policy. For example, a re-structuring of governmental entities was included in order to achieve better coordination between them. The AC had pointed out that in the pilot projects each entity would have their own agendas and goals, which impacted the work negatively and impeded collaboration. In addition, the problem of interoperability of data was raised by the AC, as each entity would have different, incompatible data systems despite the data being highly relevant across entities. Much relevant data was gathered during the pilot but could not be processed because of this issue. The new cadaster policy heavily emphasizes and prioritizes interoperability of data. Lastly, the World Bank &#x2013; whose main source of information on Colombian cadaster issues is the AC &#x2013; observed that there was an excessive amount of data variables to be collected in the pilot projects and recommended a simplification of the process to eliminate the collection of redundant data. This has also been acknowledged in the new policy.
The expert from Lantm&#xE4;teriet did not produce any reports of their own. The majority of the information provided in their final report is the exact same as in the final report produced by the AC, although translated to English. Thus, it is difficult to distinguish between the results achieved by the AC as a whole and the results of the specific contribution by SIDA and Lantm&#xE4;teriet. It should be noted that the expert from Lantm&#xE4;teriet began their work late in the process, when most of the Committee&#x2019;s meetings had already taken place. Nevertheless, the expert participated in the final stages of the process including the formulation of the final reports and recommendations which served as a basis for the new cadaster policy. In conclusion, the Advisory Committee had a clear and important impact on formulation of policy, but the individual impact of SIDA&#x2019;s contribution is difficult to be established.
An unexpected result is that Lantm&#xE4;teriet, and more specifically their expert, now has a deeper understanding of land and cadaster issues in Colombia which they previously did not have. Although this specific intervention was not extended (due to the limited capacity of Lantm&#xE4;teriet and despite the Embassy of Sweden in Bogot&#xE1;&#x2019;s willingness to continue the cooperation) it could prove useful in potential future interventions in the country or region.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10338" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1050203" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1176000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Colombia 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Colombia 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
