<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5519001301-COL-25012</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public private partnership Hub-ANDI Colombia 2016-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Public private partnership Hub-ANDI Colombia 2016-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">ANDI FOUNDATION har ans&#xF6;kt till Sida om finansiering p&#xE5; 6,7 MSEK f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;rande av projektet &#x201C;Business in development facility Hub&#x201D; under perioden 1 juni 2016 till den 31 jan 2022.
Projektet syftar till att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra den ekonomiska situationen f&#xF6;r kvinnor och m&#xE4;n som drabbats av konfliken eller i konfliktdrabbade omr&#xE5;den genom att underl&#xE4;tta inf&#xF6;randet av sm&#xE5;skalig produktion i v&#xE4;rdekedjan hos ankar f&#xF6;retag, genom inkluderande och milj&#xF6;m&#xE4;ssigt h&#xE5;llbara partnerskap mellan den offentliga och den privata sektorn.

Den totala projektbudgeten &#xE4;r p&#xE5; 9,4 MSEK varav Sverige avser att bidra med 39%.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ANDI FOUNDATIONhas applied to Sida for funding of 6,7 million SEK to carry out the project &#x201C;Business in development facility Hub&#x201D; for the period 1 June 2016 - 31 Jan 2022
The project aims at improving economic situation for women and men affected by conflict or in conflict affected regions facilitating the inclusion of their small scale production in the value chain of anchor companies, through inclusive and environmentally sustainable public-private partnerships. 
The project total budget is 9,4 million SEK, of which Sweden will contribute with the 39%.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This contribution aims at improving sustainable economic situation of women and men that have been affected by the internal armed conflict facilitating the inclusion of their small scale production in the value chain of anchor companies, through inclusive and environmentally sustainable public-private partnerships.

Output 1: Small scale producers are strengthened and highly competitive and are engaged in inclusive and environmentally sustainable public-private partnerships.
Output 2: Business sector includes competitive raw materials from small scale producers, as suppliers in their value chain.
Output 3: The Hub is recognized by all stakeholders as an articulator platform that is able to facilitate inclusive business with real impact on improving the quality of life of the vulnerable population and with strong gender and environmental perspectives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion ANDI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion ANDI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="250" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business &amp; Other Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="25010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Policy and Administration</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">175305.3234383217</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">175305.3234383217</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-01">175305.323438</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-28">175305.3234383217</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/55190013_55190013-1stamendmenttotheagreement-FAndi-Signed2019.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1st amendment to the agreement-Business in development facility Hub- F ANDI 2016-2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/55190013_55190013-SignedagreementSweden-FundacionAndi-2016.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement -55190013-Business in development facility Hub- F ANDI 2016-2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/55190013_55190013-SigneddeconamedmentandappraisalofcontribAndi2016-2022.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on amendment- Business in development facility Hub- F ANDI 2016-2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/55190013_55190013-signedDecisiononcontribution.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution-55190013-Business in development facility Hub- F ANDI 2016-2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In September 2019, an amendment to the agreement was signed with the aim of continuing to increase the number of partnerships, anchor companies, small-scale associations, allies and, consequently, direct beneficiaries.&#xA0;&#xA0; The goals have been updated and&#xA0; it is expected that, by the end of 2021:&#xA0; the number of beneficiaries will increase from&#xA0; 7,820 in June 2019 to at least 8,500; the number of anchor companies from 41 to at least 55; the number of small peasant farmer associations from 47 to at least 70; and the number of allies from 100 to at least 120.

Despite the problems caused by the current COVID-19 pandemic, in 2020 the Andi Foundation fulfilled its proposed goals. The small-scale associations, linked as suppliers, have increased from 47 to 75 and the number of committed anchor companies has increased from 41 to 49. The number of allies has also risen from 133 to 213. The partnerships for commercial links between companies and small growers associations, have improved sustainable economic conditions for 8,426 people (4,245 women and 4,181 men) in 2,061 productive units.

Due to the COVID-19 global crisis, between April and May 2020, the Andi Foundation carried out an analysis of all the projects and adapted the work plan for each one. Due to the limited access to communication technologies in rural areas and because of difficulties in the logistic distribution chain, Andi had to change the methodologies for collecting base line and progress indicators. In addition, they changed the communication channels to continue the accompaniment processes.&#xA0; They created, for instance, an agricultural line, (using telephone, WhatsApp, text messages or e-mail) to provide permanent support to small growers associations. They designed manuals, booklets, videos and audio instructional/guidance material containing technical, organizational, commercial and financial information such as: good agricultural practices; daily crop requirements; associates rights and duties; client technical requirements; financial training; savings strategies.&#xA0; It was only possible to re-establish field trips in September 2020 with biosecurity measures, but by November 2020 the majority of allies had still not been able to restart 100% of their operations.

During the last four years (2016-2020) the Andi Foundation has developed a&#xA0; total of 84 partnerships with the following results: 36 were terminated&#xA0; for various reasons such as: a lack of financial feasibility; the conditions were not viable for suppliers;&#xA0; lack of interest by companies or suppliers&#xA0; to continue with inclusive business. 17 were successfully completed with stable commercial relations and good results indicators. The other 31 were in different stages during 2020: 3 are in the pre-feasibility phase; 4 are in the feasibility phase; 18 are being implemented; 4 are in the completion phase; 2 are temporally suspended. More information of each project is detailed in the statement on narrative report.

Most of the projects have been significantly affected by the current COVID-19 pandemic. Many anchor companies have reduced their demand for supplies. The accompaniment process has also been affected because of the impossibility of conducting field visits.&#xA0; All participants have had to adapt the workplan and many virtual training sessions using virtual technology were held during the second half of 2020.

An important outcome, that was not envisaged at the beginning, is the inclusion of Mibanco (formerly Bancompartir), as a partner for savings, financial education and loans when needed. The report shows this partner participated in 10 of the 18 projects at the implementation phase, as well as in 10 of 17 projects at the closing phase. In 2020 Andi included other partners for financial training but the Embassy&apos;s goal is that the alliance with Mibanco can continue in 2021 and some of these partnerships could use the guarantee instrument for commercial loans.&#xA0;

The narrative report also contains progress indicators for 27 projects where families from the peasant farmer associations have increased incomes by 33%, on average and the associations have increased productivity by 9%, on average. Other positive changes have been an increase in the ability for peasant farmers to regularly put money aside for their future when they might be too old to be working and earning money. The anchor companies have also benefited from a reduction in costs of 6.3%, on average, by buying directly from peasant farmer associations thereby eliminating intermediaries. These results indicator evidence the positive impact of this project in the goal of improving sustainable economic situation of women and men that have been affected by the internal armed conflict facilitating the inclusion of their small scale production in the value chain of anchor companies, through inclusive and environmentally sustainable public-private partnerships.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55190013" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
