<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5519003602-COL-24030</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Financial Guarantee -Mibanco Colombia - Microcredits for rural sector -2019-2025</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Financial Guarantee -Mibanco Colombia - Microcredits for rural sector -2019-2025</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Denna insats syftar till att anv&#xE4;nda l&#xE5;n och garantier som ett instrument f&#xF6;r privatsektorsamarbete  f&#xF6;r rural utveckling</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This contribution aims at starting the use of loans  and guarantees as instrument for private sector collaboration, directed towards rural development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This contribution aims to facilitate loans and financial services to micro-, small- and medium-sized rural and urban-based enterprises, women-owned businesses, and targeted beneficiary populations (Colombian victims of the conflict, ex-combatants in the process of reintegration, people with disabilities, Afro Colombian and Indigenous peoples) in rural regions that have been especially affected by armed conflict and thereby have no or little access to financial services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="62001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mibanco S.A. (formerly called Bancompartir S.A.), Colombia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="62001" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mibanco S.A. (formerly called Bancompartir S.A.), Colombia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-06" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-06" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="240" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banking &amp; Financial Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="24030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Formal sector financial intermediaries</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="8.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja utvecklingsinriktad politik som st&#xF6;der produktiv verksamhet, skapande av anst&#xE4;ndiga arbetstillf&#xE4;llen, f&#xF6;retagande, kreativitet och innovation samt uppmuntra att mikrof&#xF6;retag liksom sm&#xE5; och medelstora f&#xF6;retag v&#xE4;xer och blir en del av den formella ekonomin, bland annat genom tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.3 - Promote development-oriented policies that support productive activities, decent job creation, entrepreneurship, creativity and innovation, and encourage the formalization and growth of micro-, small- and medium-sized enterprises, including through access to financial services.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">313276.8342078615</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">313276.8342078615</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-06">313276.834207</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">313276.8342078616</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On December 14th, 2018, after almost two years of an assessment process, the first Sida guarantee instrument was signed in Colombia and in Latin America. The agreement foresees the delivery of several reports to Sida Headquarters and to the Embassy in Bogot&#xE1;.&#xA0; 
&#xA0;
The bank has until last of August 2021, covered 4367 clients through 4511 loans in 69 of the 76 prioritized municipalities. This represents 528 additional clients and 630 additional loans since the last report from 31st of January 2020. The total amount covered by the guarantee instrument is 17.200.000.000 COP (approximately 4,8 million USD), which represents additional amount of 2.237.538.000 COP (approximately 590.000 USD), compared with the last report. This leaves the guarantee at a use of 44,5% very closed to the goal for 2020 that is 50 percent.
&#xA0;
There was a significant decrease of loans in trimester 2 and 3 this year largely due to the global Covid 19 crisis and the current situation of the country and the world in general, where many economic sectors have been affected and with a considerable drop in their income, as well as the five months of lockdown experienced as a measurement to slow down the pandemic.
&#xA0;
Nari&#xF1;o continue to be the region where most loans are disbursed, with 21 percent, followed by Antioquia, 14 percent, Atl&#xE1;ntico, 13 percent, and Cordoba, 8 percent. The report shows that most of the loans were granted to clients in the commercial sector, 54 percent, followed by the services sector, 24 percent, the industrial sector, 18 percent, and the agricultural sector, 4 percent. These numbers are consistent with the last report, hence there are no significant difference in the distribution of the loans in the different sectors compared to the last report. The bank has previously explained that in the commercial sector the clients are also involved in agricultural activities, but they classify their main activity as commerce. Since January there has been a slight increase in women as borrowers, from 49 percent to 50,3 percent. The goal is 52 percent for 2020. The most marked difference in terms of gender is present in the agricultural sector, where 56 percent of the loans were granted to men and 44 percent to women, followed by the industrial sector with 55 percent to men and 45 percent to women. In contrast, in the commercial sector the participation is shared 50%-50% and the in the service sector the women&apos;s participation is higher (55% vs. 45% of men)
&#xA0;
A large percentage of the clients have completed secondary school with a participation of 52% and a total of 2,308 clients, of which 50% are women. Very few have no education or uncompleted primary school. &#xA0;It is also important to mention that of the 286 clients who have completed and followed professional training, 56% are women. The majority of the borrowers have the socioeconomic category 1 or 2, which is a public measure that goes from 1 to 6 (with 1 being the poorest) and is linked to the place of residence, which determines the level of prices for public utilities. In 2020 the percentage of loans in rural areas was 44.5 percent, and the goal for 2020 was 45 percent.
&#xA0;
In May, the Bank made their first guarantee claim from Sida, which included 665 operations for an amount of 960.081.305 COP (approximately 267 000 USD), given that despite the recovery efforts made by the Bank, it was not possible to achieve the payment on time. Among the reasons for non-payment, the majority of the borrowers had the following reason: decrease in income/sales (314 operations); delay in payments (55 operations); domestic calamity (52 operations); no will of paying (49 operations); bankruptcy of the business (39 operations); other. The Bank continues to administrate the claims of the agreement established by their policies, through their offices, call centres and co-operative management as well as external agents.
&#xA0;
In 2019 and so far in 2020 the Bank has carried out financial education programs and sessions to which some of the clients with Sida&apos;s guarantee have joined. To advance their finances, organize their expenses and incentivize their savings models, given that within the objectives of Bancompartir, the priority is to grant credits responsibly in order to improve the quality of life of customers through the growth of their businesses.
&#xA0;
In order to maximize the effect of the guarantee the Embassy has started a work coordination process between Bancompartir and different partner organizations to be able to look for synergies, one of them being FAO. The Bank and FAO have started a dialogue in order to participate in different programs such as Financial Education, through topics such as: psychology for finances; financial awareness; savings and budgeting workshop; responsible debt among others; in order to contribute to the communities in meeting their goals through the different alliances that the Bank has. The objective is to start using the guarantee instrument as the next step in the gradual improvement process for all the entrepreneurs/ associations/ companies that have received seed capital through FAO and are now ready for indebtedness.&#xA0; After this first approach in September, a memorandum of understanding has been proposed by FAO in order to continue with the development of a work plan and the exchange of information between the two organizations to achieve the set objectives.
As requested by the Embassy, this last report included life stories, seven clients have been interviewed. This provides valuable information on the level of vulnerability of clients and helps us to conclude that the guarantee instrument is being used by the poorest people who without this instrument would not have access to commercial loans. Below two of those examples:

Ferneli Gomez in Medellin, Antioquia, has a recycling business. With the loan from Bancompartir that is backed by the guarantee, he has managed to grow his business when he made an investment in expanding. The first two months were difficult due to the pandemic but with the increase of plastic bottles used for antibacterial gel, his sales have increased.
&#xA0;
Lucia Realpe from La Cruz, Nari&#xF1;o, has a fruit and vegetable business, she has three children and two grandchildren that helps her out with the business. She needed a loan to be able to invest and expand her business. Her main goal has been to be able to buy a house. For her, investing in her business was the best decision she could make, since this helped her to combine her business and so be able to get closer to her goals every day and keep her family together with more options to get ahead.
&#xA0;
The Embassy&#xB4;s assessment is that the narrative report provides important information for assessing that the guarantee instrument is being used correctly.&#xA0; The report was approved and dialogue and coordination with other partners has continued during 2021.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55190036" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1050203" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1176000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Colombia 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Colombia 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
