<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5519003201-COL-16020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">N&#xE4;ringslivssamverkan ruta Motor 2</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public Private Partnership Ruta Motor 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Programmet Ruta Motor &#xE4;r den andra fasen av ett program som Sverige har givit st&#xF6;d till sedan november 2014. Bidraget syftar till att bryta intergenerations-cykeln av fattigdom f&#xF6;r utsatta unga genom Offentligt-privat partnerskap som f&#xF6;rser relevant arbetskraft till arbetsmarknaden. De tre avsedda m&#xE5;len &#xE4;r: 1; f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra anst&#xE4;llningsf&#xF6;rh&#xE5;llanden f&#xF6;r 1000 utsatta unga m&#xE4;n och kvinnor fr&#xE5;n Bogot&#xE1;, Medellin, Cali och Valledupar, 2; f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra deltagandet av privata f&#xF6;retag och deras koordinering med relevanta offentliga institutioner, 3; st&#xE4;rka det offentliga erbjudandet om yrkesm&#xE4;ssig tr&#xE4;ning och h&#xF6;gre utbildning f&#xF6;r att kunna svara till arbetsmarknadens efterfr&#xE5;gan.  
 
Genomf&#xF6;randepartnern &#xE4;r Neme Fundation som ocks&#xE5; genomf&#xF6;rde den f&#xF6;rsta fasen av programmet. Neme Fundation har undertecknat ett tidigare avtal med Svenska Ambassaden och har visat, sen 2014, &#xF6;verenst&#xE4;mmelse med avtalets f&#xF6;rh&#xE5;llanden. Granskningsrapporten har ocks&#xE5; visat en stark finansiell f&#xF6;rvaltning och internt kontrollsystem.  

Den totala budgeten f&#xF6;r fyra &#xE5;r &#xE4;r 20,5 miljoner SEK och det &#xE4;r f&#xF6;reslaget att Sverige bidrar med 10 miljoner SEK vilket representerar 47 % av den totala budgeten. Forts&#xE4;ttningsvis bidrar SENA med 24 %, Neme Foundation 10 %, Holding Group A 9 %, CHM Mining 68 %, Foundation Future 21 % och Plan International 0,4 %. Aktivitetsperioden kommer vara fr&#xE5;n f&#xF6;rsta juli 2018 till 31 december 2021.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The program Ruta Motor in the second phase of a program that has been supported by Sweden since November 2014. The contribution aims at breaking the inter-generational cycle of poverty for young vulnerable people through a public private partnership that provide relevant labor force to the market. The three intended outputs are, first, improving conditions for employment of 1000 vulnerable young men and women from Bogota, Medellin, Cali and Valledupar; second, improving participation of private companies and their coordination with relevant public institutions and, finally, to strengthen the public offer of vocational training and higher education in order that responds to the labor demand. This program also contributes to the UN SC resolution 2250,2015 as it aims at preventing young people from the effects of conflict, including displaced and prevent their connection with armed groups and therefore is aligned with the Swedish cooperation strategy with Colombia. 

The implementing partner is the Neme Foundation that has been also implementing the first phase of the program. The Neme Foundation has signed a previous agreement with the Embassy of Sweden and has demonstrated since 2014 compliance with the agreement conditions. The audit reports have also shown strong financial management and internal control system.

The total budget for four years is 20,5 MSEK and it is proposed that Sweden contributes with 10MSEK that represents 47% of the total budget, SENA 24%, Neme Foundation 10%, Holding Group A 9%, CHM Mining 8%, Foundation Future 21 1% and Plan International 0,4%.  The activity period will be from July 1st 2018 to December 31, 2021.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This contribution aims in the long term at breaking the inter-generational cycle of poverty for young vulnerable people through a public private partnership that provide relevant labor force to the market. The three intended outputs are, first, improving conditions for employment of 1000 vulnerable young men and women from Bogota, Medellin, Cali and Valledupar; second, improving participation of private companies and their coordination with relevant public institutions and, finally, to strengthen the public offer of vocational training and higher education in order that responds to the labor demand.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion Neme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Employment creation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="1.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2 - By 2030, reduce at least by half the proportion of men, women and children of all ages living in poverty in all its dimensions according to national definitions.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">1.2 - Till 2030 minst halvera den andel m&#xE4;n, kvinnor och barn i alla &#xE5;ldrar som lever i n&#xE5;gon form av fattigdom enligt nationella definitioner.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.a - Strengthen relevant national institutions, including through international cooperation, for building capacity at all levels, in particular in developing countries, to prevent violence and combat terrorism and crime.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.a - St&#xE4;rka ber&#xF6;rda nationella institutioner, bland annat genom internationellt samarbete, i syfte att bygga upp kapacitet p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er, i synnerhet i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna, f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rebygga v&#xE5;ld och bek&#xE4;mpa terrorism och brottslighet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.4 - By 2030, substantially increase the number of youth and adults who have relevant skills, including technical and vocational skills, for employment, decent jobs and entrepreneurship.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">4.4 - Till 2030 v&#xE4;sentligen &#xF6;ka det antal ungdomar och vuxna som har relevanta f&#xE4;rdigheter, d&#xE4;ribland tekniska f&#xE4;rdigheter och yrkeskunnande, f&#xF6;r syssels&#xE4;ttning, anst&#xE4;ndigt arbete och entrepren&#xF6;rskap.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.5 - By 2030, achieve full and productive employment and decent work for all women and men, including for young people and persons with disabilities, and equal pay for work of equal value.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.5 - Senast 2030 uppn&#xE5; full och produktiv syssels&#xE4;ttning med anst&#xE4;ndiga arbetsvillkor f&#xF6;r alla kvinnor och m&#xE4;n, inklusive ungdomar och personer med funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning, samt lika l&#xF6;n f&#xF6;r likv&#xE4;rdigt arbete.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">414250.2071251035</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">317262.2383908459</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">271452.92463381</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">97723.0528681716</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">-2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">414250.2071251036</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">317262.2383908459</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">271452.92463381</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">97723.0528681716</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-01">1150695.019791</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-28">414250.2071251036</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">317262.2383908459</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">271452.92463381</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/55190032_GrantAgreementRutaMotorII-signed02-07-2018.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement- 55190032-Public private partnership Ruta Motor 2- 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Ruta Motor program aims to improve employment conditions for vulnerable young men and women, through a public private partnership that works simultaneously along three axes: 1. The young participants, 2. The private companies and 3. The public sector. The report shows progress in these three areas: &#xA0; First, as regards young participants, up to the 31st of December 2019, 2,376 (44.6% women) satisfactorily completed the first cycle of the psychosocial support, from the 3,706 young people that were invited in 2018 to be part of the program. A further 822 participants (43% women) have started vocational training in SENA of which 175 were in Cali, 158 in Medell&#xED;n, 123 in Cesar, 315 in Bogota and 51 are from the Adolescent Criminal Responsibility System in Bogota. &#xA0; The aforementioned 822 participants had the opportunity to choose between 27 different programs related to the automotive sector (diesel, gas or gasoline engine maintenance, mining truck operations, auto electrical and electronic maintenance, vehicle and industrial machinery maintenance, painting) and others related to administration and logistics, useful for every sector and more inclusive for women. After 6 to 9 months of vocational training in SENA the first 251 participants (61% women) started internships in different companies. &#xA0; In addition to SENA&#x2019;s vocational training, other partners such as Fundaci&#xF3;n Plan and COMFACESAR (Family Welfare Fund Institute, Cesar), provided financial training to 164 female and 107 male participants. In alliance with the National Public Service Employment Institute (UASPE) and through the family welfare fund institutions, employment training was also given to 109 women and 99 men. With other partners such as Accenture y Adecco, approximately 50% of participants received additional training in: mathematical reasoning; learning to manage frustration; creativity and innovation; interest in learning; and &#x201C;learning to become digital&#x201D;. Finally, a virtual training program on Microsoft Office tools (including Word, Excel and Power Point) is also permanently available online. &#xA0; The dropout rate in 2019 was 8.7% and therefore only 72 participants, from the original 822, stopped their training in SENA due to a variety of reasons such as: a lack of interest in technical training; prioritizing work over study; low academic performance and sanctions by SENA; family conflicts; difficulties with the academic workload; unjustified absences; health issues; need to care for family members with health problems; taking up work opportunity to deal with financial hardship. To counteract the dropout rate, the Corporacion Juntos Construyendo Futuro undertook different activities, as part of the psychosocial accompaniment process, including raising awareness with participants about the need to: comply with academic goals; have greater dialogue with family and teachers to identify and prevent motivational problems; additional academic support to overcome basic competence weaknesses. In addition, the Neme Foundation increased its contacts and dialogue with companies to promote economic incentives. &#xA0; Secondly, in order to increase the commitment from private companies, during 2019 the Neme Foundation held bilateral meetings with 32 companies from the automotive, mining and textile sectors: to raise awareness about the advantages of being part of the partnership; and to share the profiles of participants. The Neme Foundation has established partnerships with other foundations such as Fundaci&#xF3;n Plan, Cuso International to carry out complementary activities and in 2019 the Association des Femmes d&#x2019;Am&#xE9;rique Latine (AFAL) joined the partnership to provide fill existing gaps such as lack of connectivity, uniforms, transport etc. that might be needed by participants to continue in the program. &#xA0; In 2019, as part of the new partnerships with foundations from the private sector, the Neme Foundation joined the Global Apprenticeship Network (GAN), sponsored by the ANDI Foundation and promoted the project with representatives from various private and public entities that are part of the network. In addition, Ruta Motor actively participated in meetings and workshops held by Fundaci&#xF3;n Corona for the formulation of the Global Opportunity Youth Network initiative/project. &#xA0; Finally, as regards the public sector, progress was made with some partners but there were significant delays caused by the change of the national government in the August 2018 elections that resulted in changes to the leadership of some national institutions such as SENA, the Colombian Family Welfare Institute (ICBF) and the National Public Service Employment Institute (UASPE). &#xA0; The formal MOU with SENA was only finally signed in June 2019. The Neme Foundation had tried to formalize SENA&#x2019;s commitment and a continuation under the previous agreement as the young participants that had completed the first cycle were scheduled to start in October 2018. However, the change in leadership and in procurement principles has affected the previously good relationship that had existed between the Neme Foundation and SENA. This has resulted in a six-month delay in planned activities. As all the participants that should have entered SENA before December 2019, will now only start sometime in 2020, an amendment to the MoU will be signed, extending the activities period until December 2020. &#xA0; The partnership with the National Family Welfare Institute (ICBF), that was signed in 2018 to include participants from the Adolescent Criminal Responsibility System, continued in 2019, including 51 participants from that system in Bogota. &#xA0; The Neme Foundation had a fluent dialogue with the offices of local mayors in Bogota, Medellin and Cali, and has established new contacts with the offices of local mayors in five municipalities of Cesar. However, as newly elected authorities started in January 2020, new relationships must now be established for the coming years.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55190032" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1050203" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1176000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Colombia 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Colombia 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
