<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5519002301-COL-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategic Peacebuilding Activities OIM OACP</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Strategiska fredsbyggande aktiviteter</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projektet syftar till att bidra till att f&#xF6;rbereda samt st&#xE4;rka det lokala samh&#xE4;llet och regionala statliga myndigheter/institutioner f&#xF6;r ett aktivt och konstruktivt deltagande i fredsbyggande insatser, i linje med Colombias regerings strategi f&#xF6;r fred (Paz Territorial). Huvudsyftet &#xE4;r att bygga upp ett f&#xF6;rtroende inom regionerna, fr&#xE4;mja institutionell f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rkning och att effektivt kommunicera till regionerna vad det inneb&#xE4;r att bygga fred. I linje med detta har OACP prioriterat tre komponenter f&#xF6;r att n&#xE5; de f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade resultaten: 1) En mekanism f&#xF6;r att finansiera nio fredsbyggande projekt som utformas och genomf&#xF6;rs av lokala organisationer f&#xF6;r offer, f&#xF6;r att bidra till en b&#xE4;ttre f&#xF6;rst&#xE5;else f&#xF6;r offrens r&#xE4;ttigheter och f&#xF6;r att leda processer som fr&#xE4;mjar samexistens, 2) fastst&#xE4;lla en kommunikationsstrategi f&#xF6;r att &#xF6;ka medvetenheten och samla in information relaterad till f&#xF6;rsvunna personer inom ramen f&#xF6;r den interna v&#xE4;pnade konflikten, 3) utforma och implementera integrerade skyddsmetoder f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rhindra rekrytering av pojkar och flickor till illegala v&#xE4;pnade grupper.

Projektet &#xE4;r relevant f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja och st&#xE4;rka fredsskapande processer i regionerna som ska bidra till en h&#xE5;llbar fred i Colombia.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategic activities on peace building to be developed to support the  preparation phase for the post agreement between the Colombian  governement and Farc guerrilla and leaded by the High Commissioner    for Peace.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the project is to contribute to strengthen the capacity of governmental entities and the civil society regarding peace building, in line with the government&apos;s Territorial Peace approach (Paz Territorial). The main objective is to build trust within the communities, promote institutional strengthening and communicate effectively on what it means to build peace from the regions.
The project was initially planned to be implemented during a period of 11 months, from December 2016 to November 2017 at the initial phase of the implementation of the Peace Agreement signed in 2016. Due to the political context, some activities were delayed, others had to be changed, and the project was amended four times. Additional resources were approved&#xA0;in two occasion. The project was finally implemented&#xA0;from December 2016 to June 2019 with a total contribution of&#xA0;SEK 12 156 187.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="47066" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM/International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47066" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM/International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">350610.6468766435</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">643500.6435006434</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">264659.8545521494</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">350610.6468766434</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">643500.6435006431</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">264659.8545521498</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">-226922.5924840114</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-28">1262198.328755</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">350610.6468766435</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-28">643500.6435006434</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-28">264659.8545521495</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">-226922.5924840114</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project contributed to the implementation of the government of President Santos&apos; peace policy with a territorial approach: &quot;Paz Territorial&quot;, in the initial months after the peace agreement was signed and after the peace referendum, in which 50.2% of the participants (approximately 40% of the colombian population) voted NO for the peace process (October 2016).
The main&#xA0;results achieved by this contribution are:
1) Component 1 Capacity building and dialogue for peace building: Due to the political context in the regions, the initial activities planned for this component were changed. Two new main&#xA0;activities were approved to&#xA0;contribute to the implementation of the government&apos;s peace policy under the leadership of the&#xA0;Office of the High Commissioner for Peace (OACP). The aim was to&#xA0;create&#xA0;conditions and capacities in the transition process from&#xA0;war to peace in Colombia through: 1)&#xA0;a citizenship participative process in the territories and through 2) regional dialogues for reconciliation (Di&#xE1;logos Improbables).
1) A common message, &quot;En Voz Confio&quot;, promoting a common dialogue on peace, was designed and implemented in 30 cities&#xA0;in different regions of the country (Caribbean, Amazonian, Andean, Pacific and Orinoquia). 9,300 persons participated (40% women and 60% men) in the different activities, focusing in recovering&#xA0;the confidence in peace by the communities.
2) 28 leaders (12 women and 16 men) from the department of Cesar and 25 leaders (8 women and 17 men) from the department of Meta, representing&#xA0; different sectors and political positions, participated in the &quot;Dialogos Improbables&quot;. A methodology was developed together with the leaders and implemented in&#xA0;10 regional meetings (5 in Meta and 5 in Cesar). A set&#xA0;of commitments were agreed to contribute to the development of the regions, which were shared with governmental authorities, civil society organizations and political leaders. The most important aspect&#xA0;in this activity was the process undertaken by the participants, with discussions dealing with&#xA0;rural development, environment, human rights and peace building issues for their regions. This contributed to find common issues for peace building, despite their political differences and to establish a network among them.
2) Component 2 Information and gathering process of disappeared persons: This component was also changed from the original one agreed, due to changes in OACP&apos;s responsibilities. Capacity building activities were implemented to&#xA0;former FARC combatants, oganizations from the civil society, personnel from the Ministry of Defence and the Armed Forces, on how to&#xA0;gather humanitarian information on missing persons. 201 persons participated in an activity in San Vicente del Cagu&#xE1;n where 166 biological samples were gathered to contribute to find information on 128 cases of forced disappearance.
The results of this component where an important input to the Unit for Search of Missing Persons.
3) Component 3 Documentation and historic memories of the peace negotiation process: the objectives wer fulfilled. The information on the peace process between the Colombian government and the FARC was gathered, organized, analyzed, selected and included in the 10 books published, called &quot;Memory Library (&quot;Biblioteca de la Memoria&quot;). This publication was launched and distributed in Bogot&#xE1;, Villavicencio, Cali, Florencia and Carmen de Bol&#xED;var. Organizations from the civil society, governmental entities, universities, schools and the international community received copies of these memories.
The translation of a summary of this publication in English was not possible due to the changes in the government in 2018. The new Office of the High Commissioner for Peace informed IOM that there was no interest in this activity and it had to be cancelled.
4) Component 4 Security guarantees:&#xA0; Two confidential documents with information on security risks for former combatants, their families and communities in Arauca, Cauca, Sur de Bol&#xED;var and Catatumbo were elaborated by&#xA0;Fundaci&#xF3;n Ideas para la Paz (FIP) and submitted to the OACP. This information was an important input for OACP&apos;s peace policy with reliable and updated information.
Eight Public documents were also drafted by the FIP on the political, social, economic and environmental context of these&#xA0;regions&#xA0;and&#xA0;published in the web portal &quot;Verdad Abierta&quot;, contributing to the national debate on the situation in these regions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55190023" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1050203" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1176000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Colombia 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Colombia 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
