<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11586A0101-COL-16080</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">NIR - Social Dialog</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIR - Social Dialogue</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the Colombian economy to grow sustainably and to break the inequality of today&#x2019;s system, to meet the challenges of tomorrow&#x2019;s labour market and overcome decades of conflict that has deeply fragmented the society, changes at the labour market are necessary. Such developments are strongly dependent on a shift in culture and perception not just in the dialogue between the employers and the trade unions, but within these groups and bodies themselves. The project  &#x201C;Private Sector contribution to Social Dialogue in Colombia&quot;,  NIR (International Council of Swedish Industry) intends to strengthen the dialogue through building trust and providing access to tools among actors at different levels at the labour market.

This two and half year project further intends to support Colombia&#x2019;s OECD implementation process by addressing needs identified in the recent OECD assessments of the labour market. The project focuses on three components; to create a labour market dialogue initiative, to develop the mediation mechanism for the labour market at firm level as well as to design local social dialogue workplace programs - all activities with a shared long-term outcome; to achieve an improved capacity for a sustainable social dialogue. The project starts with an initial phase of six months, to ensure that the specific plans are developed and modified in close cooperation with local stakeholders.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">F&#xF6;r att den colombianska ekonomin ska v&#xE4;xa h&#xE5;llbart och bryta oj&#xE4;mlikheterna i dagens system, m&#xF6;ta utmaningarna p&#xE5; morgondagens arbetsmarknad samt &#xF6;vervinna &#xE5;rtionden av konflikter som har splittrat samh&#xE4;llet, &#xE4;r f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar p&#xE5; arbetsmarknaden n&#xF6;dv&#xE4;ndiga. S&#xE5;dan utveckling &#xE4;r starkt beroende av en f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndring av kultur och uppfattningar, inte bara i dialogen mellan arbetsgivare och fackf&#xF6;reningar, utan inom dessa grupper och organisationer sj&#xE4;lva. Under projektet  &#x201C;Private Sector contribution to Social Dialogue in Colombia&quot;, avser NIR att st&#xE4;rka denna dialogen genom att bygga f&#xF6;rtroende och ge tillg&#xE5;ng till verktyg bland akt&#xF6;rer p&#xE5; olika niv&#xE5;er p&#xE5; arbetsmarknaden.

Detta tv&#xE5; och ett halv&#xE5;rsprojekt avser vidare att st&#xF6;dja Colombias genomf&#xF6;randeprocessen av Colombias nyligen godk&#xE4;nda OECD medlemskap genom att addressera de behov som identifierats i de senaste OECD-bed&#xF6;mningarna betr&#xE4;ffande Colombias arbetsmarknad. 

Projektet fokuserar p&#xE5; tre komponenter; att skapa ett arbetsmarknadsdialoginitiativ, att utveckla medlingsmekanismen p&#xE5; arbetsmarknaden samt att utforma ett arbetsplatsprogram f&#xF6;r sociala dialog p&#xE5; arbetsmarknadens  - alla aktiviteter delar ett l&#xE5;ngsiktigt m&#xE5;l, att uppn&#xE5; en b&#xE4;ttre kapacitet f&#xF6;r en h&#xE5;llbar social dialog. Projektet b&#xF6;rjar med en f&#xF6;rsta fas p&#xE5; sex m&#xE5;nader f&#xF6;r att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att de specifika aktiviteterna utvecklas i n&#xE4;ra samarbete med lokala intressenter.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of the programme Private Sector contribution to Social Dialogue in Colombia is to provide improved conditions for a Sustainable Social Dialogue. The program targets social dialogue on three levels; social dialogue among the labour market parties at 1) central, regional and sectorial level 2) the company and firm level and 3) the workplace level. The combination of these tracks is intended to be mutually reinforcing, and to provide several avenues to reach results. Thus,&#xA0;strengthen the dialogue through building trust and providing access to tools among actors at different levels at the labour market.
Hence, the project focuses on three components; to create a labour market dialogue initiative, to develop the mediation mechanism for the labour market at firm level as well as to design local social dialogue workplace programs - all activities with a shared long-term outcome; to achieve an improved capacity for a sustainable social dialogue.&#xA0;
This two and half year project further intends to support Colombia&#x2019;s OECD accession process by addressing needs identified in the recent OECD assessments of the labour market.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIR/N&#xE4;ringslivets Internationella R&#xE5;d</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIR/N&#xE4;ringslivets Internationella R&#xE5;d</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16080" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Dialogue</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">172604.2529687932</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">211508.1589272306</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">157442.6962876098</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">172604.2529687932</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">211508.1589272306</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">157442.6962876098</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-01">569594.034797</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-28">172604.2529687932</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">211508.1589272306</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-28">157442.6962876098</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/11586_11589-SignedAgreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement- NIR Social dialogue</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/colombia/11586_11586-Decisiononcontribution.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution 11586-NIR Social dialogue</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">As stated in the last conclusion on performance, dated the 5th of May, 2020, after a visit made by NIR in February 2020, the Covid 19 global crisis has forced them to postpone all activities until August 2020. NIR has also requested that the use of the budget is suspended for the time being and therefore they have also requested an extension of &#xA0;the agreement period (that initially went until the 31st of December, 2020) until October 2021 without additional funds.&#xA0; This amendment was approved on the 28th of September, 2020.
Regarding the first output, that aims at putting in place an operational structure for future dialogue between government, the three main national Trade Unions and employers (represented by ANDI) as part of the OECD agenda, the Embassy&#x2019;s assessment is that progress was very limited in 2020.&#xA0; This dialogue component is based on &#x201C;interaction-in-person&#x201D; due to the long and complex tensions that exist between the members of the group.&#xA0; As most of the members are considered as an &#x201C;at risk group&#x201D; due to age, any face to face dialogue took place during 2020.&#xA0; In addition, unfortunately, in January 2021 the President of one of the three main Trade Unions, the General Confederation of Workers (CGT is its Spanish acronym), Julio Roberto Lopez, died from the Covid-19 virus. Despite the different parties having confirmed the need for additional bilateral dialogue, separate from the normal official channels, as well as having confirmed the importance of continuing to jointly analyse the challenges posed by &#xA0;informality, the pandemic together with the lockdown measures and the polarized context made it difficult to reach any concrete results during the year.
Regarding the second output, that aims at reactivating a resource pool of mediators, the Embassy&#x2019;s assessment is that the alliance with universities has opened up new positive opportunities as it is an actor outside the social dialogue but recognized by all parties (Ministry of Labour, employers and workers). According to NIR, Universities will support&#xA0; reactivating the network with updated information as well as&#xA0; developing the idea of the creation of a Mediation Institute. The mediation component is recognized by all stakeholders as a possible way forward to help improve relations between employers and employees and as a necessary alternative to the current practice of addressing labour conflicts through lengthy judicial processes. It is an area in need of reform, as identified by the OECD which has &#xA0;recommended that Colombia set up a mediation mechanism outside the courts to handle labour conflicts.
In February 2020, before the Covid 19 crisis started, NIR came to Bogota and agreed on innovative conflict resolution activities together with the following Colombian Universities: Javeriana, Rosario and La Salle. In addition, the Ministry of Labour has also expressed its interest in being part of this component. &#xA0;As stated before, the activities were on hold between March and &#xA0;August 2020. However, during the spring, NIR coordinated the publication &quot;Labour Mediation and Labour Conflicts in Colombia&quot; edited by Tirant Lo Blanch and the Pontificia Universidad Javeriana de Bogot&#xE1; that was published in June 2020. The proposed amendment to the agreement included a new digital initiative of an Alternative Conflict Resolution Mechanism (MASC is &#xA0;its acronym in Spanish), together with ILO, the Ministry of Labour, the US Federal Mediation &amp; Conciliation Service, the Javeriana University and the Swedish Mediation Institute in the sectors of extractive and mining, energy, banking and agriculture. During the autumn, one out of four planned MASC-webinars have been held for the mining sector with the participation of the Director General of the Swedish National Mediation Office, Ms. Irene Wennemo.&#xA0; Social dialogue in the mining and energy sector is very relevant as they have strong Trade Unions with a long tradition of conflict management and solid negotiation processes. Despite the levels of conflict, the parties are open to dialogue and it is common for them to reach agreements. After the meeting and listening to the experiences of the United States and Sweden, the participants found the creation of a Mediation Institute an interesting idea.
the Embassy&#xB4;s general assessment is that the impact of the project has unfortunately been lower than expected.&#xA0; Social dialogue is very relevant in the current polarized context and the Embassy is aware of the additional challenges presented &#xA0;by the current Covid 19 global crisis. The second component made significant progress through the alliance with universities. However, apart from the participation by the head of the Swedish Mediation Institute, it is difficult to value NIR&#x2019;s added value.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="11586" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1050203" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1176000000.0" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <title>Colombia 2016-2020</title>
    <titleSV>Colombia 2016-2020</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
