<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-29-2012-6142-998-43082</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">All-spin-wave Logics</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">All-spin-wave Logics</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">In some solids the atomic magnetic moments, determined by electron spins, exhibit an ordering thanks to the so-called exchange forces between the electron orbitals. These materials are called ferro- and ferri-magnetics. At proper conditions a microwave field can excite vibrations or waves in such spin systems at very high frequencies, of 1 - 100 GHz. The most important property of spin waves is that their group velocity is of three-four orders less than the velocity of electromagnetic waves. This means that at a given microwave frequency the wavelength of a spin wave is of micrometer scale, and, hence, the dimensions of spin wave- based functional elements can be significantly reduced. Moreover, the spin wave wavelength can be conserved to be constant at different frequencies by adjusting bias magnetic field. It should be noted that spin waves possess very rich properties, which are highly interesting both for fundamental science and for applied microwave and computing technologies. For example, almost all the known in physics nonlinear phenomena have been realized by using spin waves. The spatial and temporal bright and dark solitons (signal compression), three-wave mixing and second harmonic generation (synthesis of a new signals) and parametric spin wave amplification (transistor-less signal amplifiers) have been reported and implemented in functional spin wave devices. Recent advances in the field of magnetic dynamics are focused on the realistic objective of using spin wave technology in new nano-computing architectures. The main advantage of Spin-Wave technology is that an ensemble of coupled spins transmits energy through a perturbation of magnetic polarization without electron transport. This opens a way for reducing the dimensions of ?magnetic informational channel? (to few nanometers) excluding losses of a signal and the channel thermal damage (overheating) that usually takes place in current conductors. The principal advantages of spin-wave based microchips was described by A. Khitun at all in Nanotechnology, Vol.18, p.465202 (2007) where the authors describe how spin-wave logics can be used in nano-dimensional processors. In this collaboration work we plan to realize a number of technological steps, experimental and theoretical studies to fabricate prototypes of some all-spin-wave processing elements based on interferometric principles of operation, and by using fast magnetic field excitation of spin precession in dielectric ferrites.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of this proposal is to acquire a new practically important knowledge about spin dynamics in micro-and nano-sized ferromagnetic structures. In particular, under the grant we plan to concentrate our studies on the development of some all-spin-wave logic elements for perspective *magnetic* processors, by using reach properties of magnetic excitations: spin waves and vibrations. We expect for a significant advance in the topic by combining the experience of Sweedish collaborators in the synthesis of new thin-film magnetic materials, and the experimental experience of the Mexican team in spin-wave and optical signal processing. The important point of our idea is to use a *shock* excitation of spin precession, in contrast to the classic excitation by monochromatic microwaves. The spin precession and its cancellation will be stimulated by fast electric currents with picosecond-range transition times. The all-spin-wave logics will be built on the basis of micrometer and sub-micrometer size spin-wave interferometers or coupled resonators. It is planned to use thin-film ferro-oxides as the material for the microchip design. This work can be considered as a part of a long term program on the creation of nanometer size (or even a single atomic chain) informational interface between quantum processing elements, such as a magnetic defects. We expect that our collaboration will give mutual benefits for both Swedish and Mexican participants.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-29" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Swedish Research Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University, college or other teaching institution, research institute or think-tank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Swedish Research Council</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 546 44 000</telephone>
   <email>vetenskapsradet@vr.se</email>
   <website>www.vr.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Box 1035, 101 38 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">36848.2466375975</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">34985.9327395443</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">28472.1151222521</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-11-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-11-22">106368.833931658</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-28">34985.9327395443</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-28">-53337.050526141</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://upload.openaid.se/document/ingen-myndighet-vald/generella-bidragsvillkor-2013.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Generella bidragsvillkor 2013</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
