<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41210098-FGG3BE</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41210098" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Both ENDS</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fair, Green and Global Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Fair, Green and Global Alliance (FGG) aims to increase the power and decision-making influence of organised, mobilised and informed civil society, especially women, to advance fair and green trade and value chains. FGG believes that poverty, inequality and exclusion are caused by power asymmetries. We see the unprecedented power of capital over people and planet as the primary obstacle impeding realisation of fair and green trade and value chains. The FGG programme focuses on recalibrating power within the global architecture of trade and value chains by amplifying the voices of targeted rights-holders &#x2013;  small producers and traders, workers, fishers, rural and Indigenous peoples, religious and ethnic minorities, and migrants, especially the women and youth among them &#x2013; who are practising, claiming or defending human rights and fair and green economic practices, and/or whose rights are being ignored, threatened or violated by corporations and/or governments. We aim to transform social relations so that these rights-holders&#x2019; voices are heard and heeded. FGG&#x2019;s eight members (ActionAid, Both ENDS, Clean Clothes Campaign, IT for Change, Milieudefensie/Friends of the Earth International/Friends of the Earth Europe, Samdhana Institute, SOMO and the Transnational Institute) cooperate with some 1000+ partners and allies in our many worldwide networks to strengthen collective capacities to advance a common vision of fair and green trade and value chains.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41210098" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Both ENDS &#x2013; Alliance</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41210098" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Both ENDS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41210098" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Both ENDS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Both ENDS</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>https://www.bothends.org/en/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="3"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2022229</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2059773</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="Intrest">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">6196</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Negative intrest 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-04">10492740</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-10">1213337.52</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-07">808892.48</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">445061</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">364613</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">1842871</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41210098-FGG3" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">agenda-setting, momentum-building and increased support</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># key actors (government, private sector, other) who put FGG policy/practice recommendations on their agendas (e.g. meetings, debates, media coverage)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="49"></target>
     <actual value="39">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) From July &#x2013; November 2021, following the years long call by CSOs including Both ENDS, for the need to reform EU trade policy the European Commission opened a public consultation on the Trade and Sustainable Development (TSD) Review (here civil society involvement is a key issue) seeking input from civil society. Both ENDS made a related submission: It will have to be seen what elements we have raised put on their agenda will be taken on board and addressed in their related communication [expected in 2022].
2) In December 2021, new Tanzanian politicians advising the President on Trade Policy, discussed the reviewing of current BITs signed by Tanzania and that are set to expire, after recommendations of FGG Partners. Both ENDS has been supporting with technical knowledge to CSOs in Tanzania.
3) In 2021, Ugandan Government officials requested the input of an FGG partner in Uganda, whose capacity on this topic was strengthened by Both ENDS, to understand the social impact of the investment national code.
4) In 2021, the African Union requested the input of a partner in Uganda, whose capacity has been strengthened by Both ENDS, to understand the possible social impact of the AfCFTA.

5) In 2021, after a Ugandan partner enhanced its media engagement with both print and broadcast we have seen increased media reports and publications on ECA financing in Uganda. Over 5 media channels have reported on ECAs in Uganda which has increased public awareness regarding the impacts of ECA financing on fossil fuels, unsustainable projects that have impacts on climate, economy as well as public debt.

6) In 2021, based on the meeting with local Indonesian communities, an Indonesian CSO and Both ENDS, ADSB put remedy and improved due diligence on its agenda for the resolution of the complaint procedure in relation to the support provided by ADSB for the CPI reclamation project. These include recommendations on incorporating a specific gender due diligence policy, and recommendations to defend civic space in countries where the supported projects of ADSB take place. (g) (x)

7) In November 2021, 6 key media channels in the Netherlands covered that the Netherlands was not willing to join a coalition of governments at COP26 that committed to stopping public finance for fossil fuel projects overseas. Both ENDS informed journalists before and at COP26, as well as organised an official side event on Paris alignment of ECAs together with international partners.
https://www.volkskrant.nl/nieuws-achtergrond/rutte-roept-op-tot-actie-in-glasgow-maar-weigert-zelf-daad-bij-woord-te-voegen~bbb0a230/
https://www.nu.nl/klimaat/6165737/nederland-haakt-niet-aan-bij-plan-om-te-stoppen-met-investeringen-in-olie-en-gas.html
https://nos.nl/collectie/13871/artikel/2404345-vs-en-canada-stoppen-met-buitenlandse-fossiele-investeringen-nederland-tekent-niet
https://www.dutchnews.nl/news/2021/11/dutch-dont-sign-cop26-pledge-to-phase-out-foreign-fossil-fuel-funding/
https://www.trouw.nl/politiek/na-dagen-vol-onbegrip-en-verontwaardiging-ondertekent-nederland-toch-verklaring-fossiele-energie~b2ea5862/
https://www.ad.nl/binnenland/nederland-maakt-draai-toch-einde-aan-steun-fossiele-brandstofprojecten-in-het-buitenland~aae3c89c/

8) In 2021, following the media attention on COP26, 5 political parties raised parliamentarian questions and filed a motion to call for the government to commit to the COP26 statement to stop public finance for fossil fuels by the end of 2022. Both ENDS briefed parliamentarians for years on this issue.

9) In 2021, a Parliamentarian from Senegal visited the Sendou project showing specific interest in the impacts of the project on women after lobbying and media attention raised by a Senegalese partner CSO. Both ENDS contributed through financial support, joint strategising and knowledge exchange. (g)

10) In 2021, a Cameroonian partner enhanced its media engagement which led to increased media awareness and five published newspaper articles on the negative impacts of the Nachtigal hydroelectric dam on surrounding communities. Both ENDS contributed through financial support, joint strategising and knowledge exchange. 

11) In 2021, Partij voor de Dieren from the Netherlands asked parliamentary questions regarding FMO and the Agua Zarca case, including questions on gender justice, after advocacy efforts by Both ENDS.(g)
12) In December 2021, the Dutch Financieel Dagblad published a series of several articles questioning the functioning of Dutch Development Bank FMO after advocacy by Both ENDS and partners, creating momentum for further discussions on FGG priorities such as human rights due diligence, increased transparency and adequate control systems.
13) In April 2021, the Dutch Representation in the Asian Development Bank (ADB), the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs and the Dutch Ministry of Finance discussed Both ENDS recommendations on strong banking policies, on country systems safeguards, and consultations with civil society  during the expert session about the ADB requested by the Dutch MoFa and organized by the Dutch MoFa and Both ENDS, after lobbying in the Tuesday Group by Both ENDS.
14) In March 2021, the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs discussed Both ENDS recommendations on safeguards, consultations and accountability for development banks during the deep dive sessions organized by the Ministry after lobbying in the Tuesday group by Both ENDS.
15) In 2021, the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs discussed Both ENDS recommendations on the approach paper for Development Finance Institutions policy consultations during conversations with DFIs on upcoming consultations after a learning session on consultation by Both ENDS.

16) In 2021, FMO&#x2019;s Independent Complaints Mechanism (ICM) promoted that FMO remedies the violation of FPIC rights and harms done in the Barro Blanco project during a site visit, investigation and in conversations with Both ENDS after joint advocacy by BE and partners.
17) RSPO Board of Governors adopted a proposal by Both ENDS to host a special meeting on labour with partner CSOs and union representatives: the meeting took place and local partners, including the Indonesian plantation workers union &#x2013; represented on the RSPO Board, counseled by BE, CNV-International and Oxfam - informed the Board about pressing ground realities of human rights violations, especially women rights violations, and the difficulties faced by (female) workers, young women included, to be allowed to be organised and voice their concerns and demands without fear for reprisals. (g, x)

18) The Steering Group of the convenant Duurzaam Bosbeheer (incl. the Dutch MoFA, private sector actors and NGOs) discussed during its sessions Both ENDS&#x2019; suggestion to broaden the scope of a follow up to the Convenant to the EU arena and Parijs-Glasgow Climate Accord.
19) After a first open strategic brainstorm with Both ENDS on the role of Both ENDS, other INGOs, the Ministry, the embassies and expertise networks in the regions itself &#x2013; in terms of assessing risks, and preventive and remedial actions and instruments, the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs has agreed to follow-up with a dialogue and organise a follow-up meeting to brainstorm further about this with a number of embassies. (X)

20) In 2021, FMO profiled company-community programmes as proposed by Both ENDS, featuring the promotion of non-timber forest products and other sources of livelihood and forest conservation through dedicated company community collaboration. See FMO&#x2019;s special publication: https://future-minded.fmo.nl/future-minded-biodiversity/at-the-frontlines/

21) Ugandan prime-time media invited a Ugandan partner to various talk shows, to discuss  the violations of human rights of women working in commercial investment schemes. This is has increased general public awareness of this issue. Both ENDS contributed by offering financial support and a sounding board. ( X,g )
22) Prime-time Nigerian TV covered the call to stop the illegal logging and destruction of Cross River State rainforests see for example: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FlweqrrIq8g https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JOlL5R_KuEQ. This came after Both ENDS Nigerian partner co-launched an international campaign to generate pressure of the Cross River State government, including a petition which was signed by over 100.000 people: https://www.rainforest-rescue.org/petitions/1239/nigeria-save-cross-river-states-unique-forests
23) In September 2021, after four years of inaction, the Senior Divisional Officer of a commune in Cameroon and a representative of tan agri-company operating in this commune discussed the demands and recommendations of one local community and one local CSO network in relation to respecting the community&#x2019;s rights and sticking to contractual arrangements and rights frameworks (FPIC, and ensuring civil society consultation) during a consultation meeting initiated by a local Both ENDS partner and members of the  CSO network and promised to convoke a meeting between the director of the agri-company and the Chief of  the local community to review the existing MoU based on the flaws observed and discussed during the meeting. (x)
24) In 2021, various government officials and journalists from Chirundu District in Zambia discussed the importance of human rights  and responsible land-based investments guidelines (including the National Resettlement Policy) during a training organised by a local Both ENDS partner in the Monze district, whose deliberations made top headlines on a local radio station (Modern Voice radio on 99.5 FM).

25) Based on public outreach in 2021 through media (opinion piece in Vice Versa) and a direct letter to the Dutch Minister of Trade and Development Cooperation via the informal Food4All coalition that Both ENDS helped set up, Both ENDS has stressed the importance of including the voices of small-scale farmers and food producers in multilateral decision-making processes in general and spaces like the UN Food Systems Summit in particular. In his response, the Dutch Minister of Trade and Development Cooperation has acknowledged the concerns raised, inviting Both ENDS and other members of the Food4All coalition to more in-depth discussions on the issues highlighted with high-level officials at both the Ministry of Foreign Affairs as well as the Ministry of Agriculture, Nature and Food Quality. (x)
26) In 2021, the Dutch governmental task force that leads the organisation of the UN Water Conference in 2023, formally consulted Both ENDS in three occasions in which Both ENDS shared recommendations on how to organise the process and the conference itself in an inclusive manner and by ensuring the meaningful participation of civil society, particularly youth and women.
27) In 2021, following a Letter of Concern written by a large consortium of international, Dutch and Filipino civil society organisations, Atradius DSB invited FGG partners to share their environmental and human rights concerns about the NMIA project, which were subsequentially put on the agenda of Atradius DSB.
28) In 2021, following contact with Both ENDS, members of parliament submitted questions to the Minister of Finance regarding the role of Atradius DSB and the provision of an export credit insurance to Boskalis for the land development and dredging activities for the New Manila International Airport.
29) In 2021, following a Letter of Concern written by a large consortium of international, Dutch and Filipino civil society organisations, Boskalis invited Both ENDS and other Dutch NGOs to discuss their impact mitigation plans concerning the land development and dredging activities for the New Manila International Airport.
30) In 2021, following requests by an FGG partner, the NCEA initiated a conversation with Atradius DSB to explore a potential independent review by NCEA of the ESIA associated with the New Manila International Airport for which Boskalis had requested an export credit insurance.
31) During the World Water Week in August, Both ENDS co-organised an official SIWI-seminar on the Politics of Water, for which 2 FGG partners set the stage from a justice point of view, and after which the issue was further discussed among (high-level) government officials, stakeholders from the private sector, knowledge institutes, and other civil society organisations.
32) During the World Food Safety Day in June, a national Kenyan TV Channel interviewed an FGG partner about the benefits of organic agriculture for safe and nutritious foods, after continuous outreach on the topic of the FGG partner the last few years (Both ENDS supported their work financially and by joint strategising).
33) In December 2021, The National Environment Management Authority (NEMA) of Kenya decided to host the World Wetlands Day celebration at Ondiri Wetland, which is a clear sign of the importance of this wetland and a recognition of the concerted efforts by Both ENDS and 1 FGG partner during the FGG 2 programme to promote the conservation of this wetland.
34) In December 2021, 3 local newspapers of Satkhira district Bangladesh covered the project of 1 FGG partner which talked to the newspapers during a field visit about the benefits that community-based Tidal River Management brings for the development of agroecological livelihoods. This is the result of continuous work on TRM in practice and outreach on the topic by the FGG partner (Both ENDS supported their work financially and by joint strategising).
35) In November 2021, the IOB evaluation unit of MoFA invited Both ENDS and 1 FGG partner to contribute to an evaluation regarding foreign policy coherence by the Netherlands on water, climate adaptation/ mitigation, and food security &#x2013; particularly focusing on Bangladesh for a case study. Both ENDS and the FGG partner stressed the importance of ecosystem restoration and inclusive approaches. This invitation is the result of continuous work and outreach on the topic.
36) In November 2021, after various conversations about the benefits of Tidal River Management initiated by 1 FGG partner from Bangladesh and Both ENDS, a Dutch and internationally renowned water consultancy firm brought together a potential consortium &#x2013; including Both ENDS and 1 FGG partner from Bangladesh &#x2013; to promote the implementation of Tidal River Management in south-west coastal Bangladesh by writing a project proposal to the Bangladeshi government for the strategic implementation of the Bangladesh Delta Plan.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="25">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We expect that 25 key actors, including local and national governments, parliaments, international organisations, and private actors from Africa, Asia and Europe (from e.g. Uganda, Kenya, Bangladesh, India, Indonesia, Mozambique and the Netherlands) will put FGG recommendations on their agendas regarding fair and green trade and investment agreements (incl. BITs, IIAs, and EU FTAs), and inclusive land governance, improvement of corporate accountability processes (i.a. at the RSPO and public financial institutions), financing transformative practices, and inclusive and sustainable water management and spatial planning.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">agenda-setting, momentum-building and increased support</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4x</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the recommendation a key actor puts on its agenda aims to contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="19"></target>
     <actual value="6"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">From these 25 actors, we aim for 7 policymakers and private actors from Asia, Africa and Latin America, including from India, Indonesia, Kenya, and Mozambique ), to put an FGG recommendation on their agenda that contributes to defending or advancing civic space. These recommendations concern among other things improved civil society engagement in decision making processes regarding land governance, corporate accountability processes in the palm oil sector, and water-related spatial plans and infrastructure.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">agenda-setting, momentum-building and increased support</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4g</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the recommendation a key actor puts on its agenda aims to contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="5"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">From these 25 actors, we aim for 5 policymakers and private actors from Asia, Africa, Latin America and Europe (incl. The Netherlands) to put an FGG recommendation on their agenda that contributes to gender equality. This agenda-setting concerns, among other things, protecting women&#x2019;s rights in the palm oil sector, inclusive land governance (incl. implementation of VGGTs and agroecology &#x2013; which both have gender justice at their core).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments increasing democratic decision-making</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># instances in which key actors adopt and/or implement FGG policy/practice recommendations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7"></target>
     <actual value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) In July 2021, UNCTAD agreed to let CSO participation in the events around UNCTAD 15 be determined by self-nomination procedures rather than selection by UNCTAD. This provides more room for civil society organisations to determine how to best make their voice heard at these events. This decision followed joint lobby and advocacy by the wider CSO network actively engaging with UNCTAD 15 that was supported and facilitated by Both ENDS (x)

2) On 2 dec 2021, 67 countries agreed on the text for the so called Joint Statement Initiative on domestic regulation at the WTO. As one of its elements it also for the first time translates the principle of gender equity into binding WTO law. Unjustifiable gender discrimination with respect to granting licences for foreign services providers will now be illegal and sanctionable by the WTO dispute settlement mechanism. This follows long time advocacy by Both ENDS  towards the Dutch Government to translate the principle of gender equity  into enforceable hard law. (g)

3) On 29 June 2021, WTO agreed to extend TRIPS transition period for LDCs until 1 July 2034
(https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news21_e/trip_30jun21_e.htm). BE actively lobbied for that targeting EU and NL gov and BE was also part of a joint letter targeting the WTO .

5) In 2021, with financial support of Both ENDS following advocacy by a Ugandan partner and their CSO colleagues the Ugandan Ministry of Water and Environment incorporated CSO comments into the final country&#x2019;s climate change adaptation plan and Nationally Determined Contributions to climate change. It adopted a clear roadmap for phasing out fossil fuels and recommitted to promote clean energy such as solar and wind in Uganda. The comments were generated from community and CSOs consultation and focused on ensuring that the rights of women, youth, and other vulnerable groups are taken care of.
6) In 2021, the UNCCD has incorporated recommendations on women land tenure from Both ENDS and a partner network of CSOs into the UNCCD Gender Tool that will help countries better understand how land use policies impact women and men differently (g).
7) In 2021, the Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs launched the &#x2018;Reversing the Flow&#x2019; program which was strongly informed by recommendations from FGG2 with regards to the structure and goals of the programme, including supporting local CSOs to shift the power to grassroots organizations within the context of landscape management, as well as the accessibility of Dutch funding to grassroots organizations. This programme is a direct result of Both ENDS&#x2019; advocacy for more inclusive programming and small grants funding to grassroots organizations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim for 2 instances in which UNCCD policymakers, (district) governments mainly in Asia (including. the Philippines, India, and Indonesia) adopt or implement FGG policy/practice recommendations concerning i.a. (elements of) the VGGTs leading to increased protection of communal and individual land rights and action against land degradation, desertification and droughts.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments increasing democratic decision-making</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># key actors who support and/or promote FGG policy/practice recommendations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12"></target>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) In July 2021, The Secretary-General of the UN transmitted to the General Assembly the report of the UN Working Group on the issue of human rights and transnational corporations and other business enterprises  on Human rights-compatible international investment agreements. It includes a lot of demands and recommendations made by CSOs. For example it highlights the importance of &#x201C;developing an investment policy from the bottom up with the meaningful participation of all stakeholders, including civil society organizations, women&#x2019;s organizations and trade unions.&#x201D; Both ENDS and partners actively contributed to this process by e.g. the participation in regional consultation meetings of the working group and by providing written submissions] (x) (g)

2) In a letter to parliament in December 2021, the Dutch Government declares that it intervened at the EU level to strengthen the enforcement of the sustainability chapters in trade agreements. They also insisted on a timely publication of Sustainable Impact Assessments (SIAs). The government indicated they &#x2018;paid special attention to the input of organizations that are part of the national advisory groups under trade agreements&#x2019; &#x2013; in which Both ENDS participates and has been lobbying for this.
3) In December 2021, the policy makers of Burundi committed to review all current BITs for possible stopping and renegotiation during a workshop on ISDS clauses in BITs provided by two FGG partners from Uganda and Tanzania. Both ENDS provided technical knowledge and financial support.

4) In December 2021, policy makers of Tanzania committed to reviewing current BITs for possible stopping and renegotiation after a meeting with a Tanzanian partner. Both ENDS has been providing technical knowledge and financial support..

5) In 2021, the EU started a consultation towards strengthening the implementation of the TSD chapter in current FTAs. Both ENDS participated in the EU-Central America and EU-Andean countries DAGs and provided input in the consultation.

5a) The Dutch parliament adopted a motion {MOTIE VAN HET LID PIRI C.S. proposed 17 June 2021} requesting the Dutch Government to act on the EU level to support the so called COVID TRIPS waiver at the WTO  and to work at EU level to end European opposition to temporary suspension of patents. Both ENDS has been actively lobbying on this, targeting the EU and Dutch policy makers.

6) In 2021, through financial support and joint strategizing with Both ENDS, a Ugandan partner worked with like-minded Members of Parliament and established an ECA forum of 29 MPs (11 women and 18 men) who are passionate about transvestments and Just Energy Transition (JET). This group is currently spearheading the decarbonization agenda for ECAs at the Parliamentary level. The forum works with the Ugandan partner to carry out high-level advocacy on policy formulation using the evidence generated by the partner on impacts of fossil fuel projects on communities, especially on women, youth, environment, and economy. The forum also acts as a point of contact that the partner and communities are using to raise policy and legislative recommendations for transvestments.

7) In 2021, the UNCCD Intergovernmental Working group on Drought adopted various recommendations on how to improve cooperation, coordination, policies and financial instruments related to drought preparedness and response from a.o. Both ENDS in the written advice of the UNCCD to its member countries for COP15 that will take place in Abidjan in May 2022. Both ENDS actively participated in these negotiations in the UNCCD Intergovernmental Working group on Drought.
8) In 2021, the FAO has incorporated recommendations on women land rights and IPLC land rights from Both ENDS and a partner network of CSOs into the new FAO technical guide on sustainable land use restoration and halting land degradation (g)

9) In 2021, the local agricultural government agency in Satkhira District in Bangladesh co-developed, co-produced and promotes a crop calendar for agroecology for the Tala Upazila area &#x2013; combined with a training module for local farmers &#x2013; with 1 FGG partnering collaboration with farmer groups. Both ENDS contributed financially to this partner.
10) In 2021, after collaboration with 1 FGG partner, the local agricultural government agency in Satkhira District in Bangladesh promoted open fisheries in practice (the actual release of fish) as an alternative livelihood option for farmers living in polder areas where agricultural activity is not feasible during monsoon, which also showcases the benefits of Tidal River Management for river ecosystem restoration. Both ENDS contributed financially to the FGG partner.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim for 5 key actors, including national governments in WTO negotiations (incl. Uganda) and the EU Commission to support and promote FGG recommendations, by for example expressing support for CSOs views in WTO negotiations and developing an amendment to the EU-Mercosur deal.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments increasing democratic decision-making</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6Cx</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the adopted and/or implemented policies/practices by key actors contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 1 of the 2 instances of policy or practice change, (district) governments in Indonesia , the Philippines, and Malaysia will recognise and implement elements of the VGGTs, leading to increased involvement of CSOs and communities in decision processes and ultimately increased protection of communal and individual land rights.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments increasing democratic decision-making</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6Cg</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the adopted and/or implemented policies/practices by key actors contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">n 1 of the 2 instances of policy or practice change, UNCCD policy makers will incorporate the gender sensitive FGG recommendations on how to better link gender and land rights issues in the implementation of VGGTs in international UNCCD policy.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments increasing democratic decision-making</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5Cx</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the supported and/or promoted recommendation by a key actor aims to contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No targets for 2022.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments increasing democratic decision-making</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5Cg</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the supported and/or promoted recommendation by a partner aims to contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No targets for 2022.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">D</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments regulating the private sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6D</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># instances in which key actors adopt and/or implement FGG policy/practice recommendations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) In October 2021, an agreement was reached at the OECD to further restrict support for coal fired power plants. As of now, ECAs can only support abated (effective CCUS) coal-fired plants. While this is progress, continued support for associated facilities related to coal (infrastructure and mining) remains very problematic. Also, the OECD still fails to even start talking about serious restrictions on ECA support for oil and gas. Both ENDS, together with other NGOs from around the globe, advocated towards the European Commission to submit a strong proposal. It did, however push back from mainly Japan, Turkey and Australia limited progressive decision-making. https://trade.ec.europa.eu/doclib/press/index.cfm?id=2313 and https://www.oecd.org/newsroom/agreement-reached-at-oecd-to-end-export-credit-support-for-unabated-coal-fired-power-plants.htm
2) In June 2021, the Dutch Development Bank FMO adopted a new &#x2018;Position Statement on Fossil Fuels in Direct Investments&#x2019;,  which commits to bringing an end to new direct finance in the downstream and midstream coal and oil sectors in, after advocacy by Both ENDS. In October of the same year FMO reiterated this position by under signing the COP26 statement on international public support for the clean energy transition.
3) In 2021, the Common Fund for Commodities, a multilateral organization, implemented the recommendation to establish an independent complaints mechanism, after several advocacy letters and conversations by Both ENDS. (x)
4) In 2021, AfDB&#x2019;s Independent Review Mechanism (IRM) implemented recommendations on how it would be strengthened after intense lobbying by Both ENDS and two networks of partners. (x)
5) In 2021, FMO from the Netherlands, implemented the recommendation to end all financial relations with the Honduran bank FICOHSA, after several letters written by Both ENDS and 40 other partners, and media attention.
6) In 2021, the European Investment Bank (EIB) adopted Both ENDS&#x2019; recommendation requiring an informed decision making process, in which environmental, social and climate appraisal, risk categorization, as well as appropriate monitoring requirements are included in the documentation that is submitted to the board for approval after Both ENDS participation in the consultation.
7) In 2021, the European Investment Bank (EIB) adopted Both ENDS&#x2019; recommendation on due-diligence at pre-appraisal and appraisal stages to consider analysis of country context, including those related to human right track record after Both ENDS participation in the consultation. (X)
8) In 2021, the European Investment Bank adopted Both ENDS recommendation to include gender in relation to physical climate risk assessment, and widen the definition of gender to reflect non-binary and gender non-conforming communities in the new EIB ESF Standard 5 on Climate Change after Both ENDS participation in the consultation. (g)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim for 12 instances in which key actors such as public financial institutions and the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs (incl. FMO and ADSB), mostly engaged in activities in Africa and Asia to change their policies and/or practices, e.g. by divesting from fossil fuel projects, improving their CSR policy, improving compliance with OECD guidelines, compensating local communities negatively affected by publicly financed corporate projects, improving disclosure practices, and generally amplifying the voice of communities and CSOs including explicit attention for the voice of women, to ensure changed practice of their clients.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">D</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments regulating the private sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5D</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># key actors who support and/or promote FGG policy/practice recommendations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="13"></target>
     <actual value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) In December 2021, the Dutch state secretary of finance committed to doing an independent research into the due diligence process of ADSB regarding the export credit insurance for the Mozambique LNG project. The research will especially focus on the local safety situation and the human rights situation of the affected communities. This was the result of parliamentarians raising questions in a debate based on a media article about the results of a FOI request filed by Both ENDS, Milieudefensie, FOEE and SOMO in December 2020. The results of the research will be presented at the end of 2022. (x)
2) In November 2021, the Dutch government together with 34 other governments and 5 public financial institutions committed to stopping international financial support for fossil fuel projects by the end of 2022. This commitment requires all signing governments &#x2013; including the USA, the UK, France, Denmark, Sweden and the Netherlands - to stop ECA support for the fossil fuel sector by the end of the year 2022. Both ENDS advocated for this commitment for 6 years. At COP26 Both ENDS, together with partners, organised a side event, spoke to journalists and advocated directly to the delegations. https://ukcop26.org/statement-on-international-public-support-for-the-clean-energy-transition/
3) In 2021, FMO and the Ministry of Foreign Affairs committed to organizing two High Level Dialogues between FMO, the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Both ENDS, SOMO and other CSOs that should create the foundation for a more constructive dialogue between the attending parties, after advocacy by Both ENDS in structural dialogues. 

4) In March 2021, FMO expressed support for Both ENDS and partners recommendations to adopt a policy statement on Financial Intermediary (FI) investments. Throughout 2021, Both ENDS, together with SOMO and other civil society organizations held a dialogue on improving the monitoring and transparency of FI investments. These discussions led to the publication of a draft Position Statement on Environmental, Social and Governance Standards for Financial Intermediaries, showing that the bank is considering to improve social and environmental outcomes and development impact of its FI investments, after advocacy by Both ENDS. 

5) In May 2021, FMO expressed support for Both ENDS and partners recommendations to improve their disclosure practice, by inviting civil society stakeholders to provide input to a new to be development roadmap on disclosure, showing willingness to explore and commit to steps to increase transparency surrounding investments and improving its own disclosure standards, after advocacy by Both ENDS in the structural dialogue. Positive steps are that FMO has invited civil society to provide assistance in improving local disclosure practices, and that it is considering longer disclosure periods and publishing more extended project information. (x)
6) In 2021, during several joint lobby meetings, FMO and MIGA expressed support for Both ENDS and partners recommendations to get actively involved in monitoring and seeking solutions for harm done in the Salima project, after publication of research by Both ENDS and partners, joint advocacy and several letters, by starting a Facilitated Dialogue process.
7) In 2021, after joint advocacy meetings with a local CSO organisation and Both ENDS, Dutch dredging company Van Oord committed to some of our recommendations and agreed to locate lost members of this local Both ENDS partner and support this partner and members in an agriculture support project.
8) In 2021, European representation at the AIIB supported Both ENDS and partners&#x2019; recommendation to temporarily suspend loan disbursement to the Mandalika project level, Indonesia and requested a (resettlement) action plan during board meetings after Both ENDS and partners regularly informed the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs for updates and exchange.
9) In 2021, Dutch representation at the IDB promoted Both ENDS and partners&#x2019; recommendation to implement an action plan to repair adverse impacts and compensate communities in the Guatemala Hydroelectric Projects during board meetings after Both ENDS and partners regularly informed the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs for updates and exchange
10) In 2021, at least one municipal mayor showed support for the campaign of FGG partners in Manilla (the Philippines) against the NMIA project. Both ENDS provided financial support.
11) In 2021, legislators in the Philippines developed the &#x2018;People&#x2019;s Green New Deal&#x2019; and submitted it to congress, calling for (among other things) a moratorium on land reclamations in Manilla Bay and recognition of the role of  woman and youth in biodiversity conservation. This all happened after continuous advocacy of FGG partners in the Philippines (supported financially and strategically by Both ENDS)
12) Dutch Advisory Committee on Bio-feedstock adopted recommendations from Both ENDS regarding approval of bio-feedstock. They also incorporated these recommendations in their formal advice to the Ministry of Infrastructure and Water Management concerning the latter&#x2019;s framework of minimum criteria for bio-feedstock. With an emphasis on ensuring human rights - women rights in particular, consultation of local stakeholders incl. civil society, and land rights as well as ecological and climate sustainability. Both ENDS was invited as an expert for this Committee and offered oral advise and textual input on addressing social-environmental and women rights issues. (x, g)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim for 4 key actors, including public financial institutions such as FMO and the AfDB engaged in projects in mostly Africa to support FGG recommendations by expressing support for a different theory of change and disclosure practice, implementing a GBV plan, as well as supporting outcomes of a mediation process that benefit the local community.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">D</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments regulating the private sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6Dx</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the adopted and/or implemented policies/practices by key actors contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="3"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 7 of the 12 instances of policy or practice change, key actors will advance or defend civic space. For example, we aim amongst others for ADSB to install a communication protocol on how they involve input from local communities and for FMO to amplify the voice of communities and civil society organisations, including explicit attention for the voice of women, to ensure changed practice of their clients in various cases of corporate rights violations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">D</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments regulating the private sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6Dg</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the adopted and/or implemented policies/practices by key actors contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 3 of the 12 instances of policy or practice change, a public financial institution will for example establish a policy on assessing gendered impacts, generally amplify the voice of communities and CSOs including explicit attention for the voice of women, to ensure changed practice of its clients</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">D</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments regulating the private sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5Dx</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the supported and/or promoted recommendation by a key actor aims to contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="3"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">2 of these 4 key actors, including public financial institution such as FMO will make meaningful commitments to adapt their disclosure policies and increase their support for a different theory of change with improved involvement of CSOs and local communities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">D</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments regulating the private sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5Dg</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the supported and/or promoted recommendation by a partner aims to contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">3 of these 4 public financial institutions such as FMO will implement amongst others a GBV plan and support a new theory of change that reflects FGG&#x2019;s gender justice recommendations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">F</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments, government-backed agencies, donors, private sector actors increasing policy space and support for fair and green practices</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6F</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># instances in which key actors adopt and/or implement FGG policy/practice recommendations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No targets for 2022.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">F</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments, government-backed agencies, donors, private sector actors increasing policy space and support for fair and green practices</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5F</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># key actors who support and/or promote FGG policy/practice recommendations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) An Asian provincial government endorsed and supported proposals from an Asian partner and Both ENDS to undertake reforestation schemes using native species and seedlings raised by experts from indigenous communities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim for 2 key actor such as the Dutch parliament to support increased finance for transformative practices.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">F</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments, government-backed agencies, donors, private sector actors increasing policy space and support for fair and green practices</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6Fx</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the adopted and/or implemented policies/practices by key actors contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No targets for 2022.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">F</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments, government-backed agencies, donors, private sector actors increasing policy space and support for fair and green practices</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6Fg</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the adopted and/or implemented policies/practices by key actors contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No targets for 2022.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">F</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments, government-backed agencies, donors, private sector actors increasing policy space and support for fair and green practices</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5Fx</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the supported and/or promoted recommendation by a key actor aims to contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No targets for 2022.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">F</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments, government-backed agencies, donors, private sector actors increasing policy space and support for fair and green practices</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5Fg</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the supported and/or promoted recommendation by a partner aims to contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Both of these 2 key actors -including Dutch decision makers to support recommendations that are aimed at contributing to gender justice, such as the recommendation to increase finance, especially small grants, for gender just transformative practices such as agroecology.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SCS</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments, government-backed agencies, donors, private sector actors increasing policy space and support for fair and green practices</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6SCS1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of laws, policies and norms, implemented for sustainable and inclusive development</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="16"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="14"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SCS</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments, government-backed agencies, donors, private sector actors increasing policy space and support for fair and green practices</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6SCS2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of laws, policies and norms/attitudes, blocked, adopted, improved for sustainable and inclusive development</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="11"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">E</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">private sector actors respecting human rights and the environment</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6E</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># instances in which key actors adopt and/or implement FGG policy/practice recommendations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="13">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) In April and September 2021, as a result of advocacy by a group of Ugandan and international CSOs and media attention five private banks confirmed not to support the EACOP pipeline. Since it has become harder and harder for the project to go ahead, the project costs have increased from 3.5 to 5 billion dollar. Both Ends contributed with financial support, joint strategizing and knowledge sharing. https://www.energyvoice.com/oilandgas/africa/pipelines-africa/317029/total-eacop-french-banks/ ; https://www.banktrack.org/success/east_african_crude_oil_pipeline_more_banks_to_stay_away_from_troubled_total_project
2) In 2021, as a result of petitions, communiques and media campaigns by a group of Ugandan CSOs,  the network of community champions, youth leaders and women groups from the Albertine region they support, 5 fossil fuel companies (Total Energies, CNOOC, Petrolieres, PetroAfrik Energy, Niger Delta Petroleum Resources) that showed interest in the second round of oil exploration in the biodiverse Albertine garden licensing shied away, thereby halting the project. Both ENDS contributed via strategizing and knowledge sharing.
3) As a result of advocacy pressures by Both ENDS and a Nigerian partner a logging company has ceased logging in the ancestral forest of an indigenous people, and the construction of a logging road has been halted.

4) Both ENDS and FPP and partners advocated the RSPO Board to ensure independence of the RSPO Complaints Panel. The RSPO Board adopted our proposal to reposition the RSPO Complaints Desk.&#xA0;Consequently, the Complaints Desk no longer resorts under the Assurance Department but is directly line-managed by the CEO.&#xA0;This will help guarantee a strict division of tasks within the RSPO, whereby the Complaints Desk and the Secretariat units responsible for the domain of certification are separated &#x2013; thereby also creating more guarantees for confidentiality of single voices by whistle-blowers and WEHRDs. For background see:&#xA0;https://askrspo.force.com/Complaint/s/.(x)

5) Both ENDS, FPP and Oxfam advocated the RSPO to adopt a RSPO Outreach to Intermediary Organisations Programme in both Honduras and Guatemala and seek partnership with a Central American counterpart which commands the trust of the CSO-community. This proposal has been adopted by RSPO.  The outreach will specifically enhance capacity of CSOs, CBOs, unions and women organisations to act safely and freely by addressing human rights and women rights in particular of (female) workers and communities living adjacent to (expanding) palm oil plantations (x, g)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim for 3 instances in which private sector actors (specifically the RSPO and its members) mainly active in Asia and Europe but also in Africa (including the Philippines, India, Indonesia, and Uganda) adopt or implement FGG recommendations such as improved corporate accountability processes.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">E</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">private sector actors respecting human rights and the environment</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5E</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># key actors who support and/or promote FGG policy/practice recommendations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) The RSPO board agreed on recommended follow-up actions put forward by partners and summarized by Both ENDS (formally minuted, forth coming on-line: https://rspo.org/resources/board-of-governors/board-of-governors-meeting-minutes/2021) , including ways to address women rights issues (such as GBV) and human rights (workers&#x2019; rights such as freedom of association and dissent) in general working in risk prone situations, exposed to intimidation. (g, x)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim for 2 key actors part of the RSPO, active in Africa, Asia, or Latin America to support and promote FGG recommendations for example by recognising the rights of local communities (FPIC) and expressing support for stronger compliance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">E</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">private sector actors respecting human rights and the environment</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6Ex</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the adopted and/or implemented policies/practices by key actors contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2 of the 3 instances of policy or practice change, RSPO related actors will contribute to civic space by for example improving civil society involvement in their corporate accountability processes.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">E</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">private sector actors respecting human rights and the environment</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6Eg</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the adopted and/or implemented policies/practices by key actors contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 1 of the 3 instances of policy or practice change, the RSPO and its members will incorporate gender sensitive FGG recommendations on for example inclusion of women (and labourers&#x2019;) voices in related corporate accountability mechanisms.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">E</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">private sector actors respecting human rights and the environment</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5Ex</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the supported and/or promoted recommendation by a key actor aims to contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Of these 2 key actors we aim for 1 actor part of the RSPO active in Africa, Asia or Latin America to support and promote recommendations that contribute to civic space by recognising the rights of IPLCs to have a say in decision making about their territories (FPIC).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">E</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">private sector actors respecting human rights and the environment</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5Eg</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the supported and/or promoted recommendation by a partner aims to contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim for both these 2 RSPO actors mostly active in Africa, Asia or Latin America to support and promote recommendations that contribute to gender justice. For example, we expect RSPO to recognise the concerns and demand of CSOs regarding violation of women&#x2019;s rights in and around plantations, esp. those of female laborers and effects of displacement and changing land use systems for position and workload of local women.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Process</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">process</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">l</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">learning sessions organised by FGG members and partner organisations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Several learning sessions were organised by FGG members and partners:
With partners and Both ENDS:
- In February 2022 a learning session was setup by Both ENDS to learn about mutual capacity development successes and spaces for improving with our Ugandan Partner on Trade and Investment.
- Both ENDS and Milieudefensie organised regular calls with EGI and CSOs from Ghana and Togo to exchange information, learn from each other&#x2019;s experiences and reflect on strategies around the different projects that the partners oppose, as well as discuss our joint international strategy towards ECAs.
- On 22 November Both ENDS organized the meeting &#x201C;Online Exchange and Learning on Gender Justice&#x201D; with BE FGG staff and 15 partner organizations, in which we discussed how to (better) include gender justice in our work, in particular regarding lobby and advocacy vis a vis  financial flows, international trade, inclusive governance of natural land sustainable land and water use. Topics of sharing and discussion included working with local communities on gender justice, how to include gender in our lobby messages, how to better organize our internal learning and sharing.  Subsequently we discussed further collaboration and starting developing a narrative on gender justice.
- In order to support the Indigenous-Led Education (ILED) network &#x2013; consisting of 7 indigenous federations/organisations and CSO support groups in 6 countries, Both ENDS contributed financially, logistically and strategically co-hosted 2 webinars to exchange experiences and enable a process of joint strategizing
- An NGO from Uganda: Both ENDS, and Free University of Amsterdam (Law Clinic) collaborated to enhance the NGO&#x2019;s informed strategic choices and a tool box to address women rights violation in the plantation sector though Uganda&#x2019;s court system, thereby giving women a voice to express their grievances and to seek redress.
- A fundraising capacity training was prepared with partners in 2021 &#x2013; to be executed in 2022
Internally within Both ENDS:
- Meetings related to developing the new Both ENDS trade strategy, in which we looked back on based on lessons learnt from a.o. interviews with partners and experts</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Learning is an integral part of our programme cycle and is for example one of the key objectives of the yearly reflection meetings that we organise per thematic group. In these sessions we reflect on how our work is progressing, what lessons we can learn from this and if and where there is a need for different activities, goals and strategies. These lessons inform our decision making on if and how we adapt our activities, targets, and strategies. In addition, for FGG3, we have developed a learning agenda around various key topics (i.e. gender justice, youth responsiveness, dealing with shrinking space, alternatives/solutions for public financial systems and international trade and investment agreements, case development and upscaling transformative practices)on which we aim to strengthen our capacity. In 2022, we aim to learn on these topics together with our partners from Africa, Asia and Latin America through e.g. joint learning sessions and conducting landscape mappings around certain topics.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Process</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">process</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">g</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">lines of work in which FGG members and partners build upon gender analysis and incorporate gender justice in their strategy</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TRADE &amp; INVESTMENTS:

In the work of Both ENDS on the EU trade Agreements with Indonesia and the EU Mercosur agreement, Both ENDS highlighted the lack of sufficient analyses of gender specific implications of these trade agreements and the need to reform the EU Sustainable Impact Assessment procedure. We also highlighted the importance that recognition of the importance of gender equity has to move from soft law to hard law.

Partners from Uganda, Kenya, Mozambique and Zimbabwe held information workshops and advocacy trainings on the risks of the African Continental Free Trade Area for women&#x2019;s rights . Both ENDS had provided input for the material used in the trainings and financial support

One of the important outcomes in 2021 was that unjustifiable gender discrimination related to granting license for foreign service providers will be banned by 67 WTO member states, and becomes sensational under WTO law

FINANCIAL FLOWS:
In the different ECA supported projects that an Ugandan partner opposes and the advocacy towards the Ugandan government, capacities of women and youth have been strengthened and they are part of the advocacy that the partner does. In the advocacy towards governmental promotion of renewable energies, the position of women and youth in these solutions is on the agenda.

Gender justice has been a key pillar in the work that an Indonesian partner does with the communities in and around Makassar. Building on the experiences from the past years, BE and the partner together with the communities have build a strong case towards ADSB.
Building upon earlier analyses and strategy-building, 2 partners from Malawi, strengthened their constituency/network in the communities affected by the Salima project, their access to FMO and MIGA, and their leverage/influencing skills with focus on gender justice by organizing community meetings and workshops for accountability clubs, as well as joint strategy meetings and  advocacy towards FMO, MIGA and the project owner with Both ENDS.

INCLUSIVE LAND GOVERNANCE:
Partner in Brazil held a series of workshops between September and November 2021 especially for 20 women representatives of two communities in order to empower the women to be able to claim their land rights and advance their connection to their own lands again.

A partner in Peru held training on land rights and land monitoring with a specific focus to also include youth and women representatives of the communities.

2 partner organizations in Indonesia working with communities  that are highly affected by large scale palm oil production integrated gender justice aspects in their work. They set up separate women groups or trainings for women  in order to better map and  address how women are affected by the palm oil industry, their  daily  problems like water pollution,  diminishing fish as livelihood source, as well as  rights regarding land &amp;  natural resource use and their position in their communities .  In 2021 mainly the capacity of women  was strengthened regarding leadership capacities, FPIC and gender based human rights , Knowledge and skills building specifically on IWRM &amp;  gender  and on water monitoring on pollutions and biodiversity.  In the next years the skills and the outcomes of monitoring and testing will be used in local and national advocacy. One NGO partner shared their knowledge and skills with partner organizations in the GAGGA Alliance, directed at evidence building by women on pollution by the mining industry in 5 Asian countries.

Gender and women rights have been an integral part of capacity building in the fields of (i) CSOs efforts at regulating the palm oil sector and holding plantation companies accountable for  gendered aspects of land grab and disputes and violation of workers rights; (ii) CSOs and CBOs work to engage (young) women in local goverment and village level institutions governing land and forest resources and enable them to obtain skills and confidence in order to be effective in claiming and employing decision making powers as elected/appointed representatives, officials or spokes persons.

INCLUSIVE WATER GOVERNANCE:
In Kenya (Kiambu County),  based on the research on current water governance, the capacity building workshops highlighted how current water policies and practices are disproportionately affecting women&#x2019;s access to water; the participants emphasized the importance to address gender inequality in order to promote more inclusive water governance. Lobby and advocacy work as well as work with the communities have build upon these insights.

Various lobby and advocacy workshops in Satkhira district (Bangladesh) organised by 1 FGG partner have led to strengthened lobby and advocacy capacity of farmer groups (including young and marginalised farmers, and women-only groups) who participated: more specifically the capacity of farmers for engaging in dialogue and negotiating with local government officials about the support for agroecological practices, practising open fisheries, and sustainable land use through both governmental policies, regulations, and funding mechanisms. As part of these workshops, the FGG partner trained women and youth to further develop and strengthen their L&amp;A messages tailored at their specific needs and realities, in order to promote solutions that are mindful of gender and intergenerational inequalities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender justice is one of the core pillars of our programme strategy and long term goals. This is reflected in all our lines of work under the FGG programme by focusing on amplifying the voices of women through the networks we are involved in , translate their asks to advocacy on the complicated system of public financial flows and international trade and investment agreements and the advocacy for more space for inclusive land and water management including transformative practices. In addition, both in our work with partners as well as in our own advocacy we pay attention to the gendered impacts of the issues we work on and make sure our work is responsive to that gender analysis. While for our work on inclusive land governance, inclusive water governance and transformative practices, gender is already an integral part of all activities we undertake, for our work on trade and investments and public financial flows updating our gender analysis an d further incorporating gender justice in our activities is an important priority for 2022.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Process</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">process</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">o</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">the extent to and ways in which FGG involves local groups in the design and implementation of the FGG programme</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In general, Both ENDS is in regular contact with partners throughout the year. Before plans are being made for the next year, partners are consulted by colleagues for their ideas and input. The activities and work of partners as part of an MoU and its contribution to the FGG ToC are defined by themselves in consultation with Both ENDS colleagues. Partner talks to reflect on the collaboration are done every year with a couple of partners. While doing all this, we are conscious that Both ENDS still holds the money and eventually decides upon the budget division between partners. Acknowledging this and finding ways to make it more equal are good first steps, but is something we want to continue reflecting upon and working on.

2021 was a very challenging year with the regard to collaborating with partners. The inability to see each other and have in-depth brainstorm sessions hindered the mutual capacity development. Whilst certain meetings were able to be held online, bad connection and/or limited time/different preferences made it harder to keep each other up-to-date. At the same time, those moments were we did come together (online) were used to reflect on how collaboration under a &#x2018;new normal&#x2019; can improve in the future. The outcomes of some of those reflections will be implemented in 2022.

A couple of examples of how local groups have been involved in the design and implementation of the programme:
&#x2013; In 2021, the Handels Anders coalitie, of which BE is a member, has written a publication on the EU-Mercosur free trade agreement. As representing the perspectives of local groups was a central goal of the publication, 7 local partners were strongly involved in the process. Local groups in the Mercosur countries have expressed their concerns around the EU-Mercosur agreement, and notoriously its harmful impacts on their livelihoods. in their communities and their natural living environment. However, little transparency around the FTA and little public debate in the Mercosur countries about the trade agreement fueled the need of local partners for more research and written analysis. The publication is a result of this and aims to spark further debate and knowledge exchange between CSO&#xB4;s in 2022.
- A Ugandan partner has built a group of 36 community champions that are involved in the strategizing and implementation of the advocacy by EGI and play a key role in building the capacities of the wider communities that they are part of.
- Both ENDS, FPP and Rutu Foundation and Southern based co-founding members of the ILED network organized a number of virtual meetings. This enabled joint decisions about governance of the network and the drawing up on an Action Plan by the 8 ILED-partners. It also led to a process of peer-to-peer support of local ILED project development and joint decision making on a common small grants fund and allocation of small grants. It also led to appointment of regional coordinators, mandated by the ILEDS-network partners to facilitate and initiate further network development.
- Both ENDS offered strategic and funding support aiding a Malaysian NGO a sounding board to design a new lobby agenda to address native customary land right (NCR) issues &#x2013; this in view of the outcome of the last State elections in Sarawak. The partner decided to take stock of which new policymakers and legislators, corporate stakeholders, the media and civil society to engage to promotr NCR, using the angle of climate change and good governance (especially environmental, social and corporate governance) in the light of Malaysia&#x2019;s commitments to the UN Climate Change Conference (COP26) in Glasgow in November 2021. Thereby building on the webinar - jointly organized by PPSKS and the University of Malaya Law Faculty, with Both ENDS support the previous year-  with eminent legal experts, including the former President of the Malaysian Federal Court and and a Legal Review Paper on the status of NCR lands in Sarawak.
- Both ENDS and a partner in Nigeria worked on strategizing around new avenues to halting illegal logging and environmental destruction and enhance the abilities and safety of community forest protection committees, with participation of women and youth. This encouraged the partner to step up the international campaign to put pressure on the Cross River State authorities.
- Both ENDS, in joint collaboration with four partners in Asia and SEI organized and co-hosted a webinar with grassroots Women Environmental Human Rights Defenders in Asia, and funding agencies for which the WEHRDs were assisted to present their challenges, needs and priorities to funders. The webinar was moderated and logistically organized by one of the Asian partners. A number of funders expressed interest in collaborating in follow-up support to WEHRDS. For background; https://www.sei.org/perspectives/women-environmental-defenders-protect-communities/ and https://ntfp.org/2020/11/courage-in-the-face-of-struggles/</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ownership and representation of local groups is part and partial to Both ENDS&#x2019; way of working. In all the work that we will undertake we will closely collaborate with our partners in the global South which are often local CSOs that have strong relationships with local communities, CBOs or communities directly. We ensure their involvement in all phases of the programme, from design to implementation and evaluation and are in constant dialogue with them. One of the key ways in which we will ensure sound representation of our local partners is by continuing to letting plans and agenda be driven by the issues and needs identified by our partners. FGG members&#x2019; agenda will continue to be driven by the needs identified by our partners in the global South. In addition, we will continue to engage in mutual capacity development with our partners where both BE and partners strengthen each others L&amp;A capacities by learning from each other&#x2019;s often complementary knowledge, skills, and positions. This mutual capacity building is generally followed-up with joint lobby and advocacy activities from our Southern partners and BE. In our advocacy we will continue to aim to bring our partners themselves in the room as much as possible. When this is not possible, it will be our number one priority to convey the perspectives of our partners as well as possible in these decision making spaces. While representation of local groups is already a fundamental priority in our work, in 2022, we do expect to enhance representation of local groups, e.g. we aim to start collaborating with new partners.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">strengthened capacities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs included in the FGG programme</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="133"></target>
     <actual value="142"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="107"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">strengthened capacities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># targeted civil society actors that lobby and advocate for improved policies and practices in trade and value chains and advance fair and green practices based on capacities mutually developed</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="53"></target>
     <actual value="54">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) In 2021 3 partners from Uganda, Tanzania and Indonesia used their strengthened knowledge on the link between de SDGs and trade policy, to lobby their national governments for civil society participation in Trade Policy. Both ENDS provided technical support.
2) In August 2021, a partner from Uganda used it&#x2019;s strengthened knowledge on ISDS clauses in BITs&#x2013; gained through knowledge exchange and joint strategizing with Both ENDS &#x2013; to advise policy makers of Burundi to stop current unfair BITs.

3) From September to December 2021, 3 partners from Indonesia together with partners from Europe used their strengthened knowledge on the EU-CEPA Indonesia &#x2013; gained through knowledge exchange and joint strategising with Both ENDS &#x2013; to discuss with Indonesian and European trade negotiators CSOs concerns&#x2019; on Trade and Sustainable Development within the EU-CEPA.

4) In November and December 2021, through strengthened advocacy and media skills, a Ugandan partner published lobby and advocacy materials including open letters, petitions, and communiques that were directed towards Ugandan policymakers and embassies of countries with an active ECA in Uganda. The materials were also shared with the media and called on the policymakers to embrace ECAs transvestments and align their development agenda with the commitments under the Paris Agreement. Both ENDS helped in strategising which policymakers and embassies to target, leading to a larger network and increased knowledge which the partner integrated in their lobby and advocacy activities.

4a) In 2021, together with 1 network of community champions, a Ugandan partner, used its strengthened networking and advocacy capacities to generate and submit comments to the Ugandan government on the EACOP and Mining Bill that was submitted to the parliament committee on natural resources for adoption with the Just Transition agenda. Both ENDS provided financial support, joint strategizing and knowledge exchange.

5) In 2021, 1 CSO and 3 local fishers-communities in Indonesia shared the impacts they faced from the CPI land reclamation project insured by the Dutch state with ADSB. Both ENDS facilitated the exchange. Based on this, the CSO and Both ENDS made recommendations for ADSB to improve its due diligence process and discussed remedy.

6) In November 2021, 1 CSO and 1 local fishers-community in Indonesia advocated to representatives of the local and national government and the CPI project owner regarding the impacts that they have faced of previous sand mining projects, and their concerns for future projects. Both ENDS contributed by financial support, joint strategizing and knowledge exchange.

7) In 2021, 3 partners from Senegal used their strengthened knowledge of networking and access to decision making spaces  for meetings with the IRM on the TER case, a meeting with a parliamentarians, and outreach to FMO for remediating the harm done in the TER and Sendou projects, raising specific attention on gender justice, including disaggregated impact studies for women. Both ENDS contributed through financial support, joint strategizing and knowledge exchange.

8) In 2021, 3 partners from Uganda used their strengthened constituency for advocacy meetings with the community and local government to ensure land rights are better respected by the Ugandan government. Both ENDS contributed through financial support, joint strategizing and knowledge exchange.

9) In 2021, 2 partners from Panama used their strengthened access to decision making spaces for participating in a International Complaints Mechanism (ICM) visit with the aim of recognition of FMO that the harms need to be remedied. Both ENDS contributed through financial support, joint strategizing and knowledge exchange.

10) In 2021, 2 partners from Malawi, used their strengthened constituency and access to decision making spaces at FMO and MIGA for meetings with FMO and MIGA, and advocacy letters, for ensuring that FMO and MIGA contribute to solving the concerns of community members in the Salima project, including the adverse impacts of the project on women. Both ENDS contributed through financial support, joint strategizing and knowledge exchange.

11) In 2021, 1 partner from Mozambique, used its strengthened access to decision making space at Dutch dredging company Van Oord and COP 26 for advocacy meetings with Van Oord and participation in the COP 26 for locating missing UPC members (Van Oord) and finding reparations to the harms done in the Moz LNG project (COP 26). Both ENDS contributed through financial support, joint strategizing and knowledge exchange.

12) In 2021, 1 partner from Cameroon created 6 working groups with in total 30 community representatives, among which 12 female representatives and 10 youth, to ensure engagement with the development banks responsible for the construction of the Nachtigal hydroelectric dam.  Both ENDS contributed to their lobby by joint strategizing and financial support.
13) In 2021, 1 partner from Cameroon used it expanded knowledge of international financial institutions (IFI) to extend its work on IFI-funded projects in Cameroon, which included among others a mapping exercise, the organizations of two strategy meetings which led to the development of two action plans on mitigating the negative (climate) impacts of World Bank, FMO and AfDB investments in Cameroon.

14) On 28-29 October 2021 in West Kalimantan Indonesia, 15 participants from, three communities, who had their capacity strengthened in earlier workshops supported by Both ENDS held a monitoring and advocacy meeting about asserting HR remedies by using international and corporate standards in supply chains: monitoring complaints with NDPE (No Deforestation, No Peat and No Exploitation) and downstream buyers for the plantations PT MISP, PT PLD and PT MAS. Both ENDS contributed with strategic consultation and financial support.

15) October/November 2021 in Kalimantan Indonesia, based on the training on IWRM &amp; gender which included training  on water quality monitoring, NGO partner uploaded test results on social media and raised public interest. Both ENDS contributed with financial support and international outreach

16) Second half of 2021 in Indonesia, one NGO and one CBO who received capacity strengthening on this topic in 2020 ,undertook an investigation on the implementation of RSPO and/ ISPO, by recording  violations of palm oil sustainability standards. Both ENDS contributed a.o. with financial support.

17) In 2021 in Indonesia one NGO and one grassroots community CBO that works on green economy empowerment, undertook water patrols and water quality monitoring near palm oil plantations.  Water samples were measured at BARISTAN laboratory who had SNI certification. The Water Quality Report will be used in information campaigns and for formal complaints. Both ENDS contributes with financial support, networking and strategic alliances.

18) In 2021, 3 partnering network hubs and 4 CSOs in Asia used its gained access to renewed and expanded funding to continue their efforts in terms of constructive dialogue with government authorities concerning indigenous customary land rights and sustainable forest, wildlife conservation and water management. Both ENDS contributed by offering strategic counseling.
19) in 2021, a partner in Asia used its increased knowledge on fundraising and strengthened funding base to sustain its policy work with regards to protection and restoration of forest and streams and tree nursery development, and recognition of the key role of women in successful tree nurseries and plantation programmes, e.g. by featuring a resource center and wild food nursery garden: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kwLQFqO0G3A. Both ENDS contributed through mutual capacity development incl. financial support and fundraising assistance.
20) In 2021, a women&apos;s organization from Indonesia used it&#x2019;s improved access to the COP26 to represent the Asia Pacific Forum on Women, Law and Development in relevant side-events, including the Women and Gender Constituency (WGC) side event, the COP Presidency&#x2019;s &#x201C;Dialogue with the local communities and indigenous people platform at COP26&#x2019;&#x2019; and the &#x201C;4 female PM/Presidents on feminist climate action&#x201D; side event. Interview with Canadian media on the struggle of women in Indonesia to gain climate justice. : https://apwld.org/  https://apwld.org/press-release-missingvoicescop26-yet-again-cop26-uk-presidency-fails-women-from-the-global-south/. Both ENDS contributed with mutual capacity development incl. financial, fundraising and brokering support as well as strategic advice from Both ENDS.
21) In 2021, a Nigerian partner used it&#x2019;s strengthened constituency and funding base to advocate to the Cross-River State government for the halting of illegal logging and environmental destruction. Both ENDS contributed through mutual capacity development including fundraising support.
22) In 2021, 4 partners in Malaysia improved their advocacy for improved regulation of the plantation and logging sectors in Malaysia land use systems, fair treatment of workers and remedy for women affected by exploitation and violations of their human rights. In one instance this also directly relates to Dutch policies, namely on timber imports from Malaysia. Both ENDS contributed to their strengthened advocacy by serving as a sounding board.
23) In September 2021, a Cameroonian community, together with its Traditional Ruler, organised a peaceful street protest in which they demanded immediate action from the administration of a commune in Cameroon Littoral Region to investigate and resolve the conflict between a community and an agro-company based on the knowledge acquired through the capacity building workshops of a Both ENDS partner, an action that prompted significant media attention and a response from the administration (a consultation meeting was scheduled). Both ENDS contributed with financial support to the capacity building workshops. and subsequent consultation meeting.
24) From September to December 2021,  one partner from Cameroon has helped a network of local CSOs  to convene regularly to actively support a local community in their struggle, including study sessions, strategy development and the drafting of a letter to a Senior Divisional Officer of  a commune to stick to promises made during a consultation meeting held in September 2021. Both ENDS contributed with financial support.
25) During various moments in 2021, 7 FGG partners from Manila (the Philippines), used their strengthened lobby and advocacy capacities (in terms of increasing network, access to decision-making spaces, and leverage and influencing capacity) in (i) consultations with Atradius DSB and due diligence consultants of the project&#x2019;s lenders group, and (ii) jointly submitting four letters of concern, in relation to the NMIA project, addressed to Boskalis, Atradius DSB, The Netherlands Ministry of Finance and the Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs. Both ENDS provided financial support, facilitated stakeholder meetings and access to Dutch actors, and jointly strategised with partners, which contributed to this result

26) During 2021, 1 FGG partner in Manila (the Philippines), used their strengthened lobby and advocacy capacities (mainly in terms of strengthening their advocacy message), in their advocacy towards the local government level to support their campaign against the NMIA project. Both ENDS provided financial support and the joint strategizing with partners indirectly contributed to this result
27) In January 2021, and based on the initiative of Both ENDS, 1 FGG partner from Manila (the Philippines), used their strengthened lobby and advocacy capacity in terms of knowledge, network and advocacy message to get invited to the Global Adaptation Summit and to present about the NMIA project for addressing the human rights abuses and environmental damage and calling upon Boskalis to withdraw from the project. Both ENDS provided financial support and facilitated contacts with the organisers of the Global Adaptation Summit.
28) During 2021, based upon facilitation by 1 FGG partner, representatives from local farmer groups and local water committees in Bangladesh strengthened lobby and advocacy capacities (amongst others to access decision-making spaces) to engage in quarterly meetings with local government authorities to build and maintain a constructive dialogue in order to attract government support for agroecology and open fisheries, which showcase the importance to restore the south-west tidal river ecosystem through the implementation of Tidal River Management. Both ENDS provided financial support and the joint strategizing with partners indirectly contributed to this result.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="71">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Throughout 2022, we aim for 71 civil society actors from Asia, Africa and Latin America (e.g. India, Indonesia, Bangladesh, Uganda and Kenya) to lobby and advocate among other things for fair and green trade and investment agreements (incl. stopping the expansion of the ECT, ISDS clauses and adding strong human rights and environmental chapters), inclusive land governance (incl. the implementation of VGGTs), improved corporate accountability processes (i.a. at the RSPO and public financial institutions), increased finance for transformative practices, and inclusive and sustainable water management and spatial planning. They will do so with enhanced knowledge, networking and advocacy capacities, strengthened through mutual capacity development activities including knowledge building support, joint strategising as well as network facilitation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">strengthened capacities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2x</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># targeted civil society actors with strengthened capacities contributing to and/or relevant for lobby and advocacy aiming at expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="88"></target>
     <actual value="48"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="23">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Of these 96 CSOs, 23 will strengthen capacities that are relevant for their advocacy to advance or defend civic space. Through mutual capacity development (i.a. joint strategising, network building, knowledge sharing, and financial support), these CSOs, from Asia, Africa, and Latin America, including from Indonesia, India, The Philippines, Bangladesh, Kenya and Uganda, will be better able to claim their place at the decision making table on among other things corporate accountability processes (e.g. at the RSPO and in public financial flows), inclusive water governance and inclusive land governance (incl. IPLC rights such as self determination).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">strengthened capacities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># targeted civil society actors with strengthened capacities for lobbying and advocacy</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="133"></target>
     <actual value="132">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) From February-May 2021, 6 partners from the Mercosur bloc strengthened their knowledge on the EU-Mercosur deal through knowledge exchange and in depth interviews in preparation for the EU-Mercosur publication. Both ENDS conducted and analyzed the interviews, hereby functioning as a bridge between the local groups from the Mercosur bloc and the Handel Anders coalitie.
2) In October 2021, 2 partners from the Mercosur bloc, strengthened their knowledge regarding the government procurement in the EU-Mercosur deal by/through knowledge exchange with BE.
3) In 2021 partners from Uganda , Tanzania  and Indonesia, strengthened their knowledge on the link between the Sustainable Development Goals and trade policy (i.e. the importance of civil society participation in trade policy) through knowledge exchange with and technical support from Both ENDS (x).
4) In November 2021 2 partners from Uganda  and Tanzania strengthened their knowledge on harmful clauses included in Bilateral Investment Treaties (BITs) to lobby and advocate for stopping and renegotiation of current BITs in Burundi. Both ENDS provided technical information in the virtual workshops organized by the partners.
5) In March 2021, 5 partners from Indonesia held a workshop to strengthen their knowledge on national laws related to the SDGs, and Trade and environmental protection regulations in Indonesia. Both ENDS provided financial support and shared technical information.
6) In November 2021, one partner from Indonesia together with European partners (incl. SOMO) and European CSOs held virtual meetings and presentations to strengthen their knowledge on enforceability of the Trade and Sustainable Development chapter in the EU-CEPA Indonesia. Both ENDS provided technical support via a presentation and answering questions as well as financial support.

7) In April 2021, 2 partners from Indonesia strengthened their knowledge on which laws are incompatible with the Sustainable Development Goals in order to be able to advocate for stronger laws on Trade and Sustainable Development through capacity building events organized by another Both ENDS partner with financial support from Both ENDS .

8) In 2021 6 partners from Uganda, Kenya, Mozambique and Zimbabwe held information workshops and advocacy trainings on the risks of the African Continental Free Trade Area for women&#x2019;s rights. Both ENDS had provided input for the material used in the trainings and financial support (g).

9) In December 2021, one partner from Uganda, strengthened the capacity of women and girls with knowledge and skills to actively participate in activities within the energy sector and demand for transvestments from the gender perspective by organizing a community training, through financial support from and joint strategizing and networking with Both ENDS (g).
10) In October 2021, one partner from Uganda, built staff and community champions capacity on digital and physical security and adapted its operational strategies on how to continue operating safely within a volatile environment through financial support from and joint strategizing and networking with Both ENDS. (x)

11) In 2021, a Ugandan partner established a network of 36 resilient community clean energy champions, comprised of youth and women who are leading the decarbonization campaign at the grass-roots level. They are working to mobilize other communities to engage with duty bearers through the submission of petitions, letters, demanding the greening of ECA investments in the country. The champions are continuously reaching out to their fellow community members, strengthening their networks and resilience to campaign for greening investments. Both ENDS contributed through financial support and joint strategizing (g)

12) In 2021, via joint strategizing, knowledge exchange and financial support with/from Both ENDS, an Indonesian partner mobilized fishermen, youth and women from communities to stand up for their rights with regards to sand mining projects in the coastal waters around Makassar. Through exchanging knowledge and experiences the network between these communities has been strengthened and a shared advocacy agenda has been developed. The communities received trainings on what their rights are, for example on being informed and consulted in decision making that affects their livelihoods. They have formed teams that will prepare legal cases against this legislation that damages the livelihoods of fishermen, women and youth. (g) (x)
13) In 2021, 4 partners from Senegal strengthened their  constituency/network in the affected communities as well as with national CSOs, access to decision making spaces at FMO and AfDB, advocacy/communication skills to raise attention for the TER and Sendou case, and leverage/influencing skills with focus on gender justice in community meetings, through strategy meetings with Both ENDS and joint advocacy activities towards FMO and AfDB. Both ENDS also provided financial support (g).
14) In 2021, 3 partners from Uganda strengthened their constituency/network in the affected communities, access to departmental and national decision making spaces, advocacy skills by having better knowledge of rights and regulations, leverage governments institutions and ability to act freely and safely on the topic of land rights related to the development of hydropower projects in the North of Uganda. They achieved this through community workshops organized by 2 Both ENDS partners , community advocacy meetings with specific focus on gender justice, and joint strategy meetings with Both ENDS. Both ENDS provided financial support (g)

15) In 2021, 2 partners from Uganda strengthened their knowledge on shrinking civic space through organizing strategy meetings with Ugandan lawyers on state repression to strengthen their response towards shrinking civic space and joint strategy meetings with Both ENDS. (x)

16) In 2021, 2 partners  from Panama, strengthened their  local constituency  and, access to FMO&#x2019;s Independent Complaints Mechanism (ICM) and Inter American Court on human Rights, by organizing community meetings, joint strategy meetings and joint advocacy meetings with Both ENDS targeting the ICM. Both ENDS also provided financial support.

17) In 2021, 2 partners from Malawi, strengthened their constituency/network in the communities affected by the Salima project,  their access to FMO and MIGA, and their leverage/influencing skills with focus on gender justice by organizing community meetings and workshops for accountability clubs, , as well as joint strategy meetings  and  advocacy towards FMO, MIGA and the project owner with Both ENDS.  Both ENDS also provided financial support(g)

18) In 2021, 1 partner from Mozambique, strengthened  it&#x2019;s constituency network , access to decision making spaces at the COP26, and ability to act freely and safely through  joint strategizing with and financial support from Both ENDS to locate the partners&#x2019; members dispersed by war and  continue organizing themselves, organizing constituency meetings, participating in a COP 26 event organized by Both ENDS and joint  advocacy with Both ENDS towards Dutch dredging company Van Oord. Both ENDS provided financial support(x)

19) In 2021, 1 partner from Cameroon strengthened its knowledge of and access to the CAO-IFC complaint mechanism through working sessions and exchanges a.o. with CAO IFC staff, where-in  a complaint was prepared for filing at this complaint mechanism against deficiencies in compensation for communities affected by the World Bank financed Nachtigal hydroelectric dam. Both ENDS organized the working sessions and provided financial support.
20) In 2021, a partner from Cameroon worked with 3 communities and 3 groups of workers affected by the construction of the World Bank financed Nachtigal hydroelectric dam, on strengthening their knowledge of the minimum social and environmental safeguards of international financial institutions and their opportunities for engaging in dispute resolution. Both ENDS contributed through financial support, having joint strategy meetings with the partner and sharing knowledge.
21) In 2021, a partner from Cameroon organized a capacity building workshop for its CSO membership on projects financed by international financial institutions. Both ENDS contributed by providing financial support, having joint strategy meetings with the partner and sharing knowledge.
22) Between September and December 2021, a partner from Brazil engaged in training and capacity building of  20 women representatives of 2 local communities. They have strengthened their knowledge of agro-ecological practices, gender equity and lobbying strategies &#x2013; with a focus on the women&#x2019;s access to land rights &#x2013; by conducting and participating in a series of workshops and practices on agro-ecological gardening and a series of workshops for lobby skills called &#x2018;10 steps towards engaged citizenship&#x2019;. Both ENDS has contributed by continued strategizing with this Brazilian partner on for example the inclusion of agro-ecological practice into their work and information exchange about policies concerning the port of Suape.
23) From July to November 2021 , a partner from Peru has trained various local communities members strengthening their knowledge of agro-ecological practices as well as lobbying strategies with a focus on access to land rights, community monitoring, involvement of youth and women community members in decision making. They did this by conducting and participating in a series of workshops an training sessions Both ENDS contributed by financially supporting the work of this partner with the community.
24) On 16th September 2021 in West Kalimantan Indonesia four transmigrant communities and indigenous peoples strengthened their skills in participatory mapping of their indigenous customary territories in order to defend their indigenous territories from land grabbing by oil palm plantation and mining companies,  facilitated by an Indonesian partner. Both ENDS contributed with financial support for trainings and networking.

25) On 30-31 October 2021 in West Kalimantan Indonesia, 20 indigenous women participants from four communities who are involved with existing cases with oil palm plantations and forestry sector,  followed a training on women leadership for human rights and environmental defence; they have strengthened their leadership capacity and women activism , and improved the ability  to advocate  for women issues in their own home communities. Subsequently on  1-2 November 2021, the women&#x2019;s groups received training to be  strengthened  in understanding human rights and how to apply FPIC, in particular  community and gender based human rights and environmental defending monitoring system. Both ENDS contributed  with financial support . (g)(x)

26) In September 2021, in Indonesia 2 women groups in Kalimantan were established and received training on Integrated Water Resources Management (IWRM) and gender, and in the training additionally women socio-economy and environment impact  of palm oil was mapped.  The training resulted in increased skills to monitor water quality, understanding river management, mapping  changes on their socio-economy and environment, and knowledge and skill on organic waste management. Both ENDS contributed with financial support. (g)

27) Throughout 2021, with financial support and organisational advice from Both ENDS, a federation of indigenous tribes in the Philippines enhanced its ability to assist communities to negotiate land tenure and gain access to government services. For background, see: https://www.peopleandplants.org/traditional-foodways/the-philippines  and http://spnkk.org/ (x) (g)
28) In 2021, through strategic counseling from Both ENDS, a partner in Sarawak-Malaysia strengthened it&#x2019;s knowledge and advocacy skills related to Native Customary Land Rights in the context of the Sarawak elections and how to best stimulate indigenous communities to make informed decisions about this issue amidst ongoing land-grab, violation of customary land-rights and deforestation.
29) In 2021, with counseling offered by Both ENDS, CNV and Oxfam Novib, a plantation workers union in Indonesia enhanced its ability to become a more effective member of the RSPO Board of Governors by increasing its knowledge of the workings of this RSPO governance body. See e.g. https://www.rspo.org/ga17/GA17Nominations_SNGO_BOTHENDS.pdf
30) In 2021, with fund raising and brokering support and organizational advice from Both ENDS, 5 NGOs and 4 partnering network hubs in Asia gained access to renewed and expanded funding. This enabled the partner a.o. to expand it&#x2019;s capacity building training  and financial support to 12 local CSOs and, over 80 indigenous communities, which included training  to especially tribal women which encouraged these women to take up a role as community leaders and voice and advocate concerns of women in the field of forest management, land tenure and basic needs, including the lack of civil society/IPLC involvement in related decision-making processes (g, x)
31) In 2021, with fund raising and hands on strategic and practical advice from Both ENDS, a partnering tribal CSO in Asia strengthened its ability to offer legal and negotiation support to 6  indigenous communities  on matters of land rights and promotion of governmental use of the partner&#x2019;s expansive tree nurseries with endemic plants.
32) In 2021, with fundraising and hands-on strategic advice from Both ENDS, a partner in Asia increased it&#x2019;s knowledge on fundraising and strengthened its funding base which enabled the latter to sustain its policy work with regards to protection and restoration of forest and streams and tree nursery development, and recognition of the key role of women in successful tree nurseries and plantation programmes, e.g. by featuring a model resource center and wild food nursery garden.
33) In November 2021, with funding and networking support from Both ENDS,  a women organization from Indonesia strengthened it&#x2019;s access to the UNFCC COP and related sessions in Glasgow, including: the Women and Gender Constituency (WGC) side event, the COP Presidency&#x2019;s &#x201C;Dialogue with the local communities and indigenous people platform at COP26&#x2019;&#x2019; and the &#x201C;4 female PM/Presidents on feminist climate action&#x201D; side event. (g)
34) In 2021, with the financial support and fundraising assistance from Both ENDS,  an Asian partner strengthened its funding base which enabled it to support local CSOs to assist a.o an indigenous hunter-gatherer community, which was severely hit by Covid and a cyclone, to rebuild capacity to advocate  for their land tenure by an improved understanding of their legal rights and how to submit a formal submission for recognition and restoration of their land rights, and to simultaneously address immediate subsistence needs such as rebuilding houses and to gain access to primary health care.
35) In 2021, with financial, fund raising and brokering support as well as strategic advice from Both ENDS, a Liberian partner strengthened it&#x2019;s knowledge of and leverage in the RSPO, which helped this partner to successfully partner with RSPO as a key NGO-Hub assisting local CSOs to promote the regulation of the oil palm sector in post-civil war Liberia, amidst conflicts over land, with competing claims between villages and plantation companies, and neighboring Anglo-phone countries. This, with a focus on enhancing CSOs and CBOs increased influence on decision making which directly affects land rights, rights of labourers, women rights and possibilities for alternative, more sustainable and inclusive land and forest uses, and the ability of local CBOs, communities and women (incl female plantation workers) to stands up for their rights . (g, x)  https://www.rspo.org/news-and-events/news/lessons-learned-from-liberia--improving-community-modalities-towards-sustainable-palm-oil
36) In 2021, with Both ENDS offering a sounding board, financial assistance and fundraising support a partner in Nigeria strengthened its L&amp;A capacities. They strengthened their constituency by building stronger local NGO and village based activist groups and enhancing the safety of community forest protection committees amidst threats against villagers accompanying illegal logging. An important element here was training  local women in advocacy. They also strengthened their institutional capacity by diversifying their funding basis. (x) (g)
37) In 2021, through collaboration with Both ENDS,  and the Free University of Amsterdam to develop a legal position on the Ugandan government&#x2019;s legal obligations &#x2013; in the context of Ugandan law and international trade and investment agreements &#x2013; a Ugandan partner strengthened it&#x2019;s ability and &#x2018;tool&#x2019;s to address &#x2013; via the court system - serious women rights and labour rights violations on palm oil plantations (a joint venture of an international multinational and the Government of Uganda) in Uganda. Both ENDS also offered the partner strategic information, options and contacts which enabled the latter to take informed choices whether or not to use the company&#x2019;s own grievances system and the complaints system of RSPO. (g, x) (See also annual report 2020 for background: https://docplayer.net/219499754-Center-for-food-and-adequate-living-rights.html
38) In 2021, through jointly organized webinars with Both ENDS to exchange experiences, know-how and work on joint positions, 3 partners from Thailand, Panama and Kenya  enhanced their capacity  to advocate to Indigenous-Led Education as a vital ingredient to create opportunities for youth leadership, gender justice and community resilience in the face of climate change and external pressures: (g)  https://www.rutufoundation.org/indigenous-led-education/
39) In 2021, a Nigerian partner has strengthened their local constituency by entering into an agreement with the federation of traditional Village Chiefs. This framework helps to advance (1) Safety training &amp; support for village volunteers-activists; (ii) training of women on advocacy. Both ENDS contributed with strategic and financial support. In addition Both ENDS also assisted them with a diversification of their funding basis. (x, g)
40) In 2021, a global network of CSOs working with communities in drylands and Both ENDS mutually strengthened their lobby &amp; advocacy capacities through joint strategising and knowledge exchange. The network strengthened Both ENDS&#x2019; knowledge by providing input for the advice of the UNCCD and its member countries for COP15. In turn, Both ENDS strengthened the network&#x2019;s capacity by increasing their access to policy making spaces and bringing in the networks&#x2019; input in the UNCCD intergovernmental working group on Drought developing this advice.
41) In 2021, a network of CSOs working with communities in drylands, strengthened their knowledge on the implementation of the VGGTs in Land Degradation Neutrality policies by joint strategising with Both ENDS.
42) In 2021, a network of CSOs working with communities in drylands, strengthened their access to policy making spaces by joint strategizing with Both ENDS regarding participation in the UNCCD&#x2019;s gender tool development (g)
43) In July and August 2021, one CSO and one community from Cameroon strengthened their capacities on advocating for the respect of human rights in large-scale land based investments by jointly carrying out a situational analysis, learning more about Free, Prior and Informed Consent (FPIC) to have their voices heard, and the rights and obligations of different stakeholders in the land concession process of Cameroon through various trainings and workshops facilitated by a local Both ENDS partner.  Both ENDS contributed with financial support.(x)
44) In the second half of 2021, three Community Land Advocacy Committees (CLACs) from Zambia  have been trained by a local Both ENDS partner  on advocacy, land rights, responsible land investment and monitoring impacts of land-based investment  and the development of advocacy plans around awareness raising, certification, lobbying and paralegal support. Both ENDS contributed with financial support.

45) Throughout the year 2021, 3 FGG partners from Kenya strengthened their lobby and advocacy capacity (mainly in terms of evidence building, which was used in their advocacy messages) on the governance of, and access to water surrounding Ruiru Dams 1 and 2 in Kiambu county through research and validation workshops with community and government stakeholders. Both ENDS provided financial support, and joint strategizing with partners and networking contributed to this result
46) During various occasions and based on the research conducted in 2021, 3 FGG partners from Kenya strengthened the lobby and advocacy capacity (mainly in terms of influencing skills, network, knowledge and access to decision-making spaces) of approx. 30 farmers and water users in Kiambu county on the governance of water in Kenya and the possibility to exert influence on the local management of water resources surrounding the Ruiru Dams 1 and 2 through active membership in a Water Resources Users Association by organising various public &#x2018;baraza&#x2019;s (meetings) and workshops. Based on the research on current water governance, the capacity building workshops highlighted how current water policies and practices are disproportionately affecting women&#x2019;s access to water; the participants emphasized the importance to address gender inequality in order to promote more inclusive water governance. Both ENDS provided financial support and the joint strategizing with partners and networking indirectly contributed to this result.
47) Throughout the year 2021, 3 FGG partners from Kenya strengthened their lobby and advocacy capacity (mainly in terms of knowledge and evidence building) to address the threats of conventional farming and to promote agroecological farming as a socio-economically, and environmentally viable alternative, by conducting research on the current policies and practices of agriculture in Kenya. Both ENDS provided financial support and the joint strategizing with partners and networking indirectly contributed to this result. During a workshops organised in 2021, which built on the research done by the 3 FGG partners, the lobby and advocacy capacity (mainly in terms of building the advocacy message) of approx. 100 farmers and water users in Kiambu county (Kenya) was strengthened to more effectively address the policies and practices that promote conventional farming, including the use of dangerous agro-chemicals, and to promote agro-ecology as a a socio-economically, and environmentally viable alternative which can contribute to more gender. Both ENDS provided financial support and the joint strategizing with partners and networking indirectly contributed to this result
48) Throughout the year 2021, various lobby and advocacy workshops in Satkhira district (Bangladesh) organised by 1 FGG partner have led to strengthened lobby and advocacy capacity of farmer groups (including young and marginalised farmers, and women-only groups) who participated: more specifically the capacity of farmers for engaging in dialogue and negotiating with local government officials about the support for agroecological practices, practising open fisheries, and sustainable land use through both governmental policies, regulations, and funding mechanisms. As part of these workshops, the FGG partner trained women and youth to further develop and strengthen their L&amp;A messages tailored at their specific needs and realities, in order to promote solutions that are mindful of gender and intergenerational inequalities. Both ENDS provided financial support and the joint strategizing with partners and networking indirectly contributed to this result.(g)
49) During quarterly meetings in 2021, through participation in exchange visits organised by 1 FGG partner, farmer groups working on agroecology and open fisheries in Satkhira district (Bangladesh), and the youth water committee of the area, strengthened the argumentation of their messages to lobby and advocate more effectively for community-based Tidal River Management based on the benefits that this brings for alternative livelihoods that incorporate agroecological practices and open fisheries. Both ENDS provided financial support and the joint strategizing with partners and networking indirectly contributed to this result
50) In 2021, with the support from Both ENDS in terms of joint strategizing and access to Dutch stakeholders, 7 FGG partners in Manilla (the Philippines) have strengthened their lobbying and advocacy capacities in terms of increasing network, access to decision-making spaces, and leverage and influencing capacity to oppose to the New Manila International airport.
51) The lobby and advocacy capacities of the fishing communities of Bulacan (the Philippines) opposing the New Manila International Airport project have been strengthened in 2021 in terms of capacity to mobilize communities and create awareness, mainly through activities by 1 FGG partner. Both ENDS provided financial support and the joint strategizing with partners and networking indirectly contributed to this result
52) In 2021, 1 FGG partner in Manilla (the Philippines) has strengthened their lobby and advocacy capacities (mainly in terms of strengthening their advocacy message) towards the local government level to support their campaign against the NMIA project. Both ENDS provided financial support and the joint strategizing with partners indirectly contributed to this result
53) Throughout 2021, 1 FGG partner in Manilla (the Philippines) strengthened their lobby and advocacy capacity to formulate effective lobby messages by conducting policy research on the NMIA project. Both ENDS provided financial support and the joint strategizing with partners indirectly contributed to this result
54) In 2021, 2 indigenous communities in Kalimantan Indonesia strengthened their capacity through trainings on customary institutions and management of customary areas and critical law ; and on strategies  of securing recognition to Indigenous Peoples customary territories and forests.  This increased their leverage/bargaining position, critical awareness and knowledge in defending their territories and customary forests as their identity and life. It facilitated the process of reclaiming the customary lands and forests from corporations and the government back to customary institutions. Both ENDS supported with networking and financial support.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="96">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim for 96 civil society actors from Asia, Africa and Latin America (including the Philippines, India, Indonesia, Uganda, and Kenya) to strengthen their capacities (knowledge, constituency building, access to decision making spaces, communication skills, ability to exert influence and to act freely an safely) to lobby and advocate towards governments, private sector actors and international organisations for among other things fair and green trade and investment agreements (incl. renegotiation of BITs, IIAs, EU FTAs and seed IPR clauses), inclusive water governance, inclusive land governance (incl. Implementation of VGGTs and FPIC), improvement of corporate accountability processes (i.a. at the RSPO and in public financial flows), increased finance for transformative practices, and the protection of (E)HRDs. To this aim, we engage in mutual capacity development activities such as learning exchanges, joint strategising, network building, and trainings.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">strengthened capacities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2g</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># targeted civil society actors with strengthened capacities relevant to advance gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="63"></target>
     <actual value="58"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="22">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Of these 96 CSOs, 22 including will strengthen capacities that are relevant for their advocacy for gender justice. These CSOs, from Africa, Asia, and Latin America including from Indonesia, Bangladesh, Kenya and Mozambique will for example strengthen their knowledge about the VGGTs (which have gender justice as one of their key pillars) and the gendered impacts of the EU-Mercosur deal, as well as improve their skills to advocate towards an IFI for the implementation of a GBV plan. In addition CSOs will enhance their understanding of the RSPO to protect women&#x2019;s rights incl. inclusion of women voices in decision making spaces, violation of women (laborers&#x2019;) rights in and around plantations and effects of displacement and changing land use systems for position and workload of local women.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
