<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-IATI-LPI-4000003194</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-IATI-LPI" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Living Peace Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Working with Men to Increase Security and Stabilization in North Kivu, South Kivu and Ituri provinces</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Living Peace project seeks to achieve its goal by pursuing following objectives at five different levels: 1. Individuel Level: Men and women (spouses), healed of severe mental health and psychosocial problems, adopted positive non-violent coping strategies and experience greater personal efficacy to build meaningful relations with self and others. 2. Family Level: Reduced violence at home and restored peaceful partner relations create a safe and healthy environment for women, men and children. Reduction of violence use by men against their partners and children and increase gender equitable behaviours in the household create a safer environment for all members of the family. 3. Community Level: Restored community-based social support systems increase social cohesion between families, individuals and community structures resulting in higher levels of inclusion, and solidarity between community members. 4. Society Level: Congolese civil society organizations and public institutions of Police, Army and Health Care and religious leaders institutionalized the Living Peace approach in their services to adequately address the consequences of SGBV, promote positive masculinity and prevent (mainly) men getting involved in conflicts and/or (re)join armed groups. 5. Women Social and Economic Empowerment: Women, partners of male participants in Living Peace groups, enjoy greater social and economic autonomy with positive support of husbands that participated in Living Peace groups.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of the proposed intervention is to achieve sustainable, gender-equitable peace at all levels of society in provinces of South Kivu, North Kivu and Ituri in eastern DRC by: 1. The overall goal of LPI is to reduce level of violence and build trust in the community by working with men through psychosocial support programs that will help them to end violence and adopt norms and values that support gender equality at all levels; &#x2028; 2. Promoting women socio-economic empowerment with positive support of husbands through an adaptation of the Living Peace methodology, (Journeys of Transformation). LPI will partner with a local organization that is implementing VSLA groups and/or women involved in other economic empowerment activities. LPI will train the local partner in the application of Journeys of Transformation module to engage men as allies of women in economic empowerment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention targets the  categories below:
1. Husband&#x2019;s of  women survivors of SGBV; 2. Military Men; 3. Police Men (PNC); 4. Civilian Men living in Community in high risk zones; 5. Ex-combatant and ex child soldiers living in Community in high risk zones; 6. Spouses of military men and policemen participating into the LP program</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000003194" ref="XI-IATI-00000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Living Peace Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000003194" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Living Peace Institute</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aloys Mahwa</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+243970965771</telephone>
   <email>a.mahwa@livingpeaceinstitute.org</email>
   <website>http://livingpeaceinstitute.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">info@livingpeaceinstitute.org</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity is implemented in Noth-Kivu, South Kivu and Ituri provinces</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-29">2583076</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="EC09S3049">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-18">2035836</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">installment for the last semester for the year 2020-2021 and for the first semester of the year 2021-2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000003194" ref="XM-DAC-7"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="XI-IATI-LPI4000003194" ref="XI-IATI-LPI"></receiver-org>
   <sector code="XI-IATI-LPI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://livingpeaceinstitute.org">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Living Peace Institute</narrative>
   </sector>
  </transaction>
  <result type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 2: Family Level: Reduced Violence at Home and Restored Peaceful Partner relations in the family</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">At family level, the LP program aims at reducing violence at home and restore peaceful partner relations in the family. At this level, the men&#x2019;s psychosocial support groups and the inclusion of women through weekly homework tasks and in shared sessions with men both work to reduce the use of violence by men against their partners and children, increase relationship quality, and increase gender equitable behaviors in the household, thus creating a safer and more equal environment for all members of the family.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 2.1. Number of Targeted men actively participate in gender and violence components of the psychosocial support group.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to LP methodology, gender and violence components covers from session 5 up to session 8. during this sessions, men participants discuss and share experiences about power and interpersonal relations , sex and sexuality,  breaking the cycle of violence and Responsible man, husband and father. The  rate of participation  is 92%, 91 % and 90%  respectively  at session 5,6 and 7.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="91"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 2.2.1: Number  of women (spouses of men) participating in LP group who attend at least four sessions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The LP methodology includes family-focused shared sessions of the LP Program psychosocial support groups during which targeted men and their spouses meet together to discuss how their can put their effort together to end the cycle of violence in their families and communities. Shared sessions reinforce more gender equitable attitudes and behaviors, improve communication in partner relationship and reduce men&#x2019;s use of physical, sexual, psychological and economic, violence against women &amp; violence against children. Shared sessions are 9th entitled family sharing, 11th entitled new rules, attitudes and habits at home, 12th session entitled Barriers and opportunities for change, 13th session entitled security networks and neighbors&apos; groups and the 15th session entitled community celebration.  Although the essential parts of this indicator will be reported at the end of the phase because there is no shared session which took place at the period of reporting, weekly psychosocial support group report from the field show that 866 husbands are involving their spouses in the process of change through home works, per session.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 4: Society Level: Political Engagement. Involve Congolese civil society and public institutions in order to institutionalize the Living Peace approach and influence</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">At society level LP have the objective of involving Congolese civil society and public institutions in order to institutionalize the Living Peace approach and influence policy. Living Peace Institute transfers the message of peace to local CSOs and Congolese government institutions to persuade them to take responsibility and action against SGBV, starting with SGBV between uniformed men and civilians. Living Peace builds the capacity of state actors and CSOs, by engaging them in activities and debates, and by actively participating in all technical working groups and platforms that seek to end SGBV.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 4.1.2.Number of Facilitators recruited by CSOs and trained to conduct group therapy sessions in communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For first round of the intervention for the year 2021-2022, LPI in collaboration with its partner identified and trained facilitators on the identification of LP group participants and the facilitation of LP psychosocial group sessions.  180 facilitators among them 141 males and 39 females were trained to facilitate psychosocial support group sessions.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 4.2.1.Number of training events tailored for military and police men</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the first round of the intervention for the year 2021-2022, LPI in collaboration with its partner ISL identified and trained 18 military and 32 police forces on gender equality, prevention of SGBV and LP methodology. They are now contributing in the implementation of 32 LP psychosocial support groups in military and police communities in north and south Kivu</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 4.1.1.Number of representatives from community organizations, CSOs, trained in gender transformative approaches.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the first term of the year 2021-2022, LPI trained 20 staffs of 5 Civil Society Organizations  on gender  transformative to engaging men and boys in violence prevention and 40 staff  on  monitoring and evaluation. Transformative approaches actively seek to examine, challenge and change rigid gender norms and power imbalances. They encourage critical awareness; question the cost of harmful and inequitable gender norms and highlight the benefits of changing them; it emphasizes the empowerment of women / girls and people and engages / empowers boys and men in the areas of gender equality, violence prevention and sexual and reproductive health.  the training on M&amp;E focused on data collection and treatment, analyzing data and communicating results and the use of analyzed data.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 3:  Creating and restoring social support systems at the community level</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the community level, LP project aims at creating and restoring social support systems to support men, women and families in the target communities (both participants and non-participants in the LP psychosocial support groups) in establishing an environment that is gender-equitable, peaceful and favorable to positive social change. Restored community-based social support systems increase social cohesion between families, individuals and community structures resulting in higher levels of inclusion, and solidarity between community members.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 3.1.1. Number of men and women actively participated in LP program group sessions where they learn to mitigate obstacles to support SGBV victims within their communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to Living Peace Methodology, during the last phase of the process of change (consolidation and dissemination in the community), which cover the last four sessions ( from 12th to 15th ) men and women learn to organize community activism activities aiming at raising awareness on gender equality, positive masculinity, and SGBV prevention among community members. During this phase, security networks and groups of neighbors are created to allow participants to continue discussing to find solutions to problems that affect their lives and their communities. This indicator will be reported at the end of the phase</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 3.1.5.People attending mobile cinema screening films within the community</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">As mentioned in the above paragraphs, more than 2000 people attended LP films during during tree days of Amani Festival between 4th and 6th February 2022, and more than 1500 people attended LP film during Hadisi festival between 24th February and 3rd March 2022.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 3.1.2.Number of community campaigns or activities resulting from LP Program participation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community campaigns aim at increasing the levels of social cohesion in the community and reduction of conflict in communities in the targeted areas. They contribute to the reduction of stigmatization and facilitate re-integration of SGBV survivors by husbands, families, community in target communities. They are also intended to improve perception in terms of equal right to inherit land and promote peace and gender equality among community members. During the first semester of the year 2021-2022, two sensitization events have been conducted. Those are Amani festival which took place during the period from 4th to 6th February 2022 and Hadisi festival which took place during the period from 24th February to 3 rd March2022. For LPI, Amani festival constitutes a great opportunity to share its message and experiences about positive masculinity, gender equality promotion and the promotion of peace with more than 30 thousand people who attend this event very day and more than 300 international and local institutions. During the Amani Festival, 57 community facilitators of LP psychosocial support groups shared their experiences and journey of transformation with more than 3000 persons who visited directly LPI stand. More than 2500 brochures with clear message about the promotion of gender equality, positive masculinity, and peaceful cohabitation were distributed. During the trees days of Amani Festival, LPI has also disseminated the message about the role of the men in peace stabilization and SGBV prevention through direct animation on Kivu Star  and Bura FM Radios. During Hadisi festival, 40 military couples from LP beneficiaries of Katindo Military camp and and 40 police couples  form Munzenze Police camp shared their journey of transformation with more than 1500 person who visited the stand of LPI directly. More than 2000 brochures were distributed.  Note that the overall objective of Hadisi festival is to promote the role of women in the art , as well as to make visible the work of artists women in the region.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 3.3.1.Number of ex-combatants and ex-child soldiers who participated in LP Program psychosocial support groups</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">LPI is working with ex-combatants and ex-child soldiers in Kirotche and Mweso health zones to help them to address a range of psychosocial challenges during their transition to civilian life in order to increase their prospects for successful reintegration. This includes the healing of individual and social trauma; reduce the effects of stigma and exclusion in order to create a space that facilitates the process of reconciliation between ex-combatants, their families and communities. In the context of the on-going conflict in eastern DRC, it seems that the social fabric is extremely weak. The fragmented nature of society is a serious obstacle to the reintegration process of ex-combatants. The building of social capital through the expansion of social networks, and then the more general establishment of social cohesion in the community, should be at the heart of the processes of social reintegration. the average rate of participation in LP psychosocial support group for ex-combatants is 91%. This means that 13 ex-combatants per group participate regularly in LP psychosocial support group session.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 3.5.1.Number of psychosocial and gender-equitable peace messages broadcasted via Radio/TV/social media</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">LPI works with la Benevolencia to develop and broadcast gender equitable messages on radios in north and south Kivu provinces. Radio campaigns intends to disseminate living peace messages on the importance of working with men to prevent sexual and gender-based violence and conflict; stress the importance of support for SGBV survivors and those indirectly affected by it; and to encourage cooperation between civilians and the security organs. For the period from October 2021 to 31st march 2022, 6 radio drummers (sketches) were developed and disseminated on 38 radios in North-Kivu province and 28 radios in south Kivu province. Disseminated messages focused on: managing frustration and anger,  communication and dialogue to solve couple and family problems at home, creating peace at home with his wife and happy children,  improving family health conditions, stop alcohol and reduce drinking , gender equality and positive masculinity, sex and sexuality.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 3.2.1.Number of military men and police men who participated in LP Program psychosocial support groups</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Living Peace groups with police and military men as participants aim to influence both the private and professional behavior of the participants. By learning positive and non-violent coping strategies, including management of power relations in the household and in the workplace, the role of the male participants as protectors of the community will improve. In turn, better relationships with community members will result in more adequate responses to SGBV and its prevention. During the first round of the intervention for the year 2021-2022, 240 military and 240 policemen were identified to participate in LP group session in north and south Kivu provinces. The average rate of participation for military is in north Kivu is 97% and 89 in south kivu. For the police, the average rate of participation is 98 in north Kivu and 77% in south kivu. In general, the average participation rate for men in uniform is 90%.This means that 13 participants per group participate regularly in LP psychosocial group session.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 3.5.2.Number of people reached by media campaigns</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media campaigns aim at making visible the work of LP, sharing success stories and disseminate messages of gender equality and promotion of peace. LPI Face book page helps to assess people who are interacting with message developed by LPI. During the period from 1st October 2021 to 31st March 2022, LPI media campaigns reached more than 75 countries with a total of 264605 followers. 74% of them are from different cities of DRC.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 3.1.4. Number of mobile cinema developed to promote gender equality, positive masculinity, SGBV prevention/ mitigation in target communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mobile cinemas are developed to support the work of community facilitators of LP psychosocial support groups. It aims not only at consolidating the effect of the intervention on individual and family level, but also to raise the awareness of the whole community about the problem of SGBV   and its consequences on the lives of both men and women and the benefits resulting from engaging men in the transformation of harmful gender norms for peaceful families and communities. In order to attain this objective, two types of film were developed. The first one is 45 minutes film that reflects the LPI approach, its successes, to be used in community events. The second one is a 5-minutes promo film that mainly serves to show to partners and other stakeholders (including the donor) for advocacy and fundraising.  These two films ware visualized during Amani and Hadisi festivals and will be visualized during community celebrations in more 22 community of intervention in may 2022.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 3.4.1.Number of religious and community leaders trained as facilitators of LP program psychosocial groups</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Religious and community leaders were trained in gender transformative approaches to restore social cohesion at community levels. Training religious leaders in the Living Peace methodology helped them reach out to members of their religious communities while applying a methodology that combines promotion of gender equality, mental health care prevention and psychosocial support. During the first term of the intervention for the year 2021-2022, LPI in collaboration with its local partners has identified 171 community facilitators to facilitate 72 therapeutic group sessions.  171 community leaders among them 139 males and 32 females were trained as facilitators of LP psychosocial support groups</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 3.1.3.Number of people attending community celebration sessions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will be reported at the end of the year because there is no community celebration that was organize during the period of reporting</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator 3.4.2.Number of traditional and community leaders involved in all process of LP intervention to support and promote peace, gender equality and intervene as appropriate in families and community conflict.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Traditional and community leaders are involved in all process intervention to increase their capacity to support individuals and community in presenting positive models of masculinity, preventing and mitigating SGBV, and gender equality. During the first round of the intervention for the year 2021-2022, 276 community leaders contributed to the identification of 171 facilitators and 178 community leaders contributed to the identification of  1080 participants in 20 communities in north Kivu, 10 communities in south-Kivu and 3 communities in Ituri.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 1: Individual Level: Trauma healing of individual men</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the individual level, the goal of the LP psychosocial group sessions is to reduce trauma and related issues (such as mental health symptoms, substance abuse, negative coping skills), and the restoration of a sense of trust, belongingness and social cohesion. In addressing men&#x2019;s trauma and coping strategies that often include SGBV, new space is provided for behavior change and adaptation of gender-equality attitudes.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 1.1.1: Number of Master trainers trained in delivering LP methodology</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the period from October 2021 to 31 March 2022,  LPI organized  4 trainings for 12 master trainers ( 9 males and 3 females). The first training was a 5 days training on trauma and SGBV.  This training focused on building the capacity of LPI master trainers on how to identify psychosocial and mental problems associated with SGBV. Building awareness of Violence and trauma in the lives of children, youth, and families and competency about Trauma Informed Care (TIC) and about Current Models and Tools for Implementing Trauma-Informed Care.  The second training was a 5 days training on LP methodology, group dynamic and group facilitation. The training focus on how LP methodology works, as a designed psychosocial support group and the effective methods of training community facilitators. The third training was a 5 day training on clinical supervision. The training focused on building the capacity of LPI master trainers in providing specific support to LP group facilitators in term of managing the stress and personal challenges arising from their particular role, through both individual and group supervision. the fourth training was  a 5 days  training on monitoring and evaluation The content of the training focused on the operationalization of project indicators, data collection and treatment, analyzing data and communicating results and the use of analyzed data.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output indicator 1.1.1. Number of Master trainers trained in delivering LP methodology</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the period from October 2021 to 31 March 2022, 12 master trainers were trained on delivering LP methodology/approach notably the training on gender, violence and trauma, the training on LP methodology, group dynamic and group facilitation, the training on clinical supervision and the training on monitoring and evaluation.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 1.1.2: Number  of targeted men attended LP Program gender-specific psychosocial group education sessions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the year 2021-2022, LPI have to reach 2025 men in two round. For the first round of the year 2021-2022, 1080 men were identified to constitute 72 groups. 600 men which represent 56% are in North Kivu province, 360 men which represent 33 % are in South Kivu province and 120 participants who represent 11 % are in Ituri province. Husband of SGBV survivor represent 11% of all participants, the men in uniform are representing 44% (Military men 22% and policemen 22% respectively), the participant living in the high risk zone are representing 33 % while the ex-combatants and ex-child soldiers are representing 11 % of all participants. The average age of men is 39.3 year old whereas the average age for women is 32.6 year old.  1080 identified families have 5579 children. The average child by family is 5.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2025"></target>
     <actual value="1080"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome1.1 Improved mental health (depression/ PTSD symptoms) among LP Program participating men</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participation in LP psychosocial support groups is expected to produce effects on  the mental health of beneficiaries by helping them to heal from symptoms of depression, PTSD,...This is linked with changes in individual ways of thinking and perceiving past and present life experiences and  adoption of  new and positive attitudes and behaviors when interacting with his social environment.  Results related to this indicator will be reported after participants completed the whole process.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 1.1.3: Percentage  of men who attended more than 70% of sessions of LP
Program psychosocial group sessions for men</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 1st  round of Living Peace psychosocial support groups started in February 2022 to end up in Mai 2022. At the period of reporting, seven psychosocial support sessions was already conducted. The average rate of participation is 90%. This means that 13 out of 15 participants per group participate regularly in each session.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="90"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2..Reports (from men and women participants) of men&#x2019;s reduced use and abuse of alcohol and drugs</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will be reported at the end of the first round in may 2022</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome Indicator 1.3.1: Reports (from men and women participants) of improved positive coping skills among participating men</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will be reported at the end of the first round of the intervention in may 2022</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome Indicator 1.4.1: Reports (from men and women participants) of improved trust and confidence in others, stronger social cohesion in the community and a restored sense of belongingness among participating men</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This indicator will be reported at the end of the year</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clinical supervisions  and Mentorship</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In order to  strengthening the quality of the intervention  LPI performs  mentorship and clinical supervisions that involves LP facilitators, technical supervisors, project &#x2028;coordinators (or assistant coordinators). The purpose of clinical supervision is to provide a safe and confident environment for project staff to reflect on and discuss their work and their personal and professional response to their work. The focus is on supporting staff personal and professional development and reflection on their practice, critical analysis of LP group evolution to ensure quality service for participants and the psychosocial well being of the facilitators by helping them to learn to cope positively with distress which should resulting from both working environment and personal life experiences. T</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of facilitators who participate in clinical supervision  sessions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to LP methodology, clinical supervision are  organized once a monthly after 4 successive psychosocial group sessions aiming at  offering emotional support to the facilitators of the groups.  For the period of reporting, only one clinical supervision was organized in 22 community of intervention.  140 facilitators among them 112 men and 28 women participated in the first clinical supervision. Individual and group supervision are designed to help LP group facilitators to effectively deal with the double burden resulting in the their daily exposure to stressful and distressing situations in their community and their first role as helpers in listening LP group participants painful experience.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 5.Promoting women socio-economic empowerment with positive support of husbands through women&#x2019;s participation in Village Savings and Loan Associations (VSLAs) and men&#x2019;s participation into the Living peace program enriched with select topics from the journey of transformation program.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main activity carried out to achieve this objective is the implementation of VSLA with women spouses of military and police men former beneficiaries of LP psychosocial support program. The implementation of VSLAs is entrusted by Centre Rafiki, a Congolese local organization which was identified based on its previous experience on women economic empowerment and after a satisfactory organization capacity assessment. For the year 2021-2022, VSLA are being implemented in Katindo military camp and Munzenze police camp.  The primary purpose of a VSLA is to provide simple savings and loan facilities, in a community that does not have access to formal financial services.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 5.3.1. Number of Men and Women members of VSLAs attending the training on cross-cutting issues which include sexual and reproductive health and rights and sexual and gender-based violence (SRHR &amp; SGBV)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the first term of the VSLA implementation, LPI trained 40 women from 20 VSLA groups on cross cutting issues including: gender stereotypes and norms, Sexual and Reproductive Health and Rights (SRHR) and Sexual and Gender-Based Violence (VSBG), power relations and decision-making in the home, joint management of economic affairs and many others. Participants in this trained were reinforced in how to organize a group communication aiming at behaviour and attitude change. Those women will work with Field Agents to engage other VSLA members in discussions generate communication leading to awareness of their problems, thus initiating a process of critical reflection to find effective solutions. The table below show the number of people trained on cross cutting issues</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-05-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output indicator 5.2.1. Number of selected men attended LP-JOT joint sessions for positive support of women empowerment and joint economic management</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the implementation of VSLA, joint sessions are planned focusing on how men can positively support women&#x2019;s economic empowerment, engage women in decision-making, in doing business together and income sharing to increase family wellbeing. 293 men participated in the first shared session, 289 men participated in the second shared session and 299 men participated in the third shared session.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-05-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output indicators 5.1.1.Number of field officers trained in the VSLA approach to support existing and to create new VSLAs in target communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the implementation of VSLA group to be effective, 2 field officers and 4 field agents were trained on VSLA implementation and supervision. The trainings focused on how to undertake effective community mobilizations towards the formation of a VSLA, to ensure that community leaders understand the intervention and its contribution to their respective communities, to secure the commitment of the VSLA members in the communities to form and run VSLA, equip VSLA members with knowledge and skills to effectively manage and benefit from a VSLA, to inculcate the savings culture among VSLA members, inculcate a culture of planning and savings for emergencies, to ensure effective functionality and operations of VSLA. trainings helped the staff of Centre Rafiki to have a clear understanding of VSLA methodology, and how to make beneficiaries to become active savers and borrowers.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output indicators 5.1.2.Number of VSLAs groups of women organized and fully functioning in selected communities.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the year 2021-2022, 20 VSLAs grouping 500 beneficiairies (250 spouses of Military men and 250 spouses of  police men were created and are functioning in Katindo Military community and Munzenze police community. At the period of reporting 13 VSLA sessions  took place with an average rate of participation evaluates at 96.7%. This means that 24 women per group participate regularly in VSLA sessions.  During this period, 500 VSLA members gathered 30224500 Congolese francs  and offered loans to  256 members of VSLA.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-05-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output indicator 5.1.3. Number of women actively attended VSLAs sessions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">VSLAs are implemented in tree main phases. The Preparatory phase, which consists of providing general information to local leaders and prospective VSLA members, the Intensive phase  with consecutive training meetings aiming at helping the association elects its leaders, establishes its constitution and sets out the rules and procedures that govern financial activities. It then continues to meetings, in which the association learns to manage social fund, share-purchase/savings and loan transactions.  VSLA cycle 2022 started in the first week of January to close in September 2022.  For the reporting period 13 sessions have been completed. the average rate of participation in VSLA sessions is 96.7%. This means that 24 women per group participate regularly in VSLA sessions.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
