<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-21/DDA-3379/SA2/NFI/ES/INGO/21176</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lifesaving Emergency Shelter/ Non-Food Items Response to IDPs in Tuliguled Woreda of Somali region in 2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia continues to face severe humanitarian conditions as needs emanating from conflict, climatic shocks, disease outbreaks, desert locust and the adverse effects of the ongoing Covid-19 pandemic continue to grow. Conflict has remained the main driver of humanitarian needs in the country in 2021.

According to Ethiopian Humanitarian Needs Overview (HNO 2021), more than 23M people nationwide were projected to have humanitarian needs in 2021, a majority of whom were in Oromia (6.7 million followed by Somali (3.8M) then thirdly Amhara (3.4M). One of the biggest impacts from conflict and climate shocks in Ethiopia is population displacement. As per the Displacement Tracking Matrix, there are 2.1 million internally displaced persons (IDPs) across the country, outside of Tigray. 67 per cent of the IDPs have been displaced due to conflict. Most IDPs live in sub-standard conditions, with limited access to essential services.

In the Ethiopian Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP)  Mid-Year review for 2021, 14.8M people are targeted for support with 1.488B funding requirement country wide. Somali region ranks second in the regional targets, having 3.9M people targeted. 

As the Es/NFI dashboard (published in October 2021) shows, only 1.4M peoples have been reached so far, which is only 37% of the cluster target (3.9M). In Somali region only 23% has been reached and the gap remains 70% with the remaining 7% under commitment. The S/NFI cluster prioritized 10 woredas those extremely at high need for Es/NFI assistance across Oromia, Somali and Benishangul Gumuz regional states.  

A conflict erupted in July 2021 between two communities/clans (Gerri and Jarso) that was caused by a combination of disputes over the border separating the Oromia and Somali regions and disputes on resources and farming land. As a result, 1,840 households (11,040 individuals) were displaced according to the government-led joint assessment report released in late October 2021.

The proposed intervention will support the most vulnerable crisis affected individuals by providing lifesaving emergency shelter and non-food items to 1,440 displaced HH including affected persons with disability. The intervention will target HHs whose living standards and ability to pursue normal productive and social activities are low, and who are unable to meet this basic needs due to conflict, drought, and disease, and who are in need of emergency shelter and non-food items (ESNFI V1).

The project will provide in-kind assistance in Emergency Shelter and Non-food Items for lowlands (ESNFI V1 ) and  Emergency Shelter and Non-Food Items for persons with disabilities ( ESNFI V1-Disable) for IDPs, 15% for host communities and 5% for disables based on the context of project areas. These all, the process will be done considering the COVID19 precautions both for ZOA/OWDA staff and targeted beneficiaries in line with the current pandemic disease and its means of transmission. ZOA/OWDA will ensure to minimize COVID19 pandemic dissemination by putting in place adequate prevention measures like facemasks, handwashing facilities, using sanitizer, and ensuring social distancing during the distribution.

The provision of ESNFI is critical to the survival of displaced households as they are at risk of violence, especially women and girls. As the needs assessment revealed women and girls are disproportionately affected by the conflict and are vulnerable. Despite the provision of ESNFI, the intervention ensured gender mainstreaming in the designing of project components while integrating activities, such as awareness-raising and distribution of IEC materials on gender equality. While ensuring the involvement of women and girls in every step of implementation, the implementing partner will ensure distribution is conducted by a gender-balanced team while creating a safe environment. Furthermore, training on PSEA will be provided to anyone involved in the implementation of the action.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organisation for Welfare and Development in Action (OWDA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atsbha Teklehaymanot</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Response Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 921 408076</telephone>
   <email>a.teklehaymanot@zoa.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dawn Hoyle</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 911 207908</telephone>
   <email>d.hoyle@zoa.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vera Djabali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251911217147</telephone>
   <email>v.djabali@zoa.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.92946999 43.32903576</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-25">300000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-21176">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-25">300000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305466733">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-11">300000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
