<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-21/DDA-3379/SA1/E-N-P/NGO/18560</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response for Crisis affected  communities  through provision of education, Nutrition and Protection  Intervention of Deka Suftu Woreda of Liban Zone Somali Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for welfare and Development in Action (OWDA) is proposing multi-sectoral lifesaving, Emergency Response for Crisis affected communities through provision of education, Nutrition and Protection Intervention. The main objective of the project is to improve emergency affected school age girls, boys&apos; through equitable accessible, safe and inclusive education, quality of formal and non-formal learning opportunities, address the protection need of crisis affected people, promote protection safety and dignity, support preventive nutrition, and treatment service to children under five years of age and pregnant and lactating women for conflict and disaster affected  vulnerable population in Deka Suftu Woreda of Somali Region. Similarly, the project will support on the current COVID-19 pandemic prevention and control measures to contain the spread of the virus, and prevention of sexual exploitations and abuse. The project will support 41,928 beneficiaries including 10 IDPs sites with 12,844 H.Hs (source of DTM23) by an estimated budget of $ 499,900($300,000 for Education,109,900 for protection and 90,0000 for Nutrition). 

Deka Suftu has 20 sites of conflict inducted IDPs comprising of 4,237 households with a total of 25,688 individuals (Source: DTM23) with no schools, limited access of education formal and non-formal learning for the host communities, limited Nutrition workforce, Lack of trained nutrition staff with limited capacity to undertake the nutrition activities. furthermore, the availability and access to protection services is limited among IDPS sites and host communities. Child protection and gender-based violence concerns are high within the IDP populations.  Child protection risks and GBV are exacerbated in all emergencies (including infectious disease pandemics), while GBV in particular remains grossly underreported due to social norms and stigma associated especially with sexual violence and rape (HRP2020).

 The proposed response project will support and prevent, detect and treat vulnerable communities for acute malnutrition through Community Management of Acute Malnutrition (CMAM), family MUAC screening at community level, early identification of SAM cases and referral of malnourished children, promotion of IYCF activities promotion and support, Support the treatment of SAM with/ without medical complications in children between 6-59 months in the OTP and SC sites, and Targeted Supplementary Feeding for moderately malnourished children of 6 to 59 months old and malnourished PLW. Similarly, the project support improving the knowledge of health care workers, health extension workers through a short session training using prevention and control measures of COVID19. support the optimal Infant and Young Child Feeding in Emergency (IYCF-E) practices for infants and young children under 24 months and support the nutritional needs of pregnant and lactating women (PLW) and continuum of care. The project will improve safety and wellbeing of the children and women through emergency CP and GBV intervention, capacity building and support of enhancing the identification and case management system and support to children at risk, including Unaccompanied and Separated Children. likewise, the project will support GBV risk prevention and mitigation, community raising campaigns on GBV and CP, and provision of psycho-social support to GBV survivors and at-risk children. The project will   establish temporary learning spaces, emergency school feeding to address short term hunger and improve attentiveness, provide scholastic materials, equip schools with the necessary hygiene and sanitation supplies, liaise with health extension workers to train  for school directors and teachers on the implementation of the safe school operations, train teachers on Psychosocial Support Skills (PSS) psychosocial support and commencing back to school campaign in order to maximize retention after the school closures.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Welfare and Development in Action</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Welfare and Development in Action</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Abdulkadir  Ahmed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251915320833</telephone>
   <email>Mohamedak@owdaeth.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.92946999 43.32903576</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="61" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="18" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="21" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-10">269459.22</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-10">281615.28</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-18560">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-10">551074.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Welfare and Development in Action</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305147736">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-18">220429.8</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Welfare and Development in Action</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305384006">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-21">165322.35</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Welfare and Development in Action</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305469499">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-15">165322.35</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Welfare and Development in Action</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
