<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-21/DDA-3379/SA2/N-H/INGO/21241</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To provide critical life-saving assistance through nutrition interventions to most acutely vulnerable groups affected by the expanding severe drought in Dhas, Dire, Elwaye, and Miyo woredas of Borena Zone, and through health interventions in Chinaksen and Gola Odda woredas of East Hararghe Zone of Oromia Region with a special attention given to children under-five 5, pregnant and lactating women (PLW), people with disability (PWD) and old people.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the 2021 Mid-Year Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP), 14.8 million are targeted for humanitarian assistance. About 3.2 million of them are targeted to receive basic lifesaving health services, the majority (55%) being children. Likewise, an estimated 2.91 million people are targeted for humanitarian nutrition response, with children under the age of five accounting for 72% of the targeted beneficiaries. This EHF-funded emergency Nutrition response aim to contribute to the reduction of nutrition related morbidity and mortality among children under five years of age (U5), Pregnant and Lactating Women (PLW), and women of child-bearing age in six drought-affected and prioritized woredas of Borena zone, Oromia region.
The nutrition response will contribute to the reduction of morbidity and mortality among children under five years of age (U5), PLW, and women of childbearing age in the intervention woredas. Key nutrition intervention focus areas include both preventive and recuperative services. The recuperative services include strengthening the local health system capacity to detect, refer, and treatment mainly acutely malnutrition children under five years of age and PLW in TFP and TSFP. While the preventive nutrition intervention focuses on the protection, promotion, and support of adequate Infant and Young Children Feeding (IYCF) program in the context of emergency by applying effective and proven methods and mechanisms. In addition, strengthening local health system capacity on early warning, nutrition situation surveillance, and nutrition emergency preparedness and response planning will be given due emphasis. Logistically and technical support will be delivered to nutrition service delivery sites. Procurement and provision of gap-filling routine medications, supplies, and equipment will be done to ensure the quality of SAM and MAM management in intervention areas. Provision of standard nutrition training such as IMAM/CMAM, IYCF will be provided to frontline health workers based on needs and gaps and in line with the national guidelines. Post-training follow-up, mentoring, and coaching of health workers will continue to be key attributes of the AAH&#x2019;s nutrition intervention approach in proposed woredas. 
AAH endeavors to achieve results stipulated in this EHF project through the active engagement, collaboration, and coordination between local health authorities, WHO, UNICEF and WFP as well as targeted communities. Moreover, cross-cutting issues such as PSEA, AAP, and Gender will be mainstreamed across all proposed activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-21" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-21" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-02-20" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beza Abebe</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0911 25 54 06</telephone>
   <email>pd@et-actionagainsthunger.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.50805539 38.76512402</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-21"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-23">737946.43</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-23">132053.57</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-21241">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-23">870000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305492378">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-30">162000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
