<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-21/DDA-3379/RA2/P/INGO/20106</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community based integrated child protection and gender-based violence assistance for the Crisis-affected communities in Amhara and Afar Regions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following the ethnic conflict between Somali and Afar and escalation of the Tigray conflict in bordering Amhara and Afar regions, more than 1.3 million IDPs in Amhara and 112,158 IDPs in Afar regions are in acute humanitarian assistance.   Conflict is still ongoing and more causalities are reported, and additional displaced and conflict-affected persons are expected. 
The conflict and displacement have had severe adverse effects on the physical, social, and emotional well-being of the communities as a result of exposure to violence, family separation, deterioration in living conditions, loss of property and livelihoods, disruption to social networks, inability to provide for oneself and family, and lack of access to basic services. 
This project aims to make a significant contribution to the reduction of and response to Gender-Based Violence (GBV) and Child Protection (CP) problems in Afar region &#x2013; zone 4 (Chifra, Ewa, Awura and Gulina woredas) and Amhara - North Wollo (Wolidiya and kobo towns) by assisting survivors become more confident and comfortable in accessing support and strengthening the existing referral pathways.
To respond to the child protection and gender-based violence concerns exacerbated due to the recurrent displacement in both regions, GOAL Ethiopia (GE) and the local implementing partners (MCMDO and DPO) proposes to address the concerns through implementing integrated community-based child protection and gender-based violence program. 
Based on this evidence the project is designed in an integrated approach that would effectively meet the needs of beneficiaries and complement our wider humanitarian response programs.  Hence, this project combined Gender-Based Violence (GBV) and Child Protection (CP) to help the beneficiaries in addressing several protection-related issues, such as abuse, discrimination and inequality through a more efficient and integrated intervention. 
The integration will also be reflected during the awareness-raising, events planning, shared prevention messages preparations, and strategizing response activities. Besides, we will explore existing referral pathways and strengthen relationships with local service providers to improve coordination between local protection actors.
Through the provision of case management services, psychosocial supports, capacity building activities, referrals, community awareness sessions, cash transfers, for GBV Survivors and OVC, dignity kits provision, and strengthening the coordination and local capacity of the community, GOAL Ethiopia will address GBV and child protection problems in all intervention woredas and contribute to the achievement of cluster objectives. 
GOAL will collaborate with two local partners: MCMDO (Mothers and Children Multi   sectoral Development Organization) will support to respond to the protection needs in Amhara region North Wello zone (Wolidya and Kobo towns), while Development for Peace Organization (DPO) will  support the project implementation in Awura, and Gulina woredas in Afar region. Besides, GOAL Ethiopia will directly implement the protection activities in the remaining two woredas in Afar region (Chifra and Ewa) . 
GOAL along with those two local NGOs( MCMDO and DPO) will establish and maintain coordination among humanitarian actors, identify survivors of human rights violations, facilitate referrals of individuals with specific protection cases, and provide cash support for specific protection cases that involve case management, to enable beneficiaries to cover their transportation and food costs during counselling and medical treatment, as well as cost of medical consultations and treatment themselves and per diem for caregivers of child survivors.
A total of 24,780 beneficiaries in six woredas across Afar and Amhara regions are targeted to be addressed through this integrated GBV and child protection response project all intervention.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development for Peace Organization (DPO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCMDO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dinkneh Asfaw</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 (0)911214432</telephone>
   <email>dinkneha@et.goal.ie</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fiseha Mezgebu</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Director - MCMDO</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251913618247</telephone>
   <email>fishkid27@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jemal Hassen</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 953967066</telephone>
   <email>jemalh@et.goal.ie</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maria Perrella</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 991160942</telephone>
   <email>mperrella@et.goal.ie</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.03628232 40.77273098</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="ET03">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amhara</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.56495271 38.04353749</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-26">76633.66</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-26">310366.34</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-20106">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-26">387000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305305857">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-06">387000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
