<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-21/DDA-3379/RA2/N/NGO/20088</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Nutrition Service for war and conflict -affected communities in  four  woredas in Tigray and Amhara Regions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The situation in Tigray, and the spillover of the conflict to neighboring Afar and Amhara regions, is very dynamic and unpredictable. Except the limited access for incoming humanitaraian aid, access for humanitarian actors with in Tigray is improved with an estimated 75 per cent of the area now accessible. The ongoing war and critical food shortage with limited access to humanitarian aid due to the conflict complemented by the consecutive seasons of below-normal rainfall exacerbated by the strongest climatic event in decades have caused agricultural, livestock, food security, nutrition and health conditions in Tigray and  Amhara  regions. The diminishing food security situation is contributing to high rates of malnutrition, water shortages, and emergency humanitarian needs in affected parts of the country. The project will support and provide the lifesaving nutrition services for under five children and PLW . The targeted Woredas (IDPs) are highly vulnerable communities with who have limited access to nutrition services. The intervention is required to respond and supports the dire humanitarian crisis increased needs for early identification and treatment of acute malnutrition which is on the edge of wider catastrophic crisis. There is food shortage and hunger in all woredas as grain or food items and NFI are either burned, looted or destroyed people are suffering and dying of hunger. International organizations indicate that in coming months, to mass starvation and a risk of famine in the longer term, to sustained food insecurity and dependence on external assistance. All the 5.7 million people in Tigray are affected by this crisis, of whom the United Nations estimates that 4.5 million are &#x2018;in need&#x2019;. The spillover of the conflict into neighboring Afar and Amhara regions continue to take a heavy toll on civilians with increased displacements and civilian casualties. In Amhara, an estimated 1,200,000 people have been displaced in a number of conflict-affected areas in North Gondar, Central Gondar, South, Wag Hemra, North Wello, and in various pockets across the region and MCMDO is planned to intervene in two prioritized needy woredas of North Wello Zone of Raya Kobo and Guba Lafto.  It is, first and foremost, an urgent humanitarian disaster demanding life-saving assistance. Due to this it needs close support to cascade the CMAM program to the health post level to strengthen the OTP role out and SC in the health centre level as well as TSFP and BSFP at health post level strategy, lifesaving intervention, and high number of SAM and MAM admission in the Woredas.
This project will provide immediate lifesaving emergency nutrition assistance for the war-affected, displaced, and vulnerable persons in the targeted woredas. The project will also link with other government routine health services and partner projects to prevent future relapses. Therefore, the project will create synergies for stronger complementary, integration, sustainability and strengthen CMAM services in the existing facility in a way that will safeguard against malnutrition for vulnerable groups in the future, The goal of the project is to contribute reduce mortality and morbidity in related to malnutrition, improve access to life&#xAD;saving nutrition interventions for the most vulnerable populations of under-five children and PLW, establish/strength multi-sectoral coordination for the management and response of malnutrition, increase the awareness of the community.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mothers and Children Multisectoral Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mothers and Children Multisectoral Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-08" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-07" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-07" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fiseha Mezgebu</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251930012682</telephone>
   <email>Fishkid27@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tilahun Mulugeta</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251912503354</telephone>
   <email>dg.mcmdo@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET03">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amhara</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.56495271 38.04353749</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="ET01">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tigray</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.77711683 38.43867474</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-10-08"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-06">79195.79</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-07-07"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-06">177247.72</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-20088">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-06">256443.51</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mothers and Children Multisectoral Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305229888">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-14">256443.51</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mothers and Children Multisectoral Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
