<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-21/DDA-3379/SA1/A-E-H-P/INGO/18580</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Multi-Sectoral  Response in two woredas of West GuJi Zone (Gelana  Melka Soda)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vison Ethiopia is proposing an integrated multi sector emergency response for crisis affected communities in West Guji zone to address the existing dire needs of among communities using EHF 2021 1st round allocation fund to save lives. This   project implements integrated response in Gelana and Melka Soda. In Gelana four sectors Agriculture, Health, Protection and Education will be integrated and in Melka Soda Education and Protection will be integrated. The proportion of budget allocation for each sector aligns with the directives given by UNOCHA.
A recent Inter agency&#x2019;s Field Mission Rapid Assessment (July 2020) report on protection, education, agriculture and health highlighted the existence of lack of access to health services and proper child protection responses where children are reported to be out of school. Additionally, Returnees and host communities  tend to suffer disproportionately from poor health conditions due to the hardships of displacement that often lead to high malnutrition rates and other underlying health factors, making affected communities more susceptible to illnesses. Such vulnerable living conditions are also known to increase exposure to GBV, particularly for women and girls. Climate induced hazards and impacts, intercommunal conflicts lack of basic social services and other humanitarian and protection related issues like GBV continue to affect the physical protection and the living condition of IDPs and host communities across several regions in the country. 
In Gelana there is recurrent flood and drought where the residents face several challenges to cop up with earning their livelihood. Meher/Hagaya season rainfall performance of the previous cropping season was characterized by early onset and early cessation and below the normal in quantity coupled with absence of shower. The rainfall was excessive during the onset that caused water logging and affected land preparation. Moreover, the excessive rainfall resulted overflowing of Gelana River, which crosses the woreda and flooded the croplands of 37028 HHs. The response will improve resilience of the target population through contributing for the improvement of their livelihood, Health, protection, and by creating access to quality education. 
In its education response the project will work towards enhancing  access to equitable safe and inclusive education for out of school children through flexible approaches (ASR and ALP), retain those who are in the system, strengthen the capacity of education personnel and community participation will be the focus of education.
In response to these protection issues, World Vison Ethiopia (WVE) will strengthening the case management system to identify, refer and support children at risk , GBV survivors, and vulnerable children, ensure the coordination of services through establishing functional referral pathways in all target woredas, expedite alternative care arrangement by facilitating foster care options for UASC whom parents are difficult to trace, and facilitating family tracing and reunification of UASC with their families to ensure long term care.  WVE will employ the FTR amp reunification steps in facilitating the reunification process.
As a multi-sector response, this project in its health component plans to equip existing health facilities in Guji by providing trainings to healthcare providers working at public health facilities on COVID-19 response. The project supports transportation costs for  Inter agency Emergency Health Kit/n and Emergency reproductive health (ERH block 2 kits ) from WHO/UNICEF/SWAN / warehouses in Gelana Woreda, provides logistics support for PHEM task force groups for outbreak verification, investigation, and supports mass vaccination campaigns including measles, cholera etc.
WV has proven experience in working smoothly with diverse partners. The project will identify partners exist in the project Woreda and discuss on areas of collaboration and avoid duplication</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Neway Bedada</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resource Development advisor</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2510911365753</telephone>
   <email>Neway_bedada@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samuel Tilahun</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian affairs Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2510911715336</telephone>
   <email>Samuel_Tilahun@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gedion Alemayehu</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Acquisition Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2510911694497</telephone>
   <email>gedion_alemayehu@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.50805539 38.76512402</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="22" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="10" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="10" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="58" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">456618.98</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">443383.64</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-18580">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">900002.62</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Ethiopia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305154764">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-24">720002.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Ethiopia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
