<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-21/DDA-3379/RA2/P/INGO/20092</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of life-saving EORE and VA services to IDP and host communities affected by explosive ordnance contamination in Tigray</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HI strategy in Tigray includes an integrated approach between Protection, Physical Rehabilitation, Mental Health and Psycho-social Support and Disability Inclusive Humanitarian Action, to improve access to services and wellbeing of the conflict affected populations (IDPs, local communities and refugees), including most vulnerable communities. 
For this second EHF allocation, HI is proposing a gradual scale-up in anticipation of a broader Humanitarian Mine Action (HMA) response in the Tigray region. Keeping in mind conflict sensitivity requirements and the extreme access constraints, HI is prioritizing a &#x2018;slow but steady&#x2019; approach to Explosive Ordnance Risk Education (EORE) and Victim Assistance (VA) to ensure adequate and sustainable relationship with the communities. As such, a 12-month project is preferred to secure HI presence and acceptance of the communities.
This first HMA intervention would solidify HI presence in the region, targeting North Western and Central regions. Shire will be the starting point of HI HMA activities (larger IDPs population in Tigray), with extension to other villages in Tahtay Koraro woreda depending on security, access and logistical capacities. Extension to Laelay Koraro, Tahtay Mayechew and Laelay Maychew woredas, or other woredas inside North Western and Central Tigray upon priority and access will be considered during the project period. 

Prior to integrating any new cities or villages, HI will closely coordinate with other EORE actors to ensure a coherent geographical coverage of the response. Risks of exposure to explosive ordnance are indeed concerning for both IDPs and local communities. Potential returns or further movements of IDPs in contaminated areas are to be considered in the coming months, depending on the conflict evolution. While the host community, desperately in needs of resources, is also exposed to such risks by moving in and around the city. Any people on the move are the most at risk because unaware of level of existing and new contamination.

Therefore, under this EHF opportunity, HI will first integrate EORE activities to its current activities. This will ensure a low profile but a safe and trust-based way to approach communities. EORE staff would deploy alongside other HI staff to do emergency EORE awareness raising. Basic information on behaviors and type of risks and accidents will be collected to inform future EORE messaging. As things progress, and under this grant, HI will gradually recruit and train additional EORE teams that will be able to conduct more diverse EORE sessions and deploy autonomously. There, the messaging and type of IEC material will be more diverse. HI also foresees community-focal point trainings, to ensure that the messaging is reaching more people and is locally-owned. In terms of VA, HI will scale up the physical rehabilitation and MHPSS intervention with one extra team funded under this envelop to enhance the quality of services dedicated to EO victims and other people with similar needs (physical rehabilitation, individual counselling, group/community activities). All teams will coordination their intervention and set internal and external referrals pathways. HI has led the creation of IMAS13.10 on victim assistance (VA) at the global level. Implementation of so-called VA specific efforts will lead proposed EORE activities to facilitate access to services in the domains of health (including emergency amp ongoing medical care, MHPSS, and rehabilitation) for people injured by EO, as well as indirect victims  in Tigray. HI proposed activities would facilitate Ethiopia&#x2019;s compliance with the Mine Ban Treaty as per the Oslo Action Plan in regards to EORE and VA.
HI is keen to provide a comprehensive response to the region and in time, implement the other land release activities and even some conflict transformation activities in due time. Thus really connecting well with the nexus approach.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Handicap International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Handicap International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">JAMES AVERY</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OPERATIONS MANAGER</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0961613875</telephone>
   <email>J.AVERY@HI.ORG</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET01">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tigray</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.77711683 38.43867474</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-05">398115.93</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-05">37061.84</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-20092">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-05">435177.77</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Handicap International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
