<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-21/DDA-3379/SA2/CCCM/INGO/21276</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination and Camp Management (CCCM) for the most vulnerable displaced populations in Somali region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the latest IOM DTM dataset (Round 27 of August/Sep 2021), there are 871,176 internally displaced people (IDPs) living in 427 IDP sites across Ethiopia&#x2019;s Somali Region as result of conflict, drought, and seasonal and flash floods. Out of these sites, CCCM activities are presently taking place in only three. In Siti Zone, which hosts 98,832 IDPs living in 41 IDP sites, ACTED is the only actor implementing CCCM activities, and existing funding allows ACTED to implement in just one IDP site (Hariso), reaching 6,733 IDPs. 

IDP communities living in Siti Zone of the Somali Region of Ethiopia continue to face multi-sectoral critical gaps in services, while existing vulnerabilities are exacerbated by the outbreak of COVID-19. IDP site living conditions are characterized by overcrowding, critically affecting the ability to practice key COVID-19 mitigation behavioral strategies, such as social distancing, while simultaneously lacking access to adequate and safe water sources, and basic health services. The living condition of IDPs in Siti Zone is exacerbated by limited humanitarian response. 

In response, ACTED and UNISOD aims to improve the living conditions and protection of18,701 individuals (comprised of  15,715 IDPs and a further  2,986 host community individuals) living Afase and Qaraf IDP sites of Maeyso Woreda, Siti Zone, Hariso IDP site of Gablalu Woreda, Siti Zone and  Afdem Town and Asli IDP Sites of Afdem Woreda, Siti Zone, , Somali Region, by providing coordination of humanitarian response, information sharing and empowerment of site residents through establishment of governance structures, cash for work for site improvements and increased protection for most vulnerable individuals. Due to the mixed nature of IDP sites, which typically include IDPs and host communities, ACTED and UNISOD will formalise the inclusion of the latter as beneficiaries through their representation in Site Maintenance Committees (SMCs) and Camp Management Committees (CMCs). More broadly, host community members will benefit from various other activities under this Action.

Moreover, the proposed Action takes seriously the responsibility of addressing all forms of marginalization, exclusion and inequalities in access while upholding the principles of gender equality and non-discrimination. ACTED and UNISOD will address the susceptibility to marginalization in participatory processes of vulnerable groups by prioritizing inclusive policies in program design and implementation. Women, men, girls and boys, among other groups, often experience crises very differently due to their different roles within the family and society, as well as unequal power dynamics that exist between and among them. Specific attention has therefore been allocated in the design of the present intervention to prevent and reduce those vulnerabilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNITED SOCIETY FOR SUSTAINABLE DEVELOPMENT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-03" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hussein Salat Birik</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sr CCCM Technical Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251(0)984787792</telephone>
   <email>hussein.birik@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rossella Lombardi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Representative</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 977353733</telephone>
   <email>rossella.lombardi@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.92946999 43.32903576</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-03"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-05">400000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-21276">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-05">400000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
