<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-21/DDA-3379/SA2/N/NGO/21302</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lifesaving emergency nutrition response to conflict affected communities in Kamashi, Sedal and Mizigan woredas, Kmashi zone, Benishangul Gumuz region, Ethiopia.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FIDO is an Ethiopian national non-governmental (NNGO) organization that has been founded by Ethiopian volunteers in Jimma zone since 2002 with 20 years of experience in community service. The organization is structured in two program wings, i.e., the developmental wing and the emergency and relief wing. With a mandate to work in all regions of Ethiopia, FIDO gives precedence to the quality of service delivered to the community. Emergency response to IDPs has been among the first intervention areas for the organization, and it remains the primary area of intervention to date. 
FIDO has designed this emergency nutrition response with a primary aim of addressing the humanitarian needs identified among Internally Displaced Persons, returnee and their host communities affected by conflict in Kamashi, Sedal and Mizigan woreda, Kamashi zone - Benishangul Gumuz region, Ethiopia. Up-to-date data from targeted woredas put into view a broad range of nutritional needs among women, children and other vulnerable groups affected by acute malnutrition as well as poor access and availability of basic health care services. 
The key drivers for the deterioration of the emergency situation in all three woredas are armed group conflict and intercommoned violence resulting in loss of life, property and dislocation from their livelihood while putting extra pressure on the host communities. Overall, the crisis-impacted populations are experiencing acute food shortage, lack of adequate access to nutrition screening and Health service, disruption in referral pathway, shortage of nutritional supplies as well as barriers in MAM and SAM case treatment resulting in sustained malnutrition cases. The security situation in the area has been impeding humanitarian actor&#x2019;s ability to operate in the areas. 
With full realization of the major issues mentioned above, this lifesaving emergency nutrition response focuses on reducing morbidity and mortality associated with under nutrition among children U5 and Pregnant amp Lactating Women. The project will work to strengthen and sustain the existing health system and provide support for vulnerable communities through strengthening the capacity of the Woreda Health System to screen cases by providing technical support during regular screenings and support the woredas in conducting exhaustive mass screening. In addition to this it plans to support Woreda health Office to strengthen/establish referral linkage. Furthermore, In collaboration with UN agencies, This project aims to provide technical support for SAM and MAM treatment and strengthen TSFP, TFP and SC supply chain in target woredas. Promotion of Care Practices and IYCF among children and their care-givers and psychosocial support for IDPs, returnees and host communities. Mental Health and Care Practices (MHCP) support will be provided to the most vulnerable households through targeted psychosocial support services such as Mother-to-Mother Support Groups.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fayyaa Integrated Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fayyaa Integrated Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mikiyas Girma Demelash</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program manager of emergency and relief</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>mikiyasd@fayyaa.org</telephone>
   <email>MD</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FIDO nutrition focal person</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior project officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>MD</telephone>
   <email>Mekuanent Belayneh Misikir</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rev.Dr. Anbessu Tolla Feyissa</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chief Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>atolla@fayyaa.org</telephone>
   <email>Phd</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benishangul Gumz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.50292407 35.44030741</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-17">240000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-21302">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-17">240000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fayyaa Integrated Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
