<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-21/DDA-3379/SA2/A/INGO/21209</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening responses to the emerging needs in conflict and drought affected communities of Liban and Goro Dola districts of Guji zone in Oromia region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Zonal DRM Taskforce (Multi-Agencies) has conducted need assessment in 8 districts of the zone (RNA report attached) in October 2021. The report revealed that the onset of the Hagaya/Gana rainfall was below not normal, unevenly distributed, erratic with about one month of dry spell and ceased before a month in all 9 visited pastoral and Agro-pastoral Waredas of the Zone. Together with the effect of the conflict that affected  of lives and livelihoods of the community (with 600,048,000 Birr loss of assets), there was about 79.1% production losses in the zone while the losses is account 76.2% and 95% for Liban and Goro Dola districts respectively. The Rain fall performance was not sufficient for all Agricultural activities-crop cultivation and livestock production, availability of water and availability of pasture. Security problem significantly hampered agricultural production and put majority of communities in most part of the zone food insecure. Due to current drought, there is serious shortage of pasture, food and water for both human and livestock. Security problem restricted movement for search of pasture and , negatively affected livestock performances and increased livestock morbidity and mortality. In line with this, the recent zonal assessment indicated that in nine assessed districts, where there are about 2,094,130 livestock population, 16,360 livestock are reportedly died while 46,444 livestock are failed and uplifted regularly and 11,305 HHs (30%F) are affected. Similarly, out of the total population of livestock found in Liban (143,336) and Gorodola (317,111), 4965, 4865 are reportedly died and 13,810 and 19,794 uplifted, this in turn affected 2,672 and 3,242 HHs respectively. Overall, are 11,305 (30%F). Even if there is no report of unusual livestock disease outbreak, such diseases as LSD, Bovine Pasterurolisis, Black-lag, Newcastle, Ovine Pasterurolisis, CBPP, CCPP, Anthrax and Rabies are the major identified livestock diseases in assessed districts while FMD is started as endemic and expanding into and across the districts. 

The resent assessment conducted by zonal DRM taskforce indicated there is about 63% of production losses mainly due to drought and conflict. The significant yield failure in targeted districts has been linked to poor and erratic rain patterns during previous seasons as well as insecurity problem (due to armed forces and conflict between communities in the zone and communities of neighboring region resulted in a displacement of a total of 220,584 population). This in turn  and has negatively impacted the food security of the target population, increasing malnutrition among children under five and pregnant and lactating women. A rise in the prices of staple foods, deterioration of livestock body condition, a decline in livestock prices as well as unusual migration by the population between districts have left the population in a difficult situation. Zonal assessment indicated that school-aged children and adolescents are unable to access quality education opportunities as a result of closure of 21 and 23 schools in Liban and Goro Dola districts, which also affected 4516 (1691F) and 4270 (2055F) students respectively. Market condition for livestock is very poor due to low demand associated with emaciated body condition of livestock.  As a result, livestock price is highly decreasing while the supply is increasing due to existing negative coping mechanisms exercised by households to compliment food consumption through grain. This means, the market condition is not favorable (bad ToT) for the pastoralist as the crop price is hiked. TSFP that was supplied by NGOs such as Mercy Corps is terminated in targeted districts due to security problem. Vulnerable households have employed negative coping strategies that include distressed asset sales, consumption of immature seeds, indebtedness, tree sales, labor migration, withdrawal of children from school and increased firewood and charcoal sale.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mothers and Children Multisectoral Development Organization (MCMDO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hiwotie Simachew</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Country Director &#x2013; Humanitarian</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>Tel: +251-115571916 &#x2013; Extension 623 | Mobile: +251 911 591825</telephone>
   <email>hiwotie.simachew@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.50805539 38.76512402</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-14">400000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-21209">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-14">400000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
