<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-21/DDA-3379/SA2/NFI/ES/INGO/21110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESNFI/Cash for Rent Response in Oromia (East Wellega, Guji and East Bale)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since 2018 there have been increasing clashes between unidentified armed groups (UAGs) and Government forces, along with different intercommunal conflicts and natural disasters. These shocks continue to cause major displacements in the Oromia region.  According to DTM Ethiopia DTT- 99 there has also been a significant increase in conflict and drought displacement in Guji zones. There has also been new conflict displacement in East Hararge, East Wellega, West Wellega, Horo Gudru Wellega, Kelem Wellega, West Shewa, and North Shewa zones. As a result, the number of Internally Displaced Persons (IDPs) in the Oromia region has reached 506,133. CRS conducted a multi-sectoral needs desk review. The assessment highlighted that many IDPs do not have access to shelter and are forced to sleep in overcrowded spaces including emergency shelters or communal sites. These IDPs share household items and sleep communally increasing the risk of COVID-19 transmission and protection issues. The situation of the IDPs in East Wellega is complex, some of these IDPs live with the host communities while others have settled in the rural areas living in substandard living conditions. IDPs are living dispersed throughout the host community in rental houses, and it has been difficult for the IDPs to afford the expensive cost of rental houses due to limited incomes from displacement.

Sasiga Woreda in East Wellega Zone and Goro Dola Woreda in Guji Zone are identified as priority woredas for IDP responses by the cluster. In the two woredas, there are a total of 278,682 IDPs: 134,338 in East Wellega and 144,344 IDPs in Guji.  The national Shelter and NFI cluster recommended providing six-month rental support for IDPs living in the host communities and Non-Food Items (NFI) V1 for IDPs. Accordingly, CRS with its partner Ethiopian Catholic Church Social and Development Commission Office of Nekemete (ECC-SDCON), also known as NCS and Ethiopian Catholic Church Social and Development Commission Office of Hawassa (HCS) will target a total of 2,780 HHs in East Wellega and Guji zones with the following interventions:
	In Sasiga woreda in East Wellega Zone 1,950HHs will be targeted for NFI V1 kits, 1850HH will receive the standard NFI V1 kit (15% directed to host community) and CRS will plan to distribute 100 NFI V1-Disable kits to eligible HHs. The average cost of each NFI V1 kit is 102 USD and the NFI V1-Disable kit is budgeted at 130 USD, excluding overheads.
	Of the 1,950HHs targeted in Sasiga, 580 HHs will also be targeted for cash for rent.  The cash will be provided for six months with an average cost of cash for rent is 25 USD per month per HH, total $150 per HH. The cash will be provided to targeted households in 2 rounds (distribute 3 months of house rental in one round).
	In Goro Dola woreda, Guji zone, 830 HHs targeted for ESNFI V2, 790HH will receive the standard ESNFI V2 kits (15% directed to host community) and 40 ESNFI V2-Disable kits will be  distributed to eligible HHs. The average cost of each ESNFI V2 kit is 140 USD and the ESNFI V2-Disable kit is budgeted at 182 USD, excluding overheads.

Before conducting cash for rent and NFI distributions, CRS will conduct a rental market assessment in the woreda to confirm the appropriate transfer value. This assessment will involve consultation with affected communities.  

CRS and partners will provide sensitization to the targeted HHs and the community including families who are renting out their houses. The orientation for the targeted HH will focus on the best use of the NFI and cash for a rental. An orientation on the CRS Code of Conduct will be provided to families who are renting a house.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ECC SADCOA&#x2013;Ethiopian Catholic Church-Social And Development Commission Nekemte (NCS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ECC SDCOBR&#x2013;Ethiopian Catholic Church-Social And Development Commission of Bale Robe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Catholic Church - Social amp; Development Commission of Hawassa(ECC-SDCOHA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-07" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-06" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fasil Tefera</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251-973-344-120</telephone>
   <email>fasil.tefera@crs.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Getahun Shimelis</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0000</telephone>
   <email>getahun.shimelis@crs.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Suganya Kimbrough</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251-960-36-8171</telephone>
   <email>suganya.kimbrough@crs.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.50805539 38.76512402</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-07"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-06"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-23">963287.94</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-21110">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-23">963287.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305492377">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-30">451991.65</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
