<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-21/DDA-3379/SA1/WASH-P-N-E/INGO/18521</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisectoral lifesaving emergency response on Education, WASH, Nutrition and Protection to IDPs and drought affected host communities in Filtu woredas, Somali regional state.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This integrated emergency response project will be implemented by NCA in consortium with OWDA in Filtu woreda of Somali region. The project will have a period of 7 months amp would address critical needs of vulnerable community mainly IDPs amp drought affected host communities residing in the proposed woreda. The project will address a total of 31,200 IDPs amp 20,816 HC on 4 sectors: Education, WASH, Protection and Nutrition.  Total planned budget for this project is 500,000 $. Out of which 60% is planned for WASH, 17% for protection, 16% for education amp 7% for Nutrition. Major activities of the project include school feeding to 400 children, provide scholastic supplies, Train schoolteachers amp administrators on socio-emotional learning, provide children with emergency school feeding support, Provide learning supplies amp furniture to O&apos; class students. Construction of 2 shallow wells amp 20 latrines, Provision of WASH NFIs, Sanitation amp hygiene promotion, Strengthen WASHCOs amp latrine cleaning committees, Provide support on COVID-19 prevention. Train on case management amp referral pathways Provide child protection services through case management, family tracing amp reunification, alternative care arrangement, individual PSS Strengthen Child Protection amp GBV Committees on child protection, cases identification amp referral through training amp capacity building support Train social workers amp project staffs on how to facilitate socio-emotional learning amp parental skills based on training packages contextualized for Ethiopia Deliver structured socio-emotional learning curriculums up on the Ethiopian contextualized package for children Provide structured parenting support amp parenting skills to parents, caregivers and foster parents Establish amp equip safe space for adolescent girls in the school compound through making the scholl latrine friendly to MHM Train on PFA to CP amp GBV committees, women groups amp youth networks, social workers, CP/GBV officers Train on mental health amp psychosocial support for health professionals, teachers, WoWCA amp woreda  staffs and social workers  organize mass awareness raising on their rights, child protection amp GBV risks and services including 16 days of activism Conduct community dialogue sessions on GBV, FGM, child marriage amp GBV referral pathways amp reporting mechanisms Provide Dignity Kits to  reproductive age women/girls and GBV survivors,  Safety audit at the beginning amp end of the project to identify potential protection risk for most vulnerable segment of the community, advocate on behalf of beneficiaries for the availability of services and assistance such as mobile protection and health team in hard to reach areas. Reinforce routine growth monitoring amp malnutrition screening at HP amp community level, Food support for care takers amp children admitted at SC, Train amp Strengthen on IYCF amp CMAM guideline, Print amp preposition OTP, SC amp MAM registration amp reporting tools, Conduct Quarterly Joint Supportive supervision, Transport nutrition supplies, provide training for HWs amp HEWs, provide job aides to support management of SAM amp MAM with medical complications in SC, OTP and TSFP.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organisation for Welfare and Development in Action (OWDA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zelalem Ayichew</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Program Head</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251911640752</telephone>
   <email>zelalem.ayichew@nca.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.92946999 43.32903576</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="16" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="7" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="17" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-30">363105.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-30">140942.33</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-18521">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-30">504048.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Church Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
