<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-21/DDA-3379/SA2/A/INGO/21139</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency  Livelihood Response to Strengthening agricultural capacity of internally displaced people and host community in Guto-Gida and Sasiga woredas of East Wollega Zone, Oromia Regional State, Ethiopia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">East Wellega zone of Oromia region has experienced massive displacement and worst food shortage during the year 2021 due to internal conflict. As per the recent DTM conducted from 6-12 November 2021, a total of 15,496 HHs (80,832) individuals) are displaced in the Sibu Sire and Guto Gida woredas of East Wellega zone. According to the, inter agency rapid response need assessment report of 21 July 2021 the IDPs and hots communities are in need of urgent humanitarian assistance. The number of IDPs are increasing day to day.
According to the data obtained from the Zone Agricultural Department prevalence of livestock diseases remains a major challenge that has been affecting production and productivity of livestock in the targeted woredas. Many of livestock diseases can easily be prevented through treatment campaigns the livestock departments are expected to conduct regularly. However, the office does not have adequate resource to conduct the annualized vaccination and treatment campaigns. 

The Assessment conducted by multiagency team suggests that emergency is on the rise and its impact is being reflected on the conditions of loss of livelihoods of the pastoral and agro-pastoral communities across all woredas of East Wellega Zone. Since 2018, the woreda has been hosting IDPs from Kamashi. Recently, a renewed conflict started in May 2021 have increased IDP caseload in the woreda. So far, a total 1,350HHs or a total of 7,316 individuals (3,582 female) were displaced from Mizyiga Woreda -Soge and Didesa/Haro Kebele to Sasiga woreda, Balo town. Unconfirmed number of IDPs are currently located in other kebeles namely: Anger, Kersa Mojo, Baredu Balo, and Hora Wata. Discussions with IDPs indicated that they have not received any humanitarian assistance since they arrived at their current location but are supported by the host community. They are currently residing with their relatives, in the street, verandas, yet there is no collective site that should be established otherwise. 
The main cause of the displacement was ongoing &#x2018;group conflict&#x2019; between UAG and government forces. The assessment findings indicate that the safety and security of these people of concern were at risk and had to flee from their habitual residence. Government offices and commercials centers including small markets in Soge town have been closed since 16 July 2021. 
This project is aimed to undertake livestock emergency and agricultural inputs intervention in two woredas of East Wellega zone, specifically in Sasiga woreda and Guto &#x2013;Gilda where the situation has reached emergency stage already. Given limited resource capacity the project now will focus on four Kebeles (Sasiga and one in Guto &#x2013;Gilda). totally in four kebeles. Key components of the project are 293 quintals of seed distribution, 116,900 kg of NSPB, 175,000 kg of Urea, Veterinary drugs, Vaccine and equipment The project targets 1701 households (9357 individuals) and 3800 livestock.
Proper identification will be made using the criteria to be set for the project implementation. The Woreda and Zone agricultural offices and the DRM staff at the two levels will actively participate in the operation. The internally displaced people representatives will also participate in the project implementation. The required materials for the operation will be procured and distributed in close collaboration with the agricultural offices. The modality of distribution will also be decided in collaboration with the concerned offices, IDPs representatives and leaders of religious organizations. The focal person of the implementing organization will actively discharge its duties and responsibilities concerning the operation</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Christian Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Christian Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopian Evangelical Church Mekane Yesus Development and Social Services Commission(EECMY-DASSC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abay Gena</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Humanitarian Programme Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251913795530</telephone>
   <email>AGena@christian-aid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.50805539 38.76512402</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-14">349999.85</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-21139">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-14">349999.85</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Christian Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
