<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-21/DDA-3379/SA1/NFI/ES/NGO/18614</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency NFI kits assistance  to Conflict and Flood Affected IDPs and Host communities in East imi, Shebele Zone of Somali Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia has not yet fully recovered from the consecutive drought that resulted in massive livestock loss in pastoral regions and crop failure in the ago-pastoral areas. The past three years have seen major changes in Ethiopia&#x2019;s governance landscape. Internally displaced persons (IDPs), particularly those living in collective sites, experienced deplorable conditions and limited access to basic services, lack of opportunities to rebuild their livelihoods, protection risks, and wider security concerns. These have an additional burden on families whose coping capacities were already stretched. According to HNO 2021, 23.8 million people nationwide are projected to have humanitarian needs in April to June 2021, of whom in Somali region 3.8 million people in needs. 4.5 million people are in needs of support of ESNFI in Ethiopia. Of the 4.5 million IDPs in need, 2.8 million have various critical ES/NFI needs. In East Imi of Somali region 111,298 people needs support. 
The Gu rain in 2021 started in end of April 2021 which causes flash floods in East Imi, Abaqorow, and Bercano. Multi-agency assessment team was deployed to the affected areas on May 5, 2021 and completed the assessment on May 5, 2021. According to the rapid assessment report, the current flood from Shebele river affected 85,100 households, displaced 24,008 households and dead seven people in Shebele zone. The flood affected eleven kebeles found in East Imi and 2427 households affected, 4362 households displaced, 4362 houses affected, 450 houses damaged, death of 328 cattles, 170 SHOATs, 56 donkeys recorded and 1200 hectare of standing crop damaged. The crisis has placed a significant strain on existing Shelter infrastructure and practices, particularly in remote areas where returned IDPs have integrated into communities with already limited access to basic services. The safety and well-being of returned IDPs depend on effective and timely humanitarian intervention while meeting urgent needs. OWDA (Organization for Welfare and Development in Action) designed this project in response to the tremendous Non-food Item (NFI) response needs of IDPs communities of East Imi district of Shebele zone. The proposed areas are the most affected areas with the limited services available for IDPs communities. Hence, the proposed intervention will support 1,441HHs (9,364 people) flood, drought and conflict induced IDPs households with life-saving humanitarian assistance through the provision of cluster approved in-kind NFI kits and cash based assistance for NFI materials will be procured and transported by OWDA that will be directly distributed during implementation. Cash for NFI Kits will be provided for 370 IDP households using the convinent modalities in the East imi woreda. A total of 1071 IDP households will be provided NFI kits including bedding sets (2 pieces of mosquito net, 2 pieces of blanket and 2 pieces of bed mat for each households), Kitchen sets (1 pieces of cooking pot, 1 piece of cooking ladle, 1 piece of kettle, 2 pieces of plate and 4 pieces of cups per households) and hygiene sets (1 pieces of jerry can, 1 pieces of hand washing jug and basin set, 1 liter of multipurpose liquid soap and 2.5 pieces of multipurpose soaps per households). Cash-based assistance will be considered in areas where a market is functional and offers items needed by IDPs and where IDPs have a preference for cash-based assistance. Protection mainstreaming and COVID-19 preventive measure training will be provided for 20 IDP households, local government authorities, local community members in order to ensure CP and GBV and to raise awareness and take appropriate measures to COVID-19 pandemic. Market assessment and post-distribution monitoring of NFIs will be conducted. Therefore, the project will be implemented through a coordinated response of OWDA considering geographic coverage, cost-effectiveness and past partnership history with SampNFI Cluster members.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Welfare and Development in Action</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Welfare and Development in Action</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-21" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-21" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-20" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-20" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammed Abdikadir</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 915 320833</telephone>
   <email>mohamedak@owdaeth.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.92946999 43.32903576</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-21"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-20"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-23">199999.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-18614">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-23">199999.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Welfare and Development in Action</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305087756">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-01">119999.64</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Welfare and Development in Action</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
