<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-21/DDA-3379/SA1/A/INGO/18567</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture support and cash labeled for agricultural inputs support to conflict-affected communities in Tigray Region, Ethiopia.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall, food insecurity situation has been deteriorating across the Tigray region, especially since the conflict erupted during the harvest season. The interim Regional Administration has estimated that 4.5 million people are now in need of food assistance. Further deterioration is expected as the conflict continues and disrupts the next planting season. Nutrition partners have expressed grave concern that the significant number of moderately malnourished cases identified so far will become severely malnourished unless the food and nutrition responses are urgently scaled up. 

This project will address the immediate and lifesaving needs of the conflict-affected communities through the promotion of nutrition-sensitive agriculture where targeted households receive crop seeds including vegetables, pulses, cereals, provision of cash labeled for agricultural inputs, and livestock services to ensure adequate animal fodder and veterinary services are available. Cash will be used as the preferred modality to provide this agricultural support to help farmers to purchase agricultural inputs like fertilizers, chemicals, and tools given the functionality of local markets. The cash response aims to boost the devastated local market affected by the conflict. All these proposed interventions will enhance household food security in Kilte Awlalo, Saesi Tsaedaemba, and Gata Afeshum woredas of Tigray Region. GOAL has operational presence in these woredas since the onset of the conflict in the region and has been a key factor in providing nutrition, health, WASH, ESNFI, and protection where cash has been the key modality of assistance.

Cash distributions are proposed to address the lack of basic agricultural inputs including fertilizer, chemicals, and farm tools for a total of 1,500 households impacted by the conflict. In addition, the project will address a total of 10,000 households through the provision of animal veterinary drugs and vaccines. The proposed activities will be implemented in three woredas where the need is high. Each household will receive 1,500 ETB in total. This will be provided as an unconditional cash transfer through the Bank transfer modality as a once-off payment. As a part of improving food security and livelihood recovery, GOAL will distribute short-maturing and drought-tolerant crops (cereal, and vegetables) to 1500 households across the three targeted Woredas. The modality for the distribution of crop seeds will be in-kind as GOAL believes that the seed market has not yet recovered from the conflict yet. As a sensitive planting material, GOAL will ensure the procurement of quality seeds with desirable germination, purity, and viability rates be procured from certified seed enterprises or traders at the Addis Ababa level and assistance will be provided on in-kind modality. However, cash will be the preferred modality for veterinary drugs, animal fodder seeds, purchase of small farm tools, and fertility enhancement materials. The seeds intervention is proposed to deliver in time for the Meher planting window, however, this is highly dependent on a timely proposal review process, availability of seeds supplies in Ethiopia Seed Enterprise or the neighboring region of Amhara to ensure timely procurement, as well as collaboration with local stakeholders in facilitating agreements rapidly and supporting beneficiary targeting and verification. GOAL will maintain regular communication with the DRM-ATF on the progress and coordinate closely with local-level stakeholders to ensure that this project will have maximum impact and effectiveness. GOAL&#x2019;s existing presence will be a value-added to hasten the project implementation as the project will contribute to the realization of the 90-days plan.

This project aims to address the immediate food security needs of 10,000 households adversely affected by conflict-induced displacement residing in three woredas in Eastern Tigray.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dinkneh Asfaw</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251911214432</telephone>
   <email>dinkneha@et.goal.ie</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jemal Hassen</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assistant Country Director &#x2013; Programmes (ACDP)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251912689400</telephone>
   <email>jemalh@et.goal.ie</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yared Ayele</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Livelihood and Economic Opportunity Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251913072842</telephone>
   <email>yareda@et.goal.ie</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET01">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tigray</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.77711683 38.43867474</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-13">349640.98</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-18567">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-13">349640.98</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305108782">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-23">349640.98</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
