<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41160054-200296</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DRC - R&#xE9;duction de la vuln&#xE9;rabilit&#xE9; des adolescentes et des jeunes femmes</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3 main objectives of the project are: 
(i) to increase the proportion of adolescents and young women with adequate knowledge of SRH, HIV,
human rights and GBV; 
(ii) to reduce the proportion of adolescents and young women who have been the victim of GBV in the school environment, and 
(iii) to improve access to and the delivery of adolescent-responsive health services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The link between gender-based violence (GBV) and increased risk for HIV is well-established. GBV
prevention and response are critical to effectively treating and reducing the spread of HIV,
particularly in the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC).
The HIV epidemic in DRC is generalized with a prevalence of 1.2% in the general population (15 to
49 years) and notably higher among women (1.6%) than men (0.6%). According to data from the
DHS 2012-2013, the prevalence of HIV doubles among women 25 to 30 years of age. Incidence
data from 2013 also indicates that 0-24 year olds represented 72% of all new infections.
Overall, DRC ranks 153 out of 159 countries in the 2015 Gender Inequality Index, and national data
on gender-based and intimate partner violence suggests that approximately 43% of women in DRC
have experienced domestic violence, with a sharp increase in risk after 20 years of age.
Given the limited treatment-seeking behavior and general poor access to integrated HIV-sexual
and reproductive health (SRH) services, particularly among adolescents, there is a need for
increased attention and efforts in DRC. Adolescence, particularly from 15 to 24 years, is a crucial
moment for preventing HIV by not only increasing information and awareness, but also by
generating a change of social norms and gender inequalities. Through its investments in HIV
programming, the Global Fund is currently targeting women and adolescents to fight gender
inequalities and GBV, reduce HIV prevalence and build resilient and sustainable systems for health
that are able to better respond to adolescents&#x2019; needs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Young women and adolescent girls in 3 health zones in Kinshasa (Kalamu 1, Makala and Kintambu) and 3 in Kasai Oriental, Mbuji Maji (Diulu, Kansele, Nzaba).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid RDC (R&#xE9;publique D&#xE9;mocratique du Congo)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-29" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0) 70 &#x2013; 31 36 300</telephone>
   <email>info@cordaid.org</email>
   <website>https://www.cordaid.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grote Marktstraat 45, Den Haag, Zuid Holland, 2511 BH</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-09-29"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-29">515240.92</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
