<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41160054-200925</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response Mechanism (ERM) in Uruzgan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid assessments confirmed the in the HIP and DG ECHO&#x2019;s Integrated Analysis Framework (2020) mentioned extreme needs and high vulnerabilities in Urozgan and Kunduz, where people continue to be exposed to multiple shocks (ongoing conflict and floods/ droughts), resulting in new/prolonged displacement, jeopardizing people&#x2019;s lives and livelihoods increasing humanitarian needs. People are acute food insecure and increasingly use negative coping strategies.

In 2020, 8,775 people were displaced in Urozgan (DoRR) because of conflict. 65% did not receive any assistance. Annually, some 20% of the population (KII) is affected by natural disasters. Because of ANDMA&#x2019;s limited capacity, timely response to disasters remain a challenge. Urozgan is also a conservative, male dominated province (40% of the women have a Tazkeera, lack access to education and health services). It is a hard to reach (HTR) province because of insecurity and limited (logistic) infrastructure. 50% of the population is in IPC3+ (2020 SFSA) and 57% is in LCS extreme. Assessments showed that 49% of the assessed people is female, 51% is male, 49% is female and 64% is under 18 years. HH have multiple vulnerabilities; the majority are headed by an elderly or chronically ill person, 20% by a female and 8% by a child, making them less likely to access assistance or basic services. On average a HH exist of 10 people and the majority of the responding HH were displaced because of conflict and unlikely to return to their place of origin. With 45% depending on agriculture and livestock as their main source of income, they are more affected by displacement and natural disaster. 14% rely on daily skilled and unskilled labor which is unreliable, making them livelihood insecure and 23% is jobless. With 64% 18 years or younger, unemployment among young people is high. The bad livelihood situation is reflected in people&#x2019;s use of negative coping mechanisms. Only 3.5% has no debts and nearly 75% has a debt of more than 8,000 AFN. People apply high coping strategies such as reduction in frequency of meals and rationing food, signifying high food insecurity. 44% has food stocks for less than 1 week or no food stocks at all. None of the respondents has adequate access to sufficient water to meet the minimum sphere standards for water use, drinking, cooking and maintaining personal hygiene. People are prioritising water for drinking and cooking which implies low hygiene and sanitation practices, increasing the risks on waterborne diseases and public health risks, especially given the current pandemic (COVID-19). Although 86% of the people have access to a HH latrine, more than half of the people (60%) practice ODF. ODF is a public health risk, contaminating surface and underground water. It is also a protection risk for women and girls, who have no safe/ protected place to defecate. 50% is living in owned houses but 25% is renting which is an additional financial burden (on average 2,000 AFN per month), especially with half the people unemployed or dependent on daily labour. Nearly two-third of the respondents are living in partially or completely destroyed houses representing a health risk for children, elderly and chronically ill, especially during hot summers and harsh winters.

On the 13th of May, fighting between State and Non-state Actors erupted in Kunduz, resulting in the Taliban capturing several districts, and displacing some 10,000 families (DoRR) from Imam Sahib, Aliabad and Khanabad to Kunduz City. Furthermore another 150 families from Takhar have been displaced to Kunduz City as well (UNOCHA). Assessments show that needs are high and multi-sectoral. As people left instantly, they left their belongings behind and in need of household NFIs. People were also found to be highly food insecure and in need of food. Because of the new wave of COVID-19 in the country, and people living in overcrowded places, health needs are high as well and so are WASH needs. Most people are living with relatives or in rented accommodation. With few livelihood opportunities and many needs to be met, in addition to insecure tenancy agreements, people are at risk of eviction. According to WoAA 2020, high vulnerabilities were reported with 36% of the HH having at least 1 member with a vulnerability. People are newly displaced and have not received any assistance. People have have incurred debts and are resorting to the use of negative coping mechanisms. WFP and UNHCR have provided food in kind but this is not sufficient.

The conflict has also resulted in the deterioration of family and societal relationships and caused mental illnesses among civilians. Girls lack education and early/ forced marriages are a common coping strategy according to FGDs and KIIs. Key challenges faced by women in the community include &#x201C; the conservative environment, lack of access to basic needs and no income.&#x201D; In both provinces Child labour is often used to ensure income for HH because of the rising levels of poverty and the worsening economic conditions, exacerbated by displacement and COVID-19. Most at risk of violence are poor people who face warlords taking their land by force, violence about water and land, and people with chronic illness, people with disability, and families whose members are working in ANA or in police. Trauma and post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) is common. Children, women, the elderly, persons with disabilities, and the chronically ill are most vulnerable to conflict and insecurity and are disproportionately affected. This is confirmed by the assessments. Children, girls and those under the age of 5 in particular, are impacted by the shocks and are often unable to go to school because of high costs and lack of (female) teachers. Or they need to work to contribute to the HH. Poor shelter is affecting peoples dignity and health, exposing elderly/ ill to health risks and women, girls to protection threats as they lack privacy. ODF and waterborne diseases are common, increasing health and protection risks respectively for elderly, women and children. Early and forced labour is a common coping strategy as well. Women live in isolation, often without a registration Tazkeera unable to access basic services. They are denied education and are unable to work, and with limited access to health services, unable to seek health care or health care is too costly and not a priority. With so many HH food and livelihood insecure, (S)GBV will be common as well. Elderly, ill people and PWD as well are faced with limited health services and difficulties accessing assistance or other services.

People have limited access to health services, sufficient water, hygiene practices are low and live in inadequate shelter. There are increasing protection concerns especially among women, children, PWD and the elderly/ chronically ill with the majority of the respondents being displaced. KIs and FGDs mentioned that people&#x2019;s coping mechanisms are exhausted and that they will not be able to withstand another shock and malnutrition was observed among small children. The assessed people prioritized their needs as follows: In Urozgan 1) food and 2) cash followed by 3) shelter. In Kunduz people had left at once, leaving most essentials behind. They mentioned food, household NFIs and Health</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newly displaced (less than 3 months) because of conflict 80% and affected due to sudden onset natural disaster</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To contribute to lower the adoption of livelihood strategies overall and prevent the adoption of crisis and emergency strategies of the most vulnerable, shock affected and newly displaced people in Afghanistan through timely, needs based and inclusive cash assistance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-EC_ECHO" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ECHO - European Civil Protection and Humanitarian Aid Operations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Rehabilitation Association for Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0) 70 &#x2013; 31 36 300</telephone>
   <email>info@cordaid.org</email>
   <website>https://www.cordaid.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grote Marktstraat 45, Den Haag, Zuid Holland, 2511 BH</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="679" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="16050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-04-01">600000</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
