<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41160054-200381</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH Emergency Support in Paoua</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the start of this phase, the population was estimated to be 81,763 but now (in March 2019) the total target group is estimated to be 84,705. (Health project)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The humanitarian and security situation in the sub-prefectures of Paoua in the prefecture of Ouham Pend&#xE9; and Markounda in the prefecture of Ouham remained throughout the period of implementation of this project dominated by the persistence of violence causing displacement forced of the population. Incidents against civilians and inter-community tensions persisted. Areas such as Bedjangala and Begouladj&#xE9; in the northern sub-prefecture of Paoua, Kadjamakota and Dokabi in the northern sub-prefecture of Markounda have all remained inaccessible until recently (January 2019). The activities planned to start since July 2018 have only been started in January 2019 in these areas. This shifting context had a negative impact on the project&apos;s implementation schedule. Thus, the construction / rehabilitation activities of the water works were only carried out during the last quarter of the project (between January and March 2019). The project monitoring staff did not have enough time to evaluate the effects of the activities on the lives of populations and communities. 
The relative lull seen in the areas listed below coupled with efforts at pacification, peace and the restoration of state authority, has encouraged whole families, formerly IDPs or refugees in neighbouring countries (Chad &amp; Cameroon) to return to these areas. Thus, although some WASH responses are being implemented by the various actors (DRC, Oxfam, Solidarit&#xE9;, CICR), the needs in this sector remain enormous and not covered.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aimed at improving the hygiene and sanitation conditions of the most vulnerable people and communities through a process of access to water infrastructure in eight (8) health areas of the sub-prefectures of Paoua in the prefecture of Ouham Pend&#xE9; and Markounda in the prefecture of Ouham.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Central African Republic</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government of the United Kingdom - Department For International Development DFID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0) 70 &#x2013; 31 36 300</telephone>
   <email>info@cordaid.org</email>
   <website>https://www.cordaid.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grote Marktstraat 45, Den Haag, Zuid Holland, 2511 BH</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14031" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-08-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-15">145320</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
