<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41160054-200822</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Women Empowerment</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key target groups:

Geographic focus: The action will be implemented in following Bor (Jonglei State), and Malakal (Upper Nile State). The target beneficiaries of this Action are women and girls, particularly in rural communities of Bor and Malakal, with a focus on the most vulnerable (women head of household, women and girls with disabilities, displaced, survivor of sexual violence in conflict, etc).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One of the consequences of the prolonged civil wars in South Sudan is increased gender inequality and increasing cases of sexual and gender-based violence. &#x2013; Women and girls and boys are also extra vulnerable to forced labour and sexual exploitation, inter-ethnic abductions and abductions by criminal groups. The abductees are subsequently forced into domestic servitude, herding or sex trafficking. Women contribute 80% of the agriculture labour, but still have limited access to productive assets like land title, finance, control over produce sold, and are usually excluded from various decision-making processes. Cordaid Studies conducted in Bor, Yambio, Torit between 2018- and 2019 found that average annual income for female-headed households (SSP 7,959 ($34.60)) is significantly lower than that of male-headed households (SSP 22,078 ($95.99)). Education rates for adult men are 40%, compared to 16% of women. Domestic violence is common: 82% of women and 81% of men agreed that &#x201C;women should tolerate violence to keep her family together&#x201D;. 45% of girls are married before 18.
Cordaid launched the Women Peace and Security (WPS) Barometer Report (link to report) on women&#x2019;s perspectives on security in South Sudan in 2019, confirming a lack of awareness on women rights, leading to acceptance of domestic and gender-based violence. There is a strong linkage between traditions (stigma and gender norms), lack of economic opportunities and different forms of (S)GBV. It was also reported that civic space is under increasing pressure as democratic rights and freedom of speech are often curtailed constraining lobby and advocacy efforts on women&apos;s rights.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall objective: 
Narrowing the &quot;gender gap&quot; through the synergy of economic, political and social empowerment of women in Malakal and Bor counties of South Sudan.
Specific objective(s):
1. Promote women&#x2019;s economic empowerment at the local level, with specific attention to those in the most vulnerable situations through promoting Climate Resilient Livelihoods, Market System Development and Business Development Services
2. Promote a culture of respect for women&#x2019;s social, economic, and political rights at the local level in identified states/counties through strengthening and reinforcing capacities of key actors</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid South Sudan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-EC_DEVCO" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Commission - EuropeAid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hope Restoration South Sudan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0) 70 &#x2013; 31 36 300</telephone>
   <email>info@cordaid.org</email>
   <website>https://www.cordaid.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grote Marktstraat 45, Den Haag, Zuid Holland, 2511 BH</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15164" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-01-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-01">1000000</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
