<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41160054-201083</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving the lives of vulnerable Yemenis</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General context Yemen:&#x202F; 

When Houthi supporters&#x202F;took control of Sana&#x2019;a&#x202F;in 2014,&#x202F;and negotiations between the warring government and Houthis failed,&#x202F;the Houthis seized the presidential palace in January 2015, leading President Abd&#x202F;Rabbu&#x202F;Mansour Hadi and his government to resign. In March 2015, a Saudi-led coalition of Gulf states launched a military campaign of aerial bombardments, and the blockade of international airports and&#x202F;Al&#x202F;Hudaydah&#x202F;seaport against Houthi government and territories, herewith igniting the conflict&#x202F;resulting in the world&apos;s worst humanitarian crisis. The country is currently divided between de facto (Houthi) government in the North East and North West, including Sana&#x2019;a, and the Saudi-supported government of Hadi in the Southern areas.&#x202F;&#x202F; 

&#x202F;Years of conflict&#x202F;has caused&#x202F;economic decline and institutional collapse, with an estimated&#x202F;20.7&#x202F;million&#x202F;(66% of the population)&#x202F;Yemenis&#x202F;of whom 22% are women, 54% are children and 15% are people with disabilities,&#x202F;need&#x202F;humanitarian assistance (HNO 2021).&#x202F;According to the HRP 2021,&#x202F;16.2&#x202F;million people are&#x202F;in IPC3 or worse, and&#x202F;5.1&#x202F;million of them are in acute need of food assistance&#x202F;(IPC 4 and 5).&#x202F;IDPs are among the most food insecure&#x202F;people&#x202F;with 43% of the displaced households unable to meet their minimum food needs.&#x202F;Large parts of the country are in IPC3 or worse with famine looming.&#x202F;WASH services are limited:&#x202F;15.4&#x202F;million Yemenis&#x202F;lack&#x202F;safe drinking water, adequate sanitation facilities and hygiene items. More than half of these (8.6&#x202F;million) are in acute need. The lack of adequate WASH represents a major public health risk, worsened by&#x202F;new waves of&#x202F;COVID-19. It is also a major protection risk for women and girls, lacking dignity and hygiene items for their specific needs.&#x202F;20.1&#x202F;million people&#x202F;are&#x202F;lacking&#x202F;access to basic healthcare&#x202F;affecting women and children disproportionately as they make up 75% of the affected population.&#x202F;In Yemen, where the average 25-year-old has already lived through 14 armed conflicts, an&#x202F;estimated 19.5% of the population&#x202F;suffers from mental disorders, most prevalently anxiety, depression, trauma, and schizophrenia.&#x202F;Yemenis are increasingly forced to resort to negative coping mechanisms in relation to WASH access and behaviours, significantly heightening the risk of malnutrition and increasing WASH-related disease and outbreaks including, cholera and dengue. Protection of civilians remains a priority in Yemen. Some of the highest levels of vulnerability are concentrated in IDP sites where very few services are available.&#x202F;While the impact of armed conflict is expected to severely affect civilians, women and girls are expected to continue to be disproportionately affected and remain at&#x202F;high risk&#x202F;of violations and abuse. Yemen is ranked the worst globally in terms of gender equality according to the INFORM Risk Index.&#x202F; 
Context Aden&#x202F;&amp; Lahj governorates&#x202F; 

Aden&#x202F;governorate has been a site of conflict&#x202F;and protests&#x202F;for many years resulting in high humanitarian needs.&#x202F;68% of the total&#x202F;population&#x202F;(estimated population of nearly1M,)&#x202F;are in severity phase&#x202F;&#x2018;severe&#x2019;&#x202F;(20%),&#x202F;&#x2018;extreme&#x2019;&#x202F;(36%) and&#x202F;&#x2018;catastrophic&#x2019;&#x202F;(12%).&#x202F;&#x202F;According to integrated food security phase&#x202F;classification&#x202F;(IPC Analysis June 2021),&#x202F;485,500&#x202F;persons&#x202F;need emergency aid.&#x202F;Crater&#x202F;is one of Aden districts that require emergency aid. Although the district is classified IPC3, (45% of its population is acutely food insecure and in IPC3+. Fifty-eight thousand five hundred (58500) people require food assistance. In addition, people lack increasing make use of irreversible coping mechanisms. 

In Lahj governorate (estimated population of 1M) there are 345,500people in need of which 33% is in acute need. People lack access to basic services such as healthcare, adequate water and sanitation and are severely and acute food insecure. People&#x2019;s food insecurity was already precarious but latest reports are showing that the situation continues to deteriorate. According to the HNO 2021, the first priority of IDPs, returnees and host community in Lahj is food. Al-Had&#x202F;is one of Lahj districts&#x202F;that&#x202F;require&#x202F;emergency aid since the district 35% of the total population (estimated population of nearly 78,000 people) in Al-Had district is classified in IPC3+ or worse. Also, Al-Had district received more than 700 families from Al-Bayda governorate during July 2021 due to the conflict. While more than 3 families lives in the same houses in most of the houses received IDPs in Al-Had district.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall Objective:  

To contribute to reduced suffering of conflict and COVID-19 affected families in Yemen.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total beneficiaries: 350 Families (2,450 people) 

Women &gt; 18yrs: 661 individuals) 

Children: 465 boys and 564 girls 

Men &gt; 18yrs: 539 individuals 

Elderly: 221 individuals 

Disabled: 88 individuals</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afaq Shababia Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0) 70 &#x2013; 31 36 300</telephone>
   <email>info@cordaid.org</email>
   <website>https://www.cordaid.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grote Marktstraat 45, Den Haag, Zuid Holland, 2511 BH</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-01">250880</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
