<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41160054-201078</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addressing urgent food needs in ISIS clear and formerly Taliban held areas in Nangarhar</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghani people (men, women, youth, elderly, PWD)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General description and link with proposal: In response to the urgent food needs, Cordaid together with
its local partner (RRAA) will deliver cash for food in Achin, Speen Ghar, Nazyan districts of Nangarhar. As
Cordaid is in process of securing additional funding for the urgent ES&amp;NFI needs ahead of the winter,
which will complement the proposed cash for food distribution.

Overall objective: To contribute to improved food security of conflict affected people in Afghanistan</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Late 2020, the Humanitarian situation in Afghanistan rapidly declined. High levels of violence and conflict, natural disasters, high rates of poverty, and the COVID-19 pandemic, contributed to a worsening humanitarian and grave protection crisis, causing significant displacement and high multi-sector humanitarian needs across the country. The armed conflict, ongoing for more than 40 years, was exhausting coping mechanisms of the population, making them extremely vulnerable. At the start of 2021, according to HRP Afghanistan 2021, 18.4 million people (nearly half the population) are in need of humanitarian assistance and 17.6 million Afghans are acute food insecure. 50% of the children under 5 years are acute malnourished (HRP). 

The already precarious humanitarian situation was aggravated by the US/NATO Troops withdrawal announced earlier in 2021, but confirmed by the Biden Administration in April 2021. The US/ NATO Troops withdrawal intensified the conflict between the Afghan government and Non-State Armed Groups (NSAG) with fighting and displacement affecting nearly all provinces by July, causing loss of lives, further destruction and displacement by a rapidly advancing Taliban. From April until August, more than 670,000 people were displaced due to heavy fighting in the North (Kunduz), East (Nangarhar, Laghman) and South (Helmand &amp; Kandahar) of the country. People were unable to tend to their fields and couldn&#x2019;t harvest their crops, increasing food insecurity levels. Much to everybody&#x2019;s surprise, the fighting came to an end on 15th August, when the former president of Afghanistan handed over Kabul peacefully to the Taliban to prevent further bloodshed. Recently the UN launched a new flash appeal, requesting an additional US$193M to cover the most urgent needs of 10 M Afghans until the end of the year, an increase of 2 M people. 

Additionally, in spring the previous government announced another drought , likely to last 2 years and affecting food insecurity and food prices further. With most of the Afghans relying on agriculture, this is affecting their crops but also their income and live-stock, compounding the acute food insecurity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD- Catholic Agency for Overseas Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Austria - &#xD6;sterreichische Caritaszentral</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Rehabilitation Association For Afghanistan (NPO/RRAA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trocaire</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0) 70 &#x2013; 31 36 300</telephone>
   <email>info@cordaid.org</email>
   <website>https://www.cordaid.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grote Marktstraat 45, Den Haag, Zuid Holland, 2511 BH</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="679" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="52010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-01">40000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-12-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-15">23600</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
