<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41160054-201045</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Health Global Access III</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Primary results (outcomes and outputs) of this project will achieve or significantly contribute to increased Dutch public and political support for Development Cooperation (0.7% GNI) and increased investment (0.1%) in global health for vulnerable populations in low and middle-income countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The GHGA III project aims to help all people lead healthy, productive lives and in particular vulnerable populations who have minimum access to quality health care in low and middle-income countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The impact of COVID-19  
The Dutch budget for development cooperation (ODA) was immediately at risk as it is linked to the GDP, which decreased due to the COVID-19 crisis and the immediate negative impact of lockdowns on the economy. The sudden attention to a public health emergency made politicians aware of the detrimental effects of chronically underfunded national health systems, fragmented prevention landscape and serious lack of domestic production of essential health products, thus being vulnerable to their scarcity in the global markets. Travel and lockdown restrictions for Dutch citizens are further contributing to public awareness of the importance of a coordinated global response and the necessary role of the Netherlands.

COVID-19 is also having an enormous impact on gender and women&#x2019;s access to health care. Hard-fought gains for women&#x2019;s rights are under threat. And there is a noticeable increase in (S)GBV and maternal mortality. Responding to the pandemic is not just about rectifying long-standing inequalities, but also about building a resilient world in the interest of everyone, with women at the centre of the recovery . 

Political landscape 
Throughout 2020, most of the political attention was diverted to the COVID-19 situation within The Netherlands and its likely impacts on the economy. But it had its perks. Both global health security and health systems strengthening are high on the Dutch political agenda now. The traditional focus of the Dutch government on SRHR is slowly widening to strengthening health systems and multilateral mechanisms, such as the Global Fund, Gavi and the GFF, all of which also have expanded their scope in view of the drastic impact of the COVID-19 crisis on the realization of SDG 3, especially linked with SDG 5.  

The parliamentary elections of 17 March 2021 have resulted in a very scattered Dutch political landscape, and a difficult coalition agreement period is going on, which might run until autumn or even early winter 2021.

To safeguard the ODA budget, the Dutch government decided to add an amount from the general funds, and frontloaded part of the future ODA budget to compensate for the decreased ODA in 2020. In the Spring Bill 2021 it became clear that there will not be a budget cut for 2021 and coming years and the frontloading of money has been completely compensated for. This is obviously good news.

Public mindset 
Many in The Netherlands have gone through a rough time during the COVID-19 crisis, which could negatively influence the public support for development cooperation. However, our two recent polls indicate a rather positive public opinion towards global solidarity and global health. We expect this positive change will be sustained depending on how the number of COVID-19 infection and morbidity rates are developing in the Netherlands.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DAC-1601" role="1" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0) 70 &#x2013; 31 36 300</telephone>
   <email>info@cordaid.org</email>
   <website>https://www.cordaid.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grote Marktstraat 45, Den Haag, Zuid Holland, 2511 BH</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="12110" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15114" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15121" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-01">780188</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
