<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41160054-201071</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ES&amp;NFI assistance for conflict affected people</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of shelter repair/ upgrade through cash assistance to 950 HH (cat B 550 HH and cat C 400 HH) most vulnerable households whose shelters have either been severely or partially damaged.
Provision of cash for NFIs (in line with ES&amp;NFI cluster amount annex 13) to 1,100 most vulnerable conflict affected HH.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recent assessments (annex 8, 9a and 9b) in Kunduz and Nangarhar show high shelter and NFI needs in both provinces. Needs are a direct result of the intensifying conflict over the previous months, causing new displacement and destroying people&apos;s lives and livelihoods, (partially) damaging people&apos;s shelters. Many people had to flee at once and were unable to bring their personal belongings including basic HH items. Fighting between state and none-state actors in Imam Sahib district, Kunduz escalated in May. Since then clashes has also been reported from other districts (incl. Khan Abad, Ali Abad and Dash-e-Archi when fighting intensified, displacing at least 12,000 people in the province (DoRR). Assessments (Annex 8) show that people are acute food insecure, and need food, NFIs, shelter, health and hygiene items. There are severe protection concerns as there is a large percentage of People with Specific Needs (PSN) (19% of the families have PWD and nearly 40% of the HH are headed by a female). 77% of the assessed people have a poor food consumption score (FCS) and 23% has borderline FCS. All HH apply coping strategies with 66% are applying high (and irreversible) coping strategies. 95.5% of HH have a LCS &#x2018;emergency&#x2019;. Furthermore people lack NFIs as none of the HH reportedly had sufficient NFIs. Most of the interviewed people were living in make-shift shelters, increasing protection risks for women and girls in particular but also creating health risks for PLW, children elderly and ill people especially with winter arriving. With the situation in the country stabilizing, people are also returning to their place of origin and some of their shelters (partially or completely) destroyed. Although Cordaid addressed some of the needs through cash distribution (MEB) to newly displaced people via ECHO ERM in June, there are many unmet ES&amp;NFI needs such as shelter repair enabling people to return . Since June, new displacement has also taken place and most of the needs of these people go unaddressed. Heavy fighting in Nangarhar in May - June displaced an estimated 12,000 people. According to reports (Annex 9a), in Nangarhar province, most of the newly displaced people are coming from Achin, Pachieagam, Dehbala and Surkhrod districts and are now primarily staying in Jalalabad, Behsud, Mommand Dara, Khogyani and Surhrod. Needs remain multi-sector and high, despite the assistance provided so far. According to the July Eastern Region Monthly Snapshot (Annex 9b) there is a high need for shelter upgrades and NFIs as 93% and 76% of the people respectively still require shelter and NFI assistance. People lack jobs and there are limited livelihood opportunities and cannot afford to meet their daily basic needs. Previous assessments showed there were no HH NFIs. In both provinces people continue to be severely affected by the escalating conflict and or (recent) related displacement. The target population in the proposed Kunduz response has been displaced since June and the majority of them indicated that they do cannot return home. They are living in substandard and overcrowded shelters, lack employment opportunities, are acute food insecure and prior to the lean season they are already resorting to negative coping strategies. They also cannot afford the necessary repair to their houses, destroyed by the conflict. This makes them extremely vulnerable to winter as they will not be able to address their additional winterization needs. As there is a large percentage of PSN, there are many protection concerns. Although the situation in Nangarhar is somewhat different, half of the assessed population is displaced but people are living in similar conditions. Previous assessments showed that people were already severely food insecure, and have very few employment opportunities/ little means to provide for their families, making them extremely vulnerable and likely to adapt negative coping strategies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the project is to provide extremely vulnerable conflict affected people in Kunduz and Nangarhar with dignified shelter solutions through conditional cash transfers for shelter repair and cash for NFIs, ensuring their well-being, privacy and dignity whilst mitigating protection and health risks of these people.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Rehabilitation Association For Afghanistan (NPO/RRAA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNOCHA - United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0) 70 &#x2013; 31 36 300</telephone>
   <email>info@cordaid.org</email>
   <website>https://www.cordaid.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grote Marktstraat 45, Den Haag, Zuid Holland, 2511 BH</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="679" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location ref="AF">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
   </name>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
  </location>
  <sector code="16040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-01">665712</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conditional and unrestricted cash</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSH-I2:  Number of people benefitting from conditional and unrestricted cash transfers</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A conditional transfer requires beneficiaries to undertake a specific action/activity (e.g. attending school, building a shelter, attending nutrition screenings, undertaking work, trainings, etc.) in order to receive assistance; i.e. a condition must be fulfilled before the
transfer is received. Unrestricted transfers can be used entirely as the recipient chooses i.e. there are no restrictions on how the transfer is spent (Definitions of CALP). Conditional cash transfers can include cash for work, cash for assets and cash for training.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="CSH-I2" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-12-31" value="0" year="2021">
     <location ref="AF"></location>
     <dimension name="Gender - genre" value="Female - feminin"></dimension>
    </baseline>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-12-31" value="0" year="2021">
     <location ref="AF"></location>
     <dimension name="Gender - genre" value="Male - masculin"></dimension>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0">
      <location ref="AF"></location>
      <dimension name="Gender - genre" value="Female - feminin"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="0">
      <location ref="AF"></location>
      <dimension name="Gender - genre" value="Male - masculin"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5600"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individual household shelter</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">SHL-I1: Number of people having access to basic, safe and dignified shelters solutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic, safe and dignified: 
- affected individuals have an minimum covered floor area of 3.5m2 per person.  
- all shelter solutions and materials meet locally agreed technical and performance standards and are culturally acceptable. 
- all household (re-)construction is in accordance with safe building practices and standards.
- all household (re-)construction demonstrate involvement of the affected population and/or are culturally acceptable by the affected population.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="SHL-I1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-12-31" value="0" year="2021">
     <location ref="AF"></location>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0">
      <location ref="AF"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5600"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saving Lives Corporate Indicators</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSH-I2:  Number of people benefitting from conditional and unrestricted cash transfers</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A conditional transfer requires beneficiaries to undertake a specific action/activity (e.g. attending school, building a shelter, attending nutrition screenings, undertaking work, trainings, etc.) in order to receive assistance; i.e. a condition must be fulfilled before the
transfer is received. Unrestricted transfers can be used entirely as the recipient chooses i.e. there are no restrictions on how the transfer is spent (Definitions of CALP). Conditional cash transfers can include cash for work, cash for assets and cash for training.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="CSH-I2" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-12-31" value="0" year="2021">
     <location ref="AF"></location>
     <dimension name="Gender - genre" value="Female - feminin"></dimension>
    </baseline>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-12-31" value="0" year="2021">
     <location ref="AF"></location>
     <dimension name="Gender - genre" value="Male - masculin"></dimension>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0">
      <location ref="AF"></location>
      <dimension name="Gender - genre" value="Female - feminin"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="0">
      <location ref="AF"></location>
      <dimension name="Gender - genre" value="Male - masculin"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5600"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of beneficiaries reached (SL)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people  who benefitted directly or indirectly with life-saving humanitarian assistance and/or resilient recovery services and/or disaster preparedness from activities in a humanitarian response implemented by Cordaid and implementing partners</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="SL0.01" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0">
      <location ref="AF"></location>
      <dimension name="Direct/ Indirect" value="Direct beneficiaries"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="0">
      <location ref="AF"></location>
      <dimension name="Gender - genre" value="Female - feminin"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="0">
      <location ref="AF"></location>
      <dimension name="Gender - genre" value="Male - masculin"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="8100"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate Resilience</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project integrates climate risks in programming</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The integration of climate risks in programming includes an undertaking of concrete actions to reduce and/or mitigate risks related to climate change impact and disaster risks  ( for example droughts, erosion, salinization, flooding, etc.) 
The projects we refer to could be on the themes of health education, justice, security, disaster management, finance and livelihoods.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="CC1.03" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0">
      <location ref="AF"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
