<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41160054-201069</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Appeal For Saving Lives of the Displaced Families in Chin and Kayah States</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDPs, youth/children, Church in minority</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar obtained independence from the British colonial rule in 1948. However, from the start of independence peace and stability have never been obtained. The country&#x2019;s valuable resources have fueled tensions and even civil wars over the past 70 years. Most recently the democratically elected government led by Aung San Su Kyi was overthrown by the Myanmar military (the Tatmadaw) on the 1st of February. This military coup was followed by massive demonstrations and violent crackdown of these demonstrations by the Tatmadaw. The demonstrations were mostly initiated by young internet savvy people who were loosely organized in the Civil Disobedience Movement (CDM).

Martial law was installed in 6 townships in Yangon. As a result, most of the demonstrations stopped. The democratically elected parliament organized themselves in the CRPH (Committee Representing the Pyrthu Hluttaw; Pyidaungsu Hluttaw is the name of the parliament). The CRPH organized a National Unity Government (NUG). The CRPH and the NUG started organizing federal armies at state level in the ethic areas. People Defense Forces are organized at township level and also mandated by the NUG. The federal armies are teaming up with the Ethic Armed Organizations (EAO). The EAO and the CRPH have issued statements to demand the release of democratically elected leaders and to stop all violence against innocent and peaceful citizens. They also mentioned supporting the establishment of a federal state with much more self-governance by the ethnic minorities. Currently the most severe opposition to the Tatmadaw is in Chin state and Kayah state. 

Chin State is also one of the poorest states in Myanmar. Chin State does not have a history of protracted conflicts such as the eastern part of Myanmar. Ethic armed groups are not as active as in the Eastern part of Myanmar. In My the NUG initiated the establishment of the Chinland Defense Force (CDF). When the Tatmadaw started attacking parts of Chin state the CDF became the major armed group fighting the Tatmadaw. The hostilities between the CDF and the Tatmadaw are one of the most intense fighting&#x2019;s in the country and have uprooted thousands of families and individuals. Currently, the people that are uprooted are mostly in need of food.

In Chin state markets are functioning and cash grants has been selected by the partner as the best and most efficient modus of operandi. In Kayah state markets have been disrupted and food aid is the most realistic option and prioritized by KMSS Loikaw. Moreover in Kayah the IDPs mentioned that they are in need of mats, mosquito nets and blankets as the second priority. As the third priority access to (safe) drinking water was mentioned.

About 70% of the population in the Kayah State depend on agriculture for their livelihood. Most indigenous communities rely on shifting cultivation for livelihoods while some are doing permanent cultivation. 

Thousands of people have been displaced in Demoso Township after the armed conflict between military troops and People Defense Force troops which took place in DawNganKha on the 21st of May 2021. The conflict was sparked as a result of confrontation between the military troops and local people over the destruction of road blockages set up for protection of families from malicious attacks especially at night and the arrest of at least 8 people at a funeral house. In fact, the tensions had already increased with gradually harsher crackdowns on the protesters against the military coup and the previous arrest of at least 70 young people now detained in Loikaw prison.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project is based on assessments conducted by the partners and based on the needs expressed by the target group.

2.1 Ultimate Objective 
To provide lifesaving supports to 1556 IDPs in the Chin and the Kayah states in Myanmar.

Specific Objective 1
To provide relief assistances to 1056 people affected by the Coup in the Chin and the Kayah States.

Result 1: 
1056 IDPs in Chin and Kayah have access to food.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Myanmar</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KMSS - Karuna Mission Social Solidarity (Caritas Myanmar)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kerk in Actie</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0) 70 &#x2013; 31 36 300</telephone>
   <email>info@cordaid.org</email>
   <website>https://www.cordaid.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grote Marktstraat 45, Den Haag, Zuid Holland, 2511 BH</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14031" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="OT-2021-000042-MMR" type="1" vocabulary="1-2"></humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-02-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-15">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
