<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41160054-201014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Borderlands Youth Forum</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3 youth led CSOs in DRC, Burundi and Uganda and their networks / constituencies, youth leaders from the borderland communities. 

local, national, and regional political and peace and security stakeholders.*
Once the report will be finalized the results will be shared with key stakeholders</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the Great Lakes region, countries are connected through a transnational, cyclical complex of state fragility, violent conflict, and mass displacement. While Burundi, DRC, and Uganda are culturally, linguistically, historically, and politically distinct, all three countries are characterized by unresponsive, unaccountable institutions that largely fail to deliver security, justice and basic services to people; and by deeply-entrenched patriarchal and gerontocratic norms and practices that underpin governance arrangements at all levels.  These characteristics have particularly deleterious implications for young people, especially young women, who constitute the majority of the region&#x2019;s population.

This is especially evident in the region&#x2019;s borderlands, peripheral spaces which tend to become sites of conflict due to their physical remoteness and political marginalization. Borderlands are often volatile, but also where regional interdependence is deepest and most visible, with communities connected by routine cross-border mobility, mixed migration flows, ties of family and identity, and management of common risks such as food insecurity, environmental degradation, and climate change vulnerability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall objective: Empower youth groups and networks in borderland communities of Burundi, DRC, Rwanda and Uganda to influence national and regional policymakers to strengthen cross-border political dialogue and cooperation in the Great Lakes, contributing to a more stable and peaceful future for the region
Evidence generating for lobby &amp; advocacy purposes and exchange: Strengthen the capacity of youth groups from borderland communities to generate locally-grounded insights on conflict, security and justice issues with a cross-border or regional dimension</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0) 70 &#x2013; 31 36 300</telephone>
   <email>info@cordaid.org</email>
   <website>https://www.cordaid.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grote Marktstraat 45, Den Haag, Zuid Holland, 2511 BH</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="BI" percentage="33"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="33"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="34"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-01">114000</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
