<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41160054-201037</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saving lives of conflict affected newly displaced people in Afghanistan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Currently 18.4 million Afghans are in need, and 5.1 million of them are children. One in three Afghans is acute food insecure and 50% of all children under 5 are malnourished. According to pre-harvest IPC Analysis (March&#x2019;21), 35% of the population (11 million people) are in IPC3 or worse. Badakhshan, Faryab, Ghor and Daikundi are worst affected.  Furthermore, spring 2021 is expected to see a volatile and unpredictable pattern of conflict with an anticipated escalation in fighting, in line with seasonal patterns of conflict each year and worsened by the start of the withdrawal of US forces. At the same time low winter rainfall and hot temperatures associated with a La Ni&#xF1;a weather event are anticipated to drive drought-like conditions over spring, affecting rain-fed and irrigated agriculture/livestock, as well as availability of water for drinking, washing and sanitation. It is anticipated that 25 provinces, already with high levels of food insecurity and malnutrition, are likely to be most acutely affected. Furthermore, flash floods can be expected as well.  
The food security situation will further deteriorate throughout the year as armed conflict and security incidents will increase displacement levels heavily. Since the start of 2021, the number of armed clashes between the Taliban, the Afghan National Security Forces and Non-State Armed Groups has surged, causing displacement and loss of livelihoods across 29 out of 34 provinces of Afghanistan. From 1 January until date, 2021 116,000 people were forcibly displaced due to conflict. Under the US Biden administration since 1 May, 2021, US and NATO troops are being withdrawn from the country, leaving a power vacuum. As a result militants have launched assaults around the country, with heavy fighting reported in Kunduz, Kunar, Uruzgan, Nangarhar, Helmand, Kandahar, Faryab and Badakhshan. The offensive in the south of the country as well as armed attacks along the border of Pakistan as well as the northern Baghlan province raises concerns over the security situation once the US withdraws (Reuters, 2021). It is expected that the Taliban is aiming to annex more districts, as the Taliban currently controls around 65% of the country. In Q1 2021, the conflict caused 1,783 civilian casualties, a 29% increase compared to Q1 2020. According to UNOCHA, at least 500,000 people will be displaced in the next few months due to conflict and drought. They will require life-saving assistance for which UNOCHA is seeking an additional US$47 million in addition to the HRP. Currently the HRP is funding by 13%.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food insecure people and IDPs</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the project is to save the lives of multiple shock affected people who are recently displaced because of conflict and are in IPC phase 3 or phase 4, through unconditional cash assistance, contributing to a minimum household food consumption score above 42.5.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization of Human Welfare - OHW</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Rehabilitation Association for Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-06" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0) 70 &#x2013; 31 36 300</telephone>
   <email>info@cordaid.org</email>
   <website>https://www.cordaid.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grote Marktstraat 45, Den Haag, Zuid Holland, 2511 BH</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="679" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="16050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-06"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-06">449540</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
