<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-290767-ALERT00497_S12426_A</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-290767" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Jewish Relief</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medical Assistance to Sulawesi Earthquake Survivors</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the afternoon of January 14, 2021, a 5.9 magnitude earthquake struck West Sulawesi province near the cities of Majene and Mamuju. Hours later, this initial earthquake was followed by a more powerful 6.2 magnitude earthquake in the early hours of January 15. In the aftermath of the earthquakes, initial reports indicate that 20,448 people have been directly affected, 91 people have died, 3 people are missing, 253 people were seriously injured, 240 people were moderately injured, and 679 people were slightly injured. In addition, there are an estimated 9,390 displaced persons. The earthquakes also caused significant damage to buildings and public infrastructure, and obscured road access and transportation.

With health facilities and infrastructure damaged, and access to farther afield medical services limited due to widespread displacement, the crisis has had a significant impact on affected individuals as it pertains to health and health services. As many affected individuals and families are unable to access health services, they are at risk of not receiving appropriate medical treatment following the earthquakes or having pre-existing medical conditions worsen due to not having access to medical practitioners or basic medication.

Project:

This proposed project and response will address the lack of available general medical services and psychological services for those affected by the West Sulawesi earthquakes. Following a rapid needs assessment conducted by our local partner, IBU Foundation, we are proposing to target 1,250 unique individuals to benefit by providing them with access to general medical services, psychological first aid (PFA), and psychosocial support.

 The general medical services will be provided by medical practitioners and a mobile medical unit that is equipped to offer primary health services and medicine. The mobile medical unit will have the capacity to prescribe basic medication. For those that have health conditions that extend beyond the capacity of the mobile medical unit team, the health practitioners will refer them to appropriate medical centres or hospitals. The proposed project&#x2019;s general medical services will attempt to reach 1,250 individuals.

 Psychological first aid activities will be administered by PFA specialists, and the proposed project will consist of assistance for displaced individuals that can support individuals and communities to heal the psychological wounds and rebuild social structures after an emergency or a critical event. PFA activities will aim to reach 100 total individuals.

 Finally, the proposed project&#x2019;s psychosocial support activities will attempt to reach the same 1,250 individuals reached by the general medical services and focus on developing participants resilience. To provide psychosocial support, our local partner offers activities that include exploration of emotions and feelings to help aid fear and distress, developing one&#x2019;s emotional regulation, building up one&#x2019;s independence, as well as other activities.

 All activities will be conducted by trained, accredited, and registered professionals. Our local partner, IBU Foundation, has access to relevant medical networks and connections with medical practitioners. All actions, including the proposed general medical services, PFA, and Psychosocial Services, are based on SPHERE standard for Health Action and IASC for filling basic service needs. Practically, this means that medical services will not be serving more than 50 patients a day. The supply of medicines and medical equipment will be in accordance with the regulatory standards. The services of PFA and PSS will also be in accordance with these standards.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia Bhadra Utama (IBU Foundation)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-213890" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for International Development (DFID)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12191" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="12340" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-23"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-09"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-01-23">45000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-01-23">42954.52</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBU Foundation spends</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-01-23">45000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
