<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-18/HSD20/SA2/E/INGO/8053</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusive Education  Environment for Vulnerable Children in Protracted IDPs and Host Community at Tawila and Dar Al Salam localities - North Darfur state - Under Envelop 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is designed to improve the quality of education for protracted children in Tawila and Dar Al Salam (Shangli Tobaia) and the host communities in both localities. The targeted communities and as a result of protracted conflict have not benefited fully from quality education .The main objective of this project is to improve access to inclusive education environment for direct 3277 children (1449 boys and 1708 girls) and 66 men amp 54 women and indirect 16230 children ((8330 girls amp 7900 boys) are a identified as the most vulnerable children in Tawila and Dar Al Salam localities. 

The project will ensure inclusive and attractive education environment in the targeted 19 schools , 8 in Dar Al Salam namely (Shangil Tobay (B ) for boys, Alhurriya (B) coeducation school , Shangil Tobay ( A) for boys, Shangil Tobay (B) school for Girls,Shaddad coeducation school, Alhurria (A) Basic coeducation school, Alfath Coeducation shoal, Shangil Tobay (A) for Girls and 11 schools in Tawila locality (Osama Bin Zaid school for boys, AL Nuzooh Aljadeed for Boys, AL Zahra co-education school, Abu baker Alsideeg school for boys, Abu dujana co-education school, Omalmumineen school for girls, Alkhannsa School for girls, Khalid Ibn Alwaleed co- education school, Aleimam Malik co-education school, Dabba Nira co-education school and Alnuzooh Aljadeed for girls become attractive and protective for the children in the targeted 4 host communities and 7 protracted IDPs camps. Actually the intervention per school is decided based on the school needs and considering the coordination with the other actors working in the targeted localities to avoid the overlapping and duplication of work.

Also the project will provide an essential school equipment (125 set of seating and desk for 7 schools targeting 500 children in 9 classrooms), the schools is in highly needed for the blackboard to be provided compare to the other LTM. Also (80 Teachers (36 male and 44 female from which 70% are volunteers from the camps and host communities by building their capacities in the core subjects (Arabic, Mathematics and English), and in addition to that the project will built the capacities of 80 teachers and 40 PTAs ( 30 male and 10 female) in Child protection subject, psychosocial support and referral mechanisms to enable them deliver quality learning as well as address the protection concerns including the inclusion of children with disability and School Management to be able to engage with children and community members and to ensure the role of women, especially mothers, in school governance and community mobilization. 

The project will support the targeted schools and children by provision of safe and protective learning spaces and gender sensitive WASH facilities which respond to the critical gaps in access to learning spaces and WASH services especially among female school children. Providing WASH in most needy schools (as in the target schools there is a functional latrines but not covered all the children as per the standard, so the project will contribute to fill this gaps) with a special emphasis on child friendly and gender sensitive school latrines and washing facilities as well as hygiene and sanitation promotion for children will directly improve attendance as well as health of school children. Furthermore it will have wider benefits, by enabling children to be effective agents of change and to promote improved health and hygiene practices within their families and communities, Beside that the project will contribute to enhance the awareness of the children and the community members in Dar Al Salam and Tawila community on the issues of environmental and WASH issues by conducting awareness sessions for 10 schools. Although of all this intervention still additional support is needed to ensure inclusive and attractive school environment for the IDPs children in the target localities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Peace Humanitarian Organization (SPHO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Misgana Amanuel</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>09123508852</telephone>
   <email>misgana.amanuel@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Munier Mohammed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00249 83 231905</telephone>
   <email>munier.mohammed@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU13">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">North Darfur</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.76619690 24.90422080</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-02">185757.01</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-02">91355.91</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-8053">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-02">277112.92</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00201551">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-13">69278</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00207495">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-21">140000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00213010">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-08">47601.9</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
