<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="193" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/18969" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-UUSC-MX-16-18969</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundaci&#xF3;n Para la Justicia y El Estado Democr&#xE1;tico de Derecho</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To promote the effective implementation of the Transnational Mechanism for Search and Investigation, a tool to identify migrant victims of forced disappearance, violence, and other human rights violations in Mexico and Central America.

Since its founding in 2011, the Foundation for Justice and the Democratic Rule of Law (FJDRL) has focused on upholding the human rights of migrants and refugees in transit through Mexico. Members of this highly vulnerable population are frequently the victims of forced disappearance, extrajudicial killings, kidnapping and torture at the hands of criminal networks and corrupt state actors. Adding to their vulnerability in many cases is their lack of regularized status, which creates a barrier to access justice and has led to a grave lack of accountability for crimes and human rights violations committed against them. 

FJDRL has addressed this crisis of violence and impunity by partnering with other civil society actors and committees of migrants&apos; families across the region to coordinate the systematic documentation of disappearances, extrajudicial killings, and other rights violations against migrants. 

FJDRL&apos;s task in the present project is to ensure the effective implementation of this new mechanism; to coordinate between Mexican and Central American authorities to ensure that victims and families receive care and access to relevant services (such as legal assistance in navigating criminal and administrative procedures, psychosocial and medical care); and to expand the work of the Forensic Commission in identifying and returning the remains of missing persons.&quot;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-04-6186012" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unitarian Universalist Service Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="UUSC-MX-16-18969" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unitarian Universalist Service Committee</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.uusc.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MX" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Rights Democracy and Governance</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
