<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="193" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/17455" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-UUSC-US-15-17455</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COLORS Food Enterprise Incubation Academy - NY Pilot</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic, Workers&#x2019; Rights</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In order to carry out this work, ROC will engage in the following activities over the next year:

Objective 1: Train 500 low-income restaurant workers through CHOW workforce development program in order to support their advancement into positions that pay a higher wage.
&#x2022; Activity 1a: Each affiliate will offer a minimum of 2 ten-week CHOW courses per region, enrolling 20 students in each class.
&#x2022; Activity 1b: Place 70% of graduates in new employment or promotions that pay higher than their original wage.
&#x2022; Activity 1c: Release mobile app to reach broader base of restaurant workers and simultaneously engage consumers as advocate on policy issues.
Outcome of Objective: Paying particular attention to recruiting workers of color, we will train participants in the skills they need in order to compete for the industry&#x2019;s highest paying positions. As our industry study has shown us that workers of color have lesser opportunities than their white counterparts of equal qualification, it is our expectation that this boost in their skills will help keep them competitive. While ROC, our members, and allies continue to work to dismantle the industry&#x2019;s systematic discrimination long term, CHOW remains an important part of ensuring that workers of colors have immediate access to opportunities for economic stability. 

Objective 2: Grow ROC&#x2019;s network of RAISE employers to 200 partners who practice responsible employment practices and serve as vocal supporters of raising industry standards.
&#x2022; Activity 2a: Hold RAISE convening and provide information and presentations on safe workplace environments.
&#x2022; Activity 2b: Conduct focus group to determine barriers to internal promotions.
&#x2022; Activity 2c: Conduct assessment of employer needs in order to produce comprehensive catalog of helpful resources.
Outcome of Objective: Expanding ROC&#x2019;s network of responsible employers will allow us to build broader partnerships that will help us raise the public profile of the issues that impact workers in the restaurant industry. The support of restaurant owners is a key component of winning support from the public and from policymakers on certain legislative issues such as raising the minimum wage and guaranteeing paid sick day benefits. As well, good relationships with restaurant owners helps ROC develop a deep understanding of business owner mentalities. They guide our ability to plan compelling and effective conversations with even more employers in order to continue improving the culture of the industry.

Objective 3: Expand COLORS restaurants into New Orleans, Washington DC, and Oakland.
&#x2022; Activity 3a: Hire general manager and finalize location details for COLORS New Orleans.
&#x2022; Activity 3b: Secure funding to seed launch of COLORS On the Grill in Washington DC.
&#x2022; Activity 3c: Work with community partner Ella Baker Center to secure funding from private and public sector supporters to fund the launch of Restore Oakland Center.
Outcome of Objective: The COLORS model is increasingly becoming the embodiment of ROC&#x2019;s vision to grow the impact of CHOW, build our membership base, and integrate food justice and food-security with economic security. Ultimately, COLORS aims for a holistic approach to the convergence of interests among workers, employers and consumers, linking economic empowerment of low-wage works, to promoting healthy environments and communities, to growing a sustainable food system.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">to expand the Co-Op Academy to support the ability for low-wage workers to own their power and create their own opportunities within the food service industry</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Restaurant Opportunities Centers United</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-04-6186012" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unitarian Universalist Service Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="UUSC-US-15-17455" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unitarian Universalist Service Committee</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philip Hamilton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Associate for Economic Justice</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>phamilton@uusc.org</email>
   <website>http://www.uusc.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="US" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-06-01">30000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-04-6186012">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unitarian Universalist Service Committee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
