<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="193" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/21707" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-135-21707</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organizational and Administrative Strengthening of Las Diosas Cooperatives</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2017, La Central developed its strategic plan. In the line of institutional strengthening considers as a strategic objective: Strengthen the management structures and capacities of management and administration bodies with generational change and better communication and coordination with grassroots cooperatives.

The objective of the project is to contribute to the strengthening of the Las Diosas Plant for the implementation of its strategic plan for the period 2017-2022 to strengthen the functioning of its management bodies and democratic governance through transparency in its accountability processes. The grant will be used to strengthen the implementation of the Strategic Plan, through financial support to hold meetings and assemblies that favor the consensus and decision-making processes that involve evaluation planning sessions and the holding of the ordinary assembly of delegates to the Central where the management bodies are ratified and elected, the POA (Annual Operating Plan), the general budget, the balance sheet, the financial statements and the development plan proposed as a requirement by fair trade certifiers, organic certification among others are approved. To improve democratic governance and the process of accountability to associated cooperatives. As well as comply with the provisions of the Cooperatives Law and its regulations. Law 499. And the requirements of the certifiers, for this it is necessary to support the Central with a full-time accountant. Every year All cooperatives and the Central must submit their financial statements to the DGI and the MEFCCA with the requirements established by the Cooperatives Law 499 and the Law of Tax Coalition. And fortnightly statements must be made to the Electronic Office of the General Directorate of income. As well as presenting to the certifiers the balance sheet each year and to the assembly of associates for approval.

Support to the technical team of the Central in transport to carry out harvest monitoring, preparation of fertilizers and support for certification in 7 base cooperatives. And the realization of assemblies of the base cooperatives.

The Central has two field techniques that must be mobilized to the communities where the basic cooperatives are located. On average they make average accompaniments of 6 visits x 7 cooperative for a total of 42 visits per year.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-04-6186012" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unitarian Universalist Service Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="135-21707" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unitarian Universalist Service Committee</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.uusc.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NI" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="24" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Strengthening for CSOs (general)</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
