<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="193" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/17475" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-UUSC-US-15-17475</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establishing a Dalit Women-led Solar Distribution Enterprise in Gorkha District</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity Breakdown:
1. Planning and Preparation (RECRUIT AGENTS): Empower Generation (EG) will meet with ADWAN to prepare the project and conduct a household energy assessment of the Dalit community in Gorkha as well as the surrounding communities. EG will train ADWAN to collect inventory orders from sales agents, until an entrepreneur is selected and to monitor and support sales agents. Together with ADWAN, EG will identify and recruit up to 40 Dalit women as solar sales agents. This will include the 20 Dalit women that have already been introduced to Empower Generation&#x2019;s work in July as well as 20 more interested participants. 
A1 OUTCOMES: 
&#x2022; Household energy assessment of a minimum of 50 households 
&#x2022; 40 Dalit women recruited as potential sales agents 
&#x2022; Income baseline for sales agents conducted 

2. TRAIN AGENTS: EG will conduct one full day of Sales &amp;amp; Marketing and Mobile Money training for up to 40 participants. Following the successful completion of the training, 30 agents will be selected and provided solar starter kits (demos) from EG&#x2019;s distributor, and sales agent identification and marketing materials. 
A2 OUTCOMES:
&#x2022; Sales and marketing training held 
&#x2022; 30 solar sales agents selected and provided marketing materials and demos

3. SELECT &amp;amp; TRAIN ENTREPRENEUR: After a few months of working as a sales agent, EG will begin an interview selection process for interested to become an entrepreneur. Successful candidates will be women who have made significant sales, show management and leadership capacity and are interested in continuing in this line of work full-time. Empower Generation will select an entrepreneur to support and mentor. She will be sent to EG&#x2019;s annual 7-day Capacity Building Workshop in early 2016 for intensive business basics skill training and be sent to the entrepreneur-only trainings throughout the year. 
A3 OUTCOMES: 
&#x2022; 1 entrepreneur selected
&#x2022; 1 entrepreneur trained 
&#x2022; Detailed baseline on decision making power conducted for entrepreneur 

4. ESTABLISH &amp;amp; SUPPORT ENTERPRISE: EG will support the selected entrepreneur in registering her business and opening a bank account. EG will conduct a series of official launch events in the entrepreneur&#x2019;s community, introducing her as our network representative in the area. The entrepreneur will be provided a revolving inventory credit loan, marketing materials, a cell phone (if needed), and training in financial and inventory management, and in how to expand and incentivize her sales force. The entrepreneur will be enrolled in EG&#x2019;s incentive program, trained to use our CRM and reporting system. EG will conduct a series of sales promotion programs with the entrepreneur and her sales agents to promote their busiess. 
A4 OUTCOMES
&#x2022; 1 enterprise registered 
&#x2022; 1 bank account opened 
&#x2022; 1 line of credit for inventory issued 
&#x2022; 3 startup events conducted 
&#x2022; 2 sales promotion programs conducted 

5. REPORTING: Conduct baseline and endline assessments on sales agents and entrepreneurs to evaluate impact of the program on their business acumen, self-efficacy, personal income and impact made on their community via provision of clean energy. Collate and analyze assessment findings and create a project report for UUSC. Write profile posts on four high-performing sales agents and profile the selected entrepreneur in Empower Generation&#x2019;s online blog. Write one article to be published in the Huffington Post on the impact of a project that empowers Dalit women to become solar energy providers and entrepreneurs. 
A5 OUTCOMES
&#x2022; Baseline 
&#x2022; Endline 
&#x2022; Energy assessment 
&#x2022; 4 Sales Agent profiles 
&#x2022; 1 entrepreneur profile 
&#x2022; Project Report for UUSC 
&#x2022; Dalit women article for Huffington Post</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic, Women, Rights of Disaster Survivors</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">distribute much needed solar light and mobile charging to those who have been displaced by the earthquake and to create income-generating opportunities for marginalized Dalit women as entrepreneurs and solar sales agents</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Empower Generation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-04-6186012" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unitarian Universalist Service Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="UUSC-US-15-17475" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unitarian Universalist Service Committee</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rachel Freed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vice President and Chief Programs Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>rfreed@uusc.org</email>
   <website>http://www.empowergeneration.org</website>
   <website>http://www.uusc.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="5" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="17" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="26" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-11-01">22000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-04-6186012">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unitarian Universalist Service Committee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.empowergeneration.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
