<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="193" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/18983" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-UUSC-HN-16-18983</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centro de Investigaci&#xF3;n y Promoci&#xF3;n de los Derechos Humanos</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UUSC is investigating protection failures in the U.S. State Department&apos;s Central American Minors (CAM) program in the  Northern Triangle countries of Central America-- Honduras, Guatemala, and El Salvador. The CAM program ostensibly aims to provide a safe means for eligible minors to process their claims for refugee status in their home countries. Since its establishment in December 2014, however, only a few applicants have made it through the CAM system, and numerous concerns have been raised about deep flaws in the program. Advocates have pointed to the fact that CAM makes no provision for the safety of applicants throughout the processing period (which is inordinately lengthy, involving waits of more than a year for most applicants so far). Moreover, processing centers are located in major urban areas, and in order to reach them, applicants often must travel long distances across country by bus. For minors who are fleeing from violence, in hiding, or facing plausible death threats -- in short -- for the refugee population CAM was ostensibly created to serve -- these requirements are likely to place them in extreme danger by effectively broadcasting their vulnerability and their intentions to escape. The unsafe quality of the CAM process and its failure so far to bring a substantial number of minors to safety also raise the disconcerting possibility that the program is  a P.R. gesture on the part of the U.S. government to discourage informal migration and asylum seeking and not a serious effort to protect minors at the greatest risk.

Such, at least, are the chief criticisms that have leveled at the program. To date, however, there has been no systematic documentary evidence substantiating these concerns. Through interviews with asylum seeking children from Central America, this project aims to remedy this gap by providing the first comprehensive record of the program&apos;s deficiencies. 

Our partners at CIPRODEH will provide the Honduras portion of this documentary evidence. They will achieve this by working through their existing partnerships with 30 migrants&apos; families&apos; committees in Honduras. These committees will be able to direct our partners to relevant interviewees, without compromising the safety and anonymity of the latter. CIPRODEH estimates that it can conduct around three interviews from each committee, making for a rough total of 90 interviews.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-04-6186012" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unitarian Universalist Service Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="UUSC-HN-16-18983" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unitarian Universalist Service Committee</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.uusc.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="HN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="25" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Refugee Resettlement</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
