<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2017-2016161328</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Reduction of vulnerability in Ethiopian coffee production</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia, the birthplace of coffee, has more than 1.2 million coffee growers, 95% of which are smallholders, and around 16 million households, nearly a fifth of the population, depend on coffee for their livelihood. Coffee contributes a third of the countr
y&apos;s foreign exchange earnings. Ethiopian coffee farmers face challenges like low productivity, quality inconsistency, lack of access to capital, lack of direct sales contacts and marketing skills. As temperatures rise and rains become more erratic, Ethiopi
an coffee farmers have seen decreasing yields. A poorly developed insurance market prevents people without collateral from getting access to credit, and leave farmers vulnerable when facing, for example, droughts and diseases on coffee trees. It also preve
nts farmers from affording the investment required for diversification of farming income. In rural areas, manual agricultural wage workers are in the very weakest position. Small producer organisations usually don?t have capacity dealing with seasonal hire
d labour. With huge youth unemployment in Ethiopia, youth are especially vulnerable. The project reduces Ethiopian coffee workers? and producers? vulnerability to climate change, natural disasters, human rights? violations and social exclusion. The project
?s planning phase will start in 2016 with participatory planning workshops and analysis with stakeholders. In the conception phase in 2015 preliminary ideas were agreed and the project responds to the vulnerability challenges by enhancing farmers? skills o
f sustainable production and strengthening organisational capacity with particular focus on human resource managerial skills. The project also promotes multi-cropping as a way to decrease vulnerability to both market shocks and natural pest outbreaks or ir
regular weather patterns among coffee farmers. The project?s development goal is to contribute to sustainable living standards for coffee workers and producers. The project?s purpose is that vulnerability of coffee workers and producers is decreased. Benef
iciaries are over 170.000 coffee producers and nearly 100.000 seasonal workers. Implementing partner organizations are the regional producer network Fairtrade Africa and two local second-level coffee cooperatives. The project focuses especially on youth, w
omen and poorest farmers and workers. http://www.fairtradeafrica.net/</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-55" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fairtrade Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="1ETH1" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Sidama"></location>
  <sector code="31162" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">1908</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
