<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2017-2010100146</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impacts of climate change on ecosystems in Eastern Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is continuation to a research and development project (Climate Change Impacts on Ecosystem Services and Food Security) funded with 49 million Euros between the years 2011-15 in Kenya Tanzania and Ethiopia. The overall purpose is to disseminate 
and communicate the research results of the first project phase to rural communities and professionals working with climate change related issues as well as to strengthen their capacities to monitor and adapt to climate change. The overall objective/impact
 is to develop adequate capacity of public and private actors in Eastern Africa to gather information on and to adapt to the effects of climate change. Support to the second phase of the project is 1 million Euros between the years 2016-17.The objective of
 the first project phase was to increase knowledge on the effects of climate change in Eastern Africa and develop the capacity of project beneficiaries to adapt to these effects. The project enhanced climate monitoring capacities in collaboration with loca
l meteorological agencies strengthened the capacity of farmers researchers and government officials through training and information dissemination introduced new techniques (e.g. rainwater harvesting modern irrigation systems and biological pest management
) and increased knowledge on the effects of climate change of researchers and stakeholders utilizing the research results.The final beneficiaries of the second phase are 11 200 smallholder farmers in project countries National Environmental Management Auth
orities primary secondary and high school teachers as well as decision makers administrators and governments. They will be reached through the intermediary beneficiaries namely smallholder farmers? groups associations and unions extension organizations (go
vernment and NGOs) youth organizations private sector scientist and technicians in National Agricultural Research and Extension Systems and civil society actors. The project is coordinated by the International Centre of Insect Physiology and Ecology (icipe
) located in Nairobi. Main implementation partners are Jimma University in Ethiopia Kenyan NGO Taita Environmental Research and Resource Arc (TERRA) Pangani Basin Water Board in Tanzania University of York University of Dar es Salaam and University of Hels
inki. The project also cooperates with 23 stakeholders from government organizations to local universities and civil society actors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="51000" ref="51000-4" role="3" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University research institute or think-tank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="29891601" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-11-05" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">500000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">500000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
