<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2017-2013130098</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community based outreach project among elderly (OPE II)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Traditionally the role of older people in Namibia has been to advise their families and communities and to receive care and respect by their children. Today their role is often overlooked. Elderly people need immediate social support and practical assistan
ce but it is likely that public support will assume greater dimension only over the coming years. Immediate objectives of the project are: 1) Increased skills on participatory working methods on elderly work among Evangelical Lutheran Church in Namibia (EL
CIN) and the community2) Improved knowledge and awareness on elderly issuesand 3) Responsive family and social support structures established in communities. Namibia has seen the breaking down of the moral fabric within communities which causes a lack of r
espect for elderly people. Older women in particular have to deal with a double battle as they face abuse and inequality because of their age and gender. Participatory community development strengthens human rights and gender equality of elderly. Project r
espects climate sustainability too.The project does not create any new structure or institution but is positioned at the ELCIN Department of Diakonia and Social Services. Along with the project ELCIN will be capacitated to create a new community work appro
ach for the most vulnerable elderly. The ultimate beneficiaries of the project are the most vulnerable elderly people over the age of 60 and their communities. Particularly attention is paid to marginalised elders without family members and vulnerable kins
hip caregivers who unexpectedly find themselves in the position of raising a second family. In both cases elderly people are subject to abuse. Major indirect beneficiary is the ELCIN.The key project activities include Curriculum Development; Development of
 elderly policy in ELCIN; Training of ELCIN personnel and volunteers; Strengthening institutional capacity of ELCIN; Discussions on sustainable future strategies; Research on relevant approaches; Development of home based care; Training on adult education;
 Providing psycho-social support and counseling; Awareness raising campaigns; Annual Ageing Seminars; Lobbying on preparation for ageing;Creating platforms for intergenerational dialogues;Establishing alliances with local authorities;Formation of Elderly c
lubs;Strengthening family ties for elderly support;Improving elderly security;Enhancing integration and networks of elderly in the community;and experience sharing.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deaconess Institute in Helsinki</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-17" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">127205</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
