<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2017-2015150841</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Strong Transport Unions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ITF commissions updated baseline research about the Southern Africa transport corridors problems based on documents and field research. The results will be presented in a meeting where continuation project will be planned. At the same time Mozambican union
s start national level information and organizing campaigning. Zambians are supported by Namibians when having difficulties driving on Namibian territory. During October Action Week visible campaign action at border crossings will be organized. ITF?s wider
 action plan includes five countries: South Africa, Mozambique, Namibia, Zambia and Swaziland, but of these AKT and SASK support Mozambique and Zambia, whilst ITF uses its own resources to cover the participation of the others.

The purpose of the pilot is
 to compile baseline data about the problems and solution options of transport workers and their unions, in order to towards the end of the year develop a longer-term plan for making the unions stronger. Workers face the same problems as along other transp
ort corridors: differences in salaries between countries even in the same companies and generally low income level, non-compliance with work and rest time and other safety regulations, harassment by authorities and corruption, robberies of cargo goods, lac
k of sanitation facilities en route, long border crossing waiting times and border bureaucracy as well as inadequacies in social security. At the same time when a more precise mapping is done to form the basis for continuation planning, Mozambican and Zamb
ian unions will already 2015 start tackling these issues through campaigning.

Immediate results will be exact information for continuation planning as a result of the mapping. Additionally the visibility of the unions in Mozambique and Zambia will improve
, and this is expected to bring new members to the unions. Beneficiaries are Mozambican and Zambian transport workers working in road transport, railways and ports.

ITF is the international umbrella organization of transport workers that with this project
 supports its affiliates in two countries. The project is linked to wider ITF interest representation tackling the problems along Southern Africa Transport Corridors focusing on transport hubs and corridors. ITF coordinates and manages the project from its
 London head office and Nairobi Africa regional office, and is recruiting a local project coordinator in Mozambique to ensure progress with local level focal points in each country.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SASK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">40900</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
