<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2017-2008080112</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing the Support and Rehabilitation of School-aged Children with disabilities in Yerevan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The first development project (2009- 2013) established the Day Care and Rehabilitation Center in Yerevan serving 450 under school aged children with disabilities and their parents. The request for the continuation of the rehabilitation services for school-
aged children with disabilities came from their parents. The parents shared their concerns that the conditions of their children and the quality of their life are in the risk of decrease due to lack of rehabilitation and support services during the school 
years. Thought the services provided by the Day Care and Rehabilitation Center the children&apos;s school preparedness increased and as the result of the project 80 children were able to attend the schools. The main purpose of the project (2014-2017) is to prev
ent the inequalities of children with disabilities and to enhance their inclusion to the society: 1) by promoting the integration of the children with disabilities to normal life through providing multi-professional rehabilitation for enhancing the abiliti
es of functions of the child; 2) and by sharing information about disabilities to project&apos;s different shareholders. The project aims to establish the Support and Rehabilitation Center in Yerevan for children from 6 to 10 years old with disabilities. The ac
tivities of the Rehabilitation Center is targeted to children who are not attending the schools. The professionals of the project will provide rehabilitation advise and individual rehabilitation to school environment to children with disabilities who have 
been already integrated to the schools. The project will have about 480 children and their families as direct beneficiaries during the whole project. The center will provide psychosocial support for parents. The project will enhance the capacity of the phy
siotherapists speech therapists and other rehabilitation professionals and teachers by conducting trainings in cooperation with UNICEF Armenia. The project will hire seven local professionals. The project will pay attention to gender equality throughout th
e project&apos;s activities such as the selection of the group supporting the parenthood of fathers as well. Theroject is taking account the environmental sustainability for example when purchasing rehabilitation equipments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Patmos Lahetyssaatio</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-11-14" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="AM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="16010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">6565</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
