<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2017-2016160209</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Energy for Urban Households in Hanoi</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives:1) Research survey design networking on the potential for generating renewable energy at household scale focusing on typical townhouse typology in the urban of Hanoi. This aim to change middle-class?s energy behavior as well as consumption behav
ior to a more sustainable manner.2) Deliver training sections to motivate and encourage self-help solutions for innovative communities and professionals to produce renewable energy at household scale. This can be achieved by training transferring and bring
ing sustainable urban energy knowledge and experience from Finland to Vietnam. To exchange knowledge research training network and create background for future ideas between Finland and Vietnam in this topic.3) To design model for renewable energy system t
hat is suited with typical urban housing typology in Vietnam which is the tube-house typology. To construct and monitor a complete solar PV system tailored for a typical tube-house for middle-class urban households of Hanoi;?Expected Results: 1) To create 
a sustainable energy community through research design and practice and social impacts2) To initiate new research and innovation collaborations between academic design and business groups between two nations in the area of sustainable energy3) To encourage
 these collaborations to work with civil society and individuals to support the exchange of research innovation and technology expertise and the translation of research knowledge into tangible benefits4) To establish local hub for Finland-Vietnam country a
ctivity in a particular area of sustainable energy transferring knowledge in green design and sustainable use of resources and consumption5) To contribute alternative solutions for renewable energy at the household scale in urban of Hanoi. Our design for a
 wind-solar system could potentially produce 50% of the total household electricity consumption. The system is also expected to meet certain design requirements such as high reliability ease of transportation and low maintenance no impact on the environmen
t.6) To promote green economy through small-scale renewable energy solutions ??Activities:1) Research survey design networking and managing the project organized by IHS2)?Sustainable urban energy training transferring and bringing knowledge and experience 
from Finland to Vietnam organized by IHS and EEE3) Demonstration project delivered by IHS and 112????</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11000" ref="11000-1" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="76909162" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-23" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Hanoi"></location>
  <sector code="23230" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PP2 is primary priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">118580</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
