<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2017-2016160234</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">JUZOOR - Promoting integrated and multi-sectoral approach to provide services to women and girls victims of Gender Based Violence (GBV)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">?Promoting integrated and multi-sectoral approach to provide services to women and girls victims of Gender Based Violence (GBV) by piloting district-level referral networks and by encouraging effective civil society participation in GBV prevention efforts?
.GBV is widely recognized as a violation of human rights and threats the rights status and well-being of women and girls. Juzoor together with partners from civil society and public sectors has successfully initiated a national referral system that has bee
n endorsed by the Council of Ministers. Juzoor will activate the national referral system in at least two West Bank districts (Jenin and Tubas). It will do so through strengthening the institutional capacity of service providers developing district-level r
eferral networks raising community awareness and knowledge on GBV including on the availability of existing services. While the focus is to improve district-level GBV prevention protection and response the project will also work towards strengthening the r
eferral system at the national level. It will do so through documenting and sharing lessons learnt in the piloting of district-level referral networks with national stakeholders involved in the national referral system. The project is fully corresponds to 
one of the four priorities of Finland?s development policy: promoting the rights of women and girls. It is in strategic alignment with the expected result of the FLC: ?increased support to the victims of gender based violence?. The project will work with b
oth rights-holders and duty-bearers in the fight against GBV and its adverse impact on the advancement of women?s rights and status through facilitating changes at multiple levels including at the level of service providers (Output 1.1: The capacity and re
sponsiveness of 40 service providers in the health social and justice sectors to GBV in particular detection prevention treatment and referral of GBV is enhanced); at the district level (Output 1.2: Referral protocols are effectively being implemented in t
he two targeted districts); at the community level (Output 2.1: four community-based organizations in targeted communities are capacitated to deliver effective GBV prevention and referral services to women and girls victims or at risk of GBV) and finally a
t the national level (Output 2.2: National Referral Committee is activated and are sharing lessons to enhance the performance of the national referral system).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11000" ref="11000-1" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="85906239" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-12" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">22000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
