<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2017-2016160048</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Women&apos;s Peace Link - Making 1325 Count at Grassroots Level through the Localization Strategy</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Women Peace Link is a grassroots women-led organization that mobilizes influences and promotes the participation of local women in peace building governance and development through collaboration and networking with diverse actors.The Kenya National A
ction Plan on UNSCR 1325 was a major milestone for the country because it is a dedicated instrument that institutionalizes women?s right to contribute in peace-building conflict resolution and conflict prevention. However its implementation remains a chall
engeThe KNAP acknowledges that threats to women?s security in Kenya are also rooted in long-standing gender-based discrimination which prior to 2010 was structurally embedded in the country?s constitution laws policies and practices. Some cultural and trad
itional practices still discriminate against women and limit their participation in the public sphere thereby curtailing their full enjoyment of and access to socio-economic rights. Women?s vulnerability is exacerbated by unequal access to resources servic
es and opportunities. These concerns are addressed in UNSCR 1325 and succeeding resolutions.The KNAP encompasses all the pillars of UNSCR 1325 and adopts the concepts of human security and sustainable peace in projecting outcomes. The KNAP is also aligned 
with the Sustainable Development Goals (specifically Goal 5 and Goal 16) which seek to promote peaceful and inclusive societies for sustainable peace and development by providing access to justice to all and to build effective accountable and inclusive ins
titutions at the national and county levels.. The specific objectives of the project: 1)To raise awareness and understanding of the KNAP (Kenya National Action Plan) and related international regional and national policies among local government officials 
traditional leaders local women leaders community elders religious leaders and the respective constituencies of these local actors; 2)To promote systematic coordination between national and local authorities in implementing the KNAP; and harmonization of K
NAP with relevant national policies; 3)To promote local ownership of the KNAP and identify concrete actions toward effective implementation in local communities; and 4)To facilitate cross learning and promote solidarity among civil society peace activists 
in East Africa through the Peace Exchange component of the Localization program.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11000" ref="11000-1" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="24821220" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-04" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PP1 is primary priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">63500</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
