<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2017-2017170043</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tunapanda Institute - Spreading ICT and Coding Skills to girls and boys in Kibera Slum in conjuction with the Code Bus</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tunapanda Institute will work to create digital learning experiences for girls and boys from the community of Kibera as well as other communities in East Africa. The purpose of the project is to provide young women and men in low-income areas of East Afric
a with skills that will bring them into the digital age. Most young people in Kibera and other communities lack awareness of how powerful IT skills can be and the various technological tools that are available to assist individuals in their personal and pr
ofessional development. The project will focus on events to be held in March in conjunction with the Code Bus and will include provisions to ensure a continuing impact. By combining computer programming and music using Sonic Pi Software participants of the
 workshops will be introduced to information technology and computer programming and allow them to begin their journey into technological literacy. The event will simultaneously celebrate Finland?s 100th birthday by engaging with local musicians and artist
s to participate in an event for the Kibera community. Tunapanda will also assist with the organization and execution of events related to Nairobi Innovation Week. Continuing impact will be achieved by digitizing the workshop course materials which will th
en be used on Tunapanda?s open eLearning platform to allow the content to reach a wider audience.The main activities of the project will consist of in-person training training and the creation of digital materials that will assist other learners from vario
us communities in achieving the same knowledge and skills. The project will ensure that that Codebus project will have a continuous effect on the beneficiaries and will not be a one off event that lacks long term positive benefits for the communityThe proj
ect will target young people aged 12 - 25 especially girls who lack access to ICT education and would like to learn some skills related to the field which can help them to plan for a related career and earn income. The beneficiaries will be both 1) student
s who receive in-person training through workshops hosted by Tunapanda Institute and the Codebus team and 2) students who can access the skills through a digitized curriculum that is created by Tunapanda team members.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11000" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11230" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">8700</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">8700</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">8700</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
