<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2017-2014140728</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to Building of a Sustainable Mineral Sector and Facilitating Responsible Use of Mineral Resources in Namibia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ICI Project (Institutional Cooperation Instrument for cooperation between state actors in the partner country and in Finland) between the Geolocical Survey of Finland (GTK) and the Geological Survey of Namibia (GSN) strengthens the capacity of the Geoc
hemistry and Laboratory Division of GSN to offer companies and auhtorities services that support the decision making and administration of the mineral sector. The Project contributes to GSN&apos;s need for improving its capacity in geochemical analysis and in g
enerating information needed by the mineral sector as well as developing data management systems. The overall objective environmentally and socio-economically sustainable use of georesources is closely linked to the strategic objectives of GSN and the Nami
bian Ministry for Mines and Energy MME. The cooperation in the mineral sector between Finland and Namibia started in the 1990&apos;s and it has enabled Namibia to capitalize on Finnish expertise in developing their own capacity. The cooperation also has an impa
ct on how Finland is seen as an actor in the mineral sector. Maintaining good relations with governmental bodies is important groundwork for providing cooperation opportunities for Finnish companies in Namibia.The two-year Project will include training and
 cooperation in both Finland and Namibia. The budget of the Project is approximately 500 000 euros. The Project is linked to one of the Finnish Development Policy&apos;s priority areas: sustainable management of natural resources and environmental protection. E
nvironment is also one of the priority areas of Finland&apos;s development cooperation in Southern Africa. Cooperation between Finland and Namibia is implemented through various partnerships as well as in regional projects. There is still a need for capacity bu
ilding in Nambia and this need can be met through the ICI instrument . Direct beneficiaries of the Project are the staff of GSN whose skills and capacity are strengthened. Final beneficiaries are the Namibian people as a sustainable and efficient mineral s
ector contributes to generating welfare and jobs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="3" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Geologian tutkimuskeskus</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-10-16" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="32210" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">86513</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
