<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2017-2016161139</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Community, Family and Youth Wellbeing Development Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burundi experienced a brutal civil war which displaced more than a half million people. After a cease-fire about 600 000 refugees returned. Upon their return young people were excluded from education due to different education systems and different languag
es. Hunger is also a major problem in Burundi because of the land issues, as the conflict has destabilized food production. The farmers in Burundi lack access to new farming methods for increasing the food production. Especially young people, who have retu
rned to their home country after the war, have difficulties in finding vocational education, employment and reintegration into the society because of language problems and poverty. Supporting the families? development towards financial independence and equ
ipping churches? capacity to address the social problems in their communities is a sustainable solution in improvement of societal wellbeing in the country. Farmers and families are trained and assisted in food production and animal husbandry, and environm
ental protection. Food security and climate change policies have been ratified and put into practice through church partner&apos;s trained staff. Youth centres offer youth activities and vocational training. Fida partners with la Communaute des Eglises de Pente
cote au Burundi (CEPBU, The Community of Pentecostal Churches in Burundi).The project contributes to a sustainable impact to the wellbeing of communities, families and young people in Burundi through a just, safe and caring church. The purpose is empowered
 families and church relevantly addressing the needs of youth, and improving the food security for 600 families of Giharo and Bukemba by 2016. The youth social interventions (youth centres) will give thousands of youth a safe place to learn and develop the
ir life and vocational skills. As a result, the well being of youth will be improved ? whereby thousands of young people will be able to face challenges of employment in formal and informal sectors. The beneficiaries include children, youth, their families
, farmers, and the whole communities through a long-term impact, when youth employment will be increased and food production improved. The churches also benefit by gaining recognized positive social influence in their communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-173" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fida International ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="5284" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BI" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Giharo, Bukemba, Bujumbura, Ruyigi, Maramvya, Kayo"></location>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">153356</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
