<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2017-2014140085</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Sustainable Agriculture Project for Rural Women in Liberia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A large proportion of the economically active population of Liberia is engaged either directly or indirectly in small-holder subsistence agriculture, and women constitute the majority of small-holder producers and the agricultural labor force in general. A
t the same time, cultural and social organisation limit women?s access to and control over productive assets. Within the agriculture sector, poultry production still remains a challenge with approximately 95% of eggs consumed in Liberia being imported. The
 main objective of the project is to reduce poverty among rural, in particular female-headed households through the development of backyard poultry and vegetable farming. Additional objective is transformation of partner?s semi-commercial poultry farm into
 a sustainable profit-making social enteprise that integrates backyard farmers into a larger production system that generates income for beneficries and for the implementing partner to carry out rural development projects thereby reducing its dependency on
 donor funding and thus increase its sustainability. The project will have the following expected results: ? functional and independent farm/production unit created and opportunities for business expansion enhanced through provision of business development
 support to the implementing partner;? beneficiaries? income earning capacities improved through backyard poultry (egg production) and vegetable farming, and formation of farmers? cooperatives and training of participants in small business and management s
kills to properly market and manage their products? improved farming methods for the cultivation of crops (corn and soya) for feed production adopted by beneficiaries.Right-holders/beneficiaries: Rural women, in particular vulnerable women, small-holder fa
rmers Implementing partner: Project New Outlook (PNO)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finn Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Margibi County, Liberia"></location>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">873</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
