<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2017-2014140762</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FLC/ WiLDAF Promoting Women?s Participation in Democratic and Electoral Process</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Despite efforts from government development partners and civil society organisations to build the capacity of women candidates and to advocate with political parties and law-making institutions the number of women as elected parliamentarians dropped from 1
4% in 2006 to 11.4% in 2011; and the number of women elected as councillors remained unchanged at the low level of 6.1%. The voter turn-out in the 2011 elections also decreased to 54% from 71% in 2006 and 68% in 2001. Registered voters in Zambia are overwh
elmingly young with 54% aged between 18 to 35 and the previous elections showed a large proportion of first time voters (25% of registered voters). Still most young people especially young women lack knowledge about democratic and electoral processes and b
asic civic awareness to be able to meaningfully participate in political and decision-making processes. Against this context WiLDAF?s project aims to increase meaningful participation and representation of women and girls in electoral and democratic proces
s in six districts of Zambia. Specifically the proposed initiative seeks to achieve three interrelated results: 1) Increasing number of women as elected candidates in the 2016 local elections through mainstreaming gender into the existing legal and elector
al framework advocacy with political parties for formulation and adoption of gender-positive measures or quota system in the party capacity building of prospective women candidates and organisation of regional network forum for prospective women candidates
 and women?s party leagues for experience and information sharing; 2) Enhancing capacity of young women to actively and meaningfully participate in democratic and electoral process through establishment and support of well-functioning girls? clubs promotio
n of youth debates on democratic and electoral issues and increasing community awareness on key democratic concepts and electoral process; and3) Strengthening democratic process and practices at the local level through state and non-state dialogue mechanis
m to increase the focus on women?s issues and enhance the culture of constructive interaction between the two actors. The project?s direct beneficiaries are the prospective women candidates for the council election in 2016 and women from women?s leagues of
 key political parties young women and men aged 16 to 25 and community members including religious and traditional leaders parents and teachers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11000" ref="11000-1" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="28816558" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-20" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">14000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
