<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2017-2016161285</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Strengthening Community Conservation Resilience in Africa and the LDCs</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project supports indigenous peoples? organisations or other CSOs working with local communities in five countries (Democratic Republic of Congo, Ghana, Kenya, Nepal and Tanzania) in implementing a participatory assessment on the resilience of indigenou
s peoples? and local communities? biocultural approaches and biodiversity conservation as well as restoration initiatives. In addition, capacity-building events will be organised on the participatory assessment methodology developed by the CCRI. The Uganda
n NAPE will provide technical support to the actors implementing the assessments, and organise meetings for the new leaders of the communities, which have participated in the CCRI previously in order to support them in implementing the agreed recommendatio
ns. The preliminary findings of the at least 15 assessments to be implemented will be documented in five national reports. An advocacy campaign will be implemented during the UN Biodiversity convention?s Conference of the Parties in December 2016 in Mexico
 in order to disseminate the CCRI findings. The main findings of the assessments will also be disseminated within the involved communities and to the broader public through for instance social media, leaflets and radio programmes. The project aims at promo
ting more effective and appropriate forms of legal, political, technical, financial and other support that can address the most important internal and external threats to the resilience of community conservation. There is increasing scientific and politica
l acknowledgement of the significance of indigenous peoples? and local communities? conservation and restoration initiatives to the protection of biodiversity and climate change mitigation as well as resilience. The initiatives face, however, both external
 and internal threats, and there is lack of sufficient analysis on the support needed by the communities. Resilience assessments carried out by the communities enable presenting their own alternatives to strengthening the resilience. Project beneficiaries 
include indigenous peoples and local communities implementing collective biodiversity protection and restoration initiatives. During the project 100 community representatives trained on the participatory assessment methodology are expected to reach 7 500 p
eople in 15 communities, in which the assessments will be implemented. Gender equality and women?s participation will be paid particular attention to during the assessment processes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-769" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Siemenpuu-Kansalaisliikkeiden yhteistyosaatio sr</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="16003AFR" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="41030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">20000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
