<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-28604</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Universal II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Facilitating the development of the tourism industry in the Seychelles: Because of the similarities in geography and infrastructural limitations between the Maldives and the Seychelles, Universal was one of two Maldivian hospitality companies approached by the Seychelles Ministry of Tourism to help develop the Seychelles&apos; tourism industry, which was virtually non-existent before 2006. Despite having been present in the Seychelles for less than three years, Universal has contributed significantly to the local economy by providing employment opportunities, establishing a clinic and a school, by building required infrastructure (e.g. a jetty) and by providing free transport for the island&apos;s locals to Mah&#xE9;, the capital.

Environmental support: IFC&apos;s biodiversity and environmental specialists, together with external consultants, are working with Labriz to ensure that the resorts&apos; operations have minimal impact on the biodiversity of the island and the resort&apos;s surrounding environment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2003, in an attempt to replicate the success of the Maldives tourism industry, the Seychelles government invited Maldivian hospitality companies, including the sponsors of the Universal Enterprises Pvt Ltd (UEPL, or Universal), the Maniku family, to invest in the country (which faces similar geographical and infrastructural limitations). Consequently, the 111-room Labriz Silhouette Island Resort (Labriz, the Project) was developed and commenced operations in late 2006. Belonging to the collection of the 480 Small Luxury Hotels of the World, Labriz is positioned as an affordable luxury resort that blends elegant hospitality with the Seychelles tropical rainforest environment and is currently the largest five-star resort in the Seychelles. Labriz has 325 employees, 135 of which are local.

In 2005, IFC committed a $30 million A loan to three companies within the UEPL group of companies in the Maldives, under IFCs $150 million Tsunami Tourism Loan Facility. IFCs A loan was used to partially fund: (i) the reconstruction and refurbishment of two of Universals properties that were damaged during the tsunami; (ii) the refinancing of certain existing overdraft facilities for recently renovated properties in anticipation of the downturn in the tourism market as a result of the tsunami; and (iii) the development of one new property.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIVERSAL ENTERPRISES PRIVATE LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-28604" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-05-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-05-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Risvi A. Majeed
Chief Financial Officer
39 Orchid Maqu,
P.O. Box 2015
Mal&#xE9; 20-02, Republic of the Maldives.
Email: risvi.majeed@universalenterprises.com
Phone: +960 333 2211
Fax: +960 333 3618
Website: http://www.universalresorts.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SC" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Seychelles</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="SC-Seychelles">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Silhouette Island is the third largest granitic island of the Seychelles.  It lies approximately 20 kilometers northwest of Mah&#xE9; with a land area of approximately 20km2 and a maximum altitude of approximately 750 meters. Silhouette Island is surrounded by a National Marine Park declared in October 1987. The Marine Park extends around the entirety of the Island to a distance of one kilometer from the low water mark. In addition much of the Island is soon to be declared as a National Park; however, the resort itself is located outside the National Park.

The Resort is constructed on land that previously housed a 22-room hotel and land that was historically used for farming.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-4.5833302000 55.6666720000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AB - Resort Hotel (Including Lodges)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $20.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2010-05-28"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-05-28">20000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-05-28">20000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIVERSAL ENTERPRISES PRIVATE LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/28604/universal-ii">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
