<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-PSI13UG04</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impala Feeds</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Note: This project has been cancelled, due to cooperation problems and financial problems. The operation has been stopped.The project aims to improve poultry feed in Uganda by setting up a chicken feed manufacturing plant in Kampala. The mother company of the Ukrainian applicant is specialized in animal feed production. Since 2009 the applicant, FeedLance Ukraine, is responsible for the international activities which are concentrated in the Middle East and Moldova. The mother company, Agrovet Atlantik, is involved as a third party. For the applicant this joint venture is an opportunity to profit from the fast development of the poultry sector in Africa. The local partner, Hatches Ltd, is a hatchery with a capacity of at least 33,000 hatching eggs per week and considers this project as a major boost for the poultry sector. The chicken feed will be sold to small-scale poultry farmers.Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR)The project intends to implement a CSR in the entire value chain.All l project partners and their l business relations/stakeholders acknowledge the CSR standards that will include, amongst others: no child labour or forced labour, healthy and safe working conditions; Proper wages and benefits; no excessive working hours; promoting gender equality; freedom of association and environmental protection form part of the formalised CSR policy of the project.Impact&#x2022;	Employment and working conditionsThe salaries will be 20% above salaries for comparable positions.All recruited employees will be trained according to the training programme.The joint venture will co-finance health insurance for all employees ensuring regular access to medical examinations.The protective clothing will be provided for the production and storage employees if necessary, such as shoes / boots, overalls, jackets, etc.&#x2022;	Innovation / Transfer of knowledgeThe project has several innovative aspects:- This will be the first facility that will micronize soya in Uganda, and in Eastern Africa: Soya Micronization is short treatment of soya, which eliminates toxic trypsin activity while doubling. The energy value of the soya, which ultimately increases the live weight of broilers by 15%.- The joint venture will be the first feed producer to exclude fish in the feed formula in Uganda. Currently, 100% of the poultry feed in Uganda contains fishmeal. Being the only source of protein used in animal feed, this leads to high demand of the fish: Over 60% of the fish (Mukene) caught in Ugandan lakes is used for animal feed. The high demand, coupled with scarcity, has increased the price of fish considerably. The fish price ranges from 0.97 euro for the best grade to 0.57 euro for the low grade while the price for processed soya is about 0.47 euro per kilo. Replacing fish with micronized soya the pressure on the fish stocks can be reduced.- The joint venture will be the first feed producer to formerly partner with the Uganda National Bureau of standards(UNBS) and the Ugandan ministry of Agriculture Animal Industry and fisheries (MAAIF) to produce certified chicken feed under the HACCP.- The joint venture will be the first to have a formal back to back value chain linkage among poultry farmers involving poultry breed multipliers including incubation breed multipliers, commercial farmers, farmers, dressed chicken processors, poultry drug dealers and extension farmers training farmers in modern farming practices that will improve productivity and reduce post-harvest losses, The project/its partners will also establish a demonstration farm for this purpose.- The joint venture will be the first of its kind to include most players in the poultry chain: the seed multiplication companies for maize and soya, small-scale maize and soya farmers, the joint ventures customers of day old chicks and a dressed chicken processor who procures dressed chicken from small-scale commercial farmers for processing and eventual sale to the end user (Hotels, restaurants and supermarkets. All have signed MoUs or Letters of Intent for their involvement in the project.- The project will implement its quality principles in partnership with the Ugandan Bureau of Standards and the Ministry of Agriculture by way of a private public partnership (PPP).&#x2022;	Chain effectsImpact on local suppliersAt the end of the project a total of over 6,000 farmers will have been contracted to supply the joint venture with 11,800 tons maize and 6,200 tons of soya.The project will effort to promote female gender in the farmer value chain given that they form a bigger part of the smallholder farming communities in Uganda.Impact on local customers or consumersLocal customers will get the much needed higher quality feed in order to run small-scale poultry farms. Through the improved productivity they can increase profits. The MoU of the joint venture with a buyer of chicken intended for the supermarkets provides the farmers with a reliable market and a higher price thereby addressing another farmer problem of lack of good market for their chicken.&#x2022;	Impact on the sectorAs the first certified producer of chicken feed under the HACCP, the joint venture will act as an example for other feed producers in the country which will have a positive effect on the quality of the feed in the poultry sector.&#x2022;	EnvironmentA positive environmental impact is the use of soya instead of fish in the chicken feed. Currently, 100% of the poultry feed in Uganda contains fish (Mukene) from lake Victoria. Being the only source of animal protein used in animal feed, this creates pressure on the fish stocks excessive demand. Replacing fish with soya will reduce the pressure and promote a more sustainable avenue to manage lake resources in the country.&#x2022;	Position of womenAlmost half of the staff members in the joint venture will be women (eighteen of the forty) and almost a quarter will be medium- to high-level.Poultry farming is an attractive economic activity for women because of the relatively easy practice and light workload.Expectation is that in the second year of production (third year of the project) the number of supplying farms will be 4,200 of which more than half is headed by women. The numbers will increase to over 6,000 farmers by the end of the third year.&#x2022;	Impact on food safetyThe outgrowers are encouraged to cultivate on their remaining idle lands (most farmers do not have 100% under cultivation) to minimise the competition with human food. As part of the interventions, the project will encourage farmers who will be grain outgrowers to dedicate part of their land to food production so there will be an assurance of food for the farmer homesteads.&#x2022;	More informationUganda is a known regional food basket but its comparative advantage has for long been compromised by its inefficiency in production technology. The technological advancement of the project will leverage production efficiency with in the sectors of both grain, soya and livestock in particular poultry making the country become more competitive especially now that if forms part of the East African community with mostly food deficit member states with over 120 million people.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of the project is to improve poultry feed in Uganda by setting up a poultry feed manufacturing plant in Kampala with a capacity of 19,000 Mtons per year for small-scale poultry farmers on the local market.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="73">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agrovet Atlantik</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-60631503" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FeedLance B.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="73">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FeedLance Ukraine Ltd.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hatches Ltd.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-03" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="UG">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.373333 32.290275</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="31163" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-06-21"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-06-21">748500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-02"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-02">-72581</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-12-21">261975</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feedlance B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-03-04">37425</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feedlance B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-06-03">37425</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feedlance B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-09-05">37425</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feedlance B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-05">99800</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feedlance B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-06">49900</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feedlance B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-04-11">49900</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feedlance B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-04-14">-49900</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feedlance B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-04-19">49900</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feedlance B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-09-05">49900</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feedlance B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-04">49900</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feedlance B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-03">2269</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feedlance B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-06-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-06-21">748500</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-02">-72581</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-06-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-06-21">748500</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-02">-72581</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-23408" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable trade and investment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated PSD results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of full-time (equivalent) direct jobs supported - female</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable trade and investment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated PSD results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of full-time (equivalent) direct jobs supported - male</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable trade and investment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated PSD results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of full-time (equivalent) direct jobs supported - total</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable trade and investment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated PSD results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of full-time (equivalent) indirect jobs supported - total</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained or skills developed - Outgrowers</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-03"></period-end>
     <target value="1,425.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1,200.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained or skills developed - Total</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-03"></period-end>
     <target value="1,465.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1,219.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of indirect jobs supported - Total</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-03"></period-end>
     <target value="3,525.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1,500.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of companies with a supported plan to invest, trade or provide services - Dutch companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-03"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of companies with a supported plan to invest, trade or provide services - Local companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-03"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained or skills developed - Low-level employees</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-03"></period-end>
     <target value="20.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="10.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of direct jobs supported in individually supported SME by PSD programmes - Male</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-03"></period-end>
     <target value="22.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="10.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of direct jobs supported in individually supported SME by PSD programmes - Total</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-03"></period-end>
     <target value="40.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="19.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of companies with a supported plan to invest, trade or provide services - Other companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="2.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="2.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="2.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="2.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="2.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="2.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="2.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-03"></period-end>
     <target value="2.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="2.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of companies with a supported plan to invest, trade or provide services - Total</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-03"></period-end>
     <target value="4.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="4.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amount of co-investment generated by ODA in EUR - By private sector/companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-03"></period-end>
     <target value="748,500.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="675,919.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amount of co-investment generated by ODA in EUR - Total</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-03"></period-end>
     <target value="748,500.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="675,919.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of direct jobs supported in individually supported SME by PSD programmes - Female</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-03"></period-end>
     <target value="18.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="9.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained or skills developed - Medium/high level employees</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-03"></period-end>
     <target value="20.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="9.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
