<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-PCB22VN02A</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Building Programe for Enterprises to Accelerate CE Transition in Viet Nam</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands embassy in Vietnam -together with the Norwegian Embassy and the Finnish Embassy- supported UNDP project for the Vietnamese Ministry of Natural Resources and Environment (MONRE) on the development of &quot;Viet Nam Circular Economy Hub&quot; (CE Hub). The CE Hub aims to raise awareness and build the capacity of all stakeholders (public authorities, businesses, civil society, academia) to systematically adopt the Circular Economy principles, and create synergies and integrate financial and technical resources for supporting the transition towards a low-carbon and circular in Viet Nam.In Viet Nam, Small and Medium Enterprises account for 96% of the total number of companies, employing 47% of labor and contributing 36% for the national value added. The business sector plays a key role in accelerating the transition, application and operation of circular business models, low-carbon technologies, and clean technologies. With outstanding technical supports from experts of Saxion University of Applied Sciences (Saxion UAS) in the Netherlands and financial supports from the Dutch Embassy, the CE Hub has designed a capacity building program for enterprises in Viet Nam, to deliver knowledge on what Circular Economy can be meaning for them, share Circular Economy best practices, connect with the network of experts, and strengthen capacity of this target group. The Circular Economy transition within an enterprise requires both changing in awareness and behavior of shifting production and business activities towards green and sustainable, beside the environmental and economic benefits.This project will aim to:-	Deliver knowledge on circular economy, current policy from the government on circular economy development, and relating European-Vietnam Free Trade Agreement (EVFTA) requirements for trading goods.-	Share potential circular economy models and benefits, bring international best practices on CE to be applied in Viet Nam, to create motivations for business communities in circular economy transitions.-	Strengthen capacity for businesses in development of their own circular business models, monitoring and evaluation of the effectiveness the transition.-	Connect businesses within value chains to promote the exchange of resources and establish (new) partnerships.The CE training documents, communication materials, and articles on the CE trainings will be published on the CE Hub website.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands embassy in Hanoi, Vietnam</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="VN">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>21.0294498 105.8544441</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="12" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="14050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-06-03"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-06-03"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-03">72648</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-03">72648</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-03">72648</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-26067_3" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
