<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-PVW522CO02</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development of the &#x2018;Setting the Scene&#x2019;-docment for Water as Leverage Cartagena</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water as Leverage (WaL) is an initiative of the Government of the Netherlands and an the programme in Asia consisted of an active and committed group of international partners. It is built on the recognition that a result-driven, holistic and inclusive project preparation approach is the only way to kick-start and create scalable sustainable urban solutions, which are supported by decision makers locally and nationally, have long-term and sustainable impact, and are bankable. The widespread underfunding of early project development activities results in a growing difficulty to fill the project implementation pipeline of national and international financiers. While climate financing availability for project implementation is on the rise, the investments in the early phases of project identification and development are still widely lacking. As part of the bilateral collaboration between Colombia and the Netherlands on the topics of water, climate and resilience, it is the ambition to start a Water as Leverage inspired trajectory in the city of Cartagena, together with a group of local, national and international partners. Water as Leverage Cartagena aims to invest &#x2018;the millions&#x2019; in this early project development phase to unlock the &#x2018;billions&#x2019; of implementation finance. The first analysis on water-, infrastructure- and other related policies, projects and priorities is the basis for generating the Setting the Scene document and shared knowledge repository. Based on priorities, potential partnerships and pressing problems, a city-wide analysis will be executed by a group of national and international experts. This Setting the Scene narrows the focus of the Water as Leverage pre-project preparation process by providing a focus on three pillars:a)	Technical challenges: what are the pressing issues and challenges in Cartagena, in need of a technical solution?b)	Governance arrangements: what are the local/national policies and priorities that steer, stimulate or limit the options for projects to be developed in the context of Cartagena? What are the key stakeholders and their roles as part of any project preparation and implementation cycle?c)	Financing arrangements: what are local, national and international funding options for infrastructural projects in Cartagena and what are the general requirements and limitations to take into account as part of the (pre-)project preparation phase? This assignment is financed through the Partners for Water Program, executed by the Netherlands Enterprise Agency (RVO), part of the Netherlands Ministry of Economic Affairs and Climate. The Partners for Water Program is commissioned by the Ministry of Infrastructure and Water Management on behalf of the Interdepartmental Water Cluster.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-55525474" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Koninklijke HaskoningDHV Groep B.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="CO">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.4195841 -75.5271224</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="34" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14020" percentage="33" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="17" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="43060" percentage="33" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-13"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-05-13"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-13">94962</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-14">14244.3</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Koninklijke HaskoningDHV Groep B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-13">94962</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-13">94962</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-119607" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
