<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-PVW4S19023</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advanced beach monitoring and management: Feasibility Study Bacton Sand Engine, United Kingdom</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022;	Short general project overviewThis application is for a pilot project for the feasibility study of innovative monitoring techniques (developed on the Sand Motor) and management (by means of a Digital Twin, near-time integration of a 3D model with simulation and monitoring data) of sandy coasts with a critical role in coastal safety, to be carried out on the Bacton Sand Engine in the United Kingdom, which will be installed in the Summer of 2019.Beach erosion threatens critical infrastructure, homes and the recreational value of beaches, and can lead to flood risk. This is the case in Bacton, but also elsewhere in England, and worldwide. In the past, hard coastal defences were often used, but it is now clear that a soft solution (through beach replenishment) is more sustainable and economically advantageous in many locations. An additional advantage (certainly in England) is its adaptive nature: a sand motor-like solution &quot;buys time&quot; so that society can adapt to the inevitable erosion.Adaptive beach management is essential in that context. Beach Management Plans are used for this. This contains the management goals (safety but also recreation, nature, shared use); this is linked to &apos;triggers&apos; for intervention, supported by a monitoring program and associated analysis to support intervention decisions.North Norfolk District Council (NNDC) is working in partnership with the Bacton Terminal Companies (BTC, including Shell and Perenco) towards the implementation of the Bacton Sand Engine, scheduled for March till October 2019. This is the first outdoor application of the sand engine concept the Netherlands. They have developed a management plan with a basic package of monitoring techniques and associated analysis. They also like to offer room for more innovative methods and will consider adopting them if they prove successful (better decisions and / or lower costs).This application concerns the implementation of a &apos;plus package&apos; for both monitoring (by application of techniques developed and applied to the Dutch Sand Motor) and for analysis and information management (through the development of a Digital Twin of the Sand Engine that translates monitoring data &apos;near real-time&apos; into a 3D model, and on that basis runs a simulation model that predicts future developments, in support of management and investment decisions.&#x2022;	What makes the technology, product, method or approach used innovativeThe activities concern:- Actual implementation of advanced monitoring and processing of the results, in six cycles over the subsidy duration of two years;- Development and implementation of a Digital Twin of the Sand Engine;- Support for the end user in the application of the Digital Twin;The intended results are twofold:- For the Bacton project: better information to support decision making (about how much time there is to replenish again). This means there is less chance that people will wait too long (risk of major damage and casualties) or invest too early (unnecessarily high costs). In addition, operational decisions, regarding recreation, fishing, nature, and communication towards the public and stakeholders;- For the techniques: evaluation of the applicability and added value of the monitoring techniques and the Digital Twin concept for coastal management.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-56515154" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HaskoningDHV Nederland B.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-63003112" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shore Monitoring &amp; Research B.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-16" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="GB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="GB">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>52.835652 1.12765977</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-05-27"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-27">104304</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-28">46937</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Haskoningdhv Nederland B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-02">15646</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Haskoningdhv Nederland B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-02">15646</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Haskoningdhv Nederland B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-05">15646</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Haskoningdhv Nederland B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-16">10429</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Haskoningdhv Nederland B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-27">104304</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-27">104304</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-26067_1" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
