<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-PSI12ET05</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">High quality tomato seeds for international market</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Note: This project has been cancelled, because the applicant has not been able to acquire proper land, in combination with the social unrest in the country.Set up a 4 ha production company of high quality hybrid determinate tomato seeds for export, with a maximum production of 1,750 kg of high quality seeds per year and a first production of 400 kg per year of lower quality seeds from two outgrowers. Vegetable seed production is very labour intensive. Most production of tomato seeds takes place in China. The climate in the specific growing region allows only one growing cycle per year. Therefore, most of the leading vegetable breeders have moved their focus towards East Africa, in particular Kenya. Ethiopia possesses good growing opportunities for vegetable seeds. The climate around Ziway is very suitable to produce year round high quality tomato seeds. Currently, there are no producers of high quality hybrid tomato seeds for export purposes. Ammerlaan Roses B.V. and their local production company AQ Roses PLC were asked by Syngenta Seeds B.V. to start a production location of their hybrid determinate tomato seeds in the region of Ziway. A 4 ha production farm will be started to produce the seeds on an environmentally friendly way. Rain water will be collected, stored and disinfected for drip irrigation purposes of the tomato plants growing on substrate system. The latter allows re-using the drain water. The affluent water will be filtered through wetlands. In addition to the main production location, ten farmers will be trained as outgrowers on lower quality tomato seeds production. In the years after the project it is the intention that hundreds of outgrowers will start the production of hybrid tomato seeds. AQ Roses PLC is well known for its high social standards in Ethiopia, including Ethical Trade Initiative, certified by the NGO Africa Now.Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR)The partners will apply the same, well developed, CSR policy of AQ Roses PLC also for AQ Seeds Plc. In addition, the company will produce according to GSPP standards (Good Seed and Plant Practices) and will be certified according to the Ethiopian Code of Practice. Besides, Syngenta requires their suppliers to adhere to the ILO Principles and the Human Rights declaration of the UN.Impact&#x2022;	Employment and working conditionsThe company will have good and safe working conditions and fringe benefits. Besides a minimum salary which is at least 50% higher than the minimum salary in Ethiopia, the company will provide transport allowance, presence bonus, access to clinic and hospital, coverage of all medical cost, working and protective clothing, permanent contracts only and subsidised lunch. It will provide trainings on health and safety, HIV/AIDS, hygiene, family planning and in all work related issues. The staff is encouraged to participate in further education. A health and safety committee will be set up, as well as a gender committee and a workers council. Drafting a collective bargaining agreement with the assistance of the union is part of the work of the workers council. Discrimination is not tolerated between different ethnic groups, gender, age, disabilities, politics or religions. Sexual harassment will result in dismissal. A gender policy is in place, including all kind of arrangements for pregnant women or recent mothers.&#x2022;	Innovation / Transfer of knowledgeIt will be the first company in Ethiopia producing hybrid tomato seeds.&#x2022;	Chain effectsLocal suppliers include suppliers of fertilisers, crop protection materials, maintenance of irrigation systems, carton boxes and working clothes. However, the main suppliers will be the outgrowers producing lower quality hybrid seeds at their farms. At least 10 outgrowers and their 20 employees will be trained during the last year of the project and they expect that 1 or 2 of them will be able to supply in total 400 kg of seeds to them. The outgrowers will have a fixed contract, where one failed harvest does not automatically mean no income. Costs will be covered at any time in cooperation with Syngenta. It is expected that the number of outgrowers will grow rapidly after the PSI phase, in order to have a home farm with hundreds of hectares of outgrowers&apos; production.Not relevant, as the seeds are for export purposes. Also, the lower quality seeds will first be tested, treated and coated by Syngenta in the Netherlands before being exported to countries like Ethiopia. It has been agreed however, between Syngenta and the Ethiopian Government, that trials will be started to allow Syngenta seeds to be sold in Ethiopia.&#x2022;	Impact on the sectorInternational vegetable seed companies are still reluctant to invest in Ethiopia, because of the unstable investment and business climate. Once the project is successful, other breeders will follow Syngenta. This creates many opportunities for suppliers but especially for outgrowers. This project will set the first example how to implement such a company in a sustainable way, taking proper care of environment and social impact. It will be the first company implementing the strict GSPP standards (Good Seed and Plant Practices) in Ethiopia. The company will work together with the EHPEA on the implementation of the Code of Practice, which will be the first vegetable seed production company being CoP certified. It will also organise the phytosanitary control with the relevant ministry in Ethiopia, as such strengthening their capacity to deal with others. The company will offer internships for students of relevant Universities and try to seek cooperation with the Agricultural University on curricula development.&#x2022;	EnvironmentThe project will try to minimise the use of ground water by harvesting and storing rain water, using drip irrigation and growing on substrate. The effluent water will be cleaned and used for outside small scale vegetable production. The plant waste will be composted and used as well. The hygiene requirements of Syngenta are very strict, with zero tolerance on pests. Therefore, the employees will have to work under very strict hygienic conditions, making it less likely that an outbreak will occur. The project will be certified both under GSPP and Code of Practice. An EIA will be conducted prior to the project.&#x2022;	Position of womenThe project will generate employment for 100 women (out of 147 employees), of which 10 management positions (out of 15). A gender committee will be started, with a person taking care of day-to-day confidential issues including sexual harassment. The gender policy also describes the policy for pregnant women and recent mothers. AQ Roses PLC noted that the amount of young women getting married and having babies has decreased enormously since the start of job opportunities in Ziway. They also noted that the number of children per women has decreased and that fewer incidents with domestic violence occur. They expect similar impact on the new project location.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Set up a 4 ha production company of high quality hybrid determinate tomato seeds for export, with a maximum production of 1,750 kg of high quality seeds per year and a first production of 400 kg per year of lower quality seeds from two outgrowers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AQ Roses PLC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-34235744" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ammerlaan Roses B.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="5"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-03" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.9507716 38.6921203</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="32161" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-06-21"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-06-21">749925</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-10-17"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-10-17">-749925</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-06-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-06-21">749925</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-10-17">-749925</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-06-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-06-21">749925</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-10-17">-749925</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.rosaplaza.nl/uk">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Website Rosa Plaza</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-23408" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable trade and investment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated PSD results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of full-time (equivalent) direct jobs supported - female</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable trade and investment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated PSD results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of full-time (equivalent) direct jobs supported - male</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable trade and investment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated PSD results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of full-time (equivalent) direct jobs supported - total</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable trade and investment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated PSD results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of full-time (equivalent) indirect jobs supported - total</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of companies with a supported plan to invest, trade or provide services - Other companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-03"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of companies with a supported plan to invest, trade or provide services - Local companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-03"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained or skills developed - Outgrowers</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-03"></period-end>
     <target value="10.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of direct jobs supported in individually supported SME by PSD programmes - Female</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-03"></period-end>
     <target value="100.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained or skills developed - Low-level employees</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-03"></period-end>
     <target value="132.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of direct jobs supported in individually supported SME by PSD programmes - Total</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-03"></period-end>
     <target value="147.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained or skills developed - Total</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-03"></period-end>
     <target value="177.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of companies with a supported plan to invest, trade or provide services - Total</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-03"></period-end>
     <target value="2.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained or skills developed - Medium/high level employees</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-03"></period-end>
     <target value="35.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of direct jobs supported in individually supported SME by PSD programmes - Male</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-03"></period-end>
     <target value="47.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of indirect jobs supported - Total</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-03"></period-end>
     <target value="7.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amount of co-investment generated by ODA in EUR - By private sector/companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-03"></period-end>
     <target value="749,925.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amount of co-investment generated by ODA in EUR - Total</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-03"></period-end>
     <target value="749,925.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of companies with a supported plan to invest, trade or provide services - Dutch companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-03"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
