<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-DHIF21H089</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Opportunities for setting up an Electric Vehicle Charging Ecosystem in Uganda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NTCS is a telecommunications, energy and electric mobility engineering firm that is active worldwide, but with a focus on the Caribbean/South America and recently also on Africa. They help their customers (international telecom operators and energy companies) through all phases of their projects by means of research, engineering, delivery and construction, training and support during the start-up and operational phase.The Ugandan state-owned Kiira Motors Corporation (KMC) designs and manufactures diesel and electric motor vehicles. KMC has been mandated by the Ugandan government to set up Electric Vehicle (EV) charging ecosystems in Uganda to meet the growing demand for electric and zero-emission vehicles. Several years ago, KMC set up the first EV pilot bus shuttle service between Kampala and the airport in Entebbe. However, the pilot project is not running as desired. They now want to upgrade this project to a well-functioning charging ecosystem with the ultimate goal of further rolling out this system in Uganda. This project is therefore not only about the design of a well-functioning charging system, but also about the development of a (national) strategy for an accessible charging infrastructure for electric vehicles.KMC wants to invest in a reliable and sustainable EV charging business model that is scalable and replicable, but first they want to be convinced that this investment is (in the longer term) profitable and operationally feasible. NTCS has been asked to conduct a feasibility study. NTCS wants to use their expertise together with the Dutch companies Qurato (knowledge supplier) and Heliox (supplier charging stations) to be able to develop a customer-specific technical and commercial solution for KMC.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="UG">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.373333 32.290276</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="12" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="23642" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-02-18"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-02-18">98733</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-02-18">98733</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-02-18">98733</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-28385" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
