<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-PVW4A21001</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spatial Development Plan Truong Giang region, Quang Nam Province, Vietnam</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Truong Giang runs north-south from Cua Dai river mouth to Cua Lo river mouth connecting the downstream of Vu Gia - Thu Bon rivers in the north and Tam Ky - An Tan rivers system in the south. The river is about 67 km length, it is one of the main flows to drain the water during the flood season and waterway route in the region&apos;s inland waterway transport network. However, with the characteristics of the central estuaries, under the influences of mud, sea sand and aquaculture activities, the riverbed is filled by sedimentations. This has contributed to narrowing the rivers floodplain and significantly reducing the flood drainage capacity as well as the water transport capacity.Along the Truong Giang River, there are many important points where erosion often occurs, such as curved river sections, or weak soil of the riverbanks. This narrow river is adjacent to densely populated areas that require additional protection from landslides in the rainy season, along with river and coastal flood protection. The Truong Giang borders Hoi An to the north and has significant economic potential, including tourism development.  However, given the sensitive nature of the natural environment, as described above, development must be managed carefully to avoid locking in new risk and to enable resilient and productive development.  The PPC is seeking guidance on how best to manage the development. To support Quang Nam province, the World Bank and the Dutch Government are looking for a qualified international consultancy firm to:I.	To develop a Spatial Development Plan including initial Project Identification and potential Implementation Pathways for the area south of Hoi An between Truong Giang river and the sea that:-	Builds on existing knowledge and research, connected to governmental and private ambitions for the region;-	Recognizes the risks, needs, opportunities and challenges of the region;-	Identifies and minimizes conflicts between industries and localities in the exploitation and use of natural resources, serving the parallel needs of socio-economic development, environmental protection (and or restoration)-	According to an inclusive, integrated and innovative and design driven approach.II.	To develop, strengthen and advocate for innovative, integral and/or nature-based solutions for riverbank protection in a Basic Design for the Truong Giang river, connected to the Feasibility Phase of the World Bank financed Integrated Resilient Development Project (IRDP) in Quang Nam and integral part of the Spatial Development Plan Focus will be on generating basic design(s), calculations, modelling, visualisations, etc. which build on the advice, alternative approaches and technical solutions for riverbank protection of Truong Giang river, presented by the previous Dutch/Vietnamese team that was involved during the pre-feasibility phase of the IRDP.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-09036504" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arcadis Nederland B.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-22" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="VN">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.9537073 108.4306103</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="14015" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="17" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="41050" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-06-15"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-15">399999</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-12-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-20"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-20">-356599.89</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-06">39960.07</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arcadis Nederland B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-22">3439.04</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arcadis Nederland B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-15">399999</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-20">-356599.89</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-15">399999</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-20">-356599.89</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-26067_1" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
