<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-PVW4S18048</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Low Energy ZLD Technology by FO-HBRO for Textile Industry (ZeroTex)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022;	Short general project overviewMotivation of using FO-HBROTM technology towards zero-liquid discharge.The current regulations in India require that industrial waste water treatment (textile, tanneries, pharma, etc) is carried out following the Zero Liquid Discharge (ZLD) concept, which implies that wastewater is completely separated into clean water, which can be reused in the production facility, and solids which can be disposed or reused in the same or other processes. Current ZLD approaches use state-of-the art multi-effect evaporation and crystallisation units, which are energy intensive techniques typically using 30 to 120 kWh/m3.Forward osmosis (FO) coupled with high brine reverse osmosis (HBROTM) is an innovative technology developed by BLUE-tec which has the potential to compete with evaporators in wastewater treatment aimed at zero-liquid discharge. In forward osmosis, the wastewater and a high concentration salt solution are brought into contact with a semipermeable membrane. Due to differences in osmotic pressure, clean water naturally passes through the membrane from the wastewater stream towards the salt solution, resulting in a concentration of the waste water. Unlike evaporation, which is a very energy intensive process, forward osmosis takes place without any phase change. The draw solution concentration is recovered through the HBROTM technology, which uses specific high pressure membranes resulting in both a high concentrated draw solution and clean water. FO-HBROTM has a significantly lower energy consumption compared to conventional evaporators bringing it down to 15 kWh/m3.The goal of the project is to have an FO-HBROTM pilot operated in India, which will treat UF/RO concentrate from the existing ZLD unit of Soft Tex Processing Mills in India. A volumetric concentration factor of 2 to 3 and an average FO flux of 5 to 7 L/m2/h are expected in continuous operation. Operational parameters and optimal cleaning procedures will be investigated. Batch tests will be made to determine the maximum concentration factor achievable. This will prove the potential of FO-HBRO&#x2122; towards ZLD in wastewater treatment in Indian industry.&#x2022;	Initial activities and results of the projectThe project duration is 2 years and it consists of a preparation phase, a testing phase and a dissemination phase. In the preparation phase a pilot is designed and constructed and, in the testing phase the pilot will be operated. The dissemination phase deals with ensuring the commercial success of the technology by interacting with customers, publishing results and drafting a business plan. The design will be done on the BLUE-tec site in the Netherlands, while the construction and operation will be done in India. The dissemination of the project outcome will take place in India as well as in Europe. The activities from the preparation phase are related to developing the test program including the necessary analytical plan, preparing the engineering package, process automation, documentation, drawings, purchase of materials, construction and factory acceptance test. The activities from the second phase include a site acceptance test, pilot operation, data evaluation and scale-up engineering calculations. Business related research, market strategy development, pilot visits, and publication of the results are activities included in the dissemination phase and will be performed by BLUE-tec, Nuvas and KWR.A 24 m3/day FO-HBROTM pilot for waste water treatment towards zero liquid discharge in textile industry will be constructed and operated in the project. The results of the operation will give more insight in the reverse salt flux, average flux, energy consumption, fouling potential and concentration factor for the pilot operation and will allow the construction of a full-scale unit. The results will form new insights for the application of the FO-HBROTM technology in general and specifically in textile industry applications and will influence the business strategies of BLUE-tec and Nuvas.&#x2022;	What makes the technology, product, method or approach used innovativeThe technology is innovative and innovative. It has already been tested in Spain as part of an EU project, this is not explained further. Apparently, HBRO is a trademark, what this means and with whom the rights lie is not explained further.FO is a new technology that is being further developed by Blue Tec. KWR has been working on this for a long time, but of course it does not bring systems to the market. For further scaling up, Blue Tec is also working on a few water boards in the Netherlands (https://www.blue-tec.nl/news/2018/7/31/waterschappen-en-tki-watertechnologie-sluiten-aan-bij-core-water and of course the pilot in Spain).Commercially, it&apos;s all still in its infancy and this Partners for Water project can contribute to further market introduction. Worldwide, only a few parties are working on FO so it is a great opportunity for Bluetec to get this technology on the market. In terms of innovative technology, this is very special.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-58758526" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Blue-Tec B.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27279653" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KWR Water B.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuvas</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-22" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="IN">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>28.6138954 77.2090057</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14015" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-12-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-10">252444</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-06-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-22">-86</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-11">113616</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Blue-Tec B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-18">14198</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Blue-Tec B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-02">14198</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Blue-Tec B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-31">14198</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Blue-Tec B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-02">14198</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Blue-Tec B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-08">14198</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Blue-Tec B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-04-03">14198</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Blue-Tec B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-07-02">14198</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Blue-Tec B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-10-02">14198</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Blue-Tec B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-22">25158</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Blue-Tec B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-10">252444</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-22">-86</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-10">252444</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-22">-86</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-26067_1" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
