<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-PSI12BO22</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Production of feed-grade copper sulphate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Procesadora Elvira is a Bolivian manufacturer of sulphuric acid and copper sulphate for the local mining industry. Together with their partner Chilean Copper Ltda, Procesadora Elvira identified a good market opportunity for high quality feed-grade copper sulphate in the USA and Canada. The joint venture company will produce feed-grade copper sulphate as feed additive, by using its surplus sulphuric acid and recycling locally collected copper scrap and abandoned ore with low copper content.A pilot plant with up-to-date, environmentally sound technology will be set up in Oruro. The project will present a solution for the current bad practice of burning plasticised copper wire by the scrap collectors. The joint venture will sign long-term supply contracts with the scrap dealers, under the condition that the copper wire will be supplied including the plastic. The company will separate the plastic from the copper through an environmentally friendly mechanical process, after which the plastic will be sold for recycling purposes. Further, it will train the collectors and the small-scale mining companies on prevention of child and forced labour and on environmental care. The company will be certified according to ISO 9001, ISO 14001 and OHSAS 18001.Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR)The joint venture will develop its own CSR policy, it will be certified according to ISO 9001 (quality management), ISO 14001 (environmental management) and OHSAS 18001 (Occupational Health and Safety management system). The quality of the animal feed product will be constantly monitored by the company&apos;s laboratory. An environmental impact assessment will be conducted and the plant is designed according to the latest environmentally friendly technology, including internal recycling and emission control measures.The project concept is based on a clear notion of chain responsibility, by changing the current practice in Bolivia of burning plasticised copper wires in an industrially managed process of separation of plastic and copper. These scrap collectors will be trained also on CSR issues and will deliver according to long term supply contracts. Also, the second mode of copper sourcing is an example of it, as low concentration copper ore as a waste product will be used to obtain the copper. For that purpose the new company will cooperate with the National Federation of Mining Cooperatives, and make long term supply contracts with the Federation members, including requirements and trainings on prevention of child and forced labour and other CSR issues.The waste products of the production process from low-concentration copper ore will be separated in an mineral fraction, which may be used locally as foundation in road construction and a metal fraction (not containing heavy metals), which will be temporary stored at the joint venture premises until an authorised permanent disposal solution is assigned by the local authorities.The employees will be offered good employment standards, with high salaries in order to maintain the trained persons satisfied within the company. All staff should at least be graduates of medium-level education as working with chemicals requires a good understanding of and strictly adhering to set working protocols and health and safety standards.Impact&#x2022;	Employment and working conditionsThe employees will be offered good employment standards, with high salaries in order to maintain the trained persons satisfied within the company. Salaries are ranging between 250 euro (220% of the official minimum wage in Bolivia of Bs 1,000) and 1,667 euro. Fringe benefits include all legally prescribed benefits including social security, paid holidays, overtime payments, annual premium of 1.5 monthly salary, pension fund, insurance against occupational accidents, illnesses, incapacity and death, unemployment indemnity, right to associate with trade union. All staff will be intensively trained in technical issues and in issues related to environmental care, occupational health and safety.&#x2022;	Innovation / Transfer of knowledgeAs there are no other producers of copper sulphate in Bolivia, a lot of knowledge needs to be transferred. The joint venture will directly set the benchmark at a high level by implementing an ISO 9001, ISO 14001 and OHSAS 18001 certified process. It will change the existing copper scrap sourcing process by demanding the scrap collectors to supply them the copper scrap including the plastic. As such, the project will positively influence the working and health conditions of the scrap collectors, who currently burn the plastic copper wires to obtain the copper. Internationally the process is also innovative as both copper scrap and low concentration copper ore is used as raw material. It creates hereby a market for the low concentration copper ore, which currently is a waste product. Another innovative element, which will be promoted, is the use of the mineral residue of the ore as road foundation material.&#x2022;	Chain effectsThe project will source 7,000 tons of low-concentration copper ore per year from 15 artisanal mining companies. Currently, this is a waste product of the mine and has no value for the miners. The transport in small wheel barrows to a place where the truck can come will generate employment for 100 people. These small mines normally employ not more than 4 to 5 people. They will be trained in CSR related subjects. Procesadora &quot;Elvira&quot; will also extend their current network of scrap collection centres and provide pre-finance capital to these centres to enable them to buy from the small-scale scrap collectors. The employees of the collection centres will be trained on CSR subjects as prevention of child labour.Further, the supplier of the sulphuric acid will benefit from this project, which in this case is the local partner Procesadora &quot;Elvira&quot;.The joint venture will promote the use of part of their feed-grade copper sulphate to potential local clients, i.e. animal feed factories. The use of balanced feed will result in healthier and more productive animals in Bolivia. Further, the mineral part of the ore can be used for road construction, providing an alternative to the use of sand or gravel.&#x2022;	Impact on the sectorThe joint venture will continue the current cooperation between Procesadora &quot;Elvira&quot; and the Technical University of Oruro to provide possibilities for internships and research opportunities for students. It cooperates with the National Federation of Mining Cooperatives on selection of potential suppliers of copper ore, as well as on the training of key staff from the supplying mining companies.&#x2022;	EnvironmentCurrently, the plasticised copper wire scrap is burned at the level of small-scale copper collectors, causing the formation of dioxins. This not only represents a big environmental problem, but also a direct health hazard of the people burning the plastic. The joint venture company will train the collection centres and part of the collectors and make them aware of the detrimental environmental and health aspects of this practice and stimulate them economically to only sell them the plasticised wire. The company will use a mechanical process to separate the plastic and the copper.The joint venture will be certified according to ISO 14001 (environmental management). An environmental impact assessment will be conducted and the plant is designed according to the latest environmentally friendly technology, including internal recycling and emission control measures. The waste products of the production process from low-concentration copper ore will be separated in a mineral fraction, which may be used locally as foundation in road construction, and a metal fraction (not containing heavy metals), which will be temporary stored at the joint venture premises until an authorised permanent disposal solution is assigned by the local authorities.&#x2022;	Position of womenFour out of 6 managers will be women, which is rather high in a male dominated sector.&#x2022;	Impact on food safetyOnly indirectly it could have a positive impact on food stability, as the feed-grade copper sulphate has a beneficial effect on the productivity and health situation of the animals.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To establish a production plant for feed-grade copper sulphate, recycling copper scrap and ore with low copper content.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="73">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chilean Copper LTDA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Procesadora &quot;Elvira&quot; (PROCEL)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="BO">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-17.966667 -67.116667</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="32264" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-12-21">595465</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chilean Copper LTDA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-29">-12000</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chilean Copper LTDA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-09-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-09-18">208414</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Procesadora &quot;Elvira&quot; (PROCEL)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-12-16">29773</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Procesadora &quot;Elvira&quot; (PROCEL)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-03-10">29773</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Procesadora &quot;Elvira&quot; (PROCEL)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-06-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-06-09">29773</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Procesadora &quot;Elvira&quot; (PROCEL)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-09-09">79395</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Procesadora &quot;Elvira&quot; (PROCEL)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-12-09">79395</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Procesadora &quot;Elvira&quot; (PROCEL)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-03-10">79395</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Procesadora &quot;Elvira&quot; (PROCEL)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-30">47547</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Procesadora &quot;Elvira&quot; (PROCEL)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-12-21">595465</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-29">-12000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-23408" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable trade and investment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated PSD results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of full-time (equivalent) direct jobs supported - female</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable trade and investment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated PSD results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of full-time (equivalent) direct jobs supported - male</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable trade and investment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated PSD results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of full-time (equivalent) direct jobs supported - total</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable trade and investment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated PSD results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of full-time (equivalent) indirect jobs supported - total</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of companies with a supported plan to invest, trade or provide services - Dutch companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained or skills developed - Outgrowers</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of companies with a supported plan to invest, trade or provide services - Local companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of companies with a supported plan to invest, trade or provide services - Other companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of indirect jobs supported - Total</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="34.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="20.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of direct jobs supported in individually supported SME by PSD programmes - Female</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="3.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of direct jobs supported in individually supported SME by PSD programmes - Male</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="30.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="35.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained or skills developed - Medium/high level employees</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="34.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="40.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amount of co-investment generated by ODA in EUR - By private sector/companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="595,465.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="583,465.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained or skills developed - Low-level employees</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="40.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="8.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
