<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-PVW4S16055</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feasibility of sustainable ocean thermal energy for the urban delta Barranquilla Colombia (OTEC Barranquilla)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022;	Short general project overviewThe goal of this project is to make the first step towards providing a new and reliable source of renewable power for urban delta Barranquilla, Colombia, which later can be exported to other urban deltas / coastal regions in the wider Caribbean and other tropical regions.This subsidy is needed in order to perform a feasibility study that will de-risk the project and convince the market of the feasibility of Ocean Thermal Energy Conversion (OTEC) for Barranquilla, Colombia. It will provide the necessary funding to bridge the gap from concept phase to engineering phase, in which the market has indicated to be willing to make available resources.First, this feasibility study is needed to identify the local environmental factors and stakeholders, to carry out local on-site measurements, and to carry out an assessment of the commercial viability of the project. It will help to remove uncertainties and pave the way for the start of a project in collaboration with local partners.Last, the outcomes of this project will form the basis to assess the feasibility for the other urban deltas along the Caribbean coast of Colombia as well, namely Santa Marta and Cartagena.The aim of the collaboration is to complete the feasibility phase of the development of an industrial-grade, baseload operational OTEC demonstration plant in the urban delta Barranquilla, Colombia. This OTEC plant has the potential to become the first in the world, positioning both Colombia and the Netherlands as centres of know-how for OTEC with export opportunities to many urban deltas and coastal regions in the Caribbean region and in other tropical regions.The Colombian-Dutch collaboration brings together Colombia&#x2019;s vast ocean thermal energy resource, local ship building facilities (shipyard Cotecmar), its urgent interest in new and reliable renewable energy and the Dutch renowned expertise in offshore and water technologies. The combination of these elements provides the necessary momentum, experience and commitment to complete this feasibility project, and if the outcome is positive, continue with the actual project development of an industrial-grade OTEC demonstration plant. The collaboration will help to de-risk the project and stimulate knowledge transfer on OTEC technologies, construction and operation methodologies, and environmental impact. &#x2022;	Goal of the projectThe project&#x2019;s aim is to complete a feasibility analysis of a 5MW OTEC plant in Barranquilla, Colombia for a sustainable, reliable and competitive supply of electricity.Second, this project is planned to be the preparatory stage for further development of a commercial project consisting of engineering, procurement and construction, installation and operation. If the feasibility proves to be positive, the project has to lead to an approval for funding of these next phases of development.Third, this project serves as springboard for the involved organisations to collaboratively gain a &apos;first mover&apos; advantage in commercializing OTEC globally.&#x2022;	Initial activities and results of the projectThe project includes a study on the feasibility of a 5MW OTEC plant for Barranquilla, Colombia. The study consists of an analysis of the technical and economic feasibility on the basis of, inter alia:- Identification of potential project sites and energy customers;- Specify requirements for the construction of 5MW plant and capabilities of fabrication yard(s), e.g. Colombian shipyard Cotecmar;- Analysis of inter alia the energy demand of the end users;- Measurement of the temperature profile using a conductivity, temperature, and depth (CTD) probe deployed from a boat and analysis of the seabed profile using nautical charts;- Identification of project benefits and risks;- Evaluation of financial viability by Monte Carlo simulations in Palisade @RISK software;- Determine what can be done in Colombia and what needs to be imported;- Investigate sources of funding;- Stakeholder analysis.The feasibility study requires a visit to Barranquilla to analyse the local conditions and energy demand and to speak with local parties. The results of the project will be summarized in a comprehensive report, including drawings, models and other relevant information. Also, a presentation to all involved stakeholders will be given. The outcomes of this project are the preparatory stage for further development of a commercial project consisting of engineering, procurement and construction phases, installation and operation. If feasibility is positive, the project has to lead to an approval for funding of these next phases. Outcomes of this project are:- Feasibility of a 5MW OTEC plant in Barranquilla, Colombia elaborating on the local conditions, economics, etc.;- Preliminary technical design of 5MW OTEC plant for Barranquilla, Colombia;- Identified capabilities of fabrication yard(s), e.g. shipyard Cotecmar;- Identified organization for the OTEC plant operations and maintenance;- List of environmental studies to be made and by who;- Initial project planning: engineering, construction, installation and commissioning;- Budget for the plant design and construction;- Pre-assessment of the feasibility of other ocean thermal energy applications, e.g. seawater district cooling, food and drinking water production.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-50463268" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bluerise B.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="73">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">VCG Consulting Group</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="CO">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.9799669 -74.8013085</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14015" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-11-30">46060</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bluerise B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-02">23030</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bluerise</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-04-04">18424</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bluerise</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-10-30">4606</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bluerise</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-11-30">46060</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-26067_1" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
