<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-PCB22PE01</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WEF nexus project Water expert</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Government supports the Peruvian Government in integrating WEF-nexus aspects in its sustainable development and climate change policies in which water, energy and agri&amp;food are integrated. The Peru Nexus project takes as case the Santa Eulalia river sub-basin in Peru that provides 50% of the water needs and 70% of the electricity needs of metropolitan Lima. Moreover, the basin produces a wide variety of fruits (custard apples and avocados) and vegetables that are sold in Lima. Climatic variability compounded by climate change results in decreased availability of and access to natural resources (mainly water and food). This affects local populations directly and metropolitan Lima indirectly. The Peru Nexus project will result in more efficient use of water, energy and food resources, enhanced resilience to the impact of climate change, improved agricultural practices and the development of the local private sector in the Santa Eulalia river sub-basin in Peru. The overall intervention focuses on the Agriculture/food sector and the trade-offs between agro-energy and agro-food. This second phase builds on the findings of the scoping mission and aims to apply the Nexus methodology to arrive at smart and sustainable interventions to increase the efficient use of water, energy, and food resources in the Santa Eulalia river sub-basin.  The implementation phase involves expertise on water, energy, food and knowledge transfer and will be carried out jointly by Dutch and local partners. This project) will provide specific expertise on the water component focusing on expert advice in the water-food nexus.The intervention has a positive impact on:SDG 8: inclusive and sustainable economic growth; with emphasis on targets: &#x2022;	8.2 Achieve higher levels of productivity of economies through diversification, technological upgrading and innovation, including through a focus on high value added and labour-intensive sectors.&#x2022;	8.3 Promote development-oriented policies that support productive activities, decent job creation, entrepreneurship, creativity and innovation, and encourage formalization and growth of micro-, small- and medium-sized enterprises including through access to financial services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-73158550" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Helmer Consultancy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-23" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="PE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PE">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-11.7770077 -76.615263</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="14" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="23182" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="23210" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="23220" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-04"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-04">30974</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-04">30974</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-04">30974</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-26067_3" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
