<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-DSS221MZ01</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique Pemba UNICEF</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF has field presence in Cabo Delgado and Nampula with sectoral expertise to achieve the results for children planned. For the inaccessible areas, wherever possible, UNICEF will establish partnerships with organizations with capacity to operate in such areas. All actions will be coordinated with the Government and through the cluster mechanism, with UNICEF leading the WASH, Education, Nutrition clusters and Child Protection Area of Responsibility.With Cabo Delgado province being the province with the largest impact, specific technical capacity is required at field level to support implementation activities in coordination with other partners and stakeholders. To manage the field level implementation of UNICEF response and provide technical support to partners and WASH sector in general, dedicated capacity is required in the form of a WASH Emergency Specialist based in Pemba city, Cabo Delgado province. The WASH Emergency Specialist will also serve as liaison with UNICEF WASH team in Maputo and national and sub-national cluster coordination.In coordination with other WASH stakeholders and sectors, and with a focus on the activities coordinated from Cabo Delgado province, the WASH Specialist will be responsible for:&#x2022; Following-up the progress of WASH activities in accommodation centres / resettlement sites and liaising with implementing partners to navigate through bottlenecks, ensure technical and operational compliance and timely execution pf projects vis-a-vis approved plans and targets and aim for ongoing activities to cover minimum standards.&#x2022; Undertake regular field monitoring and supportive supervision visits to areas targeted by the UNICEF emergency response and WASH sector response, including discussions with implementing partners, Government stakeholders, project participants or beneficiaries. The emergency response activities to be monitored will include, but are not be limited to:o Emergency water supply interventions, including rehabilitation of water supply systems in urban areas / small towns, installation and operation of water distribution points and other water supply sources in accommodation centres / institutions.o Installation and operation of sanitation and hygiene facilities in accommodation centres / resettlement sites / institutionso Rehabilitation / upgrading of water supply sources in affected communities and institutionso Distribution of WASH NFI items among affected communities.o Community mobilization, hygiene and sanitation promotion activities at community level,&#x2022; Reporting of UNICEF WASH response interventions within UNICEF, WASH cluster and other reporting requirements ensuring compliance with key programme indictors and objectives .&#x2022; On behalf of UNICEF WASH, participate in WASH cluster and other external coordination fora (eg CCCM (Camp Coordination and Camp Management) coordination meetings, cholera task force), including joint activities for needs assessment, response monitoring, etc.&#x2022; Support sound technical and methodological design and implementation approach for WASH assessments, KAP surveys as well as Post Distribution Monitoring (PDM) and monitoring plans&#x2022; Participate in WASH and multisectoral assessments and devise implementation strategies for new populations/areas in need.&#x2022; Support analysis of WASH sector needs and priorities and definition of sector strategies and standards to ensure WASH response is implemented as per national and international humanitarian standards.&#x2022; Organise and conduct training activities in WASH monitoring and Evaluation to UNICEF WASH implementing partners and cluster partners as needed.&#x2022; Support the including identification of requirements for implementation (i.e. funding, supplies, implementing partners, etc.) in line with WASH cluster standards, UNICEF CCCs and WASH response strategies, outcomes, target population, etc.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MZ">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-19.302233 34.9144977</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="14020" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="8"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-12">39758</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-12">4365.9</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-05">11927.4</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-14">11927.4</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-21">13350</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-21">1474.2</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-27">25549.75</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-12">39758</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-12">4365.9</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-21">13350</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-21">1474.2</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-4000002159" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
