<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-WAL18CA30</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">City of 1,000 tanks</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Within Chennai city the project proposals from OOZE Architects included the following components;City of 1000 Tanks intends to develop a Water Balance Model across the city by collecting rainwater, treating wastewater and runoff pollution with decentralized Nature-Based Solutions (NBS), and by recharging both to the underground aquifer. This will prevent droughts by increasing groundwater reserves while simultaneously mitigating risks associated with high-frequency floods and sewage pollution.This project intends to fix supply-side issues by creating water retention and supply capabilities of 200-250 MLD (Million Litres per Day) in the phase first two phases of the project (out of the current 1,580 MLD urban demand). Chennai is at the risk of running out of water in the next decade, given projected increases in population and the depletion of the water table. The project relies onnature-based solutions to holistically solve problems of water supply, sewage and flooding.FOCUS AREAS1.NEW CMA- &#x2018;TOWARDS A REGIONAL URBAN LANDSCAPE STRUCTURE&#x2019; The construction of a sustainable and adaptive water system in the city and metropolitan area of Chennai requires an approach concerning a new balance of water, landscape and urban patterns at the regional scale. This project consists of a regional vision and masterplan for the New Chennai Metropolitan Area spanning 8,878 km2. This overarching structure links the four other projects to a macro-scale vision. 2.MYLAPORE TANK AREA - &#x2018;MYLAPORE TRAIL&#x2019; A historic site consisting of the famous Kapaleeshwar Temple Tank in close proximity to the Buckingham Canal. It consists of mainly residential developments and small-scale commercial establishments. Tanks historically acted as ground-water barometers that linked water management to the urban realm in a visual and understandable way, but this connection has been lost and tanks no longer perform the role of water management. Pilot projects will be designed to enhance ground water collection, recharge, treatment and overflow connections, integrated in the visible space of the neighbourhood. 3.CHITRA NAGAR AREA - &#x2018;BEST CASE FLOOD RESILIENT COMMUNITY&#x2019; Residential settlement consisting of diverse low-income housing establishments situated on the banks of the Adyar River. Housing nearly 9,000 inhabitants, the settlement is highly prone to flooding during normal rain events and was severely affected during the 2015 monsoon. Poor sanitation and lack of solid waste management further aggravate water issues and need to be addressed to present a &#x2018;best case&#x2019; model for similar low-income neighbourhoods across Chennai, creating resilience through flood and drought protection measures. 4.MAMBALAM CANAL AND SURROUNDINGS - &#x2018;MAMBALAM ARMS&#x2019; This is the last remaining trace of the former Long Tank reservoir and today it is highly polluted with sewage and solid waste. The 5.6-kilometre-long canal is lined with residential, commercial and government buildings as well as informal settlements and slums, the principle drain for a 12km2 watershed that is the commercial heart of the city. As the area floods chronically, pilots across the whole area to increase recharge are to be explored in conjunction with the restoration and public space development of the canal itself. 5.KOYAMBEDU MARKET AND SEWAGE TREATMENT PLANT AREA - &#x2018;GREEN HEART KOYAMBEDU&#x2019; Koyambedu area is a major transit hub for Chennai, containing the city&#x2019;s largest perishable goods market, the Chennai Mofussil Bus Terminus (CMBT), the Koyambedu Metro Depot and a newly installed sewage treatment plant adjacent to a marshland and the side-arm of the Cooum river. At risk of flooding, the vulnerability of the site is a major risk for the city at large. Pilot projects that enhance ground infiltration, wastewater treatment and recharge and sanitation are to be explored in this area to ensure critical services are safeguarded even at the time of any disaster.Other local partners included; Madras Terrace, Care Earth Trust, IIT Madras, Paperman Foundation, Biomatrix, Pitchandikulam Forest Consultants, IRCDUC, Uravugal Social Welfare Trust, Goethe Institute, Delft University of Technology, IHE Delft, HKV Consultants, Rain Centre, Prof. Swaminathan, Ramakrishnan Venkatesh More info: www.cityof1000tanks.org</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-24458171" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ooze V.O.F.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-21" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="IN">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.0836939 80.270186</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="33" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="33" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="17" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="43060" percentage="34" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="A01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-07-19"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-07-19">200000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-21">60000</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ooze V.O.F.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-11">100000</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ooze V.O.F.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-11">15000</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ooze V.O.F.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-27">25000</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ooze V.O.F.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-21">0</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ooze V.O.F.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-07-19">200000</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-07-19">200000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-4000001899" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
