<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-PVW4S18045</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mbinguni Mali (Water from Heaven)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022;	Short general project overviewThis project targets Tanzania esp. Arusha, where the groundwater is very contaminated (mainly fluor) and piped water is contaminated. The COWSO&#x2019;s/AUWSA in Arusha region are fully cooperating. The project aims at ensuring local access to safe and healthy drinking water by collecting and treating the rainwater (priority of the decentralized drinking water policy). The solution combines the latest technology developed by WIC, the innovator/inventor of the Water from Heaven/Mbinguni Maji technology. The technology is aimed to remove bacteria, viruses and nutrients with ultrafiltration membrane technology to use rain water to meet drinking water standards, and to remove nutrients, if these are present in rainwater in Arusha such as NH4+, TOC, NO3 (by using Denutritor, a bio filter). In Tanzanian the technology prevents fluorosis, a disease caused by dissolved fluoride in groundwater causing serious health damage. The purified and sterilized water produced by the technology can be stored in closed systems and can be kept safe for times of droughts in the same way as bottled water. This approach leads therefore to safe and secure water supply. The project will assess the viability and feasibility (technical, market-wise, social and legal) of the proposed solution.&#x2022;	Initial activities and results of the projectThe goal of the feasibility study is to asses:1. The performance of the technology mainly membrane (and if needed Denutritor as indicated) as shown in terms of producing biologically safe drinking water in local context.2. The local needs, market potential, and cost benefit analysis.3. The risks and opportunities of a demonstration pilot project.The activities focus on:- Assessment of users&#x2019; requirements by performing focus group discussion.- Define service level of the technology in the local context by knowing user&#x2019;s requirement, water quality analysis of the available water resources.- Demonstration of technical feasibility of the technology in local context yes/no.- Viability of the technology assessed by analysing market availability/interest, cost benefit, social and legal factors etc.- Develop a good business Model.&#x2022;	What makes the technology, product, method or approach used innovativeMbinguni Maji (Water from Heaven/Hemel(s)water&#xAE;) is a new, innovative drinking water technology, using rain water as the water source. The water produced is guaranteed drinking water quality (WHO). Operation and maintenance of the unit is very simple (closed membranes systems). The technology has been tested and proved to produce excellent drinking water quality in the Netherlands. Feasibility of technology in the African context has not yet been studied.&#x2022;	What are the results of the projectMbinguni Maji fits in the de-centralization policy of Tanzania. A strong consortium/partnership was built with local stakeholders: communities, hospital, greenery, Water Institute, Arusha Technical College for the analysis, AUWSA and 2 installation companies. For financial feasibility, a business model is developed. Two installation companies (RIL Solutions and Jandu Plumbers) show their interest in commercial application. The technology has been perceived as highly innovative by the Tanzania Water Institute and the initiative has been regarded as very welcome to contribute to the need for reliable drinking water.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-61216267" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consultancy 4 innovation and Susrainibility ; C4I&amp;S</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41146484" role="4" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting IHE Delft Institute for Water Education</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-64046966" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Innovation Consulting</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-20" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="TZ">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-3.3696827 36.6880794</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="14031" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-11">46453</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C4I&amp;S</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-18">11609</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C4I&amp;S</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-02">11609</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C4I&amp;S</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-02">11609</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C4I&amp;S</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-02">11609</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C4I&amp;S</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-20">10320</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C4I&amp;S</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-10">103209</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consultancy 4 Innovation and Susrainibility ; C4I&amp;S</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-10">103209</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-26067_1" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
