<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-WAL18CA10</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Resilient Semarang</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Within Semarang city the project proposals from &quot;One Resilient Semarang&quot; included the following strategic programmes and project proposals.1A. Water-Neutral Industry (demand side)1B. Feeding the Industry (supply side)Programme to promote high added-value and sustainable industrial development through revitalization of existing industrial clusters and surrounding urban areas, incorporating water-neutral strategies, and innovative technologies and services. This programme is a necessary step towards halting groundwater extraction and reducing land subsidence while simultaneously promoting sustainable and circular economic growth by creating incentives to optimize land use, water supply and management systems based on rainwater harvesting, storage, conveyance, reuse and recycling.The project proposal is called &apos;Water-Neutral Industry pilot in Genuk&apos;. With the planned toll road / seawall from Semarang to Demak, there is an opportunity to leverage safe grounds behind the toll road schemes to create high capacity water-neutral industrial clusters, establishing mechanisms for value capture and organizational upgrades. Project components include redevelopment and retrofitting of industrial clusters (Kawasan Industri Terboyo &#x2014; KIT and Lapangan Industri Kaligawe &#x2014; LIK), integration with water harvesting and retention areas, and integration with wastewater treatment, reuse, water supply and distribution.The Resilient Kampung Pilots:2. Network of Resilient Kampungs Programme that incentivizes decentralized investments in green infrastructure for water, waste, and energy in the kampungs. The programme proposes a new set of tools at the kampung level around resilient infrastructure through a Resilient Kampung Guide, especially targeted at community leaders, advocates, and facilitators. The programme will leverage existing community action planning and participatory budgeting process with integrated resilience and risk mitigation planning. It enables ecological citizenship, participatory water planning, stewardship of shared resources, data collection, and &#x2014; most importantly &#x2014; accelerate infrastructure improvements for the city.Resilient Kampung Pilots:Interventions in kampungs with urgent issues such as Tembalang, to improve the stormwater management and provide an alternative sources for water supply. Components include a floodable park for larger water management capacity, green infrastructure measures, as well as a waste-to-energy low-tech facility to support the energy supply. Additional interventions in other kampung types as demonstration key focus areas, such as Terboyo &amp; Trimulyo, Wonosari and Nongkosawit.3. Integrated Protective Coastal Zone Program to create an integrated vision and plan for a protective and productive coastal zone across Semarang, Kendal and Demak through metropolitan planning processes, including the development of an ecological value transfer mechanisms to allow cost and profit sharing. The programme aims to ensure coastal protection through a combination of hard infrastructure with soft (mangrove) foreshores, thus enhancing long term industrial competitiveness, urban and rural development and biodiversity. Three projects are proposed that achieve this by adding value and resilience to existing and planned initiatives.The two project proposals of the Integrated protective coastal zone programme, are:COASTAL BALANCE PILOT IN GENUK/SAYUNGProject that combines gray infrastructure with ecological preservation through the modification of the current toll road scheme to accommodate for coastal restoration and the creation of sediment capture areas and eco-tourism. Project components include areas for concentrated industry in Demak, ecological restoration, and river diversions in shallow areas for sediment capture. The project focuses on the cross-boundary collaboration between regencies and employs the proposed ecological transfer mechanism for profit and cost sharing for industrial growth and ecological restoration efforts.FUTURE-READY PORT IN TANJUNG EMASProposal for resilient additions to the current Tanjung Emas Port masterplan to combine ecological restoration along with coastal protection. Components of the project include expansion of the port operations on reclaimed areas as per the masterplan with the addition of more efficient logistical areas, updated design for breakwaters with sediment capture areas, facilities modernization, drainage strategies, and greenbelt restoration. A series of flood protection strategies include shelter formations in the waters, raised platforms, and onshore dune systems.Other local partners included: Kota Kita, Deltares, Wetlands International, Sherwood Design Engineers, Hysteria Grobak, Iqbal Reza, Stefanus Kristanto, Cindy Riswantyo, The Nature Conservancy, Atelier Ten, UNDIP, University of Pennsylvania.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="73">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Architecture &amp; Urbanisme, Inc</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-21" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ID">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-7.28765615 110.40194274</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="33" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14020" percentage="33" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="17" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="43060" percentage="34" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="A01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-07-19"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-07-19">200000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-07-19"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-07-19">42000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-08-28"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-28">-5631.15</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-30">60000</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Architecture &amp; Urbanisme, Inc</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-11">100000</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Architecture &amp; Urbanisme, Inc</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-11">15000</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Architecture &amp; Urbanisme, Inc</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-22">25000</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Architecture &amp; Urbanisme, Inc</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-21">0</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Architecture &amp; Urbanisme, Inc</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-07-19">200000</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-07-19">42000</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-28">-5631.15</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-27">36368.85</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-07-19">200000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-07-19">42000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-28">-5631.15</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-4000001899" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
