<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-PST20CO01</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Study B2B platform Circular Agriculture for small and medium scale farmers in Colombia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In line with the Dutch vision on circular agriculture and with the efforts of the Colombian government to introduce circularity in the country, the LAN Agricultural Department of the Netherlands embassy in Colombia has develop its own Circular Agriculture strategy: where Colombia and the Netherlands meet. This strategy supports the ambition of the Dutch government to cooperate with other countries in circularity in the most relevant sectors of the economy, in particular in which the Netherlands is dependent for its imports.   The project: Dutch&#x2013;Colombian B2B platform on circular agriculture and living lab for best practices targets local Colombian small and middle scale farmers to operationalize this strategy and sets the basis for mutual cooperation in the field of Circular Agriculture between the Netherlands and Colombia. Among the most relevant problems faced by these farmers in Colombia are low productivity rates, use of high amounts of pesticides, high water use per square meter of crop production, dependency on animal feed imports from abroad, and above all, the lack of indicators to measure and benchmark their performance against other producers. Besides, many Dutch companies have limited awareness about the needs of Colombian farmers in relation to more sustainable agriculture and hence the possibilities the Colombian market has. The Dutch private sector offers a variety of solutions in relation to circular agriculture that could benefit the Colombian farmers. For example, alternatives for pesticide use such as biological control, water saving techniques, soil improvement, know-how to locally rear insects as protein source for animal feed and digital solutions for farmers that optimize inputs and productivity.  The gap between demand in Colombia and supply in the Netherlands appears to be one of the main reasons for limited business and access to the Dutch market of Colombian  agricultural producers.The B2B platform is conceived as an space  where the needs  from Colombian small and middle income farmers can meet with the Dutch offer: know-how, technology, innovative solutions for circular production, and improvement of market access of key agro-subsectors in the country. The project provides insights about the needs, viability, feasibility, structure and the content of such a platform and living lab; which will be used by the LAN Agricultural Department of the Netherlands embassy in Colombia to take decision about  the future implementation of the platform to support small and medium scale farmers. Besides, the project also provides insights on how the existing Dutch circular agriculture platform (platformkringlooplandbouw) managed by the Ministry of LNV can eventually be linked with the future Colombian B2B platform.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dutch - Colombian Chamber of Commerce (Holland House)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-24" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-21" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="CO">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.710989 -74.072090</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-21"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-04-23"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-21">39083</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-14">14850</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dutch - Colombian Chamber of Commerce (Holland House)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-21">17450</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dutch - Colombian Chamber of Commerce (Holland House)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-21">39083</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-14">3118.5</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-19">3664.5</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-21">39083</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-26067_3" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
