<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-PVW4S19052</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WaterWin: Sustainable contribution to a solution for the water problem in the urban Nile Delta of Egypt</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022;	Short general project overviewThis feasibility study examines how and to what extent the by Solaq B.V. developed WaterWin concept can help to efficiently supply qualitatively sufficient water for the cultivation of agricultural and horticultural crops in the urban Nile Delta in Egypt. In addition, based on the most realistic estimates of production and derived production costs, the project will indicate for which applications WaterWin could be of added value. As such, the project will also determine the market conditions relevant for introducing the WaterWin concept.The WaterWin technology is an Atmospheric Water Generation (AWG) concept to produce good quality drinking water from the air. Via an innovative combination of a condensation and distillation process, a cyclical 24-hour process using solar electricity, solar heat and radiation cooling, 100% sustainable water will be produced. In combination with modern agricultural methods (drip irrigation, saline cultivation, vertical farming), the consortium believes that the WaterWin technology can make an important contribution to SEKEM&apos;s water demand and that of other companies and institutions in Egypt. The results of this feasibility study will provide insight into the techno-economic and legal feasibility of WaterWin as a partial solution for SEKEM&apos;s water problems in Egypt. In addition, a market study will be conducted into additional promising sectors in Egypt (drinking water, tourism), which will be taken into account in the validation of the intended beachhead market for a demonstration project. Perspectives for further upscaling to commercial systems are part of the study. Current competition will also be analysed. Based on these results, a go / no go decision will be made to determine whether a follow-up pilot project can be started to demonstrate the technology, whether the intended sector is appropriate for a demonstration project and, in the longer term, if the WaterWin system can be rolled out on a large scale.Based on the results of the development research and the test results so far, it is expected that WaterWin systems will be able to produce pure water for approximately 5 euro per m3. Further technical / technological improvements as well as the influence of economies of scale are expected to lead to a significant decrease in production costs per m3 of water in the coming years. Logically, this could significantly increase the market potential for WaterWin.&#x2022;	Initial activities and results of the projectThe feasibility study will include the following activities:1. Techno-economic/market feasibility study on production and use of irrigation water produced by WaterWin, compared to SEKEM&apos;s agro activities in the Nile Delta.1.1. Data collection: Performing measurements to map local climatic conditions (air quality, contaminants in the form of sand/dust, dynamic temperature flow at night/daytime, humidity at night/daytime, wind speed) and optimal growing period (period with as little risk of water evaporation as possible). Initially, it will be checked on the extent of the Heliopolis University, possibly specific tests will have to be carried out on site.1.2. Production estimate: Calculation and simulation of WaterWin obv local input data and samples. Identify the specific water demand for the specific target applications within a follow-up pilot project.1.3. Dimensioning: Comparing different intended system sizes and their advantages/disadvantages with regard to cost and investment. Sizing a prototype specific to the location in question. Calculating the costs (euro/m3) and production (m3/day) of such a system, at both pilot and commercial level. The local parameters determine to a large extent several design choices, such as eg. the working fluid, the ideal working temperatures within the system, and the rotation speed of the spirals within the dehumidification unit during the production process.1.4. Optimization: Optimising water and cultivation production. Research into possibilities to combine the WaterWin system with efficient farming methods such as vertical farming, salty cultivation, and subsurface and drip irrigation, in order to increase the cost-effectiveness of water use and thus of food production.1.5. Cost estimate: Calculation of the costs required to test the intended system at the targeted location. Comparison costs in production of the system in Egypt itself vs. production in the Netherlands and then transport.2. Legal feasibility study2.1. Import regulations: Research into import regulation and possibilities and barriers to importing the necessary materials and hygroscopic liquids.2.2. Legislation on water production: Research into the local laws and regulations regarding (irrigation) water production and use of the intended materials.2.3. Patent research: Patent research to identify (local) developments that may pose a risk to us in the field of IP.3. Partnering and collaborations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heliopolis University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SEKEM Holding</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-08037446" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solaq B.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-72116420" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Eyes B.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-06" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-06" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-17" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-22" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="EG">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>30.9000 31.1167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="33" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14015" percentage="33" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14020" percentage="34" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-10">30492</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solaq B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-04-02">30492</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solaq B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-22">6776</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solaq B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-09">67760</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-09">67760</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-26067_1" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
