<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-DHIF18D154</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Eco Furnace</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the current situation in Sri Lanka, coconut shells are removed as waste and cost money. And if they are carbonized, the results are environmentally unfriendly (air pollution, high CO2, and labour unfriendly situations). The current process is to deep a pit with clay and stabbing coconut shells in the fire, and after 3-5 days there is a moderate quality of wood coal with a low yield.Due to the mentioned method there are several concerning issues in Sri Lanka: -a high degree of air pollution in Sri Lanka-a bad quality of produced charcoal that also fluctuates-inefficient charcoal production in Sri LankaThe charcoal market offers lots of chances as some local advisors mention in current studies. In a recent report about the coconut market, several measures are suggested in order to boost the market for coconuts. &#x201C;The challenge is to focus on high value coconut products in Sri Lanka&#x201D;. But to take advantage of this growth market, the local producers will have to produce much better quality products and in more environmentally friendly ways.Moors Ovenbouw B.V. has the solution: its development of a Green-Eco Furnace is a complete, resulting in a new type of charcoal unit, to realize a nearly perfect burning up of coconut shells. Technical idea: with a modest amount of fuel the oven is warmed up; in the oven the coconut shells are burned up and transformed into charcoal. The heated warmth will be re-used to heat the oven. The Green Eco Unit makes it possible &#x2013; within a circular system (CO2 neutral way) - to situate the carbonization process. Herewith a high quality charcoal with an high percentage of fixed carbon and a high quality standard can be produced: this carbon is useful in many ways, as it is used in the medical branch, the silicon industry, in agriculture or in the ICT (metallurgic).Short description of the projectIn particular in Sri Lanka several groups need to be convinced about the technical operation of the furnace, the enormous saving of raw materials that the furnace produces, as well as the enormous benefits for the environment and health. Therefore a well-planned demonstration project will be done by Moors Ovenbouw B.V.: target groups are the decision makers (who decide about use of equipment and the finance of the investment), the employees (who need to work with new technologies, and not burning in the traditional way), and local authorities and branch organisations (which are important influencers) need to be convinced. Therefor an extended program with several demonstrations is planned. All these demonstrations are evaluated and can result in adjustments of the project. Intended results are an intensive knowledge transfer, the convincing of the three main target groups as well as the sale of ovens. The expected return could be far more than 10 times the requested subsidy.Development relevancy:Applicant wants to strengthen the locals: there will be training on the job to help the Sri Lankan employees. With this knowledge they will be more capable in future working environments in Sri Lanka. New technology leads to more effective production methods, and the high demand for charcoal out of coconut shells can be met. With this demand a group of new jobs in Sri Lanka will be created. And, the local environment and health are massively improved. There will also be training on the job to help local Sri Lankan inhabitants learn to work with the technology.As a result of the project the applicants wants to sell 13 machines within three years. After a successful build-up of market share in Sri Lanka, various other South Asian markets will be explored. These activities are very expensive and require a big financial budget. For Moors, a financial injection from the government means a very strong support in order to enter this risky market intensively.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-18034808" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moors Ovenbouw B.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LK">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.915186 79.863257</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="12" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="31161" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-12-07"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-15"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-07">80623</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-19">72562</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moors Ovenbouw B.V.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-07">80623</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-07">80623</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-28385" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of companies with a supported plan to invest, trade or provide services - Dutch companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-15"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
