<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-MHPSS21007</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNHCR &#x2013; Chad &#x2013; Support MHPSS Working Group</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNHCR works in Chad on MHPSS-assistance. The aim of the mission is to provide additional technical support and expertise to the MHPSS working group in various areas (see below) in order to strengthen the coordination mechanism and tools available to members,conducting a detailed mapping of MHPSS stakeholders and activities, sharing best practices, building capacities of MHPSS actors and partners, supporting the development of MHPSS documents (policies/guidelines/strategies/frameworks) and strengthening advocacy initiatives with the Government of Chad, humanitarian and development communities and donors.The MHPSS-expert will:1.	Strengthen the coordinating system within the MHPSS national Working Group at National level and related subgroups, ensuring key stakeholders have been identified and involved.2.	Activate the MHPSS Working Group in field locations and supervise the work of Sub-national coordinators (locations may include Bagasola, Liwa, Ab&#xE9;ch&#xE9;, Gore and the Kanem).3.	Assist with the development and operationalization of the MHPSS strategy for refugees and internal displaced persons in Chad through a common national Framework of action and the annual working plans for the MHPSS Working Group.4.	Support the establishment of functional links between the MHPSS Working Group and other coordination mechanisms (such as for Health, SGBV, PSEA and Protection Clusters Meetings) and the Inter Sector Working Group and raise the understanding and profile of MHPSS in these groups.5.	Foster stronger links of the MHPSS WG and national line ministries such as those for Health and, Social welfare, Education and with the CNARR.6.	Develop a core competencies framework in relationship skills of MHPSS staff according to professional standards (such as WHO/EQUIP) and contribute to the design of and deliver capacity building actions in line with the framework for MHPSS national Working Group members as well as in field locations and for the Government of Chad.7.	Contribute to the development of harmonized MHPSS tools for Chad. Focus will be on assessment, monitoring and evaluation tools to be used by national level actors in line with a national framework of action. Additionally, another focus will be on mainstreaming of MHPSS in project design by relevant clusters.8.	Support partners and relevant clusters in resource mobilization for MHPSS activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-27" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-27" type="3"></activity-date>
  <location ref="TD">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.6134137 19.0156172</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="8"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-27">34946</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-27">3780</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-01">16696</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-27">34946</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-27">3780</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-4000003042" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
