<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27378529-PSI13CO24</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Export of fresh papaya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Note: This project has been cancelled, because of difficulties within the partnership.The demand for papaya in the EU countries is growing. Colombia is an important producer of papaya, but is not able to export papaya because of the strict quality requirements of the EU and US market. Papaya is a delicate fruit that requires careful handling in order to minimise bruising. Bruised or damaged fruits are highly susceptible to post harvest rots which easily spread to other fruits. By establishing a controlled commercial fresh papaya export chain the partners will be able to open a new export market for Colombian fruits. The best practice farm of 2 ha, the production area of 52 ha owned by 26 selected farmers and the primary post-harvest building will be located in Cordoba region (Valencia and Tierra Alta), the second largest production area of papayas in Colombia. The packing house will be established in Cartagena. The applicant Best Fresh Group B.V. is a group of companies specialised in producing, packing, marketing and distribution of fresh fruits and vegetables all year round. The group wants to expand its production and sourcing portfolio from Colombia and create a logistic hub in the Americas to serve and develop the United States market. The local partner, Game S.A. foresees Colombia as an international player on the global fruit market able to compete with countries such as Peru and Chile. The partners will establish a well-balanced joint venture with a long term commitment. In this joint venture papaya is a first product that will pave the way for other fruits. The local papaya market in Colombia is well developed and will create a solid base for pioneering a first commercial export chain for fresh papaya fruits.Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR)The project aims to adjust common papaya cultivation practices and to introduce GlobalGAP certification in order to produce a papaya that meets market standards in Europe and the USA.Impact&#x2022;	Employment and working conditionsFringe benefits add up to 49% of the wage paid, which set the (gross) minimum monthly wage at COP 878,355 or around 462 euro. The joint venture will pay their lowest paid employees at least 10% more than the gross minimum monthly wage.&#x2022;	Innovation / Transfer of knowledgeDespite a large production of papaya Colombia does not export papayas.Papaya is a delicate fruit that requires careful handling in order to minimise bruising. The project will introduce new production techniques, new tracking and tracing systems, new packing systems and new technology for storage.The following innovations will be introduced through this project:- Adjust common papaya cultivation practices and introduce GlobalGAP certification in order to produce a papaya that meets market standards in Europe and the USA. Next to product quality requirements it deals with the size of the papaya. Whereas the local market demands a big size papaya, the export markets prefers a smaller sized papaya. By adjusting the current cultivation practices a local farmers can realise up to 60% to 70% of export proof papayas.- Introduce a new approach on post-harvest management in order to maintain product quality throughout the entire supply chain. The partners will build a postharvest facility in Cordoba, a traditional papaya growing region and the nearest papaya cluster to the port of Cartagena. From this point onwards the cool chain is closed up to the moment of delivery at its final destination.- Introduce the hot water treatment process, which is unknown to Colombia. Access to the USA fresh markets is barred for goods with pest risks, like papaya, unless a treatment or other measure can mitigate the risk. The hot water treatment process is one of the approved measures to mitigate this pest risk. Next to this phytosanitary precondition to enable USA exports, the treatment has a positive effect in terms of shelf life extension.- The fresh papayas will be packed in a Breathable Xtend packaging that extends fresh produce storage and shelf life, preserves fresh flavour and nutritional value, reduces supply chain waste and helps to bridge seasonal gaps.&#x2022;	Chain effectsTwenty-six (26) small (papaya) farmers in the Cordoba region will start producing fresh papayas for export. They will supply the joint venture&#x2019;s primary post-harvest facility which in return will select the products into export quality and local quality. The joint venture will buy only export quality products. The local quality products will be sold through the local out growers association, Appalsi (Associacion Productores Papaya Alto Sinu), who represent the twenty-six (26) small farmers. The joint venture will train and certify this first pilot group of twenty-six small (26) farmers in agricultural best practices and GlobalGAP. The intention of the project partners is to increase the knowledge and skills of the outgrowers so they will be able to produce export quality products that meet the high requirements of demanding markets. Due to the intensive training programme, the outgrowers will be able to increase their export quality up to 60%. The joint venture will pay a guaranteed price, plus a bonus for this quality.&#x2022;	Impact on the sectorAll of the twenty-six (26) small farmers are associated under the umbrella of the local outgrowers association Appalsi. This project will enable Appalsi to further develop as a professional organisation that represents the interests of its members. As such, selling remaining 40% local quality papaya on the Colombian market for the best price possible. The local market price for papaya has been quite volatile over the last years. If the price is high, more farmers will start producing papaya and thus flood the market which will make the price drop again and farmers decide to grow another crop. Appalsi expects to sell at a reasonable average price of COP 350 per kilogramme.The small farmers will partly be guaranteed a market and sales price for their fresh products. Due to the volatility of the local papaya market banks are sceptical in providing loans to small papaya farmers. The long-term supply contracts with the joint venture and the cooperation with Appalsi will enable them to obtain bank financing to invest in expansion of their farms and increase considerably their standard of living.&#x2022;	EnvironmentGlobalGAP certification implies selective use of fertiliser, herbicides and pesticides.&#x2022;	Position of womenThe project will positively contribute to the position of women in the Colombian agribusiness sector as it will contract at least thirteen women of which five at medium-/high-level positions. Within two year after the end of the pilot project, the number of female employees will grow to thirty-two of which twelve at medium-/high-level positions.&#x2022;	Impact on food safetyThe project will contribute to food security.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To establish a 2 ha best practice farm, support and train 26 outgrowers, build a postharvest facility and a packing house with hotwater treatment machine, aiming at an export volume of two 40 ft containers per week or 100,000 boxes of fresh papaya per yea</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27273256" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Best Fresh Group B.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Game S.A.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27378529" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Enterprise Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="5"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="CO">
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.41373 -75.533577</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="31161" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="1" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-02-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-02-17">538245</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-04-01">-538245</value>
   <receiver-org type="90">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-02-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-02-17">538245</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-04-01">-538245</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.bestfreshgroup.com/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Website Best Fresh Group</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27378529-23408" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable trade and investment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated PSD results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of full-time (equivalent) direct jobs supported - female</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable trade and investment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated PSD results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of full-time (equivalent) direct jobs supported - male</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable trade and investment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated PSD results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of full-time (equivalent) direct jobs supported - total</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable trade and investment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated PSD results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of full-time (equivalent) indirect jobs supported - total</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of companies with a supported plan to invest, trade or provide services - Other companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-03-24"></period-end>
     <target value="0.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained or skills developed - Medium/high level employees</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-03-24"></period-end>
     <target value="10.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of direct jobs supported in individually supported SME by PSD programmes - Female</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-03-24"></period-end>
     <target value="18.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of indirect jobs supported - Total</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-03-24"></period-end>
     <target value="26.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained or skills developed - Outgrowers</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-03-24"></period-end>
     <target value="26.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained or skills developed - Low-level employees</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-03-24"></period-end>
     <target value="43.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amount of co-investment generated by ODA in EUR - By private sector/companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-03-24"></period-end>
     <target value="538,245.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained or skills developed - Total</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-03-24"></period-end>
     <target value="79.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of direct jobs supported in individually supported SME by PSD programmes - Male</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-03-24"></period-end>
     <target value="9.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of companies with a supported plan to invest, trade or provide services - Local companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-03-24"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Development (PSD)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development, by investment or trade of local or Dutch companies with(in) low and middle income countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of companies with a supported plan to invest, trade or provide services - Dutch companies</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="M" indicator-uri="https://www.rvo.nl/sites/default/files/rvo_website_content/opendata/iati/RVO Indicator Reference.ods" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-03-24"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="0.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0000000000"></target>
     <actual value="1.0000000000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
