<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-19/3481/SA1/ESNFI/INGO/13313</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter Repair Assistance to households affected by 2019 floods and conflict in Jawzjan and Sar-e-Pul provinces</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to HRP Afghanistan, 2018-2021, one of the main drivers of humanitarian needs in Afghanistan is displacement due to conflict and natural disasters. More than 132,200 people have left their villages this year due to fighting. Deterioration of security in the country resulted in large population displacement including the project Provinces. Many of these people remain displaced across the country, as conflict prevents them from returning to their areas of origin. 

On the other hand, more than 42,000 Afghans have been displaced an estimated 226,044 people affected by flooding in the different regions of the country in March and April 2019. Heavy rains caused flash flooding on 27, 28 and 29 March in Jawzjan, and Sari Pul provinces. 
The abovementioned region are already affected by continuous conflict and Sar-e-pul whereas last year drought and recent floods badly affected to the shelter and community infrastructures of targeted provinces. Further, in the above-mentioned regions - the emergency response with regard to ESNFI support was limited and severely underserved during conflicts and drought of 2018.

Getting insight into the situation, ZOA Afghanistan together with IOM conducted shelter need assessment in May 2019 in the targeted provinces, which were affected by 2019 flooding. The collected data shows that 570 households in Sar-e-Pul province, 443 households in Jawzjan province are in category A and B (A completely destroyed and B partially destroyed) completely destroyed or severely affected by natural disaster. To verify the needs on the ground, ZOA has done reassessments in the mentioned provinces. The findings address that many of the households need to rebuild their shelters to protect themselves from the environmental hazards, e.g. upcoming winter. Still, 2130 households are in need of shelter.

ZOA proposed intervention addresses prioritized humanitarian needs in above-mentioned locations on the basis of consultation with the ES/NFI cluster, local line departments and community elders. The intervention will upgrade and repair 600 shelters which will benefit 4,246 people in 6 districts of 3 targeted provinces. The project will provide shelter repair kits and cash to beneficiaries to repair the shelter, further cash will be provided to 60 women headed and disabled households to construct their latrine along with shelter repair. The shelter repair and upgrading will contribute to winterization preparation and support.

In addition to the shelter repair, the project will provide PASSA, hygiene, and protection mainstreaming training to the targeted households in order to strengthen the disaster preparedness and reduce risks. The project includes repair of latrines. The latrines will avoid infection of the environment by open defecation. In addition, the latrines will avoid the diseases among the children born by open defecation. Latrines are especially important for the protection of women and girls. People will be able to give feedback on the shelter, latrine, and training.

The intervention ensures safer and dignified living conditions by supporting families affected by conflict or natural disasters through upgrade or repair of shelters which are in poor condition. This is established through cash for material/tools for IDPs in displacement sites and for those in need of assistance to voluntarily return to areas of origin. The intervention is supported with appropriate technical guidance and adequate monitoring</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Louis Marijnissen</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director ZOA</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 798 731 254</telephone>
   <email>l.marijnissen@zoa.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="27">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jawzjan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.89696920 65.66585680</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="20">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sar-e-Pul</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.67074730 66.04635340</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-08-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-14">263274.53</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-14">257551.18</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-13313">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-14">520825.71</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304157293">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-19">312495.43</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304790098">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-11">208330.28</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
