<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-19/3481/SA1/ESNFI/INGO/13317</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Winterization and Shelter Response in Qadis District of Badghis Province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Badghis province, located in west Afghanistan, is characterized by intense external and internal conflict, with instability from Turkmenistan to the north and along its border with Faryab Province. Due to the limited resources, remoteness and accessibility, most people live in dire poverty. 

CA/RAADA team conducted a rapid need assessment on May 31, 2019 followed by a detailed assessment on July 5 amp 6 in Qadis district and Kharistan IDP site located in Qala-e-Naw district of Badghis province. The assessment was conducted using a dedicated questionnaire, interviews, observation and FGDs. The assessment was conducted with over 50 representatives from 1500 HHs in both the locations. 

Key findings of the assessments almost 800 IDP HHs currently living in Kharistan IDP site were displaced from Qadis district due to the last year drought. They were eager to go back to their place of origin (Qadis district), but they were worried if they go back to their place of origin, they will start all over again and this will be very difficult without having no resources. To go back to their place of origin, they need assistance on transportation back to their place of origin, house repair as they have been damaged either by rain, flood or other reasons, agriculture inputs as they will start cultivating their lands again, NFIs, and assistance for upcoming winterization. While on the other hand, over 700 HHs have already been returned back to their place of origin (Qadis). According to the assessment, the returnees are living in the villages of Qarchaqai, Laka Surkh, Darah Boom, Najak, Hazar Meeshee and Abakhsh of Qadis district. The most critical needs identified for the returnees HHs were: agriculture inputs, NFIs and winterization support in the upcoming winter. 

This proposed humanitarian intervention will build the resilience of 1100 IDPs and returnees HHs in Qadis district of Badghis province through the facilitation of voluntarily return and provision of winterization and shelter/house upgrade/repair support. The project will facilitate the voluntary return of 400 IPD HHs from Kharistan IDP site to their place of origin (Qadis district). These 400 HHs will be supported by cash for transportation to their place of origin, cash for heating/fuel, cash for emergency NFIs and cash for shelter/house upgrade/repair. While the project will also support 700 returnees (already returned to Qadis district) HHs for cash for heating/fuel and NFIs. In addition, the project will also address the protection, GBV and psychosocial needs of the 1100 HHs.The project duration will be 6 months (July 25, 2019 to Jan 24, 2020). 

Key humanitarian interventions of the project will be: 
1.  Distribution of cash for heating/fuel to 1100 HHs
2.  Distribution of cash for emergency NFIs to 1100 HHs
3.  Distribution of cash for transportation for voluntarily return to the place origin (from Kharistan IDP site to Qadis district) to 400 HHs
4. Distribution of cash for shelter/house upgrade/repair to 400 newly returned HHs in Qadis district
5. Provision of 257 awareness-raising sessions on GBV, Protection and Psychosocial Support

CA&#x2019;s goal is to empower people to live with dignity, able to respond successfully to disasters, risks, and opportunities. CA is a strong believer in inclusion and the localization agenda - an imperative of the World Humanitarian Summit (WHS) 2016. CA has a long-lasting partnership with RAADA since 2007 and has implemented various emergency projects in the region. One of the great examples of CA and RAADA partnership is the successful completion of the recent winterization project, funded by AHF, on May 31, 2019 where a total of 1979 HHs were supported with winterization assistance in Qala-e-Naw and Muqur districts of Badghis province. 

In this proposed project CA will be accountable for project design, financial compliances, coordination and reporting and providing technical assistance and guidance</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Christian Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Christian Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rehabilitation Association and Agriculture Development for Afghanistan (RAADA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-29" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammad Yaqoob Rauf</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 799 20 55 57</telephone>
   <email>YRauf@christian-aid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Izharullah Izhar</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Development  Funding Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 785500053</telephone>
   <email>iizhar@christian-aid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="29">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Badghis</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.16713390 63.76953840</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-14">355470.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-14">176266.14</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-13317">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-14">531736.18</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Christian Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304157295">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-19">425388.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Christian Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
