<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-19/3481/RA3/ESNFI/INGO/14348</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Winterization Support for Conflict IDPs in Takhar via Shelter Upgrade or Repair</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Northeast Region has witnessed the highest number of internal displacement from January-September 2019 (97,000 IDPs) of any region in Afghanistan, accounting for over a third of the country&#x2019;s newly displaced population (Ref. UNOCHA Afghanistan Snapshot of Population Movements Jan-Sep 2019). In Takhar province alone, 6,972 households have been displaced due to conflict (Ref. ES/NFI Stockpile Tracking Per Province), with an additional 131 households affected by natural disasters (Ref.UNOCHA Afghanistan Natural Disaster Incidents in 2019). Takhar province holds the second highest percentage of total displacement in the country so far&#x2014;at 16 percent&#x2014; and has seen a sharp increase in displacement in comparison to previous years (Ref.ES/NFI Stockpile Tracking Per Province). Not only is Takhar facing significant surges in population displacement the province has been identified as a Priority One location under the Joint-Winterization Response Strategy for 2019/2020, with approximately 5,862 households projected to have unmet winterization needs (Ref. Winterization 2019/2020: Targets, Partners, Commitments, and Gaps per Province). Winters in the region are severe and long-lasting, with heavy snowfall and freezing temperatures, which in the heart of winter, can plummet to a negative 35 degrees Celsius. For IDPs particularly, the winter months are compounded with extreme poverty and a lack of assets. Families living in poor shelter conditions are unprepared for the harsh weather, with hypothermia among other illnesses posing a major threat. Women and children are particularly vulnerable during the winter months, and are more at risk of illness due to a lack of proper insulation and heating.

Given the substantial need for winterisation support in the region, Concern Worldwide received funding under AHF&#x2019;s first Standard Allocation of 2019, to support the most at-risk IDP, returnee and nondisplaced conflict and natural disaster-affected households with NFIs and a range of winterization support. Specifically, Concern was granted a total of $713,092.53 to respond to 6,930 IDPs, 2,430 returnees, and 2,190 host individuals in Badakhshan and Takhar provinces to effectively address the chronic and severe needs that recur during the winter months. This includes the provision of the winterisation standard package for insulation and emergency NFIs. 

Since the First Standard Allocation, the ES/NFI Cluster has identified increasing needs related to winterization in Takhar province. To supplement our first allocation package, and prior to the onset of winter, Concern is proposing the rapid provision of shelter upgrade or repair (in-cash) coupled with emergency shelter repair kits (in-kind) to 369 conflict-displaced families returning to Ishkamish and Baharak districts of Takhar province, whose houses have been identified as partially damaged. To ensure these families are adequately protected from the cold and are able to cope with the harsh weather conditions in their district of origin, Concern will provide the means for shelter upgrade or repair.  This includes providing technical support, tools and construction materials to mobilize families to upgrade or repair major damages such as cracks of shelter walls or ceilings, serious leakages of roofs, broken or missing doors and windows, and damaged roof beams. Based on rapid market assessments in both Ishkamish and Baharak districts, the emergency shelter repair kit will be distributed in-kind, and Shelter Upgrade or Repair will be provided via two cash instalments of $150 each, on a conditional basis. The repair kit consists of standard items required for various repairs such as an axe, shovel, wheelbarrow, and rope, and is based on the ES/NFI Cluster&#x2019;s standard Emergency Shelter Self-construction/Repair Toolkit. All upgrading, including repairs, will focus on the most effective response, adhere to cluster standards, and ensure no further harm to affected-families.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-29" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdul Hadi Nabil</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Representative</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 700731325</telephone>
   <email>hadi.nabil@concern.net</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jared Rowell</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 799489507</telephone>
   <email>jared.rowell@concern.net</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="16">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Takhar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.66980130 69.47845410</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-20">53949.62</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-20">107899.23</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-14348">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-20">161848.85</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304336919">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-25">161848.85</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
