<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-19/3481/RA3/ESNFI/NGO/14204</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of winterization assistance to vulnerable population in Nuristan and Paktika provinces</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project which is in line with the Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP) for 2019 (addressing SO1 and SO2) will be implemented in Nuristan amp Paktika provinces which both of them are included in the priority 1 provinces of the ES/NFI cluster as highlighted in Joint Winterization Response Strategy. The project&#x2019;s overall objective is to improve well-being of the target vulnerable people to meet their immediate survival needs winterization assistance so that they can withstand harsh winter. The project will directly contribute to the strategic objective 1 and 2 of Humanitarian Response Plan 2018-2021 which focuses on: SO1: Lives are saved in the areas of highest need and (SO2) People by sudden and slow-onset crises are provided with a timely response.

The major activities as part of this project will include: (1) conducting joint assessment aimed at identifying the highest vulnerable families in need of winterization assistance (2) Provide unconditional cash to support the needy families chiefly for winterization support (3) Awareness of the affected population (IDPs) about their rights during a project implementation by orienting them on Guiding Principles on internal displacement  (4) Conduct post-distribution monitoring. ORCD will implement the mobile money modality for the distribution of cash. ORCD has considered mobile money (SIM), mobile money (Token) and Hawala have been considered as three sperate-tier methods for the transfer of cash as Plan A, Plan B and Plan C. ORCD has already collected quotations from AWCC and Roshan in this regard. Should any plan fails, the next available plan will be implemented. 

Although, there is available commitment from other partners to provide winter assistance to 250 families in Nuristan, there is still gap of 1,521 families (2800 men, 3060 women, 2297 boys and 2400 girls) who are in dire need of winterization support in this province. In Paktika, there is no available commitment from other partners to provide winterization support to any families in need of it. Thus, there are 517 families (993 men, 1061 women, 796 boys, and 821 girls) in this province who are in desperate need of winterization support. In Parun district of Nuristan, a total 600 families ((1152 men, 1231 women, 924 boys and 953 girls) will take benefit of the services directly as part of this project. In Paktika, 300 families in Sharana, 60 families in Urgun and 40 in Sarobi districts will receive the standard winterization package (US$ 200/family)

In the view of this, the main target beneficiaries will include a total 7,000 IDPs (1920 men, 2052 women, 1540 boys, and 2400 girls) induced by conflicts and drought in Paktika and Nuristan provinces. Majority of these IDPs in both provinces are due to the recent conflict and drought (Drought affected IDPs still exist in Parun Nuristan province). 

The project will be potentially effective in addressing the needs of target people by strengthening their resilience during the upcoming harsh winter. A lack of support in terms of winterization heating materials would mean that vulnerable families including women, children and older people will be exposed to harsh weather conditions, which may lead to mortality and negative coping mechanisms such as selling belongings, early marriages, child labor and could be associated with other environmental related protection risks. 

To make sure that eligible families are identified, ORCD will establish a beneficiary selection committee in coordination with relevant stakeholders especially DORR. Ensuring the protection sensitivity, the committee will be oriented on the standard winterization assessment tool which will be used to identify and select vulnerable beneficiaries in both provinces through harmonized approach</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Research and Community Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Research and Community Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ahmad Reshad</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093729802920</telephone>
   <email>a.reshad@orcd.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mir Sayed Atefi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 79 938 9755</telephone>
   <email>finance@orcd.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sidiqullah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Managing Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093729802905</telephone>
   <email>info@orcd.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="14">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuristan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.32502230 70.90712360</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="25">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Paktika</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.26453860 68.52471490</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-11-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-21">58456.73</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-21">171557.8</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-14204">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-21">230014.53</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Research and Community Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304339013">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-25">138008.72</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Research and Community Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
