<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-19/3481/RA3/FSAC/INGO/14359</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural Recovery Project in Baghdis and Herat Provinces.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Western Provinces of Afghanistan namely Herat and Baghdis continue to face the negative impacts of insecurity, natural disasters and economic shocks. In July 2019, armed conflict caused more than 1,500 civilian casualties, the highest monthly figure since systematic tracking began in 2009. According to OCHA updates, as of September 2019, 294,500 and 238,000 were affected by natural disasters and displaced by conflict respectively. In Baghdis and Herat, families continue to face high levels of food insecurity and reduced household income.  Poverty rates stand at 47, 9% in Herat and 56, 8% in Baghdis. Many of the affected are smallholder farmers (1-4 jeribs) who rely on agriculture as their main source of livelihoods. Families  have been affected by 3 or more sudden shocks over the past 6 months (SFSA, 2019) despite having a good season last year which came with surplus harvests (FEWSNET 2019).  The FCS still remain low as well as the reduced coping strategy indexes. 62,6% and 39,6% of the families in Baghdis and Herat lie within the poor category in the food consumption score.  Over 50% of the households have adopted negative coping strategies such as disposal of productive assets including livestock, skipping of meals and borrowing.   70% of the population in Baghdis have adopted crisis coping strategies and 72% in Herat have adopted stress coping mechanisms. There is a thin line between levels of coping strategies, with no humanitarian assistance there can be regression to severe and acute levels. Women and children continue to suffer additional barriers to productive livelihoods, such as increased domestic tensions, GBV, forced marriage or early marriages and exposure to the risks of diseases and malnutrition. In 2019, the population reached with food (69%) and livelihoods (31%) assistance through humanitarian efforts under AHF but this is not enough to address the needs of the vulnerable households. Whilst there was a surplus wheat harvest from last season (MAIL, 2019) and with a prediction of favourable climatic conditions in the coming season by FEWSNET, farmers are still facing the challenges related to input access. SFSA 2019 indicates that 87, 2% and 85, 7% of smallholder farmers have no seed for the next 2019/2020 season in Herat and Baghdis respectively. If this is not addressed, the food insecurity levels in the both provinces likely going to increase to very alarming levels whilst the livelihood status of over 300 000 vulnerable households will be severely compromised. WV with FAO proposes to provide agricultural inputs to 13,500 vulnerable smallholder farmers in Herat and Baghdis with the main objective of alleviating food insecurity and increasing their income from sustainable agricultural production through provision of inputs for 2019/2020 season to improve productivity and household income. The GoA recovery planning emphasises the need to promote sustainable farming practices and agricultural technologies adapted to local conditions hence the intervention will include farmer training on wheat cultivation and proper use /management of fertilisers.  The project is aligned with the AHF 2019 strategy, which indicates that the impact of natural disasters have affected an estimated 13 million people in Afghanistan, with Baghdis and Herat being in the five most severely affected provinces. It contributes to the Strategic Objectives 1 and 3 and will assist vulnerable households to ensure no regression from IPC 3 to IPC 4. The proposed project will target 94 600 vulnerable individuals (13, 500 families)  with including female headed households living in Gulran, Ghoryan, Kushk (Rubat-i-Sangi), Kushk-i- Kuhna, Obe, Pashtunzarghon districts of Herat and Ab Kamari, Jawand, Muqur, Bala Murghas, Qadis, Qala-i- Naw districts of Baghdis provinces,  identified as vulnerable smallholder farmers  (2-5 jeribs) having experienced multiple shocks over the past 6 months. (FSAC guidelines for beneficiary selection).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonathan Chifamba</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programmes Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93799490407</telephone>
   <email>jonathan_chifamba@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sibonginkosi  Mungoni</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security and Livelihoods Sector Lead</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93797088427</telephone>
   <email>sibonginkosi_mungoni@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="29">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Badghis</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.16713390 63.76953840</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="30">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hirat</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.34194400 62.20305600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-11-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-11">43656.15</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-11">139393.32</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-14359">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-11">183049.47</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304318530">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-14">308284</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400323069">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-01">140807.6</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
