<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-19/3481/RA3/ESNFI/INGO/14222</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of winterization support to 862 IDP households in Chaghcharan.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to data gathered from ANDMA and DoRR, approximately 1740 families have been displaced from their place of origin to Chaghcharan in Ghor in 2019. It is estimated that a further 2,000 families could be displaced to Chaghcharan in the coming months by extreme weather such as heavy snowfall during winter. This is against the backdrop of worsening food security in Ghor, where the vulnerable segment of the population has struggled to recover from the setbacks of the recent drought, and ongoing violence is displacing households. With winter approaching, a significant humanitarian crisis is looming for displaced (IDP) households without adequate shelter conditions. In response to this impending crisis, and based on its recent assessment in Ghor, Afghanaid proposes to provide to 862 of the most vulnerable IDP families with emergency winterization assistance to spend on their most pressing needs, facilitated through local Saraf. Afghanaid will mobilize the Saraf system contracting with a reliable to make the cash distribution safe and smoothly.
The allocated amount to be distributed in two milestones an amount of $20 will be distributed in cash to all target IDPs in the initial stage of the project for Gas cylinder and heater purchase. After verification of the beneficiaries having the gas cylinder or heaters, the project will distribute the remaining amount of $180 for purchasing fuel/wood. We will use hand to hand cash distribution approach under the direct supervision of cash distribution committee and Afghanaid staff. The Saraf will bring the money to pre-identified distribution point and upon receipt of the money each beneficiary will sign and thumb. The distribution committee will endorse the distribution list by signing and stamping.
Just before the cash distribution, the beneficiaries will be alerted of the date, time and venue of the distribution. All transactions will be completed securely and confirmed by the distribution committee established to check and verify the process and amount transferred.
Afghanaid will provide the cash amount of $200 based on the standard Winterization assistance package rate to each of the selected IDPs. This vital assistance will help ward off diseases and infirmity in the winter, giving protection and dignity. Afghanaid will develop a mechanism and means for verification to ensure that selected beneficiaries are spending the cash assistance on heating purposes.
Further, they will be encouraged to use the assisted cash for heating purposes, particularly purchasing for winter heating. Regarding the market functionality, project staff monitoring the local market, confirm continued and reliable availability of the relevant goods. The geographic areas where project implementation will take place are relatively secure.
ANDMA and MoRR will be supporting Afghanaid in identification of the beneficiaries and we will further screen and select 862 IDP families based on vulnerability criteria such as households headed by women, widows, children, the disabled, chronically ill, the elderly and families with many children.
These IDPs displaced to Chaghcharan district in 2019 came from Shahrak, Tolak, Dolaina, Pasaband, Charsada, Chaghcharan and Dawlatyar districts and were displaced due to conflict in their area. The conflicts between government and anti-government groups, especially Taliban, escalated in Ghor in 2019. They are considered the most vulnerable as they are not receiving assistance from other agencies, except for a one-time food distribution which is exhausted.
Afghanaid has a long-established presence in Ghor, also extensive experience in humanitarian programming using different distribution methods. This includes previous OCHA projects for direct cash distribution in Ghor and other provinces a cash distribution project in Jalalabad, and with WFP Smart card (through Pass machine) system for transferring food packages. A PDM report is attached as Annex-B for further details.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-17" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-16" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-16" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ayub Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Director Finance  Administration</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93790897166</telephone>
   <email>akhan@afghanaid.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charles Davy</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Managing Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93799310498</telephone>
   <email>crdavy@afghanaid.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Najibullah Namiq</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants and Partnership Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0799733944</telephone>
   <email>najeebullah@afghanaid.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghor</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.09957760 64.90595500</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-11-17"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-21">84333.33</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-21">145666.65</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-14222">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-21">229999.98</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304336990">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-25">229999.98</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
