<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41149287-KECE0300</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41149287" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elimination of Commercial Sexual Exploitation of Children in Busia County</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will address CSEC in Busia County for 2 years with the objective of preventing &amp;amp; responding to CSEC through awareness creation and strengthening existing child protection structures</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ANPPCAN - RO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41149287-KECE0300" ref="NL-KVK-41149287" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41149287-KECE0300" ref="NL-KVK-41149287" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0)70-310 5000</telephone>
   <email>info@tdh.nl</email>
   <website>https://www.terredeshommes.nl</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">69049</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">169928</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">154017</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">83605</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">145347</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">132063</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41149287-5008" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Boys immediately safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Boys immediately safeguarded</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of boys immediately safeguarded</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of boys immediately safeguarded</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21 victims of CSEC were identified and reported to the project team. These cases were identified and reported by community structures such as area chiefs, village elders, parents and care givers, community members and fellow children;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="22">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">22 boys were immediately safeguarded in the quarter;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done a s planned, target achieved. There was an overspent because there were balances brought forward from the previous quarter. 3 boys were safeguarded. the 3 had been sexually exploited by the fishermen during fishing seasons in the islands of Uganda. The children had dropped out school. They were identified and reported by area chief. The project provided them with scholastic materials and through the area chief they were enrolled back to school. The project also referred them to Department of Children Services for further counseling.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="53">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done as planned and target achieved.
Since school closed, many children were involved in fishing. Many boys accompanied fishermen into the lake for deep fishing. As a result boys got sexually exploited as they sought accommodation in the deep waters islands. Some fishermen sexually exploited these boys in exchange of food since fishing took more than a week. Most of these boys are orphaned, child headed households and others come from very poor background where they need to support the family with meeting their basic needs.   The project together with DCS and local chiefs have been able to follow up with the children through continuous home visits to asses their well being as well as continue with the counseling services.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="21">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The balances will be spent in the next quarter. 8 boys were safeguarded from the Port Vicitoria beaches. These victims were taken advantage by the fishermen who went with them into deep fishing and sexually exploited them. 4 boys were sexually exploited by the business women who sell fish and transact trade at the beaches who use the small boys in sexual transactions to cleanse their businesses and in return give them monies. 9 boys were rescued from the sand harvesters who had been  sodomized in exchange of food;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="150"></target>
     <actual value="54">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The cost went up because when schools closed children were more exposed to child exploitation and abuse, hence supporting the field staff in identification raised the costs bacuase travelling from one point to another was a challenge the covid pandemic. So many children need support hence high costs.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="17">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overspend is because there were unutilized balances from the previous year. 7 cases were reported by CRC members through their patrons, 8 cases  by community members while 2 cases reported by local CBO. 7 boys had dropped out of school and accompanied adults into deep fishing where they were sexually exploited in exchange of shelter and food in the fishing islands. 8 victims were sexually exploited by fishmongers who use them to collect firewood during the day and provide them food and accommodation along the beaches. 2 boys were sexually exploited by sand harvesters who exploit children sexually and inform of labour. The boys continue to receive counseling services from the project. 8 have been supported to go back to school and supported. the 17 victims have received PSS services;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs representatives trained on child rights, promoting CRs, roles of government and private sector in promotion of child rights</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs representatives trained on child rights, promoting CRs, roles of government and private sector in promotion of child rights</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs representatives trained on child rights, promoting CRs, roles of government and private sector in promotion of child rights</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs representatives trained on child rights, promoting CRs, roles of government and private sector in promotion of child rights</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">AThe activity was supposed to be done in June but it never happened as planned because the were restrictions on movement due to Covid pandemic, the partner implemented the activity in September 2020.
kindly rearrange the activities under this output, they are mixed up;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity done and target achieved;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Activity was scheduled in the month of March but did not take place due to the outbreak of COVID19;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done as planned, target achieved.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="25">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The cost went up because their were balances for the previous quarter. The activity was done and target achieved. This activity was carried forward from last quarter due to COVID 19. 25 CSOs (13F12M) representatives attended the training. The focus of the training was on child protection during COVID 19. it was noted that working from home limited children access to services especially from government offices. DCS explained on their efforts to strengthen Child Protection volunteers at community level to help in identification of cases and reporting them  to DCS. Close collaborations with community structures such was chiefs and  religious leaders to help intervene in child protection matters.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="22">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The expenditure is due the balances accumulated from the previous quarters. 22(12F10M) local CSOs were sensitized on Child Protection matters including counseling of victims on CSEC. It emerged that many participants were not aware on the procedures to be followed once a child has been sexually abused. Most of them provide counseling services before the child could receive medical support and reporting the case to the police. The project team together with DCS saw the need for further training of local CSO on how to handle victims of CSEC and the reporting mechanism;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity was planned and reported in the last quarter Q1;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cases reported by community members</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cases reported by community members</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of cases reported by community members</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of cases reported by community members</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30 cases were reported by community members. increased cases were reported by community memebers since schools have closed and all children are now at home. As a result of many cases that were previously reported by the schools are now being reported by community members. The community child protection volunteers have also intensified community awareness on child protection issues and where to report CSEC cases when they arise;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity done as planned, target achieved. 


the project intensified community sensitization and also door to door awareness raising against CSEC coupled with home visits. The Community Child Protection Volunteers worked closed with the community members in identification of cases. As a result community members were able to identify and refer cases of CSEC among other exploitations including 5 cases of child trafficking and child labour. The cases reported by community members were high since previously most cases were reported from schools (Child Rights Clubs) but since schools closed community;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="17">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the quarter 17(14 girls3 boys) cases were reported by the community members to the Project team. This is as a result of awareness against CSEC that had been raised in the community including sensitizing them where to report cases of CSEC.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="32">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done as planned and target achieved. The balances are savings. During the quarter Child Protection Volunteers conducted door to door sensitization campaigns on families and community members. The community was sensitized on where to report cases of CSEC and child protection concerns. As a result a total of 32 cases were reported (4 boys 28 girls) to the project team and several intervention services provided including counseling, referral for medical support, legal intervention and scholastic materials to ensure the children stay in school. There was over achievement due to to the immense door to door  awareness raising campaigns by the project team;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="27">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The expenditure is due the balances accumulated from the previous quarters.
27(21F6M) cases of CSEC were reported by community members. This was as a result of community dialogue that had been carried out in hotspot regions ie along the lake and at the cross boarder area especially Busia Market where there are high numbers of track drivers. These cases were picked up by project team in coordination with DCS. The project provided counseling services to all the victims. 7 cases had been of trafficking from Uganda that had been married off to Busia boda boda men. The project facilitated repatriation of the girls through DCS. The girls are receiving counseling services and support from ANPPCAN Uganda Chapter;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This are expenses relating to Support 10 Child Protection  volunteers to carry out home visits to vulnerable families. The home visits revealed that COVID 19 has had very devastating effects on families and some parents had left their children to stay on their own as they sought employment opportunities in urban centers. Fathers also went for fishing. This has led to many child headed households that exposes children to sexual exploitation within the communities. The identified CHH were linked up with DCS;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is an ongoing activity and the funds will be utilized in the next remaining period. 30 cases of CSEC (27 girls, 3 boys) were reported by community members. The increased reporting was as a result of door to door sensitization done by the community CPVs on the need for families to protect their children at home. The project team teamed up with the area chiefs in barazas sensitization and awareness raising on community reporting structures. The project active involvement of BMU increased the confidence of the BMU leaders in reporting cases of SEC to project team. The project facilitated counseling process to the victims through the needs assessment and providing interventions guided by the needs of the victims.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="40">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child protection committees supported</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child protection committees supported</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of child protection committees supported</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of child protection committees supported</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity done and target achieved. The savings are due to discounted rates by the hotel since we are frequent clients. The project supported Budalangi Sub County to hold an Area Advisory Council participated by 35 members( 9chiefs, 12sub chiefs, 2education officers,2social department, 4ward representatives, 1beach management unit, 2 police 3CSO). It was noted that teenage pregnancy cases were still on the rise despite the nyumba kumi initiative to identify and report the perpetrators to the police. the chair Deputy County Commissioner appreciated ANPPCAN&apos;s effort in awareness creation especially in schools and allowed the project to continue working in schools through CRC projects. Floods that displaced families including children was also discussed. Chiefs were advised to sensitize;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the quarter the Project supported Department of Children Services to conduct an Area Advisory Meeting in Matayos Sub County;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was as planned and target achieved. The balance is because the project staff never incurred travel cost and accommodation. The project supported Sub County Area Advisory Council meeting in Budalangi Sub County.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done a s planned, target achieved. There was an overspent because there were balances brought forward from the previous quarter.
The project supported Budalangi sub county to hold one Area Advisory council at the sub county level. 37(20 F7M) attended the meeting including  representatives from the ministry of education, TSC, Sub County Health, environment, agriculture, 7 areas chiefs, 2 children officer and 2 police officers. Among the issues emerging included the cloasure of CSEC project that has been instrumental in rescuing and preventing children from CSEC. It was agreed that the ACC will continue holding the meetings on a quarterly basis and the teachers and community leaders supported by chiefs will continue supporting child protection efforts in the region;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was supposed to be done in May and July but it never happened as planned because the were restrictions on movement due to Covid pandemic, the partner implemented the activity in August 2020.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There was underspent because of restrictions of movements during the covid 19 outbreak. The unspent funds will be utilized in the coming quarter;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity was reallocated to respond to floods affected Project victims;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC6;&#x2019;&#xC3;&#x201A;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x201A;&#xAC;&#xC5;&#xA1;&#xC3;&#x201A;&#xC2;&#xAC;&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x201A;&#xAC;&#xC5;&#xBE;&#xC3;&#x201A;&#xC2;&#xA2;s knowledge on CSEC enhanced, thereby increasing their ability to make informed decision on sexual matters and therefore reducing cases of Commercial Sexual Exploitation</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC6;&#x2019;&#xC3;&#x201A;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x201A;&#xAC;&#xC5;&#xA1;&#xC3;&#x201A;&#xC2;&#xAC;&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x201A;&#xAC;&#xC5;&#xBE;&#xC3;&#x201A;&#xC2;&#xA2;s knowledge on CSEC enhanced, thereby increasing their ability to make informed decision on sexual matters and therefore reducing cases of Commercial Sexual Exploitation</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of children members of School child rights clubs who know the established response and reporting structures</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of children members of School child rights clubs who know the established response and reporting structures</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="419">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">419 children (267 girls 152 boys) were directly reached through the Child Rights Clubs that were facilitated by the project team from the 12 project schools.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done as planned, target achieved.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community members (including community, religious and traditional leaders ) participating in awareness raising sessions</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community members (including community, religious and traditional leaders ) participating in awareness raising sessions</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of community members participated in awareness raising campaigns on child rights</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of community members participated in awareness raising campaigns on child rights</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5000"></target>
     <actual value="8335">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">8292 members participated through Project Schools while 40 members were reached through community dialogues. There was over achievement since children through the Child Rights Clubs were used in creating awareness against CSEC;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3000"></target>
     <actual value="3500">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity done as planned, target achieved.

The project team was engaged in 2 radio talk shows at Bulala FM. During the talk shows the project team together with the Children Officer sensitized the community on the need to protect their children against all forms of exploitations including CSEC. The community was also sensitized on where to report cases of CSEC whenever they occur and the correct procedure to follow when the abuse has happened. The local chief got the opportunity to also inform the community to report all cases of child sexual exploitation to his office, police or nyumba kumi.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done and target achieved. The underspent is because of savings in exchange rates. 30 community members around the lake were sensitized on the negative effects of CSEC and its manifestations. As a result of the training many cases were able to be reported especially those of boys that are rarely reported. It was also agreed that the area chief will include one Beach Management Committee member in the Local Area Advisory Council where issues of children are discussed;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The funds were reallocated to facilitate ACC meetings. The budget will be utilized in the next quarter;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The were expenses relating to strengthen community child protection structures(Local Area Advisory Council) within Budalangi sub county. The objective of the meeting was to inform the members about the closure of the project. The members(32 17M 15F) present noted that there was a need to continue with the fight against SEC as COVID 19 worsened the situation. It was noted if ANPPCAN and TDH can continue the project to collectively address SEC within the county.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="46">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There was no cost because the awareness was done in chiefs barazas and churches. it will costed next quarter The project engaged the community members in awareness raising sessions. This was particularly done in churches and Chiefs barazas. Through partnership efforts with local administrators that invited the project staff in their community barazas, the community was sensitized on the need to be on the look out on child protection matters. As a result, 46(40 girls, 6 boys) cases of CSEC were reported to the project team by the community members. The project team intervened through provision of counseling services, enrolled back children that had dropped out of school and enhanced families economic livelihoods by enrolling the families into the PEEP project.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity was planned, conducted and reported in last quarter (Q1);</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5000"></target>
     <actual value="1566">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Exploited/abused boys received educational services</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Exploited/abused boys received educational services</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of exploited/abused boys received educational services</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of exploited/abused boys received educational services</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">8 victims were supported with scholastic materials including school uniforms, school bags,;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity done and target achieved. The overspend is because there were unutilized balances from the quarter 5 (January -March 2021)
10 victims were supported with scholastic materials. These were project children that had been previously supported but their school uniforms worn out.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity had been done and completed, target achieved.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The balances for the activity was reallocated to suit Covid reseponse activities.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The school levies for the children supported were less because they had carried forward balances hence reducing there school fees. the balances will be spent in the coming quarter. 15 victims of CSEC were supported with scholastic materials to settle in school hence reducing their vulnerability to CSEC. This included school levies that supported their lunch feeding programme increasing their concentration level at school and their school attendance. This has consequently improved their academic performance. The prolonged schools closure due to COVID exposed children to abuse and exploitations increasing the need for educational support;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity was planned, conducted and reported in last quarter (Q1);</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">the activity was postponed to the next Q when schools open;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Exploited/abused boys received legal advice</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Exploited/abused boys received legal advice</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of exploited/abused boys received legal advice</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of exploited/abused boys received legal advice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">2 abused boys received legal advice/guidance from the Child Trafficking Project lawyer;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">3 boys victims of CSEC received legal aid from the police and the legal officer from Child Trafficking program;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity done and target achieved. The overspend is because there were unutilized balances from the first year. The target was not achieved since victim boys culturally are perceived weak when they report cases of SEC. The two victims cases had been reported to the police station. However the perpetrators sought refuge in Uganda islands. One victims too did not proceed the matter to the court stating that he wanted to forget the incidence and taking the matter to court will keep on reminding him of the abuse. The other case is yet to be presented to court since the police as still searching for the perpetrator. The legal Officer took them through the court proceedings. They both received counseling services.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done as planned, target achieved. There was no budget in this activity since this are balances brought forward from the previous quarter. The expense was for transport, airtime and lunch for children officer during case follow up on the previous cases identified by the project and referred to DCS and also Legal officer accommodation and meals during monitoring visit in Budalangi and Matayos to hand over the previously identified cases to the prosecution department for further follow ups;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is an ongoing activity but it didnt happen  this quarter since movements outside Nairobi were restricted due to the outbreak of COVID-19. The budgetlines are being utilized we a propono Lawyer whom we only facilitate to follow up cases within Busia 
The project provided legal services to 5 boys who were sexually exploited. The local chief and police were able to apprehend 2 perpetrators. The project supported the police to ensure the cases arraigned in court (Busia Children Court 2). There the mention where the accused pleaded not guilty. The perpetrators were taken to Korinda remand but later released on bond. The other 2 cases are still under police investigation since the perpetrators are at large. The project team is working closely with the police;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">there was no spending because the project legal officer couldn&apos;t travel to the field to offer legal services because of the covid outbreak hence the partner resulted in using pro bono services;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">through ANPPCAN legal department, 5 victims of CSEC were able to receive legal counsel. 3 boys from Port Victoria and 2 boys from Busia town. the 5 cases were reported to the police station however only 1 went to the court since the other 4 the perpetrators went into hiding in the uganda fishing islands. The project team conducts follow up home visits and is working closely with the area chiefs to ensure the protection of the survivors is guaranteed.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Exploited/abused girls received educational services</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Exploited/abused girls received educational services</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of exploited/abused girls received educational services</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of exploited/abused girls received educational services</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="34">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30 exploited girls were supported with scholastic materials including school uniforms, bags, pens, books, hygiene kits- re washable sanitary towels and school levies in primary school while 4 victims of CSEC were supported with school fees, uniforms, books, bags and pens.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="78">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done a s planned, target achieved. There is no budget for this activity since this are balances brought forward from the previous quarter. 78 victims of CSEC were supported with scholastic materials. These are children from year one who had previously been supported with scholastic materials but the unfirms had worn out.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity didn&apos;t take place since schools had closed. It was pushed to the January 2021 when schools open because of covid pandemic;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity was planned, conducted and reported in last quarter (Q1);</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity was reallocated to respond to severe impacts of COVID 19 that affected our project beneficiaries;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="68">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is part of the recently reallocated budgets and activities. Activity done and target achieved. The overspend is because there were unutilized balances from the quarter 5 (January -March 2021). Also included is reallocated funds for scholastic materials. 68 project victims were supported with school uniforms and shoes to replace the worn out uniforms.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="66">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">the project supported 66 children with scholastic materials. Among them included  34  victims who had already dropped out of school due to schools closure as a result of COVID pandemic, 12 of the victims were expectant and their current school uniforms were too small. The project team worked closely with the local administrators such as chiefs on the operation return to school government project to ensure these children had been supported with scholastic materials. 20 victims were candidates sitting for KCPE and KSCE. The project facilitated them with scholastic materials that enabled;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Exploited/abused girls received legal advice</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Exploited/abused girls received legal advice</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of exploited/abused girls received legal advice</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of exploited/abused girls received legal advice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">5 cases of CSEC Victims girls received legal aid;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity done and target achieved. The overspend is because there were unutilized balances from the quarter 5 (January -March 2021). 10 sec cases are currently in Busia Law Court. ANPPCAN&apos;s legal officer is currently following up with them. The victims and their parents have been briefed and prepared  by our legal officer on court matters. The legal officer has also coordinated with the prosecutor to ensure the victims have testified to ensure their normal lives are not distracted by many court hearing attendance. Find attached a detailed case file on each victim. the victims received PSS including counseling services;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">One case involved a school going girl and a community elder who used to give her pocket money in exchange for sex. The second one involved a minor and her boyfriend who was could give her food and pocket money and in return exploit the girl sexually. There was underachievement due to breakout of COVID 19 that stopped many processes. The government directives on social distance and restricted movement of people hindered our legal officer from traveling.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project was previously using CT Project legal officer to provide legal counsel to victims of CSEC. However, since the project ended, the project only relies on probono lawyers who sometimes are unreliable due to their unavailability on court days. 5 girls had been sexually exploited by fishermen, 2 by sand harvesters and 2 by truck drivers. 7 perpetrators arraigned in court and cases ongoing, 2 perpetrators are still on run.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="22">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is an ongoing activity but it didn&apos;t happen  this quarter since movements outside Nairobi were restricted due to the outbreak of COVID-19. The budgetlines are being utilized we a propono Lawyer whom we only facilitate to follow up cases within Busia.
22 girls who were sexually abused received legal advice. 10 cases are currently in court 2 (children court) while 12 cases are under police investigation since the perpetrators are on the run. The 10 cases in court 4 cases have been mentioned and the accused pleaded not guilty to the offense. 6 cases are at a hearing stage. The legal officer together with Children officer requested the magistrate to deny the accused bond since they stand a chance of further exploiting the victims. Since they have a right to a bind, they were given;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">one of the older cases (reported in previous Q) that was in court was concluded and judgement delivered and the perpetrator jailed for 20 years;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="22">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">there was underspent because the project legal officer couldn&apos;t travel to the field to offer legal services because of the covid outbreak hence the partner resulted in using pro bono services i.e. legal officers within the locality by only facilitating there court fees and little transport hence the savings.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Families adversely affected by Covid 19 interruption and floods in Busia are supported to ensure their children exposure to exploitation is minimized</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Families adversely affected by Covid 19 interruption and floods in Busia are supported to ensure their children exposure to exploitation is minimized</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of families of child victims receiving support services (e.g. counselling)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of families of child victims receiving support services (e.g. counselling)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="35"></target>
     <actual value="35">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">35 project families affected by floods received essential and sanitation items while 50 families adversely affected by floods received cash transfers to cushion them from the effects as well as prevent their children from falling victims of CSEC. As a result, 270 community family members were reached with provision of essential items such as face masks, jerricans for storage of clean water, blankets and sheets, rewashable sanitary towels and mosquito nets;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity done and target achieved.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done and completed, target achieved.
The expenses incurred under below lines;  Support Mary Glady&apos;s shelter with beddings and food for victims of CSEC.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The families were supported with blankets, bed sheets branded jerricans in June 2020;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Families affected by Covid-19 interruptions and Floods  in Busia, supported with key WASH interventions</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Families affected by Covid-19 interruptions and Floods  in Busia, supported with key WASH interventions</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of people provided with access to WASH facilities (Humanitarian Assistance)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of people provided with access to WASH facilities (Humanitarian Assistance)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="221"></target>
     <actual value="221">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">183 girls and women received reusable sanitary towels, each receiving 5 towels to maintain and enhance their hygiene. 35 households received msquito nets to protect young children from Malaria. Each family received 3 mosquito nets.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity done and target achieved.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done and completed, target achieved;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Families affected by Floods &amp; Covid 19 interruptions  provided with income supported.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Families affected by Floods &amp; Covid 19 interruptions  provided with income supported.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of people received income assistance (Humanitarian Assistance)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of people received income assistance (Humanitarian Assistance)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
     <actual value="70">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">50 project families whose livelihoods were affected by COVID received monthly cash transfers for 3 months of Ksh 2000 per month. 20 project families affected by COVID 19 and floods received a monthly cash transfer of Ksh 2000 for two months. This lowered the vulnerability of CSEC victims and other children within the households from being sexually exploited in search of basic needs. As a result we have reported 0 cases of CSEC from these specific families during the quarter because of the financial support from the project;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity done and target achieved.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity done as planned, target achieved. The overspent is because there were balances from the previous quarters;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity done as planned, target achieved. 

This is an ongoing activity 50 Project families that were adversely affected by COVID 19 by losing their livelihoods were supported with cash transfers of Ksh 2000/- for 7 months. These funds are helping the families to purchase food stuff lowering our beneficiaries from falling victims of CSEC. These families have also been supported with face masks to prevent the spread and protect our beneficiaries from COVID 19 pandemic.
The families are however still in camps since their houses were destroyed. These families are asking for support in reconstructing their houses to be able to have a roof again. The project recommends the partner TdH-NL to support these families re start off their lives by supporting them with basic building materials;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done and completed, target achieved;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased number of community based mechanisms for child protection are in place and functioning well</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased number of community based mechanisms for child protection are in place and functioning well</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of functional community child protection systems</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of functional community child protection systems</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done as planned, target achieved.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private sector decision makers participated in events</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private sector decision makers participated in events</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of private sector decision makers participated in events</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of private sector decision makers participated in events</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="23">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">23 (18 males 5 female) private sector community was directly in a sensitization forum to increase their capacities on child protection and referral mechanism on reporting cases of CSEC. This included Beach Management Unit, Boda boda association leaders and fishmongers representatives.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funds were reallocated to Conduct 2 sensitizations of  35 Business community members (Boda Boda associations, truck drivers associations, hotel and bar owners, Beach management unit, fishmongers Sacco, on CSEC;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="35"></target>
     <actual value="35">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done a s planned, target achieved. There was an overspent because there were balances brought forward from the previous quarter.
The project engaged 35 members (30M, 5F) of private sector in a sensitization forums where the project closure was also discussed. The members largely were from boda boda sector, beach management Unit and traders representatives. The project applauded them for supporting the project by reporting CSEC cases and also creating awareness. It was agreed that through their leaders, the private sector will continue creating awareness within their communities and report cases of children at the chief&apos;s place or the children office;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="20">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done as planned 

 The only utilized lines here are project staff salaries for July and August
Beach management Unit and Boda boda management representatives were targeted with awareness raising information. They were also sensitized on the penalties and jail terms to perpetrators of CSEC. As a result they invited CSEC Project team in their meetings to sensitize their members SACCO in effort to prevent them from exploiting children in the community.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity was not carried out due to COVID 19 and the government directives;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The private sector capacities on forms of CSEC enhanced, hence increasingly contribute to ending CSEC and promoting fight against child sexual exploitation.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The private sector capacities on forms of CSEC enhanced, hence increasingly contribute to ending CSEC and promoting fight against child sexual exploitation.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of supported private sector institutions (Formal &amp; Informal) adopt CSEC focused Child Rights policies/SOPs.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of supported private sector institutions (Formal &amp; Informal) adopt CSEC focused Child Rights policies/SOPs.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done as planned, target achieved.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">girls immediately safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">girls immediately safeguarded</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of girls immediately safeguarded</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of girls immediately safeguarded</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="52">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">52 girls were immediately safeguarded through provision of counseling services and referral services  such as medical services and legal;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="62">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity done and target achieved. The overspend is because there were unutilized balances from the previous year. Included in the expenses are reallocated funds that facilitated entrprenuership skills. 

16 cases were reported by CRC members through Child Help Desks, 32 cases reported by Community Child Protection Volunteers and 10 cases reported by community members. 4 victims were expectant and referred for antenatal services, 8 girls were rescued as they had been trafficked to  Uganda Islands and sexually being exploited by fishermen. 21 supported with scholastic materials and supported to go back to school. 10 victims their parents supported enrolled into PEEP programme to be able to support their children.19 victims continue to receive counseling services.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="106">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity done has planned, target achieved, the overspent is because there were balances from previous quarters. 106 victims of CSEC were safeguarded. 41 had been sexually exploited by fishmongers around the lake, 47 victims by boda boda riders, 2 by sand harvesters and 11 by track drivers. 4 girls were rescued by the Project team, DCS and the police as they had been trafficked by the track drivers to Uganda and on transit to Rwanda. The project in coordination with DCS repatriated the children back to their homes. The project team has continued to provide counseling services to the victims and home visits to asses how they are coping at home;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="102">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done as planned and target achieved. 
COVID 19 pandemic has increased CSEC especially those from poor background, child headed households and orphans. During the quarter 102 victims of CSEC  received psychosocial services including counseling services, medical, legal and provision of essential items such as sanitary towels and face mask. The project coordinated with DCS to ensure the parents/caregivers to these children have been equipped with parenting skills to ensure they look after the children. The families were also supported with COVID 19 cash transfers to reduce their vulnerability to re falling victims of CSEC. The project has continued carrying out home visits to identify their progress;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="55">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target reached was 55 victims of CSEC who  were supported by project team with counseling services, medical and other pschosocial support;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This budget was re alocated to support families with seed capital to improve the economic incomes thereby reducing their children vulnerability to SEC;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
     <actual value="42">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">the closure of schools, closure of Uganda Kenya Boarder, loss of livelihoods pre exposed many children to exploitations including CSEC. The long distance trucks cross boarder COVID requirements led to increased and long traffic of trucks along the boarder of Busia exposing children to the idle truck drivers that exploited sexually young girls btwn age 12 to 17 yrs. Schools closure increased children access to the lakeside beaches exposed children to the fishermen who took advantage of young girls and silenced them with either money or fish. The victims who were mostly identified by the community members, police, Beach Management Unit were reported to the project team and got assistance including counseling, medical support and scholastic materials and knowledge on impacts of CSEC.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="40">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">meetings held with police and judiciary</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">meetings held with police and judiciary</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of meetings held with police and judiciary</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of meetings held with police and judiciary</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity done and target achieved. The savings are because the field staff in conjunction with DCS conducted the activity hence saving on travel and accommodation, also high exchange rate compared to the budgeted rate necessitating savings in direct project staff costs. the project conducted 2 sensitization meetings in Budalangi and Matayos respectively with police officers and chiefs to improve their interview skills especially when handling children matters at  their stations. During the Budalangi meeting, it was noted that the entire sub county police station lacks a Child Protection Unit subjecting children in need of care and protection to more harm when mixed with adult suspected offenders. they requested to be supported with a CPU at Port Victoria Police station to better protect;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The  target was achieved has planned the overspent is because there were balances from other quarters;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Activity done as planned, target achieved. The balances are savings from the activity. 32  (8 female 24male) area chiefs and assistant chiefs from Budalangi sub County participated in awareness raising on Commercial Sexual Exploitation of Children.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done a s planned, target achieved. There was an overspent because there were balances brought forward from the previous quarter.
Through the Budalangi Area Advisory Council, the project supported the children department in sensitizing 35(28M 7F) local administrators including area chiefs, asst chiefs, gender police officers and village elders on child friendly procedures during their interactions and interviews with children. The chiefs noted that even though they would want to ensure confidentiality and friendly spaces, they are constrained of resources to allow these spaces. They tasked the Children Coordinator to pick up with their bosses at the county level;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity was done as planned.

The project in coordination with the Department of Children Services engaged the police, Judiciary and the chiefs in a forum to discuss how cases of CSEC are reported. The chiefs were encouraged to ensure all cases of CSEC are reported to the police and not resolved at community level. The police were also advised to ensure evidence is not tampered with as the children Magistrate took them through how to handle cases of sexual exploitation. the chiefs raised the following challenges: they work so hard with the project team to ensure cases are arraigned in court;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity was not carried out because of COVID 19. The activity will be carried out this quarter (Q3) after the government eased up the strict measures and will also be carried out under the measures recommended by the Ministry of Health;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">vulnerable children participated in awareness raising sessions</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">vulnerable children participated in awareness raising sessions</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of vulnerable children participated in awareness raising sessions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of vulnerable children participated in awareness raising sessions</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="431">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child Rights Clubs were formed in 10 project schools as follows: Bulanda Pr 48 members (30G18B), Mabale Pr.42 members(22G20B), Lwanya Special School 22 members(13G9B), Mundika Girls Pr 45 members(45G), Burumba Pri.43 members(23G20B), Nandekere Pr.47 members(23G24B),Sisenye Pr.45 members(24G21B), Port Mixed 46(23G,23B), Musoma Pr 46members(19G27B), Bukoma Pri 47 members(26G 21B). The members of these Child Rights Clubs were sensitized against CSEC including forms and hotspots prone to CSEC and how to protect themselves and those around them. As a result, the members participated in creating and raising awareness in their respective schools during important days such as Parents Days, academic days through presentations such as poems, songs and drama;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="300"></target>
     <actual value="652">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Due to COVID 19 the activities under this output including sports tournaments were reallocated to respond to the harsh economic times that increased vulnerability of Project CSEC victims into child exploitation. As a result 50 Project families were supported with cash transfer for a period of 3 months to cushion them from the difficult economic times. 35 Project families that had been affected by floods were also supported with essential items such as blankets, bed sheets, jerricans, mosquito nets and sanitary towels since their property had been destroyed by the rains;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="235">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance; Activity done and target achieved. The overspend is because there were unutilized balances from previous quarters. 

 130 girls and 105 boys participated in awareness raising activities. 30 children (20 girls 10 boys) participated in County Children Assembly where they elected their leaders and discussed issues affecting them during COVID 19 including SEC. Through their leadership, they drafted a memorandum stipulating their concerns and presented to County Government. 155 children participated in inter school CRC debate competition  facilitated by their patrons. The debates revolved around child protection issues especially SEC. Out of school children were reached through the community football tournament organized by Community CRC;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="350"></target>
     <actual value="200">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity had been Planned to be implemented in quarter 2 of 2020 but the planning was interfeared with the Covid -19 pandemic, since the government has allowed gatherings with permission from the county commanders/ coordinators office, the activity will be implemented in November 2020. The Project team engaged Project children from the camps in Budalangi in Community Child Rights Clubs. From the 4 camps that our beneficiaries were placed as a result of floods that destroyed their homes and properties, children asked the project team if they can be engaging their time especially now that schools have closed. The Project team organized them into clubs and have been meeting twice a week. During the Community Child Rights clubs, children engage in different activities such as educative;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="400"></target>
     <actual value="551">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The funds were spent as budgeted only that the activities involving schools were pushed to the year 2021 because of covid pandemic. 360 girls and 191 boys participated in Community Child Rights Clubs. The project team organized children from the communities where they met and discussed child protection matters. Child used these community child rights clubs to report cases of CSEC and other child exploitations and abuses from communities. 13 cases of  CSEC, 34 cases of child labour, 7 cases of child trafficking and 15 cases of neglect were reported by children during these meetings.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="419">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This are balances for the last quarter of 2020. The CRC patrons and CHD were trained  as planned. 419 children (267 girls 152 boys) were directly reached. The children&apos;s knowledge on how to protect themselves from CSEC during COVID 19 pandemic was also enhanced. This was made possible through the Child Rights Club sessions that take place every week. This took place in schools and was made possible through consultations with the County and Sub County Education Directors. It was important to equip teachers with counseling skills to enable them respond effectively to children anxiety in schools due to the COVID pandemic effects on children and their familes;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">the budget was realocated to support project families with skills through trainings to better manage their small businesses thereby supporting their children stay in school;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
