<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41149287-TZCT0369</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41149287" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Countering CT for DL in Ukerewe district- Mwanza, Tanzania</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&amp;nbsp;
The project aims to reduce child trafficking for domestic labour in Ukerewe district, Mwanza region, which is both a source and destination area.&amp;nbsp;The project implementation will employ five&amp;nbsp;strategies&amp;nbsp;including prevention, provision, promotion, prosecution,&amp;nbsp;participation and partnership&amp;nbsp;while targeting five actors: The children, families and communities, the government,&amp;nbsp;Law enforcement agencies, and the private sector.&amp;nbsp;The project life is one year and will be implemented in partnership with KIWOHEDE.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kiota Women Health &amp; Development organisation - KIWOHEDE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41149287-TZCT0369" ref="NL-KVK-41149287" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41149287-TZCT0369" ref="NL-KVK-41149287" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0)70-310 5000</telephone>
   <email>info@tdh.nl</email>
   <website>https://www.terredeshommes.nl</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">88617</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">205607</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">87351</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">217884</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41149287-5008" type="1"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41149287-TZCT0299" type="3"></related-activity>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">125 Girls receive educational services  [100 exploited,  25 vulnerable to trafficking for DL]</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">125 Girls receive educational services  [100 exploited,  25 vulnerable to trafficking for DL]</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Girls exploited and vulnerable to trafficking received educational services (100 exploited, 25 vulnerable)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Girls exploited and vulnerable to trafficking received educational services (100 exploited, 25 vulnerable)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="55"></target>
     <actual value="55">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">55 children were given educational support.  50 exploited children were enrolled in vocational educational training at St. Dominic Vocational Training College. These were provided with school fees, school uniforms and stationeries. Another 5 vulnerable children were provided with scholastic materials which included school uniforms, bags, exercise books, mathematical set, pens, pencils and rulers.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
     <actual value="75">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">75 children received educational support: 55 girls (25 secondary, 30 primary schools) were provided with scholastic materials including school uniforms, exercise books, school bags, mathematical sets, pens, rulers and pencils. 20 exploited girls were enrolled in vocational educational training and   were provided with school fees, school uniforms and stationeries needs.
Results, 
The support of scholastic materials to children has contributed in improved school attendance and academic performance among the beneficiaries.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this quarter the project conducted follow up to 125 exploited and vulnerable girls, 55 who were supported with scholastic materials, children are progressing well with their studies, 70 girls who were supported with vocational training are able to design and sew clothes and make products like liquid soap for mopping.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">50 Boys exploited/vulnerable to trafficking for DL received educational services (35 exploited, 15 Vulnerable) [35 exploited, 15 Vulnerable]</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">50 Boys exploited/vulnerable to trafficking for DL received educational services (35 exploited, 15 Vulnerable) [35 exploited, 15 Vulnerable]</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#  of  vulnerable/exploited boys received educational services (35 exploited, 15 Vulnerable)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#  of  vulnerable/exploited boys received educational services (35 exploited, 15 Vulnerable)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During this reporting period a total of 15 children (5 Vulnerable, 10 exploited) who are integrated in primary and secondary schools received educational support which includes scholastic materials including school uniforms, exercise books, school bags, mathematical sets, pens, rulers and pencils.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
     <actual value="35">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During this reporting period a total of 35 children (10 Vulnerable, 25 exploited) among them 5 boys in  secondary schools received educational support which included school uniforms, exercise books, school bags, mathematical sets, pens, rulers and pencils. 30 exploited boys were supported to enroll at St. Dominic vocational educational training college to pursue mechanics, plumbing and fitting, automotive electronics, basic computer application, domestic and industrial electrical installation courses. Their educational support included school fees, school uniforms and stationeries..;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting time the project conducted follow up to 50 exploited and vulnerable boys (20 were supported with scholastic materials at school level. Boys are progressing well with their studies. 30 boys enrolled with vocational training are progressing well and they are able to   install electrical home boards.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">50 cases of trafficking for child labor are filed in the judicial system and followed-up on by partners</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">50 cases of trafficking for child labor are filed in the judicial system and followed-up on by partners</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of court cases followed up/attended by partners</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of court cases followed up/attended by partners</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="25">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the reporting period, 69 cases were followed up. 14 of them are under investigation; 8 awaiting repayment of wages and 3 cases before the  court of law for institutional or criminal procedures. Out of the rescued 116 children ( 101 girls, 15 boys), 116 cases were filed to the police stations, 44 cases were closed due to lack of vital information because children failed to identify the physical address of the trafficker. The remaining 47 cases of unsafe migration were referred to the District Social Welfare Office for further intervention including family support and counseling.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During this reporting period, the project in collaboration with the local government authorities and volunteers from SAU Law school conducted 5 legal aid sessions within the project wards of Murutunguru,Muriti, Ilangala,Bukanda and Bwisya where  304 community members (187F,117M) were reached.
The project   conducted follow-up to the 32 law enforcers (19M,13F) and discussed issues around child trafficking and prosecution of perpetrators of child trafficking and gaps which contribute to the delay of investigations and opening of court case files.
The follow ups identified that 11 cases (9 girls, 2 boys) 6 cases of unsafe migration were filed to different police stations (Ukara, Mururtunguru, Muriti ) while,5cases (2boys and 3 girls)  of CT were investgated and filed at Nansio police station.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this quarter, the project followed up 7 cases of CT which were filled to different police stations including 1 Ukara, 4 Nansio and 2 Muriti. Where 4 cases are in the investigation stage, 2 cases children were paid their wages and 1 case is at the court for hearing.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting period 10 cases of child trafficking were filed at different police stations: Nansio, Ukara, Mururtunguru  and Muriti. Where by 2 cases are before the court of law for defence session and 8 cases are still in the investigation stage.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting time 30 children (7 boys, 23 girls) were rescued and their cases were filed to different police stations (Ukara, Nansio and Muriti) where 12 cases were followed up where 4 cases are in the investigation stage, 5 cases children were paid their wages and 3 cases are at the court for hearing. 5 cases of unsafe migration were referred to the social welfare office for further intervention such as counseling and food support and 13 cases were closed due to the element of trafficking was not determined.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Boys victims of CT for DL immediately safeguarded-50</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Boys victims of CT for DL immediately safeguarded-50</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of boys immediately safeguarded</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of boys immediately safeguarded</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15 boys who were victims of CTM for CL such as domestic works and fishing activities were identified, rescued and referred to FIT persons for safeguarding and counseling.13 children were successfully reunified with their families in Ukerewe (6 children), Bunda (4 children), Simiyu (2 children) and 1 children in Musoma. 2 children are still safeguarded by fit persons while the project continue with family reconciliation.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During this reporting period, the project identified and safeguarded  12 boys who were victims of trafficking for domestic labour.These boys were identified through house withdrawal visits (1 child was identified), 3 children were reported by WCPTs, I child was reported from the fishing sites, 3 children were reported by community members, 1 child was referred by police and young reporters identified  3 children.These boys were sheltered to the  trained FIT person where they  received psycho-social support.
The project  reintegrated 9 children with their families in the districts of Bunda (3 children), Musoma (2 children), Ngara (1 child) and Ukara island (3 children). 3 children are still sheltered to FIT person waiting for  family reconciliation which  is in progress.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this quarter 07 children who were victims of CTM for CL were identified, rescued and referred to FIT persons for safeguarding and counseling. 5 children were successfully reunified with their families. 2 children are still safeguarded by fit persons while the family reconciliation is going on.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="21">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting period,21boys victims of child trafficking and unsafe migration for child labour such as domestic works and fishing activities were identified and rescued through various ways including report from leaders of beach management unity 7,community members 2,WCPTs 3,club leaders6 and door to door visits3.The Rescued children were referred to the FIT persons for safeguarding and were provided with psychosocial support and awareness on the risks of CL and CTM,personal hygiene,puberty and child rights.
The project reintegrated 18 children with their families in Bunda(4children), Musoma (2children),Chato (1children),Misungwi 2 children and  9 children from Ukerewe.3 children are still safeguarded by FIT persons waiting for family reconciliation which is in progress to be completed;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting time 8 boys who are victims of CTM were identified, rescued and referred to fits person shelter and psychosocial support. 5 children were successfully reunified with their families 3 children in Ukerewe and 2 children in Kigoma while 3 children are still safeguarded by fit persons while the family reconciliation is going on.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child victims of trafficking and those at risk (re) claim their protection rights, have access to psychosocial and educational services, and report cases related to trafficking</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child victims of trafficking and those at risk (re) claim their protection rights, have access to psychosocial and educational services, and report cases related to trafficking</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># and/or  % of targeted exploited and vulnerable children who know when, where and how to formally report trafficking risks</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># and/or  % of targeted exploited and vulnerable children who know when, where and how to formally report trafficking risks</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="225">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">From the recent evaluation carried out, of the 225 children interviewed 85.8% of the children participants both male and female know the legal actions to take when a child has been trafficked for domestic work. Most of the males 89.7% compared to the female 82.8% knew the measures to take against child trafficking.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Furthermore, the government has allocated a special budget to provide CWDs with food at school level as informed by the educational officer. Previously most of the CWD skipped lunch due to inability to run home for lunch during the lunch break coupled with limited resources at the family level to carry packed lunc;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Furthermore, the government has allocated a special budget to provide CWDs with food at school level as informed by the educational officer. Previously most of the CWD skipped lunch due to inability to run home for lunch during the lunch break coupled with limited resources at the family level to carry packed lunch;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x161;&#xC2;&#xAC;&#xC3;&#x201A;&#xC2;&#xA2;	Furthermore, the government has allocated a special budget to provide CWDs with food at school level as informed by the educational officer. Previously most of the CWD skipped lunch due to inability to run home for lunch during the lunch break coupled with limited resources at the family level to carry packed lunch;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of Children (victims and vulnerable)  accessing Child Protection services in Mwanza</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of Children (victims and vulnerable)  accessing Child Protection services in Mwanza</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children with special needs and the vulnerable are enrolling for free medical check up and treatment as confirmed by the district social welfare officer in the district. This follows the project&apos;s continuous lobby with the government for inclusion of children with disabilities.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children with special needs and the vulnerable are enrolling for free medical check up and treatment as confirmed by the district social welfare officer in the district. This follows the project&apos;s continuous lobby with the government for inclusion of children with disabilities.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="165">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 165 children so far rescued by the project received safeguarding at the rescue center, psycho social support, legal aid. 46 cases of CTM are at various levels of prosecution processes.  However, finalization of prosecution of CT cases showed little progress. There are gaps within the trafficking law and inadequate resources to support law enforcers as well as unwilling witnesses.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x161;&#xC2;&#xAC;&#xC3;&#x201A;&#xC2;&#xA2;	Children with special needs and the vulnerable are enrolling for free medical check up and treatment as confirmed by the district social welfare officer in the district. This follows the project&apos;s continuous lobby with the government for inclusion of children with disabilities.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community members with exploited/abused/vulnerable children reached with awareness raising activities -10,000</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community members with exploited/abused/vulnerable children reached with awareness raising activities -10,000</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of community members with  exploited/abused/vulnerable children reached with awareness raising activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of community members with  exploited/abused/vulnerable children reached with awareness raising activities</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1000"></target>
     <actual value="1060">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the  reporting period,the project organized various awareness sessions on child trafficking and unsafe migration, child rights, child labour and parenting skills, and risks of CTM. The awareness messages were delivered during the Parenting Skills training to 300 parents,monthly community dialogues, community outreach/sensitization visits and counseling of families with exploited children during the reunification process.These sessions reached  a total of 1060 community members (591F, 469M) who also   reported 8 cases related to child trafficking and unsafe migration to the relevant authorities, Trained parents and care-givers have commitment to generate sufficient livelihood to support their children&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x161;&#xC2;&#xAC;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x17E;&#xC2;&#xA2;s well being as witnessed by community leaders during follow up visit.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3000"></target>
     <actual value="3197">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In quarter three the project reached out 3,197 community members (1461 M, 1736 F) through community outreach/sensitization, monthly community dialogues and radio sessions.
Sign of change:
Achievement, community members dialogue on child rights protection and report cases, 22 cases ( 4 of child abandonment, 3 unsafe migration,  5 child trafficking, 3 of exploitation and 7 of child abuse) were reported to KIWOHEDE, 8 cases of CTM were referred to police and 14 cases of child abuse/exploitation were referred to the social welfare office for resolutions.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3000"></target>
     <actual value="3029">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this quarter the project managed to reach out to 3,029 community members (1464M, 1565 F) through monthly community dialogues, community outreach/sensitization, family counseling and radio sessions.
Sign of change:
Community members are becoming more aware of the risk of child trafficking for domestic labour, for example 21 cases related to child trafficking and exploitation were reported to KIWOHEDE staff by community members during the dialogues;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="693">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this quarter time the project reached out 693 community members ( 265 male,428 female ) through family counseling, sensitization visits and village gatherings which was attended by the project staff for awareness raising on the issues of CR and protection, effect of trafficking and where to report cases, roles of parents/caregivers to ensure their children met basic needs and they are free from exploitations/abuses.  .
Observed changes ;
The sensitized communities members respond by promoting CR and report cases of  CT and other forms of abuse.  12 cases  were reported to relevant authorities(2 cases of CT at muriti police post, 3 unsafe migration at Nansio ward  office, 5 cases of abandoned children to District social welfare office, 2 cases of physical abuse  to Nansio police station);</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3000"></target>
     <actual value="3692">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project conducted various awareness sessions on CTM through, monthly community dialogues and  community outreach/sensitization and radio sessions. A total of 3,692 community members (1,638 F, 2,054 M) participated and also   reported11 cases related to child trafficking and unsafe migration to the relevant authorities.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Exploited/abused boys received legal advice-120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Exploited/abused boys received legal advice-120</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of exploited/abused boys received legal advice</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of exploited/abused boys received legal advice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A total of 7 boys received legal advice, the sessions focused on CR in accordance with the child Act of 2009 and risk of child trafficking and unsafe migration, other forms of illegal labour, case reporting systems, case documentation and management. Sign of change:  The legal aid has empowered children in reporting cases to the relevant authorities such as police, ward offices and other actors involved in child rights protection, for example 2 boys who received legal aid rescued their fellow child who is a boy from hazardous work and report him to KIWOHEDE&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x161;&#xC2;&#xAC;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x17E;&#xC2;&#xA2;S shelter who then referred a case to Nansio police for further interventions.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="20">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the reporting period,the project supported  20 boys victims of trafficking with legal advice. The sessions focused on the Child Act of 2009, reporting mechanisms of CT cases, labour relations laws and how to give statements to police during interviews and before the court of laws.
Achievement: The project  supported by 2 boys to file at Muriti and Nansio police stations where children expressed themselves with confidence during the interviews with police unlikely before the intervention, both cases are in the initial stage of investigation.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting period the project provided legal advice and counselling to 50 boys. These included the 15 rescued boys and their 35 siblings. The sessions focused on how to give a statement to a police officer, to swear before giving evidence, child responsibility, evidence before the court of law, the laws of evidence, child rights, Labour relation Act of 2004, child trafficking and unsafe migration.
Sign of change: Engaged  children were able to express their needs and seek justice from relevant authorities such as police, school administration and WEOs;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting time a total of 50 children (21 victims of CTM, 29 victims of other abuses) received legal advice, the sessions focused on how to give a statement to a police officer, swearing in court, evidence before the court of law, child rights, child trafficking and unsafe migration.
Sign of change: The children provided evidence concerning their exploitation cases without fear of being arrested. Previously the children thought that they would be arrested if they reported cases of abuse to police and that they would be locked up until the judicial process was completed.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project managed to provide legal advice to 8 boys regarding issues of CR and CT according to the Child Act of 2009, Anti Trafficking in persons Act of 2008, child abuse and case reporting system.
Sign of change; The legal aid provided to boys has been a great help to children in knowing their rights and responsibilities and to those who are victims has helped them to be able to give evidence and report to the police station and the Court as a whole.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Exploited/abused girls received legal advice-180</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Exploited/abused girls received legal advice-180</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of exploited/abused girls received legal advice</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of exploited/abused girls received legal advice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">12 girls received legal advice, the sessions focused on CR in accordance with the child Act of 2009, risk of child trafficking and unsafe migration, forms of illegal labour, case reporting systems and case documentation and management.
Sign of change, 8 girls who received legal aid were able to give their statement before the law enforcement agencies, Unlikely before the intervention;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
     <actual value="73">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">85 girls received legal advice, the sessions focused on how to give a statement to a police officer, to swear before giving evidence, child responsibility, evidence before the court of law, the laws of evidence, child rights, Labour rights, child trafficking and unsafe migration.
Sign of change, 21 children gave evidence before the law enforcement agencies. Previously children would shy away from giving evidence for fear that they would be arrested for being away from their homes;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="21">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A total of 21 girls received legal advice which focused on CR and CT according to the Child Act of 2009, Anti Trafficking in persons Act of 2008, child abuse and case reporting system.
Sign of change, the legal aid provided to girls has been a great help to children in knowing their rights and responsibilities and to those who are victims has helped them to be able to give evidence and report to the police station and the Court as a whole.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="22">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A total of 22 children received legal advice sessions focused on the Child Act of 2009, reporting mechanisms of CT cases, labour relations laws and how to give statements to police during interviews and before the court of laws.
These sessions increased the awareness of children about their rights and how to claim them.For example 13 exploited children reported their cases to relevant authorities.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="80">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During this reporting time, 80 girls received legal advice, the sessions focused on how to give a statement to a police officer, to swear before giving evidence, evidence before the court of law, the laws of evidence, child rights, child trafficking and unsafe migration.
Results, The children were able to give evidence before the court of law without fearing.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Families with children at risk of trafficking or re-trafficking supported to initiate Income Generating Activities (IGA)-80</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Families with children at risk of trafficking or re-trafficking supported to initiate Income Generating Activities (IGA)-80</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#of families with children at risk of trafficking or re-trafficking benefitting from IGAs</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#of families with children at risk of trafficking or re-trafficking benefitting from IGAs</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="80">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the  reporting period, the project in collaboration with the Social Welfare Office, identified  80 families (27 male, 53 female) whose children were at risk or victims of child trafficking  and trained them on alternative income activities.The project also  supported each family with startup capital  of 100,000 TZS for initiating  income generating activities.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the quarter 4, the project conducted follow up visits to 27 families out of 80 families of exploited and vulnerable children who were provided with IGAs support. The aim was to monitor the progress of their entrepreneurship activities and challenges they face.
Challenges; inadequate of sardines which challenge the circulation of business
Sign of change.
20 families out of 27 which were supported families with IGA are able to provide basic needs such as food and scholastic materials to their children.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this quarter 28 of the 80 families with exploited/vulnerable children  who were supported to initiate IGAs were visited. 21 families have made good progress in their entrepreneurship activities such as 5 in selling sardines, 3 in poultry raising, 8 in selling fresh fish  and vegetables and  5 in selling grain. These families are able to  support their children with school needs, foods and clothes. 7 families have stopped  their business of selling fruits due to seasonal market challenges.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this quarter the project conducted follow up to 25 of 80 families with exploited/vulnerable children. The aim of the follow up was to monitor the progress of their entrepreneurship activities after being supported on IGA. 23 families are in a good progress on their entrepreneurship of selling sardines, poultry raising, selling fresh fishes, selling grains and vegetables. 2 families are still facing a challenge of seasonal markets selling fruits.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity was implemented in Q 4 2020.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Families, community members and private sector actors in Ukerewe are aware of the dangers and report cases of child trafficking and unsafe migration for domestic labour to the established reporting structures.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Families, community members and private sector actors in Ukerewe are aware of the dangers and report cases of child trafficking and unsafe migration for domestic labour to the established reporting structures.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of targeted households, Community mebers and private sector actors in Ukerewe that are  aware of dangers  of child trafficking &amp; associated reporting mechanisms</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of targeted households, Community mebers and private sector actors in Ukerewe that are  aware of dangers  of child trafficking &amp; associated reporting mechanisms</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">From the recent evaluation. 95% of the 210 caregivers know the illegality of child trafficking. 81.5 %  of the 210 interviewed caregivers knew where to report or get help if they encountered or witnessed a case of child trafficking;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The endline evaluation of phase 1 found out that 95% of the 210 caregivers interviewed know the illegality of child trafficking. 81.5 %  of them knew where to report or get help if they encountered or witnessed a case of child trafficking. The endline of the current phase will determine the increase in awareness among the family and community members;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The endline evaluation of phase 1 found out that 95% of the 210 caregivers interviewed know the illegality of child trafficking. 81.5 %  of them knew where to report or get help if they encountered or witnessed a case of child trafficking. The endline of the current phase will determine the increase in awareness among the family and community members;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Girls victims of CT for DL immediately safeguarded-250</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Girls victims of CT for DL immediately safeguarded-250</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of girls immediately safeguarded</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of girls immediately safeguarded</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="102">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">102 girls who were victims of trafficking for child labour were rescued.69 of them were safeguarded at the KIWOHEDE&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x161;&#xC2;&#xAC;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x17E;&#xC2;&#xA2;s shelter while 33 were referred to FIT persons.The girls were identified through various ways:club leaders reported(12),WCPTs(13),private sectors(3),door to door visits (8),community members(13), peer educators (36),young reporters (2),Social Welfare office(8)and police who referred(7).The rescued children were provided with temporary shelter, psycho-social support food, clothes,life skills,dignity kits,legal aid and some of them received educational support.the project conducted family tracing for102 children.78 children were successfully reunified ,18 are still safeguarded with various fit persons while 6 children are at the DIC awaiting reintegration.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
     <actual value="33">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During this reporting period, 33 girls who were victims of child trafficking and unsafe migration for domestic work were rescued and safeguarded at the project shelter  in Ukerewe.  21 children were reunified with their families in Ukerewe (11 children), 2 children in Bunda, 3 children in Shinyanga, 1 child in Chato, 2 children in Geita, 2 children in Musoma, 1 child in Tarime and Sengerema( 1 child).  A total of 56 children (39 girls, 17 boys) participated in life skills sessions at the project shelter.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="23">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting time a 23 girls who were victims of trafficking for child labour were rescued. 16 of them were safeguarded at the KIWOHEDE&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x161;&#xC2;&#xAC;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x17E;&#xC2;&#xA2;s shelter and 7 were referred to FIT persons, rescued girls were provided with different services such as psychosocial support including counseling, food, clothes, life skills, dignity kits, legal aid and educational support.
The project conducted family tracing to 23 girls where 18 girls were successfully reunified with their families while 5 girls are still receiving psycho social support and family tracing is on progress for their families.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="101">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting time a total 101 girls who were victims of trafficking for child labour were rescued. 62 of them were safeguarded at the KIWOHEDE&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x161;&#xC2;&#xAC;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x17E;&#xC2;&#xA2;s shelter. 23 of them were sheltered for 3 to 5 days as recommended  by the district social welfare officer  before they were  reintegrated  to allow them continue in school while the project is supporting them  with services like food, legal aid counselling and educational support at the family leve. 39 were referred to FIT persons. The project conducted family tracing to 101 girls where 85 girls were successfully reunified with their families while16 girls (9 at the DIC and 7 to FIT person) are still receiving psychosocial support and family tracing is on progress for their families;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="21">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting time, 21 girls victims of CTM for CL were identified, rescued and safeguarded by the project. 6 children out of 21 were referred to fit persons and 15 girls were sheltered at the DIC and provided with psychosocial support including counseling, food, clothes , legal advice, dignity kits, medical care, life skills education and reunification with their families.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government actors (service providers)  and CSO in Ukerewe adopt and implement child friendly case management practices by December 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government actors (service providers)  and CSO in Ukerewe adopt and implement child friendly case management practices by December 2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># and %  of cases handled in a child friendly manner by the targeted service providers (CSOs, Police, judicially, Social Welfare officers)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># and %  of cases handled in a child friendly manner by the targeted service providers (CSOs, Police, judicially, Social Welfare officers)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The law enforcers indicated that they are now conducting an investigation in a friendly manner. Although the evaluator was unable to establish the accuracy of this claim the project staff noted that almost all (about 90%) of the gender and children desk police investigators exercise confidentiality and interview children in civilian clothes to avoid creating a mental gap in their interview social relationship. However, the evaluation found that the children are still facing a challenge of accommodation during the investigation of the cases.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project staff noted that almost all (about 90%) of the gender and children desk police investigators exercise confidentiality and interview children in civilian clothes to avoid creating a mental gap in their interview social relationship. ,;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project staff noted that almost all (about 90%) of the gender and children desk police investigators exercise confidentiality and interview children in civilian clothes to avoid creating a mental gap in their interview social relationship;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># and % of targeted government officials [police/social workers] in Ukerewe Islands using child friendly interview techniques</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># and % of targeted government officials [police/social workers] in Ukerewe Islands using child friendly interview techniques</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the endline evaluation of phase one, 40.3% of the 89 caregivers interviewed indicated that cases of child trafficking were handled in a child friendly manner. The law enforcers said that they were conducting investigations in a child-friendly manner. The evaluation found that the children are still facing a challenge of accommodation during the investigation of the case;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the endline evaluation of phase one, 40.3% of the 89 caregivers interviewed indicated that cases of child trafficking were handled in a child friendly manner. The law enforcers said that they were conducting investigations in a child-friendly manner. The evaluation found that the children are still facing a challenge of accommodation during the investigation of the cases.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">From a recent evaluation 40.3% of the 89 caregivers interviewed indicated that cases of child trafficking were handled in a child friendly manner. The evaluator found mixed findings related to investigations and prosecution of child trafficking cases. The law enforcers and police force are well trained on the investigation of CTM Cases and admit to have started to play a critical role to investigate more cases. The evaluation confirmed that the cases on child trafficking are now being acted upon contrary to what used to happen before the project was introduced.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government and CSOs implement improved referral pathways</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government and CSOs implement improved referral pathways</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of cases referred to using referral pathways</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of cases referred to using referral pathways</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the reporting period, the project referred 3 CWDs   to CHAWATA   for further services. 17 children (boys) were referred to FIT persons for shelter and 2 children referred to the District Social Welfare Officer and District Education officer for educational support. Moreover the project conducted meetings with 69 stakeholders (41 M, 28F) including CSOs, government officials and law enforcers involved in the referral pathway. The aim was to strengthen referral linkage services to children victims of CT and other forms of abuses.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this quarter the project referred 3 children with CWDs (2 with dumb and 1 with physical disability) to district social welfare officer for medical treatment through medical exemption programs.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="7"></target>
     <actual value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this quarter, a total of 9 CWDs were referred by KIWOHEDE: 2 girls with albinism to Standing Voice to be provided with sunscreen and other skin protection items from the albinism support programme. 2 girls with hearing impairment to Lake Victoria Children for educational support and counselling,  1 boy with visual impairment to Faith Community Initiatives for medical support and 4 boys with physical disability to CHAWATA   for educational and psychosocial support;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting period the project refereed 5 children, 1 girl with albinism was referred to standing voice, she was provided with skin protection items for people with albinism, 3 boys and 1 girl with hearing impairment were referred to Lake Victoria Children for supporting them with learning materials such as pictures, videos and slides for people with hearing impairment.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting period, the project referred 6 CWDs   to Standing Voice and CHAWATA   for educational support, special needs to children with physical disabilities and albinism. 
A total of 69 were reached through training of CSOs, quarterly Coordination meetings and meetings with local government authorities.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private sector actors create action plans to prevent and respond to CTM in their operations and supply chains- 25</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private sector actors create action plans to prevent and respond to CTM in their operations and supply chains- 25</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#of private sector actors who have created action plans</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#of private sector actors who have created action plans</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the reporting period, the project organized a meeting with 25 representatives from 10 private sectors (17Male, 8Female) in Ukerewe district. The meeting was conducted on December 2020 that facilitated the private sectors to develop action plans that would end child labour and child trafficking at their working places and in transport routes. All the participants agreed that   underage children will not be employed in their working stations. The private sector also agreed to establish bylaws that would protect children from all forms of abuse in their firms. Transport owners (Bus, Tax, Ships, motorcycle and canoes) agreed to crosscheck information of children in move prior to boarding and to report cases of child trafficking to the relevant authorities.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this quarter the project conducted follow up visits to 15 private sector entities that involved  20  representatives (13 M, 7 F) of private sectors who are actively responding on child rights protection. It was noted that the private sector entities had put in place a recruitment regulation  that bars them from employing child labourers in their working stations such as fishing camps, cafeteria, restaurants, shipping  ports  and Bars, by ensuring no child is employed;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this quarter the project managed to conduct a follow up to 15 representatives of private sectors (6 F, 9 M) were reached out through follow up visits to 15 entities .
Observed changes;  the engaged fisheries groups have formulated regulations which prohibit involving children into fishing activities such as collecting sardines and fishing nets along the shore lines in Ukerewe. This has seen as a change in the village of Bukanda and Namsabo no children are engaged in fishing activities unlikely before the project implementation that was believed most of children were involved in fishing activities and increased school dropout.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting period 18 representatives of private sectors (7 F, 11M) were reached out through follow up visits to 15 entities .It was observed that the entities respond in promoting child rights and enters into dialogue against child exploitation, to ensure all laws and regulations of employment are in accordance with the employment and labour relation Act of 2004.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project organized and conducted a dialogue with 15 private sector entities on issues of CT. 80 representatives (59male,21female) participated. Agenda discussed included the role of private actors in preventing CT for CL, provisions of  the Laws such as Child Act and Anti-TIP Act.Action agreed, No child under the age of 18 will be employed in their working stations.Engaged private sectors agreed to be responsible in identifying and rescuing victims of CTM as well  as provide awareness to other colleagues.Result,private sector actors are actively engaged in dialogues on child rights and protection as well as reporting cases related to CTM, for example 10 cases of child trafficking and unsafe migration were reported to KIWOHEDE and at Nansio and Ukara police stations for further actions.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Religious leaders are aware of dangers of CT and unsafe migration and share this information in their communities - 20</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Religious leaders are aware of dangers of CT and unsafe migration and share this information in their communities - 20</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of religious leaders who are educated/sensitized on CT (and mention it/hold sessions in their community)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of religious leaders who are educated/sensitized on CT (and mention it/hold sessions in their community)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the reporting period, 20 religious leaders (15M, 5F) from three (3) religious institute (Christianity, Islamic and Pentecostal)  representatives includes RC, KKKT, Anglican, SDA, TAG, EAGT, FPCT, PTC, AICT, Muslim (Aljazeera, Markas), EFATHA, Ukombozi and, Mashahidi wa Yehova on December 2020 were  involved in the dialogue session about CP,CTM and their roles in protecting children. The participants agreed to cascade the agenda of child trafficking and unsafe migration through their teachings. They also agreed to provide counseling to families with conflict in order to curb incidences of unsafe migration and child trafficking as well as teaching issues of child rights and risk of CT and child abuse through existing Madrasa and Sunday schools.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7"></target>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this quarter seven (7) religious institute includes RC, Anglican, SDA, PAG, FPCT, AICT, Muslim and the District social welfare officer were involved in the dialogue sessions.The dialogue involved 20 religious leaders (18M,2F). Issues discussed were child rights, child protection, child trafficking, the role of religious leaders on countering child trafficking and other forms of abuse, awareness raising on positive parenting skills.
Religious leaders recommended that Social welfare officers expand parenting skills knowledge to indigenous groups where abuses and child trafficking mostly originate due to lack of knowledge of the negative effects of CTM.
Action plan agreed: The religious leaders committed to integrate and make CTM an agenda of discussions in their religious congregations.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this quarter, the project managed to conduct follow up visit to sensitized religious leaders  whereas 7 religious institutions were reached with a total of   9 religious leaders (7 M, 2 F) who were engaged in awareness raising on child rights, importance of education and risk of trafficking into child labour.   
Changes observed; Religious leaders actively engage in awareness raising through religious gathering and responding on identifying and rescuing the victims of trafficking and unsafe migration. For example 2 cases of unsafe migration reported to the KIWOHEDE office for further intervention.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting period, the project reached out 20 religious leaders (18M, 2F) from 5 religious institutes including Islamic, FPCT, TAG, EAGT and catholic. Issues discussed were concept of CTM, governing laws for child protection the roles of religious leaders in awareness raising on CT, Gender based violence, risk of child labour, child care and parenting skills.
Achievement, religious leaders actively engaged in awareness raising on CTM and child exploitation in their teaching. 7 sessions were conducted by the leaders from SDA, Islamic, TAG and FPCT as determined during the follow up.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting period,the project conducted a dialogue with 20 religious leaders (13M, 7 F) by involving five (5) institutes of Islamic, RC, SDA, CAG and EAGT on the concept of CTM, roles of religious leaders in promoting CR and awareness raising on child rights and protection, governing laws on countering child trafficking and other form of abuses.
 Issues agreed:
Religious leaders to become agents of change in promoting and awareness raising on CTM in their gatherings. 
Religious leaders in their position agreed to rally together key players in their jurisdiction in supporting the implementation of the project to ensure anticipated results are attained.
Religious leaders offer social support to the vulnerable children in collaboration with the local authorities.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social worker and police officials (75) capacities built in case management and child-friendly interviewing techniques</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social worker and police officials (75) capacities built in case management and child-friendly interviewing techniques</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of government officials trained</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of government officials trained</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="35"></target>
     <actual value="35">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the  reporting period, a total of 144 (101M, 43F) including 35 government official from distinct/ward and 40 community leaders at village/hamlet levels   were trained on child trafficking and on how to respond on child right protections. The training was facilitated by the District Community Development Officer in Ukerewe. Action plan agreed, participants agreed to implement guidelines of the   NPA-VAWC, to sensitize  community through public meetings on the impact of child trafficking and gender based violence, the issue of CT to be the permanent agenda in  the WDC/village meetings, ward and village officer to act upon and monitor employers of CDW and ensure that employers in their areas of jurisdiction  abide to labour laws and child rights.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this quarter the project conducted follow up visits to 135 members of NPA-VAWC (97 M, 38 F) from the project areas. That aimed to get feedback (achievement and challenges) from the trained government officials and NPA committees members against CTM and GBV. 
Achievement. Trained members of NPA-VAWC actively support the implementation of the project through awareness raising, identifying and taking actions against reported cases in collaboration with other stakeholders to ensure justice to victims. For example in this quarter 12 cases of CT were successfully filed at the police station, out of 12 cases 3 are at the court.  
Challenges, 
&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x201A;&#xAC;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x9D;&#xC3;&#x201A;&#xC2;&#x8F;	Limited budget to support the NPA-VAWC implementation from village level to district level.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this quarter the project conducted follow up visits to 98 ( 67M, 31 F) trained members of NPA VAWC on monitoring the progress of the project in handling cases of CT and other child abuse.
 
Results, The trained NPA VAWC are committed to to promote child rights and protection by awareness raising through community rallies and respond on identifying, rescue and reporting cases, for example 5 children who are victims of CTM for CL were rescued and referred to KIWOHEDE for further intervention.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="40"></target>
     <actual value="40">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting time, a total of  40 government officials ( 26 male, 14 female) from distinct and ward were trained on  CT, Community engagements in preventing and responding incidences of CTM into domestic works and other forms of abuse and on how to assist victims  of child trafficking, the roles of NPA-VAWC committees and WCPTs for CR protections.The training was facilitated by District immagration officer and social welfare officer in Ukerewe.
Issues agreed, trained government officials from the department of Social welfare, community development, police, immigration and education to provide education to other government officials who were not engaged in the training as well as the communities, Cases involving CT to be given priority for investigation.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">n this reporting time, the project conducted follow up visits to the previously trained 144 members of NPA-VAWC (102 M, 43 F): 75 government officials and 69 other members of NPA-VAWC from district to village levels in the project areas. The follow up aimed to get feedback on the implementation of NPA against child trafficking and gender based violence which is still a persistent challenge in their community. 
Results: Members of NPA- are accountable in taking actions against CTM incidences, for example in three months (April to June) 20 cases 11 unsafe migrations and 9 child trafficking were reported to ward offices and police stations of Nansio, Ukara and Muriti.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vulnerable  children participate in awareness raising sessions</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vulnerable  children participate in awareness raising sessions</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of vulnerable children participate in awareness raising sessions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of vulnerable children participate in awareness raising sessions</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="255">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">255children(115boys,140girls)participated in awareness raising activities through interschool dialogues and debates on CR, CT and GBV, drafting and displaying messages of CTM and GBV for awareness raising.  
Changes observed: Club members from 4 schools conducted inter school events on debates and games competition with 4 neighbor schools, 103 club members (48 boys and 55 girls) participated in the debates. The inter school events influenced other 6 schools to establish suggestion boxes for communication channels of their own resources
Lesson learnt, peer educators are well committed for awareness raising and cases reporting,For example 19 cases, 14 of CTM were reported to 5 KIWOHEDE, 9 to ward/village executive offices and 5 cases of child dropout were reported to school guardians.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="625"></target>
     <actual value="646">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A total of 646 children (338 girls, 308 boys) participated in awareness raising activities via radio sessions, CR Tuseme clubs, and community sensitizations with children, follow up with peer educators and commemoration of the world day against Trafficking in Persons. Various issues were discussed including importance of education, gender based violence, communication and case reporting, concept of CTM, child rights, child labour and abuses.
Achievement 
Children have confidence and act as agent of change in promoting CR and report cases related to CTM. 33 cases (26 related to CTM, 7 of school dropout) were reported to KIWOHEDE, village offices, teachers and police and were referred social welfare office for further actions.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="625"></target>
     <actual value="873">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the reporting period, 873 children (447 girls, 426 boys) participated in awareness raising sessions on child rights and child trafficking through sensitization sessions,  Tuseme CRs clubs, drafting messages for IEC materials and commemoration of 16 days of activism against gender based violence. 
Achievements; 
Children improved their ability of expressing  their views/needs to the duty bearers.
Increased awereness by  children on the  risk of child labour and on how to protect themselves from being trafficked.
Improved feedback mechanisms through the  use  of the suggestion boxes. For example 6 cases related to CTM were reported by peer educators through suggestion boxes installed by the project in their schools.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="625"></target>
     <actual value="634">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Jan-March 2021, 634 children (391 girls, 243 boys) participated in awareness raising sessions on CRs and CTM through child led radio sessions,Tuseme CRs clubs,follow up with peer educators,child feedback sessions and commemoration of the day of the international women&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x161;&#xC2;&#xAC;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x17E;&#xC2;&#xA2;s day.
Achievements;Children organized and led CR sessions within their schools for awareness raising on the effects of CL via interschool bonanzas.children are able to report cases and express their views to duty bearers for example 18 cases related to CTM were reported to relevant authorities (5 teachers,7 KIWOHEDE and 6 village chairperson).Participation in child led CR activities built the children&apos;s confidence to express their needs and issues related to child abuse and provided feedback on the project implementation.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="625"></target>
     <actual value="662">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting time a total of 662 children (342 girls, 320 boys) participated in  awareness raising sessions through radio sessions,Tuseme clubs and International Day of the African Child. Children were engaged as peer educators in leading CT and CL discussions via live radio sessions, conducting peer to peer education in CR clubs, organizing and leading debates and morning talks, composing and performing songs, poems and dramas with CR/CTM messages. 17 CWDs (7boys,10 girls) with physical disabilities participated in CR clubs discussion sessions. 
Achievements: 79 cases related to CT and exploitation/abuses were reported by children: 9 to KIWOHEDE, 27 to ward/village officers (WEO/VEO) and 43 to club matron/patron.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
