<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41149287-UGCT0335</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41149287" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Response Against Child Trafficking and unsafe Migration in Uganda - HO</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dwelling places shall in 2020 continue working to combat CTM along the North-Eastern corridor of uganda.&amp;nbsp;https://docs.google.com/document/d/15eSasS8g9XyW3ixtSO2AXBBhdP6BbLYt13gNAqqv0Wg/edit#</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dwelling Places</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41149287-UGCT0335" ref="NL-KVK-41149287" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41149287-UGCT0335" ref="NL-KVK-41149287" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0)70-310 5000</telephone>
   <email>info@tdh.nl</email>
   <website>https://www.terredeshommes.nl</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">152646</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">102500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-01">112354</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">148306</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">106198</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41149287-5008" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">100 boy victims of exploitation are identified, rescued and placed in (alternative) care, recieved psycho social counselling and support</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">100 boy victims of exploitation are identified, rescued and placed in (alternative) care, recieved psycho social counselling and support</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of boys immediately safeguarded</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of boys immediately safeguarded</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="66" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 boy was rescued.
The over expense is because of balances brought forward of EUR1049.19 from the previous quarter and a reallocation of EUR1540.78  from output 1.6 which was used cover family tracing and reintegration expenses for 24 boys that were in the rehabilitation home;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15 boys were immediately safeguarded within this reporting period.

We worked with KCCA in carrying out rescues and most of the children came in our homes mid March thus under expenditure.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="17">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">17 boys were immediately safeguarded. The expense was on the support provided to boys through the 10 outreaches conducted which included comprehensive minor first aid provided to 13 boys.
The under expenditure is because some of the boys were referred to the partner organization for rehabilitation services since we currently have a facility for only girls at a time.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">2 new boys rescued for immediate care and support bringing total number of boys rehabilitated within this quarter to 20 boys. Of these, 12 were successfully reintegrated in safe families and communities, leaving 8 boys in the home by close of the quarter.

Finance
The over Expenditure was as a result of more boys in the home compared to what was planned for.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="24">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">44 boys rescued within this reporting period, exceeding set target as we generally found more boys on the streets during outreaches compared to girls. Although some boys run away from the home, we spent on them for the period they were in our care thus the higher expense than the target. We also made bulk purchases for the medical supplies, scholastic materials as well as hospital prepaid account.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="43">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">58 boys have been safeguarded during 2021. In Q2 alone, 43 boys were immediately safeguarded. The boys were however rescued towards the last weeks of the quarter - , hence the underspend.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="170"></target>
     <actual value="162">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A total of 162 boys were rescued for care and protection within the quarter including 1 boy who was referred to DP by Police and 161 boys who were rescued and rehabilitated at Nakivubo blue Primary School as opposed to bringing them into the TRH due to DP&apos;s restrictions of new admissions to minimise C-19 exposure for those children who were already in the TRH. As such, DP partnered with the Ministry of Gender, Labor and Social Development, Kampala Capital City Authority, and other CSOs under the CRANE network to rescue and provide basic services and protection to 202 street connected children (196 boys, 6 girls) who had been abandoned on the streets during the lock down with no alternative source of survival. Of the 196 boys rescued, 35 ran away, leaving only 161 rehabilitated for 7 weeks and then referred to partners for further support in resettlement and additional rehabilitation as they were older than our admission age limit. 10 of these boys eventually came into the DP TRH for further support when the lock down was lifted. The rescue and the health teams, plus psychosocial support social workers were resident at Nakivubo Blue Primary School where the children were being kept, providing psychosocial support and basic health  and referral services for over 7 weeks within the quarter. Many of the street connected girls are not full time on the streets. In other words, they spend most of their time on the streets, but return to the slums for the night. While more boys sleep on the streets. We have equally engaged with the leaders of the slums to mobilise children and families willing to return to Karamoja, and arrangements are being made to have these repatriated as soon as possible.
Overall, 175 boys received rehabilitation services within the quarter including 161 at Nakivubo Blue Primary school, and 24 at the TRH, plus the 10 out of the 161 who later also joined the TRH. 18 of these were successfully reintegrated with their families in June, with the partial lifting of the lock down to allow private vehicles to operate, while 151 boys were referred to partners under CRANE for further support as they were older than our eligibility age limit
2 boys reintegrated in quarter 1 were regularly followed up on phone to monitor their well being in light of the COVID 19 situation and to ensure sustainable reintegration;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No new boys were rescued within this quarter. However, we had 6 boys in the TRH. Of these, 5 were successfully reintegrated/ placed in safe families and communities, while 1 is still in our care as we continue to search for suitable options for long term care as his family tracing has repeatedly failed since 2018. We also followed up 10 boys who had been rescued and resettled in 2020. We are happy to report that these have continued to remain in their homes to date. Continued support and psycho-social support is still being provided to them to ensure sustainable reintegration

Financially, this shows that we over spent but we made a budget reallocation to this budget line.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Two boys were rescued within this reporting period bringing total number of boys immediately safeguarded this year to 60/30.
Balances from previous quarters were utilized to support 42 boys who were in the TRH throughout the lockdown (July). Family Tracing and reintegration is still ongoing. 6 boys were already reintegrated in Q1 whereas 24 were reintegrated within the quarter - leaving  only 18 boys - to be reintegrated during Q4. 12 boys ran away from the TRH.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">100 exploited/abuse boys received educational support including School fees, scholastic materials or psychosocial support during follow up visits to stay in school and out of risk of CTM by Sept 2022.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">100 exploited/abuse boys received educational support including School fees, scholastic materials or psychosocial support during follow up visits to stay in school and out of risk of CTM by Sept 2022.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of exploited/abused boys received educational services</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of exploited/abused boys received educational services</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="64" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="16">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">16 boys were enrolled in vocational school as others wait for reopening of primary and secondary schools. 
Reallocation was made from this output of EUR1540.78 to output 1.3 to cover Rehabilitation expenses for the 24 boys who stayed longer in the home, family tracing and reintegration expenses  &quot;;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">3 boys who are still in the TRH due to failed 2019 family tracing and reintegration were enrolled in boarding school within term 1 where they will stay during the term, and return to the TRH during school holidays until a more permanent reintegration plan has been confirmed. 
Usually most of the children we resettle are enrolled in day schools apart from Karamoja region were some schools are very far away from the communities the children stay and it necessitates boarding school for the safety of the children. However, the 3 boys had to be enrolled in a boarding school in Wakiso with a relatively good standard of care since they do not have a home thus the high expense. Although we budget for education support some families upon resettlement and family assessment they are able to support their children in school and therefore not all the 35 boys might need education support.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">6 boys were supported to enroll back in school this quarter, including 5 in Napak and 1 in Kampala. The over expenditure is because the cost for the boys rescued/rehabilitated/resettled last year has been added on output 1.7 where the children have been added/counted;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Because of the COVID-19 restrictions and closure of schools, No rescued boys were resettled during the period and therefore, None has been re-enrolled back to school and hence, No fees was paid from this budget line.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No educational support services were provided within this reporting period as schools remained closed due to the COVID 19. All reintegrated children are supposed to be immediately enrolled in school to prevent re-migration. However, this was not possible due to the lock down. As such, we have developed a new initiative that involves provision of community based tutoring in a clustered-manner kind of teaching in both Kampala and Napak where we will produce study materials, and have community based tutors support small clusters of children on a weekly basis in revision of these materials to ensure reduced risks to idleness and CTM; while ensuring compliance with the MOH COVID 19 SOPs.

Finance:
The under expenditure is as a result of the closure of schools.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No school fees was paid under this output. Resettled children have not been enrolled because schools are closed. While in the TRH however, the children were provided with &quot;catch up education&quot; - as well as ensuring that they are given homework during follow-ups to keep them busy as they wait for schools to open.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not yet started

This was a wrong posting on the expenditure and this will be rectified in the next reporting period.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This cost was part of quarter 3 expenditures that was not paid. Pro grammatically, no new targets were met under this output within this reporting period as schools continued to remain closed to this category of children (non-candidates) throughout this reporting period due to COVID 19;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output was not achieved as schools still remain closed due to the C-19 pandemic;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="35"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">110 girl victims of exploitation are identified, rescued and placed in (alternative) care, recieved psycho social counselling and support</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">110 girl victims of exploitation are identified, rescued and placed in (alternative) care, recieved psycho social counselling and support</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of girls immediately safeguarded</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of girls immediately safeguarded</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="67" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="17">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">17 Girls were immediately safeguarded. The expense was on 10 outreaches conducted in Kampala where 195 children (85 girls; 110 boys) and support provided to the 17 rescued/rehabilitated girls.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="22">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">22 girls were immediately safeguarded within this reporting period.

We worked with KCCA in carrying out rescues and most of the children came in our homes mid March thus under expenditure.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">32 girls have been safe guarded since January 2021. In Q2,10 new girls were immediately safeguarded. During the street outreaches, because of the lockdown and covid-19 restrictions, fewer girls were found than boys.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Among the 32 girls rescued from Nairobi, 5 were enrolled onto the support program on this project bringing the total number safeguarded this year to 37/40 girls.
Balances from previous quarters were utilized this quarter to cater for the girls who were in the rehabilitation in Kla (22 girls) during lockdown; family tracing and resettlement as well as supporting the children rescued from Nairobi while in the rehabilitation centre in Napak.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="13">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Most of the rehabilitation purchases are made in bulk to reduce on the unit cost. such expenses include medical supplies, scholastic materials, non perishable home essentials.  We also have prepaid agreements with some of our service providers like hospitals where we made payments for the   full quarter. As we conduct rescues and take the children for medical assessments, each child is billed per visit and a statement is shared monthly. Lastly 16 girls were rescued however 3 run away although we had spent on them during the time they were in our care.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No new girls were rescued within this quarter. However, we had 1 girl in the Transitional Rehabilitation Home (TRH) who was eventually resettled in December. We also followed up 6 girls who had been rescued and resettled in 2020. We are happy to report that these have continued to remain in their homes to date. Continued support and psychosocial support is still being provided to them to ensure sustainable reintegration;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No new girls were rescued within this reporting period as we already exceeded expected 2020 targets by the end of the second quarter.

Finance:
The under expenditure is as a result of fewer girls in the home compared to what we had planned for.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This period, 10 new girls were rescued bringing the total number of safeguarded girls this year to 47/40.
A reallocation of EUR1338.23 was made to this budget line from Output 1.4 and utilized for family tracing and reintegration expenses for the girls that were in the TRH hence causing the over expenditure;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">while no girl was rescued into the TRH due to DP&apos;s restrictions of new admissions to minimise C-19 exposure for those children who were already in the TRH, however, DP partnered with the Ministry of Gender, Labor and Social Development, Kampala Capital City Authority, and other CSOs under the CRANE network to rescue and provide basic services and protection to 202 street connected children (196 boys, 6 girls) who had been abandoned on the streets during the lock down with no alternative source of survival. The rescue and the health teams, plus psychosocial support social workers were resident at Nakivubo Blue Primary School where the children were being kept, providing psychosocial support and basic health  and referral services for over 7 weeks within the quarter. Many of the street connected girls are not full time on the streets. In other words, they spend most of their time on the streets, but return to the slums for the night. While more boys sleep on the streets. We have equally engaged with the leaders of the slums to mobilise children and families willing to return to Karamoja, and arrangements are being made to have these repatriated as soon as possible.
Overall, we had 18 girls undergoing rehabilitation during the lock down, including 1 vulnerable girl in boarding school under educational support services who had failed to reach home in time when schools and the country were totally locked down in March. Of these, 7 girls were successfully reintegrated with their families, leaving 5 girls in the home by close of the quarter, while the 6 girls from Nakivubo Blue were referred to partners under CRANE for further support as they were older than our age eligibility yet in need of protection and support. 3 girls reintegrated in quarter 1 were regularly followed up on phone to monitor their well being in light of the COVID 19 situation and to ensure sustainable reintegration;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">218 vulnerable girls received educational support including School fees, scholastic materials or psychosocial support during follow up visits to stay in school and out of risk of CTM by Sept 2022.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">218 vulnerable girls received educational support including School fees, scholastic materials or psychosocial support during follow up visits to stay in school and out of risk of CTM by Sept 2022.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of vulnerable girls received educational services</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of vulnerable girls received educational services</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="249" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="35"></target>
     <actual value="116">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">116 boys were mobilized and supported to report back to school after 2 years of school closure. These received either scholastic materials or school fees support. They were also offered, individual counseling during the mobilization, distribution of school requirements as well as followed up. 
We spent more than planned under this output due to an increase in prices for the scholastic materials and school fees. schools required additional materials to meet the government SOPs standards on Covid-19 as well as the resettled children who had been planned under output 1.4.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="19"></target>
     <actual value="19">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">19 vulnerable girls in candidate classes were supported to access education within this reporting period.

Most of the children are still at home due to closure of school as a result of COVID-19 Pandemic restrictions thus the under expenditure.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="212"></target>
     <actual value="227">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">227 vulnerable girls were followed up and were provided education and psychosocial support.
The over expenditure is because savings from the previous quarters that were utilized in Q4. Follow up was scaled up this quarter because there was a lifting of the lock down and travel restrictions we experienced in the first quarters due to Covid-19&quot;;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="135"></target>
     <actual value="90">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">90 out of the targeted 135 vulnerable girls received school fees, scholastic materials and/ or psychosocial during follow up within term 1. This was however interrupted by the closure of all educational institutions due to the COVID pandemic. The overall number of 170 girls was inclusive of the 35 girls who were expected to be rescued within this year who would receive psychosocial support during follow up visits both at home and in schools to monitor their well being. 
Although some of the children were not followed up as explained above, their scholastic materials were purchased and the school fees were paid. Most of the schools raised their termly school fees this year which affected our budget and our plan was to mobilize more resources in the course of the year to cover the gap as well as work with the parents to make contributions as their income increases.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="35"></target>
     <actual value="39">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A total of 189 girls were followed up within this reporting period and received psychosocial support services, including food packages and educational materials to reduce their vulnerability to CTM during this COVID 19 pandemic as the schools remain closed. Of this total, 39 were being followed up for the very first time, while the remaining 150 were receiving either 2nd of 3rd visits since January.

Finance
The over expenditure was as a result of more follow ups for girls carried out in quarter 3 which were planned for in quarter 2.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="62">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following the abrupt and indefinite closure of schools on the 18th March 2020 due to C-19, we requested the school fees budget line to be reallocated to printing and distribution of learning materials for the home learning program. This was approved and the funds were spent for this purpose. However, the president of the Republic of Uganda finally approved for all students in final year at all levels to report back to school on the 15th of October 2020 for second term and Ministry of Education also released the time table for their final exams. As such, fees was paid for 15 girls.

We also followed up and provided psycho-social support to 62 girls within this reporting period.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="89">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No school fees or scholastic materials were provided to the girls within this quarter as schools still remain closed due to the COVID 19 pandemic. We however requested for a reallocation of part of this budget line to enable us respond to the effects of COVID 19 in the families in our care. We will buy food and deliver food packages to the vulnerable children to reduce their vulnerability to CTM, CM and other forms of abuse and exploitation. Also, 89 girls received psychosocial support during phone and physical follow up visits to monitor their well being in light of the COVID 19 situation and offer support in coping. Further still, at the time of the lock down in March, 57 girls had not yet been reached to confirm presence in school and collect school fees slips to enable fees payments. Within the quarter, with the partial lifting of the quarantine, the schools were contacted, and fees slips were collected. These will be prioritized for payment in quarter 3.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Only 3 vulnerable girls participated in online learning/coaching within this period. Because of limited access to online learning aids, other children have not been able to access education services. A plan is however in place to procure learning materials guided my the Ministry of Education and provide them to the children in Q4.
Expense here is mostly on follow-up and PSS provision to 102 girls.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="58">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">School fees and scholastic materials were paid for 58 girls in other classes other than candidate classes during Q2 because schools had been re-opened to them. 
Balance from Q1 was utilized in Q2 to cater for the fees payment for the higher number of children and also cater for the extra requirements (PPE) to manage the spread of COVID-19 at school.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="113"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">222 vulnerable boys received educational support including School fees, scholastic materials or psychosocial support during follow up visits to stay in school.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">222 vulnerable boys received educational support including School fees, scholastic materials or psychosocial support during follow up visits to stay in school.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of vulnerable boys received educational services</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of vulnerable boys received educational services</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="248" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="35"></target>
     <actual value="129">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">129 boys were  supported to report back to school after 2 years of school closure. These received either scholastic materials or school fees support. They were also offered, individual counseling during the mobilization, distribution of school requirements as well as followed up.
We spent more than planned under this output due to an increase in prices for the scholastic materials and school fees. schools required additional materials to meet the government SOPs standards on Covid-19 as well as the resettled boys who had been planned under output 1.6.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="22"></target>
     <actual value="22">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">22 vulnerable boys were supported to access education within this reporting period

Most of the children are still at home due to closure of school as a result of COVID-19 Pandemic restrictions thus the under expenditure.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="292"></target>
     <actual value="289">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">289 vulnerable boys were followed up and provided educational and psychosocial support.
The over expenditure is because of savings from the previous quarters that were utilized in Q4. Follow up was scaled up this quarter because there was a lifting of the lock down and travel restrictions we experienced in the first quarters due to Covid-19&quot;;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="83">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">83 out of 119 targeted boys (siblings) received school fees, scholastic materials and/ or psychosocial during follow up within term 1. This was however interrupted by the closure of all educational institutions due to the COVID pandemic.

Although some of the children were not followed up as explained above, their scholastic materials were purchased and the school fees were paid. Most of the schools raised their termly school fees this year which affected our budget and our plan was to mobilize more resources in the course of the year to cover the gap as well as work with the parents to make contributions as their income increases.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="47"></target>
     <actual value="47">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A total of 183 boys received psychosocial support during follow up visits within this reporting period to monitor their well being and sustainability of the reintegration as well as to ensure they do not drop out of school. Of these, 47 boys were being followed up for the very first time since January.

Finance
The over expenditure was as a result of more follow ups for boys carried out in quarter 3 which were planned for in quarter 2.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="60">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following the abrupt and indefinite closure of schools on the 18th March 2020 due to C-19, we requested the school fees budget line to be reallocated to printing and distribution of learning materials for the home learning program. This was approved and the funds were spent for this purpose. However, the president of the Republic of Uganda finally approved for all students in final year at all levels to report back to school on the 15th of October 2020 for second term and Ministry of Education also released the time table for their final exams. Therefore, fees was paid for 24 boys under this budget line.

We also still followed up and provided psycho-social support to 60 boys within this reporting period.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="69"></target>
     <actual value="62">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No school fees or scholastic materials were provided to the boys within this quarter as schools still remain closed due to the COVID 19 pandemic. However, 62 boys received psychosocial support during phone and physical follow up visits to monitor their well being in light of the COVID 19 situation and offer support in coping. We also requested for a reallocation of part of this budget line to enable us respond to the effects of COVID 19 in the families in our care. We will buy food and deliver food packages to the vulnerable children to reduce their vulnerability to CTM, CM and other forms of abuse and exploitation. Also, at the time of the lock down in March, 51 boys had not yet been reached to confirm presence in school and collect school fees slips to enable fees payments. Within the quarter, with the partial lifting of the quarantine, the schools were contacted, and fees slips were collected. These will be prioritized for payment in quarter 3;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Only 6 vulnerable boys were able to participate in online learning/ coaching within this period. The rest were affected by limited technology.
The under expenditure is because very little (611.70 EUR) was spent on online learning. More was spent on follow ups (1457.60) and Feedback sessions  (668.12).;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="59">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">School fees and scholastic materials were paid for 59 boys within this reporting period.

Majority of the boys were in lower primary classes and they were due to report in August.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="107"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children develop and academically perform in line with expectations for their age.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children develop and academically perform in line with expectations for their age.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of enrolled children that successfully transition to next year</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of enrolled children that successfully transition to next year</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Families generate sufficient livelihood to support their children&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC6;&#x2019;&#xC3;&#x201A;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x201A;&#xAC;&#xC5;&#xA1;&#xC3;&#x201A;&#xC2;&#xAC;&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x201A;&#xAC;&#xC5;&#xBE;&#xC3;&#x201A;&#xC2;&#xA2;s wellbeing.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Families generate sufficient livelihood to support their children&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC6;&#x2019;&#xC3;&#x201A;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x201A;&#xAC;&#xC5;&#xA1;&#xC3;&#x201A;&#xC2;&#xAC;&#xC3;&#x192;&#xC2;&#xA2;&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x201A;&#xAC;&#xC5;&#xBE;&#xC3;&#x201A;&#xC2;&#xA2;s wellbeing.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of supported households with increased income compared to baseline</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of supported households with increased income compared to baseline</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Will start after reintegration of the 70 rescued children in 2020;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Families of exploited/abused children participate in income generating activities by Sept 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Families of exploited/abused children participate in income generating activities by Sept 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of families of exploited/abused children participated in income generating activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of families of exploited/abused children participated in income generating activities</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="138" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 family was supported with IGA inputs. 4 Families were followed up to conduct a livelihood assessment however only 1 was  recommended for economic empowerment.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25 families were assessed this month. 9 were recommended for economic empowerment support because of their level of vulnerability while others were not. Their support plans are being developed.
In Napak, 14 VSLAs were followed up to monitor their well being and that of their families. Their weekly saving meetings had been closed down due to the nation wide lockdown. Also, the interruptions in business, coupled with the foot and mouth disease outbreak in Napak greatly affected the individual IGA businesses, and consequently, the amount saved by the members within the quarter. The members also had some misconceptions about the Corona virus (e.g. it killed only white people) that needed to be cleared out by the social workers.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="28">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28 parents received inputs for economic empowerment within this reporting period out of 39 parents who were assessed and trained after lifting the lockdown. More assessments, trainings and distribution of resources will continue in Q4;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
     <actual value="50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">50 parents received inputs to setup IGAs during this quarter bringing the total number of families supported this year to 78/70. 
Economic empowerment activities should have started in Q2 but were slowed down by the continued lockdown-Assessments of most families (69) were concluded towards the end of Q3, 50 of whom, were supported in Q4. 
The budget balances from the previous quarters were utilized in Q4 to empower these families;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="60">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A total of 60 new caregivers have received inputs for economic empowerment within this reporting period bringing total number of IGA inputs given out to 68 out of the target 70. In Karamoja, 14 caregivers received a group IGA and were formed into a village Savings and Loans Association (VSLA) due to the closeness of their homes, as well as for easier monitoring and accountability. All the other IGAs were given to individuals staying in different districts.

This cost was quarter 3 expenditure that was incurred in this reporting period.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">An overall total of 114 families have been assessed for economic empowerment since January 2020 to date. Of these, 70 have been identified as vulnerable and are currently being supported by the social workers to identify potential business ideas of interest and develop business plans. 
Within the quarter, 8 families who had completed the development and approval of their business plans received resources for economic empowerment to enable them generate sufficient livelihood to support their children&apos;s well being and sustainably reduce their vulnerability to CTM.

Finance
The under expenditure was as a result of delays in the reintegration of children due to the movement restriction that that led to delay in family assessments thus delay in implementations which was as a result of COVID-19.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No IGAs have been provided to the families because of the slowed down resettlement of children and the COVID-19 restrictions. However, 9 families were assessed in Q2. Training of the families was affected by the restrictions during the period.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The livelihood personnel was recruited in Feb thus the low expenditure.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="14">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Will start after reintegration of the 70 rescued children in 2020;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="40"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Girl victims of  exploitation supported to access education services</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Girl victims of  exploitation supported to access education services</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of exploited/abused girls received educational services</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of exploited/abused girls received educational services</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="62" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">9 girls were supported to enroll back in school this quarter, including 5 in Napak and 4 in Kampala. of the 9, 3 are in secondary school while 6 were enrolled in Primary School.
The under expenditure here is because the cost of enrollment of girls rescure/rehabilitated/resettled last year has been charged on output 1.5 where the girls have been counted;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Because of the COVID-19 restrictions and closure of schools, No rescued girls were resettled during the period and therefore, None has been re-enrolled back to school and hence, No fees was paid from this budget line.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No new girls enrolled in school within this reporting period as schools remained closed due to the COVID 19 pandemic. All reintegrated children are supposed to be immediately enrolled in school to prevent re-migration. However, this was not possible due to the lock down. As such, we have developed a new initiative that involves provision of community based tutoring in a clustered-manner kind of teaching in both Kampala and Napak where we will produce study materials, and have community based tutors support small clusters of children on a weekly basis in revision of these materials to ensure reduced risks to idleness and CTM; while ensuring compliance with the MOH COVID 19 SOPs.

Finance:
The under expenditure is as a result of the closure of schools.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not yet done

This was a wrong posting on the expenditure and this will be rectified in the next reporting period.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 5 girls rescued from Nairobi were enrolled for vocational training in Mbale and Busia during Q3. The over expense was because of the increase in the training fees and school requirements as few institutions were allowed to operate under strict COVID-19 guidelines;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output was not achieved as schools still remain closed due to the C-19 pandemic;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output was not worked on within this year;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This will commence after the rescued girls have been reintegrated and enrolled into mainstream education;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">only 4 girls, resettled outside Karamoja, received community based tutoring. Schools were closed this year which limited enrollment of the resettled children into formal schools. 
The girls that were resettled in Karamoja region did not not participate in community tutoring due to distance, inavailability of teachers within their location and some caregivers who refused them from participating because of fear of sexual abuse in their communities. 
A budget reallocation was made from this output of EUR1338.23 to output 1.2 to cover family tracing and reintegration expenses .;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="35"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
