<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41149287-KECE0308</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41149287" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusive and community-led prevention and response to SGBV/CP in Turkana West</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusive and community-led prevention and response to protection of children from SGBV in Turkana West Sub-County, Focusing on capacity strengthening of local partners in Letea and Songot.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TdHNL Kenya Country Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41149287-KECE0308" ref="NL-KVK-41149287" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41149287-KECE0308" ref="NL-KVK-41149287" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41149287-KECE0308" ref="NL-KVK-41149287" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes Netherlands</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0)70-310 5000</telephone>
   <email>info@tdh.nl</email>
   <website>https://www.terredeshommes.nl</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">222574</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">4036</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">184854</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">By July 2020, community-based coordination and referral mechanisms for prevention and protection of children from Sexual and Gender Based Violence (SGBV) in Turkana West Sub-County is strengthened</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">By July 2020, community-based coordination and referral mechanisms for prevention and protection of children from Sexual and Gender Based Violence (SGBV) in Turkana West Sub-County is strengthened</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of SGBV prevention and service provision mappings for Letea and Sogot Counties finalized</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of SGBV prevention and service provision mappings for Letea and Sogot Counties finalized</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A consultant has been hired to conduct SGBV mapping, learning and best practices assessment/ exercise in Turkana West Sub County (Letea and Songot Wards). The inception report has been shared and in the process of review. However the plan to finalise this exercise in this quarter has been disrupted by covid 19 pandemic.  The readjusted plan is to finalise all the tools (in consultation with UNICEF focal point)  in readiness for the actual field work as soon as things are back to normal.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A consultant to undertake the mapping was engaged in 
 Q1 of 2020.  Following the extension of COVID 19 related restriction beginning of May 2020, facial and virtual  data collection approach was explored with the key informants and regulated face to face FGD with communities in the two project areas. Data collection, analysis and validation processes went on well as planned. Stakeholders attending the report launch event urged the project under the support of TdH-NL and UNICEF to consider a continuation of their intervention in the two wards to address the gaps identified in the area. Over-spend is a result of implementation of activities that had been projected in Q1 but were not undertaken due to COVID-19 pandemic and hence implemented in Q2.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The consultant was engaged in the first quarter of 2020. However, owing to the COVID 19 related complications and travel/work restrictions and lockdown mid-March 2020, the assignment was temporarily brought to halt. Following the extension of COVID 19 related restriction end of April 2020, online/remote data collection via email, skype/phone interviews with the key informants, and regulated FGD with communities were explored. To this end, significant strides have been made and the draft report is expected on the 25th of July 2020 and the final one by the end of the same month.Reported expenditure relates to procurement of IEC materials. Under expenditure due to re-scheduling of planned activity (1.7). This will be undertaken in August 2020;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of child protection SGBV prevention and referral pathway developed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of child protection SGBV prevention and referral pathway developed</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The actualization of this activity is primarily pegged on the completion of Mapping, learning, and best practices assessment on existing Child Sexual Abuse and Violence coordination structures and referral pathways in Songot and Letea. The final report is earmarked for the end of July 2020, thereby giving a platform for the popularization of the developed prevention and referral pathways at the sub-County and County level the subsequent month.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project commissioned SVAC mapping research in the project areas to develop a guide for stakeholders in Child protection to create and strengthen a Child Protection Referral System to put into practice the principles of a country&#xC3;&#xA2;&#xE2;&#x201A;&#xAC;&#xE2;&#x201E;&#xA2;s existing laws, policies, and procedures through Sub County relevant state departments. Hence a key product in addition to the SVAC mapping report was an illustrative Reporting and referral pathway;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This deliverable is a product of the SGBV/CP mapping exercise currently at halt due to COVID 19 pandemic.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">By July 2020, the capacity of State and Non-State actors in Letea and Songot Locations on prevention, protection and support to children SGBV survivors is enhanced</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">By July 2020, the capacity of State and Non-State actors in Letea and Songot Locations on prevention, protection and support to children SGBV survivors is enhanced</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of child protection partners  trained on the use of contextualized SGBV reporting and referral pathway</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of child protection partners  trained on the use of contextualized SGBV reporting and referral pathway</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Completion of Mapping, learning, and best practices assessment on existing Child Sexual Abuse and Violence coordination structures and referral pathways in Songot and Letea is yet to be concluded by the end of July 2020. Once this is accomplished, the training for child protection partners on the use of contextualized SGBV reporting and referral pathways will be actualized which will offer an explicit headway to responsive action to child sexual abuse incidences in the project areas.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following the completion of capacity assessment, The project staff plan to meet the training  needs of  75 trainers of trainers (ToTs) ( 40 from Letea ward and 35 from Songot ward) who will be trained, mentored and coached by staff through ongoing monitoring and elaborate mentorship program for 4 months.
Mobilization of the 75 ToT was kicked off (40 participants from Letea and 35 from Songot) This happened before the government directive  of banning social gatherings due to COVID 19. The information regarding the ban and postponement of the training was communicated to the participants and the training will be held once the ban is lifted.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="11"></target>
     <actual value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to the training, SVAC mapping and SBCC assessment to establish underlying negative social norms was conducted as a buildup to inform the training content.The training brought together 75 participants drawn from the entire Letea and Songot wards  in Turkana West. The workshop presented a great opportunity for the participants to have a common understanding of reporting and referral pathway and basic concepts related behaviour change communication with regard to issues related to SVAC in a two days workshop.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of community-based child protection stakeholders trained on strategies for SGBV prevention and conducting outreach activities.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of community-based child protection stakeholders trained on strategies for SGBV prevention and conducting outreach activities.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the review period,  SGBV/CP capacity assessment spanning for ten days was conducted targeting Project communities (Letea and Songot wards), the state and non-state service providers in the locations.  The assessment findings were destined to gauge the community understanding of SGBV/CP  and associated risks and vulnerabilities, assess the capacity of stakeholders at the community level/grassroots in identification and mitigation of risks, prevention and response to SGBV. The assessment reached 100 (58 male, 42 Female) respondents, 6 FGDs- three from each ward with 24 Key informants. The sample was inclusive of person&#xC3;&#x2026;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#xBA; living with disabilities and the youth leaders and Women representatives. Focus group discussions (FGDs), structured andunstructured face-to-face key informant interviews were conducted.Refer to capacity assessment report.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Only Salaries and Inductions costs were uncured in Q4 2019( December 2019);</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="75"></target>
     <actual value="75">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project trained 75 (43 male, 32 female) ToT and facilitated the establishment of 12 local (village)based committees with ToR spelling out their roles, responsibilities, and expectations on explicit guidance on prevention, identification, and reporting SGBV/child abuse incidents identified in the project areas. The training drive addressed rife knowledge gaps in the institutional and legal frameworks of addressing sexual violence for boys and girls, the protection needs of the child survivors and caregivers, and the clinical management of child survivors, as well as popularising the incidents reporting procedures.Over expenditure due to procurement of laptops and expenditure related toTOT training that was undertaken in Q2 both of which had been planned  in Q1.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="75"></target>
     <actual value="75">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The training reached out to 75 (43 male, 32 female) ToTs. The sessions adopted a participatory and interactive approach, and drew on participants&apos; experiences with SVAC prevention, detection and response . The training bore the establishment of 12local (village)based committees with ToR spelling out their roles, responsibilities, and expectations on explicit guidance on prevention, identification, and reporting SVAC incidents identified in the project areas. Over-expenditure due to implementation of SBCC consultancy and training in Q3 though budgeted for in Q1 and August project staff salaries following the one month extension.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government and non-governmental partners adopt risk-informed approaches to emergency preparedness, planning and response to humanitarian needs for child protection and HIV</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government and non-governmental partners adopt risk-informed approaches to emergency preparedness, planning and response to humanitarian needs for child protection and HIV</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of UNICEF-targeted girls and boys in humanitarian situations provided with psycho social support, including access to child friendly spaces with intersectoral programming interventions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of UNICEF-targeted girls and boys in humanitarian situations provided with psycho social support, including access to child friendly spaces with intersectoral programming interventions</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="28420" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="52120"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the review period, 56 (49 female, 7 male) child sexual abuse and related cases were reported within the project areas by the Community/village-based child protection structures. Of these 35 (30 female 5 male) were from Letea and 21 (19 female, 2 male) from Songot. Of these cases, 30 are under assessment by KICOBO a CBO based in the areas, 10 are under arbitration, 6 solved, and 10 referred to police in Kakuma and Lokichoggio for legal action. However, there is Political interference in 3 of the cases reported to police as the arrested perpetrators of child Pregnancies have been released with no clear direction on case resolution. Cumulatively, the cases in the two quarters reached 91(72 female, 19 male). In all these cases, the project intervention remained as indirect support through referral to relevant community structures, government, and partners within Letea and Songot.;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="197">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the review period, 94 (87 female, 7 male) child sexual violence and related cases were reported within the project areas by the Community/village-based child protection structures. Of these 35 (30 female 5 male) were from Letea and 21 (19 female, 2 male) from Songot. Of these cases, 30 are under assessment by KICOBO a CBO based in the areas, 10 are under arbitration, 6 solved, and 10 referred to police in Kakuma and Lokichoggio for legal action. Cumulatively, the project reached a total of 133 (120 female, 13 male).;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="39">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project familiarization community entry visit  was conducted before the kick off of activities in the project target areas and to key county and national government ministries. The purpose of the visit was to  help the stakeholders understand the project background, focus and strategies to be employed, identify areas of collaboration and roles for various stakeholders for effective and efficient project delivery and collectively develop a way forward on keeping project momentum for high-quality results.
The  SGBV/CP inception meeting held in Kakuma on 30th January 2020 reached a total of  35 (23 male, 12 Female) participants from the project target areas, sub county and county level.The inception meeting held in Kakuma on 30th January 2020 reached a total of  35 (23 male, 12 Female) participants Developmental and state actors concurred that the children benefit from the trickle down effect from services tailored for refugee&#xC3;&#x2026;&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#xBA; children  Refer to project inception report;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
