<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-252224</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Energy Savings Insurance and Risk Management Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the ESI-LAC is to promote investments in energy saving measures by SMEs in five countries in the LAC region: Brazil, Colombia, El Salvador, Mexico, and Peru by addressing existing financial and non-financial barriers related to both demand and supply of financing for energy savings projects by private sector companies. The ESI-LAC program is implemented via the Inter-American Development Bank (IDB).

The project will support the development and strengthening of markets for energy efficiency services by conducting market analysis and developing financing strategies, identify energy efficiency project opportunities, providing credit lines and build trust and confidence among market actors. The program builds on partnerships with national development banks, international insurance companies and verification entities and aims at strengthening the capacity to address the barriers to climate finance in the local context. Key elements of the risk management and financing strategies include a standardized contract; the insurance instrument; and a validation and verification mechanisms. 

The ESI-LAC program is expected to mobilize credit lines of the IDB of USD 100 million, and additional private investment, resulting in reduced energy consumption and associated GHG reductions in various, targeted sectors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-252224-30414" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
