<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-245399</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democracy, Constitution Reform and Decentralisation Programme (ULEAD).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decentralisation is a top priority for the Government of Ukraine in its extensive reform programme. Although decentralisation reform remains without full constitutional legality, local councils already have new responsibilities, including larger budgets and functioning local executive committees. Since early 2015, local authorities have benefitted from decentralized budgets and recent steps forward also include the adoption of a number of laws that strengthen the linkages between districts. Further legislation will be needed to bring these arrangements into line with the new constitution, suggesting the possibility of further delay. The challenges are numerous also in relation to strengthening the capacity at decentralized levels to deliver better and more targeted services to the citizens. 

The Danish contribution to decentralisation (DKK 37 million) will be provided to the European Union&#x2019;s programme: Ukraine Local Empowerment and Accountability and Development (2016-2020) through a delegated cooperation. The overall objective of the programme is to contribute to the establishment of multilevel governance, which is transparent, accountable and responsive to the needs of the population. The specific objectives for the two components are: 1) To enhance the capacity of key actors at central, regional and local levels to implement the regional policy and decentralisation reform. 2) To improve delivery of local administrative services for the benefit of the citizens. Priority will be given to newly amalgamated municipalities (hromadas) and the support will be well aligned and coordinated.

The programme is currently a EUR 97 million jointly financed programme by the EU, Germany, and Poland and will be implemented by Germany/GIZ and Sweden/SIDA.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="403.Ukraine.1-23/2015-28956">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-245399-31156" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-245399-31158" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-245399-31227" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-245399-31228" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
