<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-263149</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM: Global Compact for Safe, Orderly and Regular Migration</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Global Compact for Safe, Orderly and Regular Migration (GCM) is the first-ever UN global declaration on a common approach to international migration in all its dimensions. The global compact is non-legally binding. It is grounded in values of state sovereignty, responsibility-sharing, non-discrimination, and human rights, and recognizes that a cooperative approach is needed to optimize the overall benefits of migration, while addressing its risks and challenges for individuals and communities in countries of origin, transit and destination. The global compact comprises 23 objectives for better managing migration at local, national, regional and global levels, including addressing irregular migration. The GCM was negotiated in 2018. The intergovernmental negotiations were preceded by a year of informal consultations. IOM&#x2019;s entry into the United Nations system coincided with the decision of Member States to develop a Global Compact for Safe, Orderly and Regular Migration.  The purpose of the Danish contribution was to support IOM to follow through with the modalities laid out in the UNGA resolution A/RES/71/280 tasking IOM jointly with the UN Secretariat to service the negotiations process of the GCM with technical and policy expertise. The GCM was adopted at an intergovernmental conference held in December 2018. IOM provided extensive support the development of the GCM throughout the process with a focus on ensuring that the process of development of the GCM was well-informed, and that it was inclusive. Ahead of the adoption of the GCM, the UN launched the UN Migration Network to support its implementation at country level. The Network will provide &#x201C;effective, timely and coordinated system-wide&#x201D; support to Member States, including by establishing the capacity-building mechanism called for in the GCM. IOM&#x2019;s Director General was appointed the coordinator of the Network and IOM will serve as the secretariat of the Network.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016 - 50570</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016001240</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-263149</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-263149-31466" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
