<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-242892</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KVINFO DAPP 2015</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KVINFO&apos;s programme &quot;Women&apos;s Societal Empowerment&quot; a Path to Gender Equality contributes to building democratic, stable and resilient societies in the Middle East and North Africa region through increasing societal gender equality. The programme builds on the assumption that the mitigation of barriers to women&#xBF;s societal participation will empower women to increasingly use their political and socio-economic rights. 
Applying a Human Rights Based approach, the programme works to promote and further gender sensitive legal reform and gender equal access to justice, to sustain and disseminate gender research and documentation, and to strengthen women&#xBF;s political and socio-economic rights, empowerment and participation. Cross-cutting issues of Danish-Arab dialogue and cooperation, youth, and men and boys are mainstreamed into all programme interventions. 
To further legal reform and sustain gender research, programme interventions aim at: preventing under-age marriage, promoting gender equality in constitutions; lifting restrictions on the CEDAW; sustain academic cooperation; support the production and utilization of gender disaggregated statistics and databases to promote female expertise. 
To strengthen women&apos;s political participation, programme interventions aim at: capacity development of and networking between female candidates and politicians, capacity development of civil society organizations; awareness raising in the fields of political and civil rights; advocacy initiatives to influence political processes and policies. To strengthen women&#xBF;s economic participation, programme interventions aim at: capacity developing female entrepreneurs, enabling more women to be breadwinners; promoting gender diversity management to increase private sector female labor force participation and women in decision-making posts. Interventions target both high and low educated citizens. Programme interventions take place in Egypt, Jordan, Morocco, Tunisia, Yemen and regionally.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015-13375</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015001067</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-242892</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-242892-29713" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
