<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-265853</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger, Democratic governance, stability and migration, 2017-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Please note the following 3 comments on this RFI reporting on the &quot;Support to HACP via UNDP&quot;: 
1.) Data made available in the Annual Reports of this project is of an adequate quality, although not always complete. 
2.) The number of indictors in the results framework exceeds the number of indicators available in the RFI format. 
3.) Data on the main outcome indicator (Number of inter-community conflicts targetted by HACP) has not been generated during the implementation period but can be recuperated. However, the relevance of the indicator, in its current formulation, to the actual work of the HACP and the changing nature of the security situation, is reducing.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The thematic programme will seek to help Niger address the many development and security challenges facing the country through a series of strategically targeted actions carried out through a range of selected actors identified as vectors of positive change. This will be done through four engagements: 

1.) In the area of security, the programme will principally buttress the capacity of the Haute Autorit&#xE9; pour la Consolidation de la Paix (HACP) to provide both short and long term responses to communities at risk, thereby furthering Danish support provided through multi-donor interventions since 2012 (EU in particular). As implementing partner of this development engagement, UNDP will accompany HACP in its efforts. 

2.) The preservation and extension of the democratic space will be promoted through support to two independent institutions, the National Human Rights Commission (CNDH) and the High Council for Communications (CSC), and to civil society organisations (CSOs) working in the field of human rights, the media, and conflict transformation. This will be complementary to the long-standing support of the Danish Institute for Human Rights to actors in this field (since 1994).  

3.) Work to further the demographic transition and increase reproductive health rights will be carried out via the United Nations Population Fund (UNFPA), in continuation of Denmark&#x2019;s support of UNFPA&#x2019;s existing Country Programme (2014-2017). A large part of UNFPA&#x2019;s work is carried out by downstream CSO partners. 

4.) In the domain of migration, the program seeks to contribute to strengthening the management of migration flows in Niger, including preventing irregular migration and helping migrants who wish to return home. The project will be implemented by IOM in close collaboration with central and local authorities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2017001249</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-265853</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger - Governance - DGSM</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Denmark, Burkina Faso</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>ouaamb@um.dk</email>
   <website>www.burkinafaso.um.dk</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ambassade Royale de Danemark, 316, Avenue Pr. Joseph KI-ZERBO</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-265853-32396" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-265853-32397" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-265853-32399" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-265853-32400" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-265853-32401" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-265853-32402" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-265853-32403" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-265853-32404" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-265853-33193" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-265853-34634" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
