<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-255106</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peace and Stabilisation Respons (PSR). Activities administrated by NIRAS 2016.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is in Denmark&apos;s interest that the international community plays an active role in helping to ensure and promote peace, stability and democratisation. This cannot be accomplished solely through negotiations and resolutions; the international community also needs to field personnel and experts to assist in hotspots around the world. The Peace and Stabilisation Response (PSR) helps to ensure that Denmark has a prominent place when it is necessary for the international community to intervene. PSR was established in 1994 as the international humanitarian Service (IHB) but renamed in 2012 to the Peace and Stabilisation Response. The PSR is responsible for deploying experts and other qualified personnel to the civilian component of peace- and stabilisation interventions; humanitarian, conflict-preventing- and peacekeeping operations or election observation missions in the world&#xBF;s most fragile and conflict affected areas and rising democracies. In essence, the PSR is a roster under the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Denmark (MFA) that receives and assesses calls for contribution from, among others, the EU, UN, NATO and the OSCE for Danish experts to be deployed to international missions. Currently, the Roster comprises approximately 480 experts ready to be deployed at short notice around the world. The PSR experts are a diverse group of election experts, crisis management experts, logisticians, legal experts, political advisors and others who at short notice are ready to undertake international assignments. The PSR is financed through the Danish Finance Act and headed by the MFA&#xBF;s Stabilisation and Security Policy Unit. Since September 2008, the administration of the PSR has been outsourced to the Danish consultancy firm, NIRAS, while the MFA keeps the overall political and strategic responsibility and defines the priorities for secondments through the PSR.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-20" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Migration, Stabilization and Fragility</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>mns@um.dk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asiatisk Plads 2, 1448 K&#xF8;benhavn K, Denmark</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-255106-30975" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-255106-30976" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-255106-31505" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
