<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-250225</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">High value Opportunity - Malaysia, Energy renovation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project support the development of a integrated system solution for increased energy efficiency in the building sector. The system comprises the full project cycle from the implementation of energy- and water efficiency in buildings, from the initial audits, through design, finance, procurement, installation and monitoring in public Buildings in Kuala Lumpur and Malacca. 

Improving energy efficiency leads to cost and energy savings for the building owners and reduce the environmental impact of energy consumption and emission of greenhouse gasses leading to climate change. The present energy mix in Malaysia is basically coal and gas which means that every saved kWh in electricity consumption will reduce the CO2 emission. And the project will thus contribute to the greenhouse gas emission reduction target in Malaysia.

The project will involve local banks, which will be capacity built to understand green projects better and become more willing to provide financing in this area


Electricity generation is subsidised in Malaysia and savings will lead to less spending of public funds for energy, which can be redistributed to other areas e.g. health sector, education etc.

Retrofitting the buildings with energy efficient components will lead to a higher value of the existing buildings and improving the economy in general. 

Energy efficiency projects will create local jobs for contractors and installers. It will in many cases be small and medium enterprises, which will benefit from the project. 


Denmark has a long tradition of improving energy efficiency in existing buildings and for continuously upgrading the upgrading the building stock. Many of the Danish technologies are there for suitable for existing buildings. Thus the project will provide technology transfer between Denmark and Malaysia in the form of products and know-how.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015-20043</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015001182</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-250225</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-250225-30210" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
