<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-243152</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deltagelse af repr&#xE6;sentanter fra udviklingslande i 3GFs m&#xF8;der i 2015-2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Throughout 2015 3GF will co-host a number of regional meetings and activities in the African, Asian and Latin American regions. The regional meetings will be organised in alignment with regional political priorities and interests in close cooperation with local stakeholders. The components of the meetings will consist of high-level deliberations on regional challenges and opportunities in terms of scaling green growth solutions, linking the discussions with presentation of new evidence and knowledge relevant to the regions. Furthermore, the regional meetings aim to inspire and instigate collaborative partnerships to meet regional green growth challenges. 

The meetings will seek to bridge global and regional challenges, stakeholders and opportunities by bringing international and regional discussions, best practice and actors together. This international-regional nexus will provide new perspectives and insights into current challenges and opportunities for both regional and global solutions. Also existing global collaborative 3GF partnerships will be brought into the regional context with the aim of developing and strengthening the regional and national attachment to the partnerships, implementing and testing partnership solutions at a regional and national level, and further engaging new regional and national partners in the partnerships. The development of partnerships that are designed to meet regional and local needs will be pursued. 

The Africa regional meeting will be co-hosted by UNEP and Kenya and take place in Nairobi on 13-14 May 2015; the Latin America regional meeting will be co-hosted by IDB and Chile and will take place in Santiago de Chile on 18-19 June 2015; and the Asia meeting will be attached to international meetings in China on 26-28 June 2015.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015-12173</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015020005</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-243152</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-243152-29702" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
