<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-262699</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DMDP 2016 &#x2013; MYPOD Work environment, productivity and social dialogue in Myanmar garment industry</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In partnership with Bestseller, 3F and Aalborg University, Danish Ethical Trading Initiative (DIEH) aims to improve the quality of jobs and create sustainable increased value addition and participation in the global garment value chain. The MYPOD project was launched in 2017, and redesigned in 2020 to respond to developments in the industry and the impact of the Covid-19 pandemic. Project activities include training and capacity-building on sector level of workers&#x2019; representatives, workers, factory management and industry stakeholders on freedom of association, social dialogue and occupational health and safety. The trainings will be developed together with trade union federations in Myanmar, and facilitated through printed and digital media, as well as workshops. Project activities are coordinated to contribute to ongoing initiatives in the Myanmar garment sector, such as the implementation of the Myanmar Guideline on Freedom of Association (FOA), agreed in November 2019 by delegates of the Employer Working Group producing in Myanmar for ACT member brands, and the Industrial Workers&#x2019; Federation of Myanmar (IWFM) affiliated with the Confederation of Trade Unions of Myanmar (CTUM) and IndustriALL Global Union, as well as initiatives by the Myanmar Joint Action Group.
As an outcome of the project, workers and employers can benefit from improved social dialogue capacity &#x2013; also at sector level &#x2013; where workers&#x2019; rights are more respected, workers&#x2019; health and safety are better protected, and work environment and productivity are improved &#x2013; all of which contribute to more decent jobs.
The Danida Market Development Partnerships programme (DMDP) is designed to support commercially oriented partnerships for sustainable market development in developing countries. In addition to reporting on individually determined outputs and outcomes, all DMDP projects report on five key programme indicators. These five indicators are the same for the whole project portfolio, enabling strategi</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar&#x2019;s garment industry will generate more decent jobs, sustainable increased value addition and participation in the global garment value chain.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016-40772</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016001203</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-262699</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Industry</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-262699-31432" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
