<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-250015</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Deliver activities in Denmark</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Denmark will be hosting the international Women Deliver Conference 16-19 May 2016. The conference is expected to attract between 5000 and 6000 participants from South and North including ministers, representatives from civil society, from the private sector as well as researchers and development and health practitioners. The conference is being organised by the international CSO &#xBF;Women Deliver&#xBF;. In order to support the actual executing of the conference including logistical challenges Associated, a contribution of 20 million DKK will be allocated to Women Deliver to cover part of the expenses associated with the implementation of the conference.

Danish actors ranging from CSOs dealing specifically with the issue of development cooperation and/or gender equality, youth organisations, professional organisations, cultural institutions and others have shown great interest in being involved in activities related to the conference. In order to ensure proper coordination and the establishment of networks to facilitate engagement and participation in activities and events related to the main topics of the conference it has been decided to create a national coordinating entity. The national coordinating entity will focus on information dissemination and communication as well as outreach, mobilisation and providing support to partners and stakeholders with the aim of transforming ideas to concrete activities. The contract of DKK 2.172.960 was put out to EU tender.

In connection to the Danish hosting of the conference, a Danish committee comprised by leaders from Danish institutions, the private sector and civil society has been established. DKK 20.000 has been allocated to cover the costs of the committee&apos;s meeting acitivities as well as other Danish Women Deliver aciitivities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-250015-30211" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-250015-30214" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-250015-30439" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
