<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-251336</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Denmark efforts in relation to the crisis in Syria, 2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With 634,064 Syrian refugees in Jordan at the end of 2015, pressures on the existing public health care system are immense. Since the Jordanian Government revised its health policy in 2014 regarding Syrian refugee access to public health care services, Syrian refugees are no longer entitled to free health care services at public health care facilities. In addition, refugees must be in possession of a valid Service Card. By end of 2015, only 50% of refugees had been issued a Card. 86% of Syrian refugees are living below the poverty line. During 2016, two Caritas Centres &#xBF; which serve up to 8,856 patients annually &#xBF; will provide access to essential primary health care services for vulnerable Syrian refugees (70%) and Jordanians (30%) in Irbid and Amman Governorates. The centres will receive essential medical supplies and consumables on a monthly basis while 3,600 patients will be covered for primary health care services. It is expected that 1,800 patients (50% of primary health care patients covered by the project) will require referral to secondary health care providers. In addition, 140 women will receive maternal and neo-natal health care services. In order to highlight the importance of pre-and post-natal monitoring and promote good practices, Caritas will conduct a health awareness campaign on maternal, neo-natal, infant health and nutritional best practices targeting 2,000 vulnerable women of childbearing age. Moreover, 46% of Syrian refugee households have at least one adult with a chronic medical condition. 56% of adults with a chronic disease are unable to access medicine or other health services as needed, primarily due to inability to pay user fees. The project will target 320 chronic disease patients with regular GP monitoring and medication, individual and group counselling sessions regarding their chronic illness and the nutritional and life-style changes they can undertake to improve the daily self-management of their disease.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015-52299</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015001209</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-251336</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-251336-30303" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
