<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-LEB-22/DDA-3604/SA1/H-P/NGO/22073</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priority 3: 

Forgotten behind bars: Providing health and protection services to one of the most vulnerable populations in North Lebanon; particularly persons deprived of their liberty in places of detention.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Places of detention are by definition closed, and keep those detained out of the sight of society with inherent risks of human rights abuses (APT, 2004). People deprived of their liberty in places of detention are one of the most vulnerable populations in Lebanon and are particularly at risk of human rights violations including torture, ill-treatment, and poor health care. Their security and well-being are under the responsibility of the Ministry of Interior (MoI) through the Internal Security Forces (ISF), which should guarantee conditions of detention that respect human rights and human dignity. 

The United Nations Standard Minimum Rules for the Treatment of Prisoners (the Nelson Mandela Rules) have stipulated the basic principles that should be respected in places of deprivation of liberty relating to, inter alia, accommodation, personal hygiene, clothing and bedding, food, healthcare services, treatment, and contact with the outside world.

In North Lebanon (NL), the Mandela Rules are completely disregarded by prison administrations. The official capacity of prisons is exceeded by 23%. In particular, around 1,011 inmates are currently incarcerated in six prisons (i.e., Kobbeh prisons for men and women, as well as Zgharta, Batroun, Douma, and Halba prisons). Lebanese detainees represent 62% of the prison population and Syrian detainees represent 25%, mainly arrested on the basis of criminal offenses (i.e., robbery, drugs). Around 10 new entries are also registered on a weekly basis in 40 police stations and two House Courts in North Lebanon and Akkar governorates including minors and women.  

Whereas the provision of health care for prisoners is a State responsibility, persons deprived of their liberty in the Lebanese places of detention do not have access to necessary and subsidized healthcare services and do not enjoy the same standards of health care that are available in the community. Restart Center has been witnessing increased risks of mortality and morbidity in places of detention in North Lebanon, due to the below reasons: 

-	Hospitalization: Most of the hospitals in NL are refusing to admit detainees because the ISF directorate is not able to cover the total costs of admission and medical services. This is particularly attributed to the gap between the official exchange rate adopted by the ISF and the hospitals&#x2019; rate. The remaining cost share is to be covered by the detainees themselves, who in most cases do not have the financial means to afford it. Other actors (such as IOM and ICRC) are also not able to cover these expenses in NL. 
-	Laboratory and other diagnostic tests &#x2500; including essential testing for infectious diseases required for new comers &#x2500; are no longer covered by the ISF directorate in most prisons since the destruction of the ISF laboratory Center during the Beirut Port explosion in 2020. 
-	Lack of specialists: Specialized doctors are refusing to work inside places of detention due to low salaries, and many general practitioners have already resigned their job inside prisons for better job opportunities. 
-	Rupture in medications: the health crisis is exacerbated by a severe rupture in medications including a shortage of essential drugs.  
-	Worsened mental health: The health crisis, exacerbated by enormous legal challenges and delays in trials, is highly affecting the mental health of detainees, particularly persons with specific needs. It is important to mention that around 64% of the prison population in NL are pre-trial inmates who are not convicted yet. Likewise, due to the socio-economic situation and fuel crisis, detainees are receiving limited support from families, which also has a negative impact on their psychosocial wellbeing.

In view of the above, under this project, Restart Center will be providing health and mental health services and legal assistance to 500 vulnerable detainees in places of detention in North Lebanon and Akkar governorates.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Restart Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Restart Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Edmonde Khawly</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Finance Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>70892903</telephone>
   <email>edmonde@restartcenter.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farah El Kurdi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Developer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>70080970</telephone>
   <email>kerdyfarah@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LBN7">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akkar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.55060000 36.07810000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="LBN5">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">North</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.43330000 35.85000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="80" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-17">129629.02</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-17">128212.3</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="LBN71-22073">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-17">257841.32</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Restart Center</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305652684">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-28">103136.53</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Restart Center</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
