<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-LEB-22/DDA-3604/SA1/P/NGO/22054</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pillar 3:Community Based Rehabilitation Project to Specific Critical Protection and Health Needs of the Most Vulnerable 500 Elderly (Above 55 years old), 100 Adults with Disabilities at Risks and their 600 Caregivers, In addition 1,000 community members  who will be receiving inclusion awareness sessions (70% Lebanese, and 25% Syrian Refugees and 5% Palestinian Refugees) in Abou Samra, Bakhaoun, Dannieh, Nabi Kazibar, Zagharta, Mhammra and Koura in North and in Fnaidek, Halba and Bireh in Akkar  (100%Protection).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Association Des Jeunes Islamiques (ADJI) will provide community based multidisciplinary rehabilitation services to elderly and Adults with disabilities to meet their emergency needs in order to prevent long-term functional/physical impairment and ensure adequate referral to specialized services in North (Abou Samra, Bakhaoun, Dannieh, Nabi Kazibar, Zagharta, Mhammra, Koura and in the surrounding areas) and in Akkar (Fnaidek, Halba, Bireh and in the surrounding areas).

The 12 month project will be implemented through innovative community based approach where ADJI will provide rehabilitation services in 10 different locations stated above through contracting 9 local physiotherapists who have equipped clinics in those localities so beneficiaries will have improved access to the project services. Also, ADJI will be working with 10 community mobilizers at the selected locations to outreach the most vulnerable population in hard to reach areas, and to sensitize the communities on the inclusion concept. Through the project ADJI will reach 2,200 beneficiaries (500 elderly, 100 Adult with disabilities, 600 caregivers and 1,000 community members) from the most vulnerable population. The project is composed of three main pillars as described below:

1. Provision of rehabilitation services to elderly and adults with disabilities. The beneficiaries will be assessed by the physiotherapists in their localities, who will conduct a general and special assessments (provided by ADJI) to capture the vulnerability status and their specific needs. Then, following to the case approval by ADJI team, the physiotherapist will set a customized action plan depending upon the need identified. The planned assistance will include the following services: i) physical and functional rehabilitation sessions, provision of rehabilitation aids, and provision of psychosocial support PSS to improve the beneficiaries&#x2019; functional independence. ADJI will assess the selected centers/clinics and will be conducting minor accessibility works if needed to remove the barriers that prevent persons with disabilities PwDs from being independence. Also, ADJI will provide technical capacity building for the physiotherapists.

2. Provision of psychosocial support PSS services to beneficiaries&#x2019; caregivers through orientation sessions and/or PSS services to enhance their coping skills to deal with the burden of caregiving and to be able to help the patients all along the treatment period. This approach will contribute to promote positive coping mechanisms of beneficiaries and their families, restoring and/or strengthening collective structures and systems essential to daily life, mental health and psychosocial well-being. The focused non-specialized sessions for beneficiaries and caregivers will be conducted biweekly by a trained PSS worker in the centers and with the support of community mobilizers.

3. Working with the community to promote an inclusive approach and ensure social cohesion. ADJI will provide a capacity building for 10 community mobilizers on outreach, safe identifications, and using the referral pathway/mechanism (including protection issues such as Gender based violence). Dedicated social workers will facilitate and follow-up on the community-based referrals completed by the community mobilizers and other external referrals where possible. Each community mobilizer will provide awareness sessions for 10 individuals on monthly basis about inclusion and rights of PwDs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASSOCIATION DES JEUNES ISLAMIQUES</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASSOCIATION DES JEUNES ISLAMIQUES</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ezzat Hussein Agha</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chief Executive Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+961 3 803 383</telephone>
   <email>ezzatagha@rahmahospital.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ihsan Al-Choghari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEO Office Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+961 3 173 432</telephone>
   <email>info@rahmahospital.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LBN7">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akkar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.55060000 36.07810000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="LBN5">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">North</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.43330000 35.85000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-15">116130.39</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-15">114861.21</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="LBN71-22054">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-15">230991.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASSOCIATION DES JEUNES ISLAMIQUES</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305645823">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-23">92396.64</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASSOCIATION DES JEUNES ISLAMIQUES</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
