<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-LEB-22/DDA-3604/SA1/FS-W-P/NGO/22072</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pillar 1: Providing an inclusive multi-sectoral response to 480 households with at least one PwD or one older person with food parcels and WASH kits and 660 PwDs and older persons with protection services in Tripoli, Akkar, and Minnieh-Dennieh.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Going into its 4th year of severe economic recession, Lebanon is facing its worst and hardest depression ever since the end of the Lebanese Civil War that went on for 15 years. Between the Syrian refugee influx crisis, street protests, COVID-19 pandemic, dangerous depletion of resources, Beirut port explosion on August 4 2020, overlapping economic, financial and social crises, Lebanon grapples to survive on the edge of collapse. The economic crisis in Lebanon is ranked as one of the top ten most severe episodes globally (World bank, 2021). The extreme depreciation of the Lebanese lira (92 per cent of its value) has contributed to a triple digit annual inflation of 214 per cent between February 2021 and February 2022 ((CAS), Consumer Price Index (CPI), February 2022). As a result, humanitarian needs increased between 2021 and 2022 as living standards continued to deteriorate and physical and mental well-being of people in Lebanon continued to worsen. All population groups in Lebanon are facing increased food insecurity and very limited access to basic services.

This project mainly targets PwDs and older persons from all population groups who are facing exacerbated vulnerabilities (socioeconomic vulnerability, food insecurity, increased protection threats, limited access to essential hygiene items, lack of critical assistive devices and therapies).
In order to mitigate the above-mentioned situation, and to address the emerging challenges and needs, this project will provide a package of tailored services that are very responsive to the needs of disability and diverse age groups through an integrated approach:
- 1,920 nutritionally balanced food parcels for 480 HHs for a duration of 4 months
- 960 WASH kits (760 hygiene kits and 200 dignity kits) for 480 HHs for a duration of 2 months

To complement the above, the following protection activities will be implemented:
- Case management for 100 cases (PwDs and older persons)
- Individual counseling for 300 cases (including those taken under case management)
- The provision of 200 assistive devices for PwDs and older persons
- The provision of 100 self/home care supplies for PwDs and older persons 
- The provision of 900 physical therapy sessions for 60 PwDs and older persons

In alignment with the FSS priorities and LHF 2022 first standard allocation strategy paper, the identification of eligible beneficiaries will be based on a validation assessment that will be revised by LHF prior starting the implementation phase. The following vulnerability profiles will be prioritized among other: 
- PwDs (men with disabilities, women with disabilities and children with disabilities)
- Older persons (older women and older men)
- Households including at least one person with disability, households including at least one older person
- PwDs and older persons facing protection threats, unable to meet their needs due to lack of family/community support, lack of financial resources will be also prioritized for different services.

Center based and home-based distribution modalities will be adopted to address the accessibility challenges faced by our targeted groups.

FoH is an organization of persons with disabilities that owns 4 accessible centers located in Mina, Koura, Dennieh and Akkar, a fully accessible fleet, disability and age expertise, and the required human and financial resources that will allow to ensure the high quality of implementation while responding to the specific needs of the targeted population in the priority areas as indicated in the LHF 1st standard allocation strategy 2022.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Forum for the Rights of Persons with Disabilities</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Forum for the Rights of Persons with Disabilities</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reem Ismail</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>71258282</telephone>
   <email>ismailreem94@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Randa Abdo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Financial Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>71685837</telephone>
   <email>randa.abdo@theforum-lb.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LBN7">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akkar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.55060000 36.07810000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="LBN5">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">North</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.43330000 35.85000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="70" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="15" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="15" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-22">201661.03</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-22">199457.08</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="LBN71-22072">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-22">401118.11</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Forum for the Rights of Persons with Disabilities</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
