<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-BOL146</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID support to indigenous campesino families in the Potosi department, Bolivia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To date Bolivia officially has over 100,000 confirmed cases and 4,000 deaths due to COVID although the actual figures are believed to be far higher. The strict quarantine that began in March caused extreme hardship for the most vulnerable people, particularly small-scale farmers in rural areas. Potosi is one of the poorest departments in the country and with restrictions in place, many Potosino farmers were unable to travel to towns to sell their produce. This cut of their only source of income and their access to markets. As a result, many families have been plunged into a food security crisis, facing a scarcity or absence of food. The crisis is affecting women and girls disproportionately as in Bolivian rural families they are charged with preparing food and caring for the family particularly if anyone is sick. Small-scale family farmers have become a fundamental pillar of feeding the population during the crisis and if their need for seeds is not dealt with quickly in the run up to the sowing season (September) it is expected that the food crisis will worsen in both cities and the countryside. 
The current social unrest which is likely to continue and worsen during September and October is also limiting the opportunities for rural families to get back on their feet. Blockades limit their access to markets and options for earning income to buy seeds.  
The Project will provide support to 255 indigenous and rural families who survive as small-scale agriculture in the municipalities of Vitichi, Caiza D and Tupiza, in the department of Potos&#xED;. On average each family is formed of 5 people between adult men and women, children and adolescents. Potatoes are the local staple food in the region however mandatory quarantine rules have led many families to lack other food supplies including vegetables, meat/fish/eggs and dry foods.  Families will able to produce vegetables for their daily consumption and for sale in local markets.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="BOL146" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acci&#xF3;n Cultural Loyola - Potos&#xED;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="BOL146" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="BOL146" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-17">5343.5114</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54307">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-18">5343.5114</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68744">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-18">5343.51</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acci&#xF3;n Cultural Loyola - Potos&#xED;</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
