<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-BOL122</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening local capacity for the participatory implementation of the SDGs in Bolivia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Urban Programme (UP) is run by key CAFOD partner UNITAS (BOL087), a network of 22 NGOs and social organisations from across Bolivia, including other CAFOD partners. The UP builds the capacity of social organisations representing vulnerable groups to protect their economic, social and cultural (ESC) human rights. Their new project for 2016-2018 is structured so that all the community groups supported by the project all contribute to Bolivia&#x2019;s achievement of a number of SDGs. This is particularly vital given the current challenge of ensuring that Government at all levels implement the SGDs via local and national development plans and the need to build the capacity of civil society and state representatives on this issue. The UP has identified six vulnerable urban groups experiencing abuses of their ESC rights: rubbish collectors; factory workers; disabled people&#x2019;s groups; landless migrants; women&#x2019;s organisations and; urban indigenous groups. The project will train these groups in the protection of their human rights and the SDGs.  This extra project is funded by PPA top-up investment fund 2016 and will enable the project to increase the training of organisations in SDGs and enable the UP to provide training on human rights and SDGs to local authorities in seven municipalities so that they are informed and aware of the importance of participatory implementation of the SDGs. The UP will engage with local authorities on the importance of funding for organisations and initiatives that contribute to achievement of the SDGs from a rights perspective and will allow roundtables to be established to promote dialogue between local authorities and social organisations. The extra funds will support the production of a guide to SDGs and human rights for participants which will include tools to help participants share their learning with other members of their organisations. Organisations supported by the UP project will participate in a foundation training course and receive accompaniment with the development of advocacy strategies to advance the cases that they are fighting to protect their human rights.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="BOL122" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="BOL122" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uni&#xF3;n de Instituciones para el Trabajo de Acci&#xF3;n Social</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="BOL122" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-04-01">20000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="48586">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-13">20000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-1-202669">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="62471">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-13">20000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uni&#xF3;n de Instituciones para el Trabajo de Acci&#xF3;n Social</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
