<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-BOL132</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Living well in the Amazon forests of Bolivia: an alternative model of development for the Amazon</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD has funded CIPCA Norte Amaz&#xF3;nico since 2011 in its efforts to support indigenous and rural farmers (campesinos) in the sustainable management of their resources in particular water resources and forests.  The Bolivian Amazon has historically been an area of political oblivion, notable for its geographical isolation and untamed nature. This change is due to burgeoning openness to the globalized economy and groups of economic and political power pushing for regional integration with an extractivist approach. These changes carry with them great threats to the natural ecosystems of the region and with it for the rural inhabitants who still have livelihoods strongly linked to their natural environment.
The products from previous phases of the CAFOD - CIPCA NA cooperation have contributed to regional debates on the vision and potential for development in the Amazon, strengthening an alternative proposal for productive development that arises from the Bolivian Amazon itself. Public entities are identifying with these proposals and the Bolivian State has begun adopting public policies that favour this organic vision of development and its multiple economic, social and environmental benefits. Unfortunately, the communities, social leaders and authorities are frequently unaware of these policies. CIPCA will work with indigenous and campesino social organisations to overcome the limited communication and coordination between producer families, their leaders and support institutions. It will help them raise awareness across the region, publicising the proposals, issues and debates on sustainable development issues that they have prioritised. It will also provide accompaniment and support to help leaders improve their capacities and skills in advocacy work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="BOL132" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="BOL132" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centro de Investigaci&#xF3;n y Promoci&#xF3;n del Campesinado &#x2013; Norte Amaz&#xF3;nico</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="BOL132" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-01">14893.617</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="50692">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-26">14893.617</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="64840">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-26">14893.62</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centro de Investigaci&#xF3;n y Promoci&#xF3;n del Campesinado &#x2013; Norte Amaz&#xF3;nico</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
