<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHAS-HPC6770-6652</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHAS-HPC6770" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="AR">King Salman Humanitarian Aid and Relief Centre</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening primary health care services and managing malnutrition cases in Yemen</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Reducing the prevalence of acute malnutrition through regular survey, referral and treatment of severely malnourished children under the age of five, as well as pregnant and lactating women.
2. Providing life-saving preventive feeding services to vulnerable community groups by focusing on appropriate infant and young child feeding practices in emergency situations, by providing micronutrients and nutritional supplements.
3. Participation in routine vaccination campaigns in cooperation with WHO and UNICEF.
4. Strengthening the role of the nutritional monitoring system during the duration of the project.
5. Increasing the access of vulnerable groups, especially internally displaced persons, to basic health services to provide appropriate diagnosis and treatment
6. Capacity building for medical and technical staff professionally and scientifically and raising their capabilities to deal with specific cases.
7. Reducing the migration of specialized medical and technical cadres.
8. Training and scientifically rehabilitating young Yemeni cadres through special trainings for the CMAM &amp; IYCF program.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing the main services in the health and nutrition sectors alike within the package of health services necessary in case of emergency, which includes providing survey and nutritional assessment for children under the age of five, pregnant and lactating women, participating in routine vaccination campaigns, medical diagnosis and providing treatment for all age and sexual segments in the targeted communities Within the project</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charitable Association for Giving</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="6652" crs-channel-code="11000" ref="XM-OCHA-HPC6770" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King Salman Humanitarian Aid and Relief Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-18" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-17" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-17"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-18">5500000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-18">5500000</value>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
