<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHAS-HPC6770-4845</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHAS-HPC6770" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="AR">King Salman Humanitarian Aid and Relief Centre</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support, protection and care for orphan children and their families in conflict areas.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Alleviating the suffering and want of orphans for a decent and safe life for them, and providing food and shelter. - Taking care of the children of deprived orphans comprehensively &quot;socially - educational - health - psychologically&quot;, to contribute to achieving social solidarity, providing safety for deprived orphan children, and creating a suitable environment for their upbringing to be active members of their society. Providing training courses and providing them with project empowerment tools to help single-headed women acquire and enhance their skills that open up job opportunities for them and improve their standard of living.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- The targeted families of 100 orphan families obtained their annual rent during the project period, (70) apartments and (30) independent houses. - Food aid reached every month for 100 families during the project. Providing health care to 600 orphans and their families. Distributing (100) personal hygiene kits (6) times, and it is distributed every two months, once during the project. - 100 families receive cultural awareness. - The targeted families of 100 orphan families obtained their annual rent during the project period, (70) apartments and (30) independent houses. Providing health care to 600 orphans and their families. Distributing (100) personal hygiene kits (6) times, and it is distributed every two months, once during the project. - 100 families receive cultural awareness. Distributing bags and school uniforms to 295 children from 7-18 years, providing them with transportation and paying their fees. Providing ten counseling sessions for male and female students and their families. - Registration of 295 orphans and orphans students in schools and the implementation of 5 school visits during the academic year to follow up on students &#x2019;regularity. - Set up (4) group breakfast tables during the blessed month of Ramadan. -600 orphans receive Eid clothing and Eid gifts. - (100) beneficiaries and their families obtained social support and alleviation of problems. - 100 female breadwinners receive training services and career tools for their projects</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing comprehensive protection, care, improving livelihoods and economic recovery for orphans and their families in Yemen in conflict areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benevollence</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="4845" crs-channel-code="11000" ref="XM-OCHA-HPC6770" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King Salman Humanitarian Aid and Relief Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-01">535000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-01">535000</value>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
