<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHAS-HPC6770-4149</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHAS-HPC6770" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="AR">King Salman Humanitarian Aid and Relief Centre</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Preparation and operation of the artificial limb manufacturing and rehabilitation center in Taiz</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Manufacture and installation of 429 high-quality (lower-upper) prostheses. 2. Physical rehabilitation for 600 injured. 3. The steadfastness of the medical and technical staff and the resettlement of the service to 36 Yemeni youths from the health cadres to work in the Artificial Limbs Center in Taiz. 4. Providing various training programs for 50 young Yemeni cadres in the fields of (Industry and prosthetic prosthesis / physical rehabilitation / psychological support).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Raise the readiness of the prosthesis center to cope with the actual need. 2. Manufacture and installation of artificial limbs of all kinds. 3. Providing a career rehabilitation service before and after installing prostheses, with physical and psychological rehabilitation, physiotherapy services, following up and benefiting from them in community service. 4. Building capacities of the medical and technical staff professionally and scientifically and raising its capabilities to deal with specific cases. 5. Reducing the migration of specialized medical and technical personnel.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project of preparing and operating the limb manufacturing and rehabilitation center in Taiz aims to provide production services for prosthetics of all kinds and the physical and psychological rehabilitation of injured and injured Yemenis who have been subjected to amputation of their upper or lower limbs as a result of the spread of random mines, which contributes to opening the way for them to return to practice their normal lives as they were With the empowerment of these services within the center, by providing training programs for young Yemeni cadres in the fields of (manufacturing and installing prostheses / physical / psychological rehabilitation).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="21000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Ameen For Humanitarian Suport.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="4149" crs-channel-code="11000" ref="XM-OCHAS-HPC6770" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="AR">King Salman Humanitarian Aid and Relief Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-12" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12191" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-12-12"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-06-12"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-12">1066666</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-12">1066666</value>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
