<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5102009701-ASI-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">BLIA - Att vara HBT person i  Asien (UNDP) - Fas 2  - 2014-2019</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BLIA- Being LGBT in Asia (UNDP) - Phase 2 - 2014-2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Being LGBTI in Asia Phase 2, is a regional partnership between UNDP, the Swedish Embassy in Bangkok and USAID. The project focus on four countries: China, Indonesia, the Philippines and Thailand. The aim of the project is to promote LGBTI inclusive development in Asia.
The project has three objectives:
Through community building and empowerment, support LGBTI individuals to know their rights, and to have access to justice to report on human rights violations and end impunity.
Through community mobilization and advocacy (law makers, local government, judiciary and National Human Rights Institutions (NHRIs) to ensure the development and enforcement of protective laws and policies (anti-violence/anti-discrimination) Through community mobilization and engagement with key stakeholders (religious organizations, private sector, law enforcement authorities, educational institutions to address stigma and discrimination and end harmful practices that fuel human rights violations against LGBTI people in public and private settings, and to ensure that LGBTI people have equal access to public services.
These are to be achieved by contributing to the following outcomes:
1) Increased capacity of LGBTI organizations to effectively mobilize, advocate and contribute in policy dialogues and community empowerment activities;
2) Improved capacity and action of governments, the judiciary, parliaments and National Human Rights Institutions (NHRI) to develop SOGIE-related protective laws and policies;
3) Reduced stigma and discrimination and harmful practices against LGBTI people.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Right holders, duty bearers and relevant stakeholders in South East   and East Asia as well as in project countries have increased capacity and willingness to advocate for, develop and implement LGBTI          inclusive laws, policies and programs. The program is being           implemented by UNDP and partners and financed by Sweden, USaid and    UNDP.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNDP har inkommit med en ans&#xF6;kan till Sverige f&#xF6;r st&#xF6;d om 25 000 000 SEK f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;rande av ett regionalt program; Being LGBT in Asia, phase 2: Supporting LGBT inclusive development in South-East and East Asia (BLIA 2) f&#xF6;r perioden 2014-2017. Programmet samfinansieras av UNDP och USAID som ocks&#xE5; har samarbetat tidigare under den f&#xF6;rsta fasen av st&#xF6;det - BLIA 1.

Insatsen syftar i i f&#xF6;rsta hand till att ha en positiv inverkan f&#xF6;r utvecklingen i Sydostasien d&#xE4;r LGBTI personer &#xE4;r inkluderade. Det &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let f&#xF6;r programmet &#xE4;r att efter tre &#xE5;r ha bidragit till st&#xE4;rkt kapacitet och vilja hos beslutsfattare och andra nyckelakt&#xF6;rer f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja, driva och utveckla lagar, politik och program som inkluderar LGBTI personer. F&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade resultat &#xE4;r; (1) &#xF6;kad kapacitet hos LGBTI organisationer att kunna mobilisera, p&#xE5;verka och bidra effektivt till politiska dialoger och gemensamma aktiviteter f&#xF6;r &#xF6;kat inflytande, (2) Regeringars, r&#xE4;ttsv&#xE4;sendet, parlament och nationella institut f&#xF6;r m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter har &#xF6;kat sin kapacitet och sitt agerande kring utvecklande av lagar och politik som inkluderar LGBTI, (3) Minskad stigmatisering och diskriminering och bek&#xE4;mpa skadligt beteende mot LGBTI personer i utvalda omr&#xE5;den.

Insatsen har en stark j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetskomponent och kommer &#xE4;ven att bidra till att bek&#xE4;mpa k&#xF6;nsrelaterat v&#xE5;ld i regionen.

Total budget f&#xF6;r insatsen &#xE4;r 8 285 929 USD varav UNDP st&#xE5;r f&#xF6;r 1 947 012 USD och USAID bidrar med 3 000 000 USD. USAIDs finansiering g&#xE5;r i huvudsak till nationella aktiviteter inom programmets fyra fokusl&#xE4;nder - Kina, Indonesien, Filippinerna och Thailand. Sverige finansierar de regionala aktiviteterna med bidrag fr&#xE5;n b&#xE5;de USAID och UNDP. Sveriges finansierar ocks&#xE5; tv&#xE5; tj&#xE4;nster inom UNDP f&#xF6;r implementeringen av programmet - en handl&#xE4;ggare tj&#xE4;nst inom LGBT och m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter samt en heltidstj&#xE4;nst inom uppf&#xF6;ljning och utv&#xE4;rdering f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka fokus p&#xE5; resultat.
Sverige finansierar det regionala aktiviteterna av programmet dvs inga av Sveriges pengar kommer att g&#xE5; till nationella aktiviteter. Programmet har en tydligt regional ansats och detta &#xE4;r formulerat fr&#xE4;mst med tanke p&#xE5; att minimera konflikter, politisk k&#xE4;nslighet och represalier p&#xE5; LGBT personer i l&#xE4;nder och kontexter d&#xE4;r de &#xE4;r utsatta pga av diskriminerande lagstiftning och/eller religi&#xF6;sa eller kulturella f&#xF6;rdomar. Att jobba regionalt f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka LGBTI personers r&#xE4;ttigheter och levnadsituation skapar f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar f&#xF6;r f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndring &#xE4;ven p&#xE5; nationell niv&#xE5;. Sveriges bidrag g&#xE5;r fr&#xE4;mst till ogranisationsst&#xE4;rkande insatser f&#xF6;r tv&#xE5; regionala akt&#xF6;rer, samt regionalt p&#xE5;verkansarbete och opinionsbildning gentemot ASEAN och andra viktiga regionala akt&#xF6;rer. Sverige finansierar ocks&#xE5; nyckelpositioner inom UNDPs program personal som n&#xE4;mnts ovan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asia, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1457747.197481013</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">830436.6910656876</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1457747.197481013</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">830436.6910656877</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">-1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-01">2478170.235717</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-28">1457747.197481013</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">830436.6910656876</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Phase 1 (2012-2013) of the BLIA project, focused on developing an evidence base of the lived experience of LGBTI people through research and engagement of civil society groups throughout the region. This engagement was facilitated through convening eight national LGBTI dialogues, publishing national reports and producing 12 videos highlighting community stories from the region.
Informed by this process, BLIA Phase 2 (2014-2018), through a combination of regional and country specific programming, has strengthened the capacity of civil society groups, government departments and human rights bodies to address priority issues on SOGIE, built broad coalitions with key stakeholders, including the private sector,media and academic institutions, and strengthened the evidence base on SOGIE and intersex issues.&#xA0;
BLIAP Phase 3, with the inclusion of Pacific in the geographical focus (2019-2023), is currently under implementation and have been supported by Sida through indirect earmarked support under the USAID Global partnership intervention (contribution no. 54050228) for implementation year 2019 and direct support from the Embassy (contribution no. 13787) for implementation year 2020.
The purpose of this statement is to assess the results from and close Sida&apos;s contribution to UNDP for implementation of Phase II, during years 2014-2018. The results generated during this period have been captured by the implementation partner through annual reports and in 2018 there was an external review performed on the project which validated many of the results reported by the partner.&#xA0;
For more annual results, please see the separate statements on the narrative reports each year. Below a few examples are highlighted:&#xA0;
- A significant volume of publications, videos, and other type of data has been generated by BLIA directly or with support from BLIA. The range of topics covered includes health, education, employment, access to justice, and, the media. Each of these publications is the result of related consultationsand other research. E.g. The &quot;Legal Gender Recognition: A Multi-Country Legal and Policy Review in Asia&quot;. The study is a comprehensive review of laws, regulations and policies relating to legal gender recognition in nine countries in Asia - China, Bangladesh, India, Nepal, Pakistan, the Philippines, Thailand, Indonesia, and Malaysia. Another example is the multi-country study on employment discrimination based on sexual orientation, gender identity and sex characteristics in China, the Philippines and Thailand. This is the first systematic study to examine the extent and forms of access to employment and workplace discrimination based on sexual orientation, gender identity or expression and sex characteristics in China, the Philippines and Thailand.&#xA0;
- BLIA has had both direct, and contributory roles, in building the capacity of three regional civil society networks, including APTN, ASC, and B-Change. Today, APTN and ASC play significant roles in advocacy, research, and programming throughout Asia and the Pacific through numerous initiatives that are building the capacity of both civil society and government departments, including NHRIs. B-Change focuses on the use of technology to further the social, economic and cultural inclusion of LGBTI persons using web-apps and web and mobile-based platforms. A success story, which also relates synergy between donors, is APTN&#x2019;s successful application for funding from a donor that has more stringent requirements for organizational capacity. That donor credits the work of BLIA for preparing the CSO for the responsibility of the grant it will receive. A success story for ASC has been its involvement with civil society partners seeking to engage with UN human rights monitoring mechanisms. As part of its &#x201C;Strengthening South-South Collaboration for a Human Rights-based LGBTIQ Activism in Southeast Asia&#x201D; initiative, funded by BLIA, ASC sponsored a Regional Workshop on Engaging with UN Special Procedures in the Philippines in May 2017 to build the capacity of LGBT activists to use the Special Procedures and to assist them in drafting evidence-based communications to the Special Procedures on various human rights issues.
-&#xA0;A total of eleven laws and policies in seven countries have been influenced by BLIA - either directly or indirectly through its partnership with organizations that do so. E.g. Thailand&apos;s Gender Equality Act (2015) for which BLIA supported the launch with Ministry of Social Development and HUman Security to support implementation and monitoring, including trainings on SOGIE for MSHDS officials. BLIA has provided input during the public consultation process of the Thai Civil Partnership Act and for the Thai Gender Recognition Law. For the latter law, BLIA also facilitated wider community consultation. In the Philippines, the project supported sub- national level consultative processes in collaboration with local partners, including the National Commission on Human Rights to the Anti-discrimination bill, to include clearer articulation of SOGIE in the bill. In China, the project held national consultation on Trans HIV/Health with health officials, provided Chinese translation of the Blueprint for the Provision of Comprehensive Care for Trans People and Trans Communities in Asia and the Pacific. In Viet Nam, the project has provided technical assistance on good practice in the drafting of the Gender legal recognition laws.&#xA0;
- BLIA has both worked with NHRIs to strengthen their capacity and willingness to protect and promote human rights for LGBTI people. In partnership with the Asia Pacific Forum of National Rights Institutions (APF), BLIAP has supported capacity development of 17 NHRIs through development of a handbook onSOGIESC and trainings which were rolled out in the three sub-regions in 2017. Following the training programme, BLIAP supported joint action plans with NHRIs and civil society in five countries (Bangladesh, Samoa, Fiji, Philippines and Timor-Leste) to further engagement on priority areas identified&#xA0;in the sub-regional workshops, including legal gender recognition, right to health, and addressing bullying of LGBTI children in schools.
- When it comes to capacity building component in the project, BLIA has built the capacity of government agencies, policymakers, civil society and other organizations to influence laws and policies. a total of 5 766 human rights defenders have been trained and supported, 37 advocacy frameworks developed by civil society groups, 3 sub- regional trainings conducted to strengthen SOGIE capacity of NHRIs in South Asia, Southeast Asia and the Pacific, and 165 government departments were engaged with, including Ministries of Health, Justice, Social Development and Education, Embassies and local government agencies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51020097" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
