<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5102010703-ASI-23210</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADB Clean Energy Financing Partnership  Facility</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">ADB Clean Energy Financing Partnership  Facility</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">CEFs huvudsakliga m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att finansiera projekt inom &quot;ren Energi&quot;,  dvs. f&#xF6;rnybart, energieff, och tillg&#xE5;ng till energi. Fonden  finansierar &#xE4;ven pilotprojekt, utveckling av policy,                  finansieringsmetoder etc. f&#xF6;r att stimulere ren energi.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clean Energy Fund is part of ADB Clean Energy Financing Partnership  Facility. Main objective to finance projects in clean energy, major demonstration projects, policy development and mode of fundings.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Clean Energy Financing Partnership Facility (CEFPF) was established in 2007 to help improve energy security in Developing Member Countries (DMCs) and decrease the rate of climate change. It will do this by financing the deployment of new, more efficient and less polluting supply and end-use technologies, through either grant or non-grant resources. The CEFPF is composed of the Clean Energy Fund (CEF), the Asian Clean Energy Fund (ACEF), the Carbon Capture and Storage Fund (CCSF) and the Canadian Climate Fund for the Private Sector in Asia (CFPS).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="46000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADB/ADB-Clean Energy Fund/Asian Development Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="46000" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADB/ADB-Clean Energy Fund/Asian Development Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asia, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="23210" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy generation, renewable sources - multiple technologies</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="232" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy generation, renewable sources</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="13.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13.1 - Strengthen resilience and adaptive capacity to climate-related hazards and natural disasters in all countries.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">13.1 - St&#xE4;rka motst&#xE5;ndskraften mot och f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;gan till anpassning till klimatrelaterade faror och naturkatastrofer i alla l&#xE4;nder.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="7.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">7.1 - By 2030, ensure universal access to affordable, reliable and modern energy services.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">7.1 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till ekonomiskt &#xF6;verkomliga, tillf&#xF6;rlitliga och moderna energitj&#xE4;nster.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="7.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">7.a - By 2030, enhance international cooperation to facilitate access to clean energy research and technology, including renewable energy, energy efficiency and advanced and cleaner fossil-fuel technology, and promote investment in energy infrastructure and clean energy technology.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">7.a - Till 2030 st&#xE4;rka det internationella samarbetet f&#xF6;r att underl&#xE4;tta tillg&#xE5;ng till forskning och teknik inom ren energi, inklusive f&#xF6;rnybar energi, energieffektivitet samt avancerad och renare fossilbr&#xE4;nslebaserad teknik, samt fr&#xE4;mja investeringar i energiinfrastruktur och ren energiteknik.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">3e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/thailand/adb-sida-agreement-re-cef-2008-2010.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/thailand/first-addendum-cefpf.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/thailand/decision-cefpf-2012-1276.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Decision on Contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The&#xA0;CEFPF&apos;s performance measure against the target outcome at the completion of all projects in its portfolio. To date, the combined support of the CEFPF and Climate Change Fund Clean Energy Component (CCF-CE) have surpassed the (two) outcome level targets for carbon dioxide (CO2) emission reduction (27.1 million tons of CO2 emission reduction/year attained vs. target of 20.0 million of CO2 emission reduction/year) and energy savings (18.7 terra-watt hour-equivalent/year of energy savings attained vs. target of 18.0 TWh-eq/year). The installed renewable energy capacity reached 2,329.8 mega-watt (MW) which is 67% achievement rate of the 3,500 MW target. Meanwhile, the renewable energy generation reached 7.4 TWh/year which is 74% achievement rate of the 10 TWh/year target.&#xA0;

In terms&#xA0;of outputs level indicators, 12 out of the 16 indicators are progressing well and have achieved at least 75% of the target.&#xA0;There are 4 output indicators that require significant work which include households provided with access to energy in participating developing member countries (DMCs) supported, households connected to modern fuels and/or efficient devices for heating, households connected to modern fuels and/or efficient devices for cooking, and carbon capture and storage&#xA0;demonstration projects.&#xA0;

Gender aspects is related to the output - Benefits from access to energy delivered.&#xA0;To date, CEFPF has supported 36 projects with access to energy components that will benefit 392,887 households provided with energy access. This number falls short of the target 700,000 household, which illustrates the difficulty encountered by the CEFPF in attracting&#xA0;access to energy projects.&#xA0;The CEFPF also supports projects that improve women access to energy, social services, economic and financial resources and opportunities, and contribute to gender equality and women empowerment. To date, 82% (of target 80%) of projects with access to energy component contribute to the improvement Results Framework of women energy access.

The CEFPF will continue the multi-sector approach including sectors such as transport, agriculture, water and education sectors that are likely to integrate more clean renewable energy solutions into project design and development.

In energy sector, the ADB is addressing the impact of CVOID-19 through projects. For example, the outbreak of the Coronavirus disease&#xA0;has raised concerns on the transmission of viruses through centralized air conditioning (CAC) systems.&#xA0;In many ADB&apos;s Developing Member Countries (DMCs), the risk of transmission in CAC systems is higher because of inadequate hygiene standards. Toward this, the CEFPF co-financed a Knowledge and Support Technical Assistance (KSTA) to support DMCs mitigate the risks of virus transmission and ensure safe working conditions in public buildings by deploying efficient, clean, and smart CAC&#xA0;systems.&#xA0;It is envisioned that pilot systems will demonstrate the effectively&#xA0;of the technology and be taken up by the DMCs to mitigate the risk of COVID-19 and other transmittable diseases.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51020107" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
