<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5100009102-ASI-15130</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNEP REN 2011-2016 Collaboration Customs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNEP REN 2011-2016 Tullsamarbete</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental crime is one of the most profitable areas of international criminal activity. Criminal organisations earn approximately $10-12 billion per year for dumping waste. Growing international concerns regarding these types of environmental crimes have led to several global Multilateral Environmental Agreements; the Stockholm, Basel and Rotterdam Convention. Building on the Multilateral Environmental Agreements, the Regional Enforcement Network for Chemicals and Waste, (REN) was set- up with the aim to build a network for improved cooperation and capacity building of front line officers on national and regional levels to reduce illegal transboundary movement of chemicals and waste.&#xA0;
Sida has provided financial support to the Regional Enforcement Network for Chemicals and Waste (REN) program with 11 million SEK from 2011-2018.&#xA0; The overall goal of the program has been to reduce unwanted trans boundary movement of hazardous chemical and waste in Asia by preventing illegal trade and encouraging legal trade. Through the improved enforcement cooperation regionally and globally and the targeted problem- solving capacity building at the national level through a network, the program enabled enforcement officers to monitor and control trans boundary movements of chemicals and waste more efficiently. &#xA0;
REN had five priority areas within the framework of the objective 1) Technical assistance for problem-solving2) Information and intelligence sharing 3) Enforcement operations and the Asia Environment Enforcement Award 4) Networking and awareness 5) Partnership for sustainability
REN consisted of a network of 25 countries across North-East, South and South-East Asia coordinated by UN Environment. Example of countries in the network were Cambodia, Thailand, India, Indonesia, Malaysia, China and Vietnam.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Kapacitetsutvecklingsst&#xF6;d till tulltj&#xE4;nstem&#xE4;n i Asien, g&#xE4;llande       hanteringen av milj&#xF6;farligt avfall. UNEP &#xE4;r samarbetspart.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kapacity development support to customs officers in Asia, concerning  the handling of hazardeous waste. UNEP is cooperating partner.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41116" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNEP/United Nations Environment Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41116" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNEP/United Nations Environment Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asia, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Legal and judicial development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="12.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">12.4 - By 2020, achieve the environmentally sound management of chemicals and all wastes throughout their life cycle, in accordance with agreed international frameworks, and significantly reduce their release to air, water and soil in order to minimize their adverse impacts on human health and the environment.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">12.4 - Senast 2020 uppn&#xE5; milj&#xF6;v&#xE4;nlig hantering av kemikalier och alla typer av avfall under hela deras livscykel, i enlighet med &#xF6;verenskomna internationella ramverket, samt avsev&#xE4;rt minska utsl&#xE4;ppen av dem i luft, vatten och mark i syfte att minimera deras negativa konsekvenser f&#xF6;r m&#xE4;nniskors h&#xE4;lsa och milj&#xF6;n.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="12.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">12.5 - By 2030, substantially reduce waste generation through prevention, reduction, recycling and reuse.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">12.5 - Till 2030 v&#xE4;sentligt minska m&#xE4;ngden avfall genom &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rebygga, minska, &#xE5;teranv&#xE4;nda och &#xE5;tervinna avfall.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="14.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">14.1 - By 2025, prevent and significantly reduce marine pollution of all kinds, in particular from land-based activities, including marine debris and nutrient pollution.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">14.1 - Till 2025 f&#xF6;rebygga och avsev&#xE4;rt minska alla slags f&#xF6;roreningar i havet, i synnerhet fr&#xE5;n landbaserad verksamhet, inklusive marint skr&#xE4;p och tillf&#xF6;rsel av n&#xE4;rings&#xE4;mnen.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">234000.234000234</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">234000.234000234</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">5.4e-9</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">-54291.344994951</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-12-01">308204.401158</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-28">234000.234000234</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-28">-54291.3938564774</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The foundation for a REN- network between customs officers and environmental authorities in the region have led to the following results: &#xA0;
Between 2011-2018 REN succeeded to support the seizure of 865,000 tons of illegally traded chemicals and waste through improved information exchange between countries. The program efforts resulted in that 1476 front line enforcement officers were trained and that five joint enforcement operations were undertaken. One of the most important joint operations included a collaboration between 43 countries and Interpol. This is referred to as the &quot;30 days of action&quot;, which resulted in that over 1.5 million tonnes of illegal waste was detected worldwide.&#xA0;
The increase in seizures in the member countries is partly a result of REN&#xB4;s long- term capacity&#xA0; building support to custom officers at national and regional level in the region.The capacity building in combination with strengthened multi-sectoral collaboration between customs and environmental authorities has been assessed as one of the key factor for success. REN&#xB4;s &#xA0; mediating role between &quot;export- and receiving countries&quot; has also been appreciated by the countries, which resulted in that some of the shipments with illegal waste were sent back to exporting countries.&#xA0; REN created the Asia Environment Enforcement Award, which celebrated&#xA0; the most successful authority and enforcement officer of the year. &#xA0;
The perspectives of gender, human rights and environment and climate change were brought up at the Annual meetings between Sweden and UNEP. UNEP focused more on gender equality, human rights and anti-corruption at the later stage of the implementation of REN as a response to Sweden&#xB4;s request. As a first step, REN raised awareness and initiated discussions on anti-corruption and on Human Rights based approach with their partners in various workshops. The gender perspective was partly addressed, through increased awareness raising and through enhancing the participation of women in the network and the workshops .&#xA0;
Many of the member countries in the network got inspired by other member-countries work and UNEP to improve their work on illegal import of waste and chemicals. For example, China&#xB4;s Custom hosted REN:s 6th Annual Workshop and organised a national waste training workshop in Shanghai. China has also introduced reforms to reduce import of illegal waste and hazardous chemicals. Malaysian Customs, Environmental and Port Authorities as well as Police and Fire Rescue Departments signed an intergovernmental Memorandum of Understanding for an efficient exchange of information to improve follow- up and enforcement. &#xA0;
UNEP undertook a final evaluation of the program in March 2018. All in all, REN partners were very positive about the established network, although some partners still were reluctant to collaborate and / or take ownership of the programme and its activities. The reasons for this is partly that partners had limited capacity and understanding of the program. A shared vision between the member- states was absent in the project design and no broad stakeholder analysis had been carried out at the beginning of the program, which consequently led to rather limited engagment and ownership of the program. &#xA0;
Besides, this it was revealed that many of the activities were delivered by a single partner in consultation with UN Environment, limiting synergies and outreach of the program. Adding incentives for collaboration among partners is something that could have generated improved results and enhanced conditions for sustainability. &#xA0;
A network was establish, demonstrating and creating awareness of the importance of regional cooperation in&#xA0; waste management to hamper and control illegal trade of waste and harmful chemicals. There were nevertheless many issues that were difficult for the program to tackle and address due to the original set- up and design of the programme.&#xA0;The evaluation concluded that the project had delivered moderately satisfactory</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51000091" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040503" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="2030000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional Asia and Oceania 2016-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt Asien och Oceanien 2016-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
