<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5102014702-ASI-43030</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADB Cities Dev. Initi. (CDIA),Phase 2, 2013-17</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">ADB Cities Dev. Initi. (CDIA),Phase 2, 2013-17</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Cities Development Initiative for Asia (CDIA) aims to contribute to the promotion of sustainable and equitable urban development, leading to improved environmental and living conditions for all in Asian and Pacific cities.&#xA0;To achieve this, CDIA bridges the gap between strategic city development planning and urban policies, services, and infrastructure project preparation.&#xA0;It uses a demand-driven approach to support&#xA0;infrastructure projects that emphasize poverty reduction, environmental improvement,&#xA0;climate change mitigation or adaptation, and good governance.
The operational objectives of CDIA, are to improve urban infrastructure and services management through:
- Assisting medium-size Asian cities to prepare sustainable and bankable quality infrastructure projects so to bridge the gap between their development plans and the implementation of priority projects;
- Linking infrastructure projects with funding sources; and
- Strengthening individual and organizational capacities of stakeholders for developing sustainable and bankable projects and for ensuring financing.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">The Cities Development Initiative for Asia (CDIA) contribution,Phase  2, 2013-2017, facilitates the identification and preparation of       projects for financing, facilitate international dialogue and         networking among city administrations and stakeholders, and also      provide training and advice to decision-makers from Asian cities and  urban areas.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Cities Development Initiative for Asia (CDIA) contribution,Phase  2, 2013-2017, facilitatse the identification and preparation of       projects for financing, facilitate international dialogue and         networking among city administrations and stakeholders, and also      provide training and advice to decision-makers from Asian cities and  urban areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="46004" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AsDB/Asian Development Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="46004" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AsDB/Asian Development Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asia, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="11.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.1 - By 2030, ensure access for all to adequate, safe and affordable housing and basic services and upgrade slums.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.1 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla tillg&#xE5;ng f&#xF6;r alla till fullgoda, s&#xE4;kra och ekonomiskt &#xF6;verkomliga bost&#xE4;der och grundl&#xE4;ggande tj&#xE4;nster samt rusta upp slumomr&#xE5;den.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11.C" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.c - St&#xF6;dja de minst utvecklade l&#xE4;nderna, inklusive genom finansiellt och tekniskt bist&#xE5;nd, att bygga h&#xE5;llbara och motst&#xE5;ndskraftiga byggnader av lokala material.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.c - Support least developed countries, including through financial and technical assistance, in building sustainable and resilient buildings utilizing local materials.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">584351.0781277391</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">584351.0781277391</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">-663669.6092163699</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-01">767671.804949</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-28">584351.0781277391</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-28">-663669.5549257848</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CDIA was established in 2007 by the ADB&#xA0;and the German government with the intent of improving the lives of 1.6 billion people in&#xA0;Asia and the Pacific.? It&#xA0;works closely with secondary cities in Asia and the Pacific to address gaps in&#xA0;infrastructure development and financing. It uses a demand-driven approach to support&#xA0;infrastructure projects that emphasize poverty reduction, environmental improvement,&#xA0;climate change mitigation or adaptation, and good governance.&#xA0;To facilitate these&#xA0;initiatives at the city level, CDIA provides a range of international and domestic expertise&#xA0;that can include, among others, support for project preparation studies for high priority&#xA0;infrastructure investment projects.?&#xA0;
CDIA operates under its five-year Strategy Business Plan (SBP). The current SBP is running from 2018 to 2022 and the two previous are SBP 2009-2012 and SBP 2013-2017. Sweden engaged with CDIA&#xA0;from the start (November 2007) with the total financial support of 104 MSEK,&#xA0;and channelled&#xA0;to ADB&#xA0;Regional Technical Assistants (RETA 6293 and RETA 8556). The Agreement between ADB and Sweden has ended in 31 December 2019 (with the activity period ended in 30 June 2019). This means that the Swedish contribution is part of the current SBP 2018-2022 until the end of December 2019. Currently,&#xA0;CDIA receives funding support from Austria, France, Germany, Switzerland and the European Union.&#xA0;In 2020, about 6.1 million&#xA0;USD&#xA0;was repaid to Sida.&#xA0;
CDIA produced results within several areas, including project approval, project preparation, projects linked to financing, support to capacity building, and knowledge products and outreach activities. According to the progress report July to December 2019, as of December 2019, CDIA has commissioned 103 Project Preparatory Studies (PPSs) in 111 cities across 20 ADB&apos;s developing member countries, of which 87 cities have been successfully linked to an estimated $11.2 billion investment. CDIA work in different&#xA0;regions, i.e. Southeast&#xA0;Asia, Central and West Asia, East Asia, South Asia and the Pacific. By region, Southeast Asia has the biggest share&#xA0;accounts for 43% of approved PPS applications and projects prepared for linking to finance accounts for 46%. By funding agency, almost two thirds of the projects and half of the PPSs supported by CDIA are linked to ADB financing, followed by the national/ local government, public-private-partnership, Agence Fran&#xE7;aise de D&#xE9;veloppement, World Bank,&#xA0;Kreditanstalt f&#xFC;r Wiederaufbau&#xA0;and others.&#xA0;
CDIA&#x2019;s outcome shall be the preparation and linking to finance of priority urban infrastructure investment projects that contribute to at least two of the following impact areas: i) urban environment improvement; ii) climate change mitigation and adaptation; iii) urban poverty reduction; iv) and improved urban governance.&#xA0;Since its inception in 2007, CDIA has been tracking the anticipated impacts of its PPS interventions using&#xA0;the Initial Development Impact Assessment (IDIA), as the main tool for tracking anticipated impacts of urban infrastructure projects. It is important to note that the development impact could be measured realistically only 1-3 years after the project is operated, which can be 5-10 years after a PPS is completed. Figure below shows the distribution of PPSs in terms of their alignment to each of the four development impact areas as of December 2019.&#xA0;

CDIA&#xA0;contributions to four development impact areas is in line with&#xA0;Sida&apos;s&#xA0;five perspectives, except conflict perspective. In terms of poor peoples&apos; perspectives, guided&#xA0;by the CDIA&apos;s Strategy and Action Plan for Pro-poor Infrastructure Development 2011-2018,&#xA0;CDIA support the development of urban infrastructure investment projects with a pro-poor focus, in which the rights of disadvantage groups (whether women, children, persons with disability or ethnic minorities) are addressed in infrastructure provision.&#xA0;For example, 10 PPSs completed in 2019 have responded&#xA0;to anticipated impacts on poverty reduction - 90% improved access to basic infrastructure, 70% equitable distribution of public services in the project area and 60% less effort and time needed for securing basic services.&#xA0;
The rights perspective, CDIA is promoting good governance includes participation&#xA0;in decision-making&#xA0;and planning, improved transparency and accountability, improved internal organizational structures and procedures.&#xA0;In 2019, 10 PPSs&#xA0;show positive&#xA0;impacts on good&#xA0;governance&#xA0;particularly in terms of better customer/ client orientation of city services and participation in decision making and planning.&#xA0;
CDIA&#xA0;adopted different&#xA0;methods&#xA0;to ensure stakeholder participation in CDIA&#x2019;s interventions, and most of the frequently methods in the PFS projects completed consisted of interviews, focus group discussion, workshops and general meetings with officials and the public. In addition, to improve openness and transparency, CDIA usually disseminates knowledge and experience relevant to its&#xA0;stakeholders in order to strengthen service delivery and linking to finance, and&#xA0;strives to use existing structures and systems with open access on the Internet.&#xA0;
In terms of&#xA0;environment and climate change, using the&#xA0;IDIA&#xA0;tool, all PPS applications must be screened from an environmental perspective. It could be seen as a quality assurance that all project is environmentally sustainable. For example, based on progress report January to June 2018, the Sewerage System Development Project in Indonesia, which covers three cities namely Bandah Aceh, Bekasi and Mataram, shall address environmental degradation and poor health of the urban population through safe collection and disposal of wastewater and septage.&#xA0;To address these environmental issues, a short-term investment program was developed for the three cities for wastewater management through sewerage network systems and waste water treatment plants and septage management systems.
In addition,&#xA0;CDIA&#x2019;s contribution to climate finance, which is assessed based on the amount of CDIA financial resources spent on PPSs that seek to address climate change adaptation and/or mitigation.&#xA0;As of December 2019,&#xA0;CDIA has spent about $34 million to support PPSs aimed at addressing&#xA0;climate change-related issues. Of this amount, 52% was utilized for PPSs dealing with climate change adaptation while 48% was used for PPSs addressing climate change mitigation.
CDIA shows commitment to strengthening gender perspective. This aspect has improved over the period of its implementation partly due to continuously dialogue with the CDIA and ADB,&#xA0;and Gender Development Specialist was added to serve as gender focal point.&#xA0;In addition, it is also shown in the Strategy Business Plans and through supporting process documents, i.e. the Gender Strategy and Action Plan. In terms of the results, for example, under the 10 PPSs completed in 2019 are estimated at 5.14 million city residents. Of this total, 42% are women, 25% are children, 16% are poor and 7% are elderly citizens. However, it remains a concern that women were treated solely as vulnerable beneficiaries and not as important agents of change by CDIA. This is something that CDIA could pay more&#xA0;attention in the future.
Using the IDIA tool, CDIA has been monitoring the anticipated SDG contribution of planned urban infrastructure investments in its client cities since 2016 when the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development officially came into force. Considering that CDIA&#x2019;s work is focused on cities, all&#xA0;&#xA0;CDIA supported PPSs are expected to contribute to the achievement of SDG 11 as well as to the attainment of one or more SDG 11 sub-goals. At the same time, the various infrastructure projects that are prepared for linking to downstream financing under the&#xA0;PPSs&#xA0;may be able to contribute to other SDGs, such as SDG 13 Climate Action and&#xA0;SDG 6 which focuses on &#x201C;ensuring availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all&#x201D;, among others.&#xA0;
Tracer Studies are one of CDIA&#x2019;s&#xA0;important instruments for determining the progress and results of implementation of PPS recommendations and validating the impact of CDIA interventions. An example,&#xA0;the tracer study on the progress of urban transport project in Palembang, Indonesia was conducted in 2018. Palembang City has been facing considerable challenges in the transport sector due to its rapidly growing urban population. The study found that after the CDIA completed the PPS on the prioritized transport investments in 2011, the Palembang city government gradually implemented the PPS recommendations with funding support from the national government. It has resulted that in Jalan Sudirman, the busiest street in the city&#x2019;s central business district, being transformed with the expansion, concreting and beautification of pedestrian sidewalks, enforcement of off-street parking and installation of street lighting.
In terms of regional aspects, CDIA has been assisting cities to link up to the regional arena to access financing for prioritized infrastructure investments. Also, CDIA supports the sharing of best practices through a range of activities, including regional trainings, seminars and conferences. CDIA developed capacity in cities by encouraging regional networking between cities, building a platform for regional collaboration.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51020147" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040503" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="2030000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional Asia and Oceania 2016-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt Asien och Oceanien 2016-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
