<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-18/DDA-3482/SA2/HNC/NGO/10725</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing first aid and postoperative care to injured participating in March of return</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to reduce the mortality rates and incidence of disability resulting from injuries during peaceful demonstration in Gaza known as march of return. March of return demonstrations in the besieged Gaza Strip persist weekly on Fridays and recently increased to three days weekly with plan to continue to end the siege of Gaza, to bring some hope and improve the lives of two million under difficult humanitarian situation. Therefore, PMRS applied to continue providing first aid interventions at the sites of clashes to the injured through deploying 40 skilled and trained first aid workers 30 males and 10 females in four site of clashes Malaka, Abu Safiys Al-najar and Annahda. Their role is to help and treat in place those with mild injuries mainly from tear gases, stabilize or minimize the deterioration of injured until they reach professional medical care and transporting injured with live bullets from site of injury to the nearest medical point or Ampulance. The first aid workers based in the previous six-month experience projected to help each month at least 452 injured including 391 young adult males and 23 females, 29 boys and 9 girls. 
Although through the project PMRS will provide long-term care to the injured through provision of medications, assistive devices, physiotherapy and dressing to injured at home. This is needed as injured required hospitalization intended to discharge even before complete treatment as most of injured treated on hospitals in need for long term wound management include dressing and treatment and may be second operation. At this point PMRS will mobilize three health teams that visit injured people at home, after getting released from hospitals, and provide them with follow up care including wound dressing, dressing kits, physiotherapy, medications and assistive devices. The home visit mobile team consist of one nurse, one physiotherapist and one social worker. Depending on the seriousness of injury the community health workers would teach the person themselves or somebody of the family how to clean and dress the wounds. The severe wounded were treated under supervision of doctors with periodic follow up in our PHC centers. The Physiotherapist is also doing session during the home visit as long staying in rest position of patients cause complication that might lead to disability. The physiotherapy services are needed for remediation of impairments and disabilities and the promotion of mobility, functional ability, quality of life and movement potential. If physiotherapy is not offered at the right moment during a patient&#x2019;s injury, the patient&#x2019; might be disabled for the rest of their lives. So far, PMRS started postoperative care at the beginning of March of return demonstration and these teams provided service to 728 injured at home were 450 of them completed their treatment, 18 were referred to ICRC for second operation and prostheses and 78 were referred to MSF for more advanced wound care and 134 still receiving treatment. In this project PMRS will expand services to reach other 520 injured including 390 adults&apos; male, 25 females 90 boys and 15 girls in three governorates including in Gaza, North and Khan Younis. Finally, the project foresees the needs to improve the skills of first aid workers in their personal safety and surveillance on health attacks documentation capacity building training.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Medical Relief Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Medical Relief Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-21" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-21" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bahia Amra</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">External Relation Department Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00972598886944</telephone>
   <email>bahiaamra@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-11-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-03">43465.31</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-21"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-03">294226.69</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-10725">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-03">337692</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Medical Relief Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303722284">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-14">202615.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Medical Relief Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304219758">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-20">135076.8</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Medical Relief Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
