<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-18/DDA-3482/SA2/EDU/INGO/10680</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing Equitable and safe access to maintain resilience of vulnerable students in Area C in south Nablus and Hebron</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Residents of Area C are among the most vulnerable in the West Bank in terms of humanitarian needs and access to basic services. Children are vulnerable to a range of International Humanitarian Law (IHL) and International Human Rights (IHR) violations while prospects of resilience building and development have been hindered by capacity and resource limitations of the Palestinian Authority. According to INEE (Interagency Network on Education in Emergencies), Guidance Residents of Area C are among the most vulnerable in the West Bank in terms of humanitarian needs and access to basic services. Children are vulnerable to a range of International Humanitarian Law (IHL) and International Human Rights (IHR) violations while prospects of resilience building and development have been hindered by capacity and resource limitations of the Palestinian Authority. According to INEE (Interagency Network on Education in Emergencies), Guidance Notes on Psychosocial support service, &#x201C;Psychosocial wellbeing is a significant precursor to learning and is essential for academic achievement&#x2019;. PSS (Psychosocial Support Service) helps facilitate resilience amongst individuals providing them with the means to bounce back from hardships. Moreover, SEL (Social Emotional Learning) supports the development of social and emotional competencies that strengthen academic performance and improve children&#x2019;s ability to face hardships. The competencies expected from utilizing PSS and SEL can provide a foundation for better adjustment and academic performance, which can also lead to more positive social behaviors. Hence, this project aims at improving the psychosocial well-being of children through integrating SEL and PSS approaches into the different domains of the affected children&#x2019; lives. The project will target 34 schools in 28 different communities from Nablus and South Hebron, Area C locations. The schools were identified upon their location in high tense areas with high number of education-related violation incidents and as per the recommendations and reports of the Ministry of Education, internal reports of World Vision school assessments. To achieve the above mentioned aim, World Vision will intentionally invest in education based PSS and SEL to help decrease the negative impact of the children&#x2019;s daily stress .the targeted children face. This will happen through the establishment of stable routines and providing opportunities for play and self-expression. Since Schools, as education settings can be considered as supportive environments as they bring children, peers, parents, and communities together. Therefore, education staff and parents will be trained and made aware of on PSS and SEL techniques to deal with their own stress as well as help support the children. The activities carried out in the project will be : 1. Use WV&#x2019;s ( Psychological First Aid) guide developed with WHO in 2011 to provide education staff ( teachers and counselors ) with stress relief techniques to deal with their own stress as well as techniques to help their students. 2. Provide education staff with the means and resources to link children to psychosocial services. 3. Provide vulnerable students with PSS school based activities (cooperative play, emotion regulation exercises, role-play, reflective discussions, etc.) which will be embedded into student-student and student-teacher relationships. 5. Coaching visits will conducted by WV&apos;s staff to targeted schools to help promote growth and learning of staff. 5. Awareness session for parents on PSS and resources for identifying signs of stress and referral mechanism should their children need further support techniques and coping mechanisms in addition to awareness on child protection. All involved adult beneficiaries (education staff and parents) will be provided with the means and resources for identifying signs of stress and referral mechanism for cases that need further support. The project targets CWDs in all activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-12" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-12" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Haya Helal</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0547749535</telephone>
   <email>haya_helal@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rania Maayah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education Lead</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0547749526</telephone>
   <email>rania_maayeh@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="1000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Bank</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.98598100 35.29994700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-11-13"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-12">49100.65</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-10-12"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-12">291535.11</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-10680">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-12">340635.76</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303672237">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-20">204381.46</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304511706">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-27">75530.69</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
