<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-18/DDA-3482/RA1/PROT/NGO/9200</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing protection mechanisms through providing mental health and psychosocial interventions to victims of current crisis at border areas in Gaza Strip</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project of &quot; Emergency Response Plan for the Current Israeli Attacks on Peaceful Demonstrators at Border Areas - Crisis Intervention 2018&quot; aims to enhance protection mechanisms through community mental health services and awareness raising through providing three main interventions. The first intervention is to mobilize 10 experienced and well trained mental health professionals to provide urgent Psychological First Aid (PFA) to families including adults and children subjected to trauma and affected by the last Israeli attacks and raise awareness towards dealing with traumatic events and educate parents to deal with their children&#x2019;s problems. The mental health professionals will form five mobile teams (one team for each governorate) and will conduct home and hospital visits to provide PFA to affected people. Also, they will detect and refer cases in need for further therapeutic interventions to the six GCMHP mobile stations, GCMHP&apos;s three community centers and other service providers. In addition, they will distribute awareness raising publications and brochures through home visits. The mobile teams will improve also the level of referral from the affected communities and will support high correct detection ratios among the referrals that will contribute to cost and effort effectiveness. A priority will be given to families of deaths, injuries, and lost persons. 
The second intervention is to provide access to specialized therapeutic mental health services through establishing six decentralized mobile stations at Community-Based Organizations (CBOs) in Rafah, KhanYounis, Middle Area, Gaza and North of the Gaza Strip. Through these mobile stations, many people will be able to receive specialized mental health services free of charge including medicines and counseling. GCMHP will mobilize also six psychologists to provide mental health and psychological support services at these mobile stations, and they will work closely with the mobile PFA teams and GCMHP community centers to detect, support and refer cases. The mobile stations will be close to family centers operated by UNICEF, and governmental and none governmental hospitals. The psychologists will provide therapeutic interventions at home and hospitals when needed in coordination with mobile teams and cluster members. Also, the project will offer the free telephone counseling service to provide psycho-education and individual and family counseling to those who couldn&apos;t reach community centers and mobile stations due to social and economical barriers.  
The third intervention will focus on raising community awareness on psychological and social impact of trauma on the Gaza Strip population, risk of engaging in protests and sensitization on available services. This will be realized through using awareness brochure, media tools and social media platforms. Also, GCMHP will promote the free telephone counseling line (1800222333) through these tools.
Strengthen coordination mechanisms: GCMHP will update and share the results of its project interventions with health, protection, CPWG and PHSS clusters and working groups including gender disaggregated information in addition to report on indicators to SRPs periodic reporting. Also, GCMHP has already a referral mechanism in which all referrals and needed information are followed up and traced. It is worth mentioning that GCMHP is already a part of the SOPs&apos; manual managed by UNICEF and includes all referral pathways.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Community Mental Health programme (GCMHP)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Community Mental Health programme (GCMHP)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Yasser AbuJamei</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director General</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+972 599770377</telephone>
   <email>yasser@gcmhp.net</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-05-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-15">199163.5</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-9200">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-15">199163.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Community Mental Health programme (GCMHP)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303337891">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-21">119498.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Community Mental Health programme (GCMHP)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303681123">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-26">79665.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Community Mental Health programme (GCMHP)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
