<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-18/DDA-3482/SA2/WASH/NGO/10714</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reducing Public Health and Environmental Pollution Risks through Solar Pumping of Selected Wastewater Pumping Stations in Gaza</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at reducing the public health and environmental pollution risks that may occur as a result of wastewater flooding from wastewater pumping stations (PS) due to electricity failure or fuel run out, for nearly 34000 people of which 47% are women in five locations in Northern, middle and southern part of Gaza namely in Abu Moalla PS (An Nuseirat) and Al Zahra PS (Madinat Ezahra) in Deir Al-Balah governorate, Wadi Gaza PS (Juhor ad Dik) in Gaza governorate, Um Al-Nnaser (Al Qaraya al Badawiya) PS in the North Gaza governorate and UNDP housing PS in Rafah governorate, southern part of Gaza. Total number of beneficiaries in each location can be listed as follows: Abu Moalla 10000, Al Zahra 7000, Wadi Gaza 9000, Umm Al Naser 5000 and UNDP housing project 3000.  Moreover, the project will indirectly benefiting all people in the target five locations through excess electric supply and also pollution prevention. 
According to the information obtained from CMWU and PWA during the coordination meetings organized with them on 25 and 26 September respectively to define the priorities, they identified the five priority locations listed above which are in need of more secured power source to avoid flooding of wastewater. The need of each pumping station is nearly vary from 14 - 25 KWh to operate 2-3 pumps at each station. However, it was recommended by both PWA and CMWU to install 30 KWh systems at each pumping stations to take into consideration any future expansion and also to ensure sufficient electricity supply under various climatic and efficiency conditions. Accordingly, the project will contribute by supplying and installing 750 solar panel, 750 galvanized mounting structure, 15 inverters 3 phase of 10 KW each, 5 electric panels, 1000 m of wiring and earthing cables, and accessories. Moreover, the project will contribute by doing the needed rehabilitation and wiring in the existing grid system connected to these pumping stations to maximize efficient electricity supply from the solar system. It will also provide capacity building for local municipal, CMWU and PWA staff (both mail and female) on the operation and maintenance of installed solar system. It is good to mention that each one of the stations has also sufficient land area to install solar panels. It is proposed to install on grid solar system to be able to supply the excess electricity to the grid and contributing to improve electricity supply in the target locations as well. The project will also contribute to reduce operation cost of the pumping stations and reduce CO2 emission by nearly 300 kg / year and thus reduce climate change and preventing environmental pollution to ensure no harm principle.
The project design has considered gender mainstreaming and also mainstreaming of protection principles including meaningful access, safety and dignity. PHG will adhere to the protection principles throughout the implementation of the project and will develop protection monitoring, vulnerability mapping and impact assessment to ensure project compliance with these principles.
PHG will also implement the project and will be responsible for the its overall management and reporting toward the donor. PHG will ensure the quality implementation and management of project in accordance with its ISO9001 - 2008 standards and will also ensure the timely implementation of the project in an efficient manner within the budget limit and will allocate relevant qualified human resources to implement it properly.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Hydrological Group</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Hydrological Group</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-08" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-07" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-07" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ayman Rabi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>022966315 or 0595222</telephone>
   <email>ayman@phg.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Riyad Janinah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Branch Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0599745442</telephone>
   <email>riyadjune@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-11-08"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-08">72010.47</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-07"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-08">339672.03</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-10714">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-08">411682.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Hydrological Group</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303669655">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-19">247009.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Hydrological Group</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
