<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-18/DDA-3482/RA1/HNC/INGO/9196</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support the MoH emergency response and emergency preparedness at PHC and Hospital levels.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza&#x2019;s current crisis is characterized by the concentration of events in a specific scope of time and space: Fridays afternoon, in five camps close to the fence between Gaza and Israel. This has allowed the MoH and other health providers to plan accordingly. One of the measures set in place by the MoH, as well as other local organization, is the deployment of Advanced Medical Points (medical Emergency Medical Team type 1 according to Who classification as fixed outpatient structures for initial emergency care and other significant health needs response) close to the demonstration areas to stabilize and treat injured cases. This model of intervention has often been used in crises situations in countries like France. In Palestine, it is the first time the MoH is activating this kind of response. Since the beginning of the demonstrations, 1,557 cases have been treated in the MoH Advanced Medical points. This first attempt on using this model will require an evaluation and capitalization process, which will aim at consolidating and improve the response for further crises. The healthcare staff working at these points are issued from the 11 primary health centers where MdM has been working for the last 4 years. MdM&#x2019;s assessment to this moment is that the teams are still in need for further training and supervision on effective triage, patient flow and case management, including the registration and data collection, and that drugs, disposables and medical equipment is required for its correct functioning 

Moreover, the chronic shortage of drugs and disposables has been exacerbated by the current needs, especially for certain items such as pain management drugs.

In addition to this, several sources have expressed their concern on the direct and indirect attacks to healthcare structures, personnel and ambulances. Some incidents have made it to the headlines in the international media. However, most of the incidents have been underreported, impeding the different concerned actors, such as Human Rights defenders and advocates to take specific actions with the intention of reducing the risk of further incidents

Taking all of the context into account MdM plans on targeting the HRP Strategic Objective 2: The basic needs of vulnerable Palestinians living under occupation are met through the provision of quality basic services and proved access to resources in accordance with the right of protected persons under IHL. 

Concretely MDM intervention aligns with the health cluster objectives as follows:
Objective 1:  To ensure the availability, accessibility, acceptability and quality of essential lifesaving health services to vulnerable communities in Gaza by enhancing the trauma pathway This will be done in 3 moments in the continuum of care: 
a)	stabilization, treatment in medical points: by providing technical support to the staff as well as drugs, disposables and medical equipment
b)	Surgery: ensuring that hospitals are able to conduct complex lifesaving surgery by deploying specialized emergency medical teams (EMTs) to the hospitals in Gaza, along with the necessary equipment and medical supplies needed. 
c)	Post-operative care at PHC level by providing technical support, drugs, disposables and medical equipment.
This will be done by two chapters of the MdM International Network organizations (MdM France and MdM Spain). MdM France will focus on the primary health care level and MdM Spain will focus on secondary healthcare. Both partners will work in the referral and counter-referral mechanisms in order to grant the casualties a comprehensive treatment plan. These efforts are all aimed at preventing unnecessary disability amongst injured.

Objective 2: Strengthen health coordination, information and health protection, with an emphasis on
advocacy for the right to health, to improve the effectiveness of lifesaving health response for
vulnerable people.  MdM France will work on a report &#x201C;violence against Health care in Gaza</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medicos Del Mundo - Spain</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">M&#xE9;decins du Monde France</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">M&#xE9;decins du Monde France</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Itziar de Miguel</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Coordinator -  Palestine</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+972 (0)59.891.4260</telephone>
   <email>genco.palestine@medecinsdumonde.net</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-05-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-16">352307.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-16">47692.31</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-9196">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-16">400000.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">M&#xE9;decins du Monde France</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303343020">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-22">320000.02</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">M&#xE9;decins du Monde France</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303839779">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-19">80000.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">M&#xE9;decins du Monde France</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
