<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-18/DDA-3482/RA2/HNC/UN/9468</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance the pre-hospital trauma care by upgrading the Trauma Stabilisation Points (TSPs) across the five governorates in the Gaza Strip</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since the start of the demonstrations, the Ministry of Health (MoH) together with the Palestinian Red Crescent Society (PRCS), established ten Trauma Stabilisation Points (TSPs) positioned in the five Gaza Governorates, these are located close to the border areas where the protests have been held. With technical input and support from WHO, the TSPs evolved during a period of 10 weeks from a treatment point for lightly injured patients, to a mandatory triage, treatment and stabilization point for all casualties. The role of the TSPs in the recent crisis has been essential in providing care close to where is it needed. 

Initial observations by WHO suggest that the TSPs have had three major positive effects, firstly the TSPs played a key role in saving lives by providing the essential care necessary during the &#x2018;golden hour&#x2019;, second, the TSP model allowed better resourcing of ambulances, and finally, the TSPs reduced the burden on hospitals. In fact, since the demonstrations, the TSPs have treated and referred or discharged almost all of the injured patients from the mass demonstrations, which currently amounts to approximately 14,000 injured people. From this total, over 6,000 have been treated and immediately discharged in the field trauma stabilization points (TSPs) and at upgraded primary healthcare clinics. 

The demonstrations are likely to continue at least until end of July and the need to upscale the TSPs to ensure that they continue playing a vital role in the emergency response is a key priority. Furthermore, the added benefit of the TSP model is that it can be used for preparedness measures and can continue to play a key role in future onset emergencies in Gaza. In summary, this project looks towards contributing to the immediate humanitarian emergency by upscaling the TSPs whilst also supporting the resilience of the health system.

What is WHOs role? 

WHO&#x2019;s role is to establish this process through a coordinated mechanism, and ensure that the TSPs are in line with the global standards. This means, that WHO is coordinating and supporting various elements of TSPs by working in a tripartite set- up with the MoH and PRCS. WHOs role within the TSPs has included/will include the following: Firstly, WHO support on the structural gaps of the TSPs this includes the perational and infrastructure of the TSP lacks resources, including medical supplies. WHO has been pivotal in identifying what the minimum standards should be and provide some of the infrastructure needs. The minimum standards will be applied across all TSPs. Second, WHO supports on Human Resources by ensuring that the number, and skill of staff (doctors, nurses and paramedics) are appropriate to the number of casualties and type of trauma injuries we are seeing. In the past few months, this has involved advising MoH on the relocation of staff from the hospitals to the TSPs. Finally, 
 WHO supports the services delivered at the TSPs by supported the EMT&#x2019;s to evolve over the 11-week period by making sure that all TSPs in line with WHO type 1 EMTs. This means that the TSPs must include: triage of casualties, resuscitation and stabilisation, stabilisation of fractures, pain management and registration and documents. In addition to clear definition on the severity of the injuries and where to refer. WHO will now start to move onto looking at how the TSPs can be incorporated into preparedness plans in case of future conflict/war.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-06" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-06" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gerald Rockenschaub</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of the WHO oPt office</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0547179025</telephone>
   <email>rockenschaubg@who.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-08-06"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-03">277565.42</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-03">630658.86</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-20">0.79</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-9468">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-03">908224.28</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303474054">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-08">908224.28</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
