<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-18/DDA-3482/SA2/PROT/INGO/10777</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MHPSS and reintegration interventions to mitigate the negative impacts of detention to survivors of political violence, especially Palestinian ex-detainee children and youth and their families in East Jerusalem.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will target ex-detainee children and young adults (until 25 years old) &#x2013; a particularly vulnerable and neglected group &#x2013; their families, as well as children at risk of detention and the wider community. The project will take place in three locations of East Jerusalem: Shu&#x2019;fat Refugee Camp, Jabal Al Mukaber and Issawiyeh. The objective is to provide mental health and psychosocial support and protection to ex-detainee boys and girls and their families including mothers and fathers, in order to improve their wellbeing and strengthen their self-help and coping mechanism facilitate ex detainee children reintegration to school and raise awareness on detention and its consequences. The direct beneficiaries for this project will be 1,664 girls, boys, women and men, including 1,330 students in primary and secondary schools (school awareness sessions) and school personnel (including counselors and teachers), in addition to 45 CBOs&apos; staff members and volunteers. The indirect beneficiaries estimated: Total population of the targeted communities (around 43,764 people). The approach is a holistic one, taking into accounts the many facets of community and family cohesion and of a child&#x2019;s reinsertion. Consequently, the project&#x2019;s strategy, which interconnects medical, social and legal support with education and livelihoods, involves work with a wide range of actors: educators, school teachers, children, parents and siblings, medical professionals, legal experts and community leaders. MdM proposes to set up quality services following IASC standards for MHPSS: psychosocial counselors will focus on conducting individual, group and family counseling sessions, and organize various therapeutic and educational activities. The project entails building a relationship based on trust with the target population including women, men, boys and girls, through the team&#x2019;s consistent presence in the targeted areas and the provision of quality services. The coordination with other organizations also took place for this project, especially with the one which may work in some of the locations we are targeting. Both TdH-CH and MdM-CH recognize our common presence the 3 locations as an opportunity for complementary programmes. In order to prevent overlapping (especially MHPSS) and avoid the risk of missing people in need, both organizations have discussed the necessity of putting in place appropriate coordination mechanisms at all levels. As a medical org. with technical expertise in the field of PHC, SRH and MH, MdM-CH will mainly focus on the therapeutical component of its services and activities, while TdH will focus on legal and social support. Thus, collaboration between the two teams on the ground will guarantee beneficiaries receive a comprehensive support package. Coordination between our 2 organizations will be ensured through regular bilateral meetings and participation in the working groups. Regarding TdH-It and the remedial and educational activities that both organizations propose to provide in Issawiyeh, coordination between our organizations is indeed paramount and has already been discussed. A scheme whereby MdM-CH will provide educational and remedial activities to children under home arrest, vocational training to interested released children, while TdH-It will focus exclusively on educational support, according to each organization&#x2019;s capacity, is under review. MdM-CH will implement all remedial activities for the target population under the umbrella of the Palestinian Directorate of Education and in close collaboration with UNRWA. Apart from the remedial activities, awareness-raising sessions will be organized, in order to sensitize children on their rights, when it comes to detention and train school counselors on intervention techniques when working with ex-detainees. Providing for an inclusive and understanding school environment will facilitate the reintegration process of ex-detainee children and youth, back into school life.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">East Jerusalem YMCA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">M&#xE9;decins Du Monde</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">M&#xE9;decins Du Monde</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-11" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-11" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kanistra Korina Kyriaki</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0543445177</telephone>
   <email>genco.palestine@medecinsdumonde.ch</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TONY BERO</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PROJECT COORDINATOR</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0594211891</telephone>
   <email>projectco.palestine@medecinsdumonde.ch</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="1000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Bank</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.98598100 35.29994700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-11-12"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-12">38355.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-11-11"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-12">246568.39</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-10777">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-12">284923.47</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">M&#xE9;decins Du Monde</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303672238">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-20">284923.47</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">M&#xE9;decins Du Monde</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
