<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-18/DDA-3482/SA1/PROT/INGO/9156</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening the protection mechanism and the community based response for GBV survivors in Gaza</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at supporting Gender Based Violence (GBV) survivors living in the north area of Gaza Strip more precisely in Beit Hanoun, and the east of Gaza city. The heavy deterioration of the socio-economic situation, and the increased tensions and violence and the aggravated economic crisis are making the situation unbearable for the population in the Strip, with result of an increase in GBV figures, with more cases receiving no assistance due to lack of funding for services from some donors.  
The proposal will provide access to a coordinated, safe and confidential, GBV multi sectoral response in the &#x201C;one stop centre&#x201D; of Beit Hanoun, and also through mobile clinics in the East of Gaza city. The provision of case management and GBV multi sectoral response includes: Sexual and Reproductive Health (SRH) services as a needed entry-point for GBV survivors, psychosocial (PSS) services and specialized legal assistance, both in the One Stop Center, mobile teams and through home visits. Furthermore, the response is complemented with prevention and community awareness activities and also group sessions. 
At the same time, ApS and its partners: UHWC and PFPPA, will work on the registration and documentation of GBV cases for consistent and evidence based advocacy purposes boosting accountability and undertaking of responsibilities of the duty bearers, both the occupying power and the Palestinian authorities. 
Aps will contribute to enhance the community capacities for the response to GBV through the training on GBV detection, first support and referral for Non-Specialist Actors. This train aims at contrinuting with the integration of GBV in a more holistic concept of Protection and to ensure those cases detected by CBOs and other non specialist actors reach the GBV specialized pathways. 
The project is putting strong efforts in providing access to multi sectoral services to GBV survivors, especially those with other vulnerability indicators, such as: female head of households, widows, and women with disabilities. Through the multisectoral services, these women will strengthen their ability to cope in a more positive way, not only with GBV, but also with protracted threats and shocks related to the heavily and permanent exposure to policies and practices related to the blockade and the occupation.
In order to improve the quality of the services provided, Focus Group Discussions (FGD) with survivors benefitting from them, community awareness and engagement activities will be conducted in order to identify gaps, opportunities for improvement and to better tailor the services to the beneficiaries&#x2019; needs. Furthermore, coordination with GBV humanitarian actors in the Gaza and also with the institutions and organizations working on the GBV response will ensure an efficient referral for GBV survivors.
Thus, the Project seeks to overcome violence, discrimination and advance gender equality, targeting women, men, girls and boys whose vulnerabilities are based on their gender roles through an effective GBV humanitarian response by rebuilding-up GBV comprehensive services in the &quot;one-stop center&quot; located in Beit Hanoun and the mobile teams</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIANZA POR LA SOLIDARIDAD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIANZA POR LA SOLIDARIDAD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-10" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-10" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eva Anad&#xF3;n Moreno</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission Palestine</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0586679735</telephone>
   <email>eanadon@aporsolidaridad.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-06-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-14">111779.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-14">88218.27</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-9156">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-14">199997.95</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIANZA POR LA SOLIDARIDAD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303401168">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-20">159998.36</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIANZA POR LA SOLIDARIDAD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304198748">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-10">39999.59</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIANZA POR LA SOLIDARIDAD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
