<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-18/DDA-3482/SA1/WASH/NGO/8999</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving the access to domestic water for Za&apos;tara vulnerable community in area C in Bethlehem Governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In collaboration with Za&apos;tara municipality, women club and animal husbandry cooperative, the project will address the community water needs, through extending and rehabilitate Za&#x2019;tara water network, to enhance water supply for human and animal use in the community.
Moreover, the project will provide permanent water filling point close to Alrashaydeh and Aljahaleen Bedouin areas, to supply them quality water in less time and cost. This enhancement will decrease the water loss, cost, time, effort, and water related diseases among people and animals, through guaranteeing better-quality water and consistent supply. 

Za&apos;tara village municipality have identified water shortage and losses as their main problem due to old and limited water networks as well as supply shortage from the Israeli occupation, they have set this problem as their priority and thus has requested AAA support in solving this problem, this also comes on the list of PWAs&apos; priority recommended Projects for Bethlehem and Hebron for 2017/2018. AAA conducted a comprehensive needs assessment in September 2017 and reviewed it in April 2018, covered water supply and needs in 5 places in za&apos;tara.

The assessment shows a great shortage in the water network outreach, as well as old parts of the network. The main needs the project will address, are listed below:

1: Rehabilitation 3360 meter of existing water network, and install 4275 meters of new water network to serve and supply clean drinking water to the community. The pipelines will serve over 740 households from Za&apos;tara for domestic, animal, and renovate their lands to increase their food security and access to diversified products. As well as provide clean and safe drinking water to Za&apos;tara, Alrashaydeh and Aljahaleen families who depend largely on water tankaring with relatively high costs and great potential losses during transportation. The new pipelines will be installed to serve a substantial part of the community. AAA, therefore, will take into consideration legal aspects and tactics during implementation to avoid any obstacles from the occupation forces. 

Planned activities are:
1-Al Jaroush Area: extend water network pipeline by 1925 meters/ 2 inches, out of them 900 meters to rehabilitate and replace parts form the old network, which established since 1972, and the other 1025 meters are to extend water network to new areas to connect new households with the water supply service. This will serve more than 50 families, those who suffer from continuous water shortages and cuts reach up to 25 days per water cycle, this will also serve 150-200 dunum. 
2-The Eastern Area: extend water network pipeline, by 2500 meters /2 inches length. This will serve around 450 people, those who live without water network or service. Expected to install 100 water meters once the extension is finished, with a potential to reach up to 300 water meters due to rapid growth and constructions in that direction. This will encourage the population to attend their land, which considered as a barrier to prevent Israeli settlements Nicodem and David expansion. In addition, at the end of the network, the project will install a permanent water filling point to serve Alrashaydeh and Aljahaleen areas by quality water.
3- Evangelical and Ras Alwad areas, replace 700 meter/2 inches old plastic pipeline to a new metal water network pipeline and install 750 meters of new water network pipeline, that will serve around 1040 students and more than 140 families suffering from continuous water supply cut due to the plastic networks, additionally this serve an extra 150 dunums.
4- Al Mareaj line: This line is more than 40 years old, 0.5 inches. It has several damages which cause huge water losses and poor ability water flows and pressure, the project will renew 1760meters/ 3 inches to increase the pipeline discharge capacity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arab Agronomists Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arab Agronomists Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-27" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-27" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-27" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Omaymah shaltaf</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public Relation</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0597666025</telephone>
   <email>info@aaa-arc.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="1000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Bank</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.98598100 35.29994700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-05-27"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-29">237606.66</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-29">63216.45</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-8999">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-29">300823.11</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arab Agronomists Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303375514">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-06">180493.87</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arab Agronomists Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304003476">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-22">115507.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arab Agronomists Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
