<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ECOS &#x2013; BLUE ECONOMY AND COASTAL ECOSYSTEM &#x2013; OPPORTUNITIES FOR A SUSTAINABLE DEVELOPMENT</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to increase the resilience of coastal communities and strengthen institutional governance in 
the protection and management of natural resources, reducing the vulnerability of the fragile subjects; the goal 
is of particular importance in this historical moment of climate change and Covid-19 pandemic, that in a single 
year has abruptly reversed Kenya&apos;s positive development indicators, which were constantly growing while 
poverty was decreasing, until 2019. In the second quarter of 2020, GDP was -5.7% year-on-year (+5.4% in 2019) 
and poverty increased by 4% (2020) (Worldbank,2020).
The project responds to 3 identified needs: providing the local population with tools for the development of 
sustainable economic activities; raising awareness and training the local population on issues related to the 
exploitation of natural resources, climate change and sustainable economic development; improving 
institutional governance, increasing the technical skills of local institutions.
The project will develop over 36 months in Kilifi County and aims to contribute to the improvement of the 
economic conditions of the coastal population and to reduce the vulnerability of those with reduced ability to 
adapt to geo-political, socio-economic and climate changes, also in the context of the current Covid-19 
pandemic and with a view to possible future pandemics. The project is mainly aimed at fishermen/farmers and 
their families, linked to the resources available in the marine and coastal ecosystem for their livelihood, and to 
the ruling class and technicians of decentralised government structures. 
The Blue Economy (BE), a priority for Kenya since2016, is key to the project, which integrates in a synergic way 
in the context of current broader projects: the European project &quot;Go Blue&quot; and &quot;Marine Fisheries and Socio?Economic Development Project&quot; (World Bank).
We refer to BE in its broadest sense, which combines Gunter Pauli&apos;s original definition (2011) with that adopted 
by UN and the Kenyan government: it thus combines the sustainable use of ocean resources for economic 
growth, livelihoods and the employment and health of the ocean ecosystem, with the winning idea of creating 
value at no cost, using resources otherwise unused or that would be destroyed (Pillon, 2013).
Fishing makes a fundamental contribution to the economic livelihood and food security of Kilifi&apos;s families, even 
more following the sharp decline in the tourism sector in 2020; free access to fishing, the use of destructive 
gear, a growing population, unemployment and the scarcity of alternative livelihoods are degrading marine 
habitats and affecting the country&apos;s fish stocks, which will also be affected by rising sea temperatures. The 
project aims to influence the proper exploitation of coastal resources, allowing the biodiversity of the marine 
environment to be preserved and contributing to the emergence of alternative production activities based on 
the BE concept. Firstly, the income of fishing families will be deferred and food security will be increased. Protagonists, women 
and their central role in the family economy. Through training and technical assistance, income-generating 
activities will create alternatives to fishing; the aim will be the innovative exploitation of resources considered 
a waste (BE), in particular stranded Posidonia; aquaculture will be developed and ichthitourism will be 
introduced, in particular aimed at domestic tourism, considered strategic by government policies (Kenya 
Ministry of Tourism, 2020).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">l progetto si propone di aumentare la resilienza delle comunit&#xE0; costiere e rafforzare la governance istituzionale 
in materia di protezione e gestione delle risorse naturali, riducendo la vulnerabilit&#xE0; dei soggetti in condizioni di 
fragilit&#xE0;; l&#x2019;obiettivo &#xE8; di particolare importanza in questo momento storico di cambiamenti climatici e pandemia 
Covid-19, che in un solo anno ha invertito bruscamente gli indicatori positivi di sviluppo del Kenya, in costante 
crescita economica e diminuzione della povert&#xE0; sino al 2019. Nel secondo trimestre 2020 il PIL ha fatto segnare 
-5,7% su base annuale (+5.4% nel 2019) e la povert&#xE0; &#xE8; aumentata del 4% (2020) (Worldbank, 2020). 
Il progetto risponde a 3 bisogni identificati: fornire alla popolazione locale gli strumenti per lo sviluppo di attivit&#xE0; 
economiche sostenibili; sensibilizzare e formare i pi&#xF9; giovani e la popolazione locale sulle tematiche legate allo 
sfruttamento delle risorse naturali, al cambiamento climatico e allo sviluppo economico sostenibile; migliorare 
la governance istituzionale, aumentando le competenze tecniche delle istituzioni locali.
Il progetto si svilupper&#xE0; nell&#x2019;arco di 36 mesi nella Contea di Kilifi e mira a contribuire al miglioramento delle 
condizioni economiche della popolazione costiera e a ridurre la vulnerabilit&#xE0; dei soggetti con ridotta capacit&#xE0; 
di adattamento ai cambiamenti geo-politici, socio-economici e climatici, nel contesto dell&#x2019;attuale pandemia 
Covid-19 e nell&#x2019;ottica di possibili pandemie future. Il progetto si rivolge principalmente ai pescatori/agricoltori 
e alle loro famiglie, legati direttamente alle risorse disponibili nell&#x2019;ecosistema marino e costiero per la loro 
sussistenza, e alla classe dirigente e ai tecnici delle strutture governative decentrate. 
La Blue Economy (BE), priorit&#xE0; per il Kenya dal 2016, &#xE8; centrale al progetto, che si inserisce in modo sinergico 
nell&#x2019;ambito di attuali progetti pi&#xF9; ampi: il progetto Europeo &#x201C;Go Blue&#x201D; e &#x201C;Marine Fisheries and Socio-Economic 
Development Project&#x201D; (World Bank).
Ci si riferisce alla BE nella sua accezione pi&#xF9; ampia, che unisce la definizione originaria di Gunter Pauli (2011) a 
quella adottata da UN e dal governo kenyota: si unisce quindi l&apos;uso sostenibile delle risorse oceaniche per la 
crescita economica, i mezzi di sussistenza e l&apos;occupazione e la salute dell&apos;ecosistema oceanico, con l&#x2019;idea 
vincente di creare valore a costo zero, utilizzando risorse altrimenti inutilizzate o che andrebbero distrutte 
(Pillon, 2013).
La pesca contribuisce in modo fondamentale al sostentamento economico ed alla sicurezza alimentare delle 
famiglie di Kilifi, ancor pi&#xF9; a seguito al brusco declino del settore turistico nel 2020; il libero accesso alla pesca, 
l&apos;uso di attrezzi distruttivi, la popolazione in crescita, la disoccupazione e la scarsit&#xE0; di mezzi di sussistenza 
alternativi stanno degradando gli habitat marini e colpendo gli stock ittici del paese, che risentiranno altres&#xEC; 
dell&apos;aumento della temperatura del mare. Il progetto intende incidere su un adeguato sfruttamento delle 
risorse costiere, permettendo di preservare la biodiversit&#xE0; dell&#x2019;ambiente marino e contribuendo alla nascita di 
attivit&#xE0; produttive alternative basate sul concetto di BE.
In primo luogo, si differenzier&#xE0; il reddito delle famiglie di pescatori e si aumenter&#xE0; la sicurezza alimentare. Protagoniste, le donne e il loro ruolo centrale nell&#x2019;economia famigliare. Attraverso la formazione e l&#x2019;assistenza 
tecnica si creeranno attivit&#xE0; generatrici di reddito alternative alla pesca, si punter&#xE0; sullo sfruttamento 
innovativo di risorse considerate di scarto (BE), in particolare la Posidonia spiaggiata; si svilupper&#xE0; 
l&#x2019;acquacultura e l&#x2019;ittiturismo, in particolare rivolto al turismo domestico, considerato strategico dalle politiche 
di governo (Kenya Ministry of Tourism, 2020).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CENTRO PER UN APPROPRIATO SVILUPPO TECNOLOGICO &#x2013; CAST ONG</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/01/5" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="31320" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fishery development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31310" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fishing policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11220" percentage="20" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Primary education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="8.9" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, devise and implement policies to promote sustainable tourism that creates jobs and promotes local culture and products</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, double the agricultural productivity and incomes of small-scale food producers, in particular women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers, including through secure and equal access to land, other productive resources and inputs, knowledge, financial services, markets and opportunities for value addition and non-farm employment</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure sustainable food production systems and implement resilient agricultural practices that increase productivity and production, that help maintain ecosystems, that strengthen capacity for adaptation to climate change, extreme weather, drought, flooding and other disasters and that progressively improve land and soil quality</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote development-oriented policies that support productive activities, decent job creation, entrepreneurship, creativity and innovation, and encourage the formalization and growth of micro-, small- and medium-sized enterprises, including through access to financial services</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote sustained, inclusive and sustainable economic growth, full and productive employment and decent work for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-14">1559469.01</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CENTRO PER UN APPROPRIATO SVILUPPO TECNOLOGICO &#x2013; CAST ONG</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-30">935697.61</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CENTRO PER UN APPROPRIATO SVILUPPO TECNOLOGICO &#x2013; CAST ONG</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
