<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-011886-01-1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Coltivare il futuro. Modelli di filiere agricole ecosostenibili per le zone aride del Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Attraverso un approccio olistico derivante dai principi della permacultura, il progetto mira a incrementare la produzione agricola e la redditivit&#xE0; delle iniziative imprenditoriali di 11 gruppi target (770 beneficiari diretti), migliorando quindi le condizioni economiche dei gruppi agropastorali di Laikipia North, e favorendo in tal modo la resilienza delle comunit&#xE0; nelle zone aride e semiaride della contea di Laikipia. Le azioni principali riguardano la formazione e dotazione di equipaggiamenti per l&apos;agricoltura, l&apos;accesso idrico per quattro villaggi, il supporto a filiere di trasformazione adatte ai climi aridi (miele, aloe, opuntia), il potenziamento del settore turistico. Tutte le azioni privilegiano metodologie ecocompatibili e hanno una ricaduta positiva nella lotta alla desertificazione e nella tutela delle risorse del territorio. La trasformazione dell&apos;opuntia stricta, in particolare, risulta una metodologia adatta al contenimento della proliferazione di tale specie infestante, la cui diffusione nell&apos;area costituisce una minaccia per le mandrie delle popolazioni pastorali masai.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through an holistic approach originating from Permaculture Principles, the project aims at increasing agricultural production and profitability of business activities for 11 target groups (770 direct beneficiaries), improving in this way the economic conditions of the agro-pastoral groups of Laikipia North, and encouraging the resilience of the communities in the arid and semi-arid areas of Laikipia County.The main actions concern the training and supply of equipment for agriculture, access to water for four communities, support to supply chains suitable for dry climates (honey, aloe, opuntia) and strengthening the tourism sector. All actions are anchored on environmentally friendly methods and principles to have a positive impact in mitigating desertification and encourage the protection of local natural resources. The transformation of opuntia stricta, in particular, is a suitable methodology to contain the propagation of this intrusive plant species, which diffusion in the area represents a threat to the community, causing injuries to people, as well to both domestic and wild animals. Due to ulcerations caused by the spines when animals feed on it, Opuntia stricta cause the death of Maasai population&apos;s livestock which is the main economic activity hence, raising the poverty levels of the already poor indigenous communities in Laikipia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IPSIA - ISTITUTO PACE, SVILUPPO, INNOVAZIONE ACLI ONG/ON</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="011886/01/1" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2019000266" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="31165" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural alternative development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="32161" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agro-industries</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43040" percentage="40" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, double the agricultural productivity and incomes of small-scale food producers, in particular women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers, including through secure and equal access to land, other productive resources and inputs, knowledge, financial services, markets and opportunities for value addition and non-farm employment</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure sustainable food production systems and implement resilient agricultural practices that increase productivity and production, that help maintain ecosystems, that strengthen capacity for adaptation to climate change, extreme weather, drought, flooding and other disasters and that progressively improve land and soil quality</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-12">1171376</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IPSIA - ISTITUTO PACE, SVILUPPO, INNOVAZIONE ACLI ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-19">502264.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IPSIA - ISTITUTO PACE, SVILUPPO, INNOVAZIONE ACLI ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-04">354822.3</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IPSIA - ISTITUTO PACE, SVILUPPO, INNOVAZIONE ACLI ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
