<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-011889-01-0</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">AGRICHANGE: PICCOLE IMPRESE, GRANDI OPPORTUNIT&#xC0; Sviluppo di filiere agro-alimentari nel bacino del Fiume Molo</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">L&apos;azione si propone di sviluppare il tessuto micro imprenditoriale dei piccoli produttori del bacino del fiume Molo. La logica di intervento si basa sulla promozione di attivit&#xE0; ecosostenibili, circolari e replicabili e a basso prezzo. L&apos;obiettivo generale mira ad aumentare il potenziale economico dei piccoli produttori con iniziative di sviluppo locale innovative, inclusive e sostenibili attraverso la creazione due micro imprese eco-sostenibili e ad alto valore aggiunto: filiere dei suini e del miele. Particolare attenzione sar&#xE0; data alla dinamica di genere promuovendo l&apos;imprenditorialit&#xE0; femminile e l&apos;effettivo empowerment. La filiera suina, con una particolare attenzione all&apos;animal welfare, sar&#xE0; sviluppata nel basso bacino con la creazione di un centro per la riproduzione, realizzato in partenariato con Rota Guido srl e un circuito di ingrasso per gruppi di piccoli produttori, specie donne per il cambiamento delle dinamiche di genere in ambito pastorale. L&apos;obiettivo &#xE8; la creazione di una cooperativa regionale che unisca i produttori del basso e alto bacino e li assista nella promozione e realizzazione del brand Toraet Pork, sinonimo di alta qualit&#xE0;, di un sostenibile e di garanzia per i consumatori. In parallelo sar&#xE0; formata una micro impresa per la produzione di mangimi animali di alta qualit&#xE0; a basso costo e non in competizione con lo human food. Per la logica della circolarit&#xE0; saranno usati i residui dell allevamento per la produzione di larve. Saranno poi sviluppate 5 micro imprese per la funghicoltura, quale attivit&#xE0; ad alto valore aggiunto, sinergica con l&apos;allevamento suino con l&apos;obiettivo di fornire reddito e migliorare le diversificazione di prodotti per la dieta.  Terza integrazione sar&#xE0; il biogas quale strumento di riuso delle deiezioni per ridurre l&apos;impatto sull&apos;uso delle biomasse per i consumi energetici famigliari.  La seconda filiera vedr&#xE0; la creazione di una impresa cooperativa regionale per il marketing del miele dell&apos;alto e basso bacino con la promozione di 2 brand. Sar&#xE0; data forte spinta anche ai micro imprenditori agricoli con la distribuzione di arnie migliorate e di fitocelle per il foraggio delle api.  Saranno poi realizzati 2 punti di raccolta nei due bacini per raccogliere il miele da zone ad alta produzione oggi non servite. Nel potenziamento dei servizi accessori alla filiera, sar&#xE0; sviluppata una microimpresa per la produzione di arnie migliorate, quale soluzione low cost e locale per il potenziamento della apicoltura con l&apos;obiettivo di espandere la produzione di miele per inserirsi nel lucrativo mercato locale.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The action aims to boost the micro-entrepreneurial potential of small producers in the Molo river basin. The intervention logic is based on the promotion of affordable, eco-friendly, circular and replicable activities. The general objective aims to increase the economic potential of small producers with inclusive growth through the development and creation of two eco-sustainable micro enterprises for honey and piggery with high social value. Pig breeding, with particular attention to the animal welfare, will be developed in the lower basin with the creation of a centre for breeding, with the technical support of Rota Guido srl and a fattening circuit focused on groups of small producers, specifically women. The goal is the establishment of a regional cooperative that unites the producers of the lower and upper basin and assists them in the promotion and marketing, with the creation of the Toraet Pork brand, a symbol for high quality meat, sustainable production and safety for the consumer.  From the main value chain, a micro-enterprise for the production of animal feed will be developed with the aim of having high quality feed at low cost and not in competition with human food. In this regard, using a circular approach, the animal waste will be used for the production of larvae. 5 micro enterprises for mushroom farming will be supported with the aim of providing income and improve diet diversification.  The third integration will be biogas as a means of reusing waste to reduce the impact on the use of biomass for family energy consumption. The value chain will focus on the creation of a regional cooperative for the marketing of honey in the two basins with the promotion of 2 brands. The project will support farmers in enhancing their production, with training and the distribution of improved beehives and seedlings for bee fodder. Within the honey supply chain, 2 collection points will be created in the lower and upper basin to collect honey from areas of high production which are not served. To foster the services for the honey value chain, it will be developed a macrobusiness for the improved beehives to increment the opportunities for the youth and the income of the producers. The goal is to expand the honey production and enter the local market.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MANI TESE 76 ONG</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="011889/01/0" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2019000269" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="32161" percentage="58" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agro-industries</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31163" percentage="42" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Livestock</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, double the agricultural productivity and incomes of small-scale food producers, in particular women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers, including through secure and equal access to land, other productive resources and inputs, knowledge, financial services, markets and opportunities for value addition and non-farm employment</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="1.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, eradicate extreme poverty for all people everywhere, currently measured as people living on less than $1.25 a day</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End poverty in all its forms everywhere</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote development-oriented policies that support productive activities, decent job creation, entrepreneurship, creativity and innovation, and encourage the formalization and growth of micro-, small- and medium-sized enterprises, including through access to financial services</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote sustained, inclusive and sustainable economic growth, full and productive employment and decent work for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-05">1749887.71</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MANI TESE 76 ONG</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-26">741369.03</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MANI TESE 76 ONG</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-07-08">579637.94</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MANI TESE 76 ONG</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-17">428880.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MANI TESE 76 ONG</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
