<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-KEN838</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced Covid-19 prevention and recovery of vulnerable households in Marsabit County</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is concern that the COVID-19 pandemic could turn into a hunger pandemic in the coming months as it continues with increasing number of positive cases and deaths across the Country. Despite the difficulties facing farmers, government support to agricultural production declined due to falling revenues. Depressed rains have adversely affected crop production. As a result, crop production was below average, leading to more severe food insecurity and malnutrition in Marsabit County. 
Due to systemic gender norms and underlying inequalities, Covid-19 threatens to significantly reduce women, girls&#x2019; livelihoods, and economic security. Marsabit County in particular, women and girls faced greater risks than men even before the pandemic. The vast majority of their employment is in the informal economy where they usually take on low-paid, less secure jobs. They have fewer earnings, fewer savings, less access to social protection and make up the majority of single-parent households. This cocktail of vulnerabilities makes them less resilient to economic shocks like Covid-19. Women and girls with disabilities are even more exposed to the impact of the Covid-19 crisis, which will amplify pre-existing barriers and inequalities. Persons with disabilities and their families are more likely to be poor and face significant challenges (in terms of greater costs) to secure the essential goods and services they need.
It is against this backdrop that Caritas Marsabit intends to enhance community food security, economic recovery and support adherence to Covid-19 preventive measures through food voucher intervention to 338households worth KSH5,000 for 3months, support 3women groups to engage in small businesses of making and selling of liquid soap, provision of 1047 reusable facemask to school going children in 3 primary schools and distribution of 1500ltrs of liquid soap for handwashing/ cleaning in the 3 schools and to other vulnerable community members  targeted in Saku Subcounty</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="KEN838" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="KEN838" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Diocese of Marsabit</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="KEN838" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-10-01">50000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="55331">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-09-22">50000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="70098">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-09-22">50000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Diocese of Marsabit</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
