<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-KEN847</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Drought Emergency Response Project in Marsabit, Phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marsabit County is experiencing one of the most severe drought never experienced before, as a result of failure of three consecutive rain seasons and this has resulted to extreme water shortage, food insecurity, migration of pastoral communities, widespread reliance on water trucking and food donations. High-water prices have been reported in most pastoral and agro-pastoral livelihood zones. With movement of livestock to strategic water points and limited access to productive land for farming and grazing, there is already increasing local tensions which could trigger further inter-communal conflict in parts of the County. Currently, water trucking and food assistance (through food distribution, cash transfers and food vouchers) to the most affected people and institutions are amongst some of the drought emergency interventions supported by CAFOD, the National and County Government and all partners working in the humanitarian aid relief. Unless supported through interventions such as water trucking and food donations most people and institutions currently do not have access to safe, clean drinking water and food.
In this 3rd Phase of CAFOD GEF funding and support from Carita Australia, this project targets 7 severely drought affected villages with food distribution, food voucher and water trucking, 5 schools with school feeding programs, 40 needy students with food for fees, construction of an underground tank in Tullu Dimtu and borehole drilling in Burgabo. The project is also targeting 11 strategic diesel-run boreholes among drought-affected communities of Marsabit County with the provision of fuel subsidies and 10 boreholes with fast moving spare parts. The direct beneficiaries will include school going children, men, women, pregnant and lactating women, People Living with Disability and youths in these villages. The vulnerable section of the community such as poor, elderly, female-headed households, people living with chronic diseases.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="KEN847" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="KEN847" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Diocese of Marsabit</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="KEN847" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-04-01">589906.9904</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="55943">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-03-24">45000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="70816">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-03-24">45000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Diocese of Marsabit</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
