<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-KEN836</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support Improved water access for 800 pastoral households in Noloroi and Tuale villages of Oldonyiro</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lack of adequate access to clean water constitutes among key challenges facing the pastoral communities in Isiolo County with Noloroi and Tuale Villages in Oldonyiro Ward among the hardest hit. The livelihoods of the pastoralists without access, or with very limited access to water are vulnerable because they have difficulty in obtaining food, accumulating other assets, and recuperating after recurrent natural shocks such as drought.
The main goal of this project is to improve water access to 800 pastoral households and 4 institutions (4,000 individuals) in Noloroi and Tuale villages of Oldonyiro Ward, Isiolo County. 
Construction of sand dams and rainwater harvesting systems will increase access to water for domestic and livestock use. Moreover, the water sources will not only increase water availability in the midterm, but it will also promote the livelihood and household economy and create access to basics of life for the targeted as well as build the capacity of the pastoral communities to face shocks. 

Improved access to water will also contribute to reduced distance to water sources which will enable children to have adequate time to study and play instead of spending that time to look for water. Availability of water in schools will allow the children to have enough time for their education rather than go fetch water for the school.

Construction of sand dams and rainwater harvesting systems will provide the long-term answers to the problem of water scarcity. Sand dams are environmentally friendly and provides reliable water within reach by the local people and will also improve water access to livestock. Sand dam has low maintenance cost. Roof catchment in Noloroi and Tuale schools will offer possibilities of collecting rainwater to supplement water collected from the sand dams. Rainwater will be used for drinking and cooking.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="KEN836" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="KEN836" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Diocese of Isiolo</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="KEN836" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-06-01">72545.5519</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="55113">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-06-16">72545.5519</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="69814">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-06-16">72545.55</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Diocese of Isiolo</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
