<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-37054</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AIB Equity Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) Access to Finance, Job creation and Private Sector Development: The project will help in giving businesses greater access to finance, thus contributing to job creation and private sector development. Afghanistan has faced chronic unemployment and a burgeoning young population implies an estimated 400,000 new entrants into the job market.  2) Strengthen the Banking Sector: IFC&apos;s proposed equity and potential advisory package will provide support to AIB, strengthening the overall banking sector and improving competition by enhancing best practices.  3) Build Confidence in Afghanistan&apos;s Financial Sector: IFC&apos;s engagement with AIB at a time when Afghanistan and many other countries in the MENA region, are faced with economic, security and political challenges will send a positive signal to the market and enforce IFC&apos;s countercyclical role. This will support the Government of Afghanistan in its reform agenda.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan International Bank (AIB or the Bank) is a local Afghan private sector bank established in March 2004. It is headquartered in Kabul. As of December 2014, the Bank had 33 branches, 2 cash outlets, 59 Automated Teller Machines (ATMs), and 136 Point of Sale (POS) devices, across 10 provinces in Afghanistan. AIBs banking services include corporate/commercial, small business and retail banking, as well as electronic and Islamic banking. With total assets of US$964.2 million, AIB has the largest market share in the Afghan banking sector of approximately 23%.  The proposed project entails IFC taking an equity stake of up to 15% in AIB in two tranches. The initial tranche is for an equity stake of 7.5%, purchased equally from AIBs two main sponsor shareholders. The second tranche comprises of an IFC option to increase its equity stake by an additional 7.5% within two years of its initial investment in AIB by subscribing to new shares issued by AIB (fresh capital injection).  The proposed IFC investment together with the proposed IFC advisory services will help to further institutionalize AIBs shareholding, strengthen the Bank in operational risk management and build its capacity for commercial lending in diversified sectors. IFCs goal is to help the Bank, and by example the banking sector, improve financial inclusion in this Frontier and Conflict-affected State (FCS), where the per capita income of US$690 in 2014, was the lowest in Asia and among the 20 lowest in the World. According to the World Banks estimates, 96% of the Afghan population is unbanked, while the 2014 Enterprise Survey reports that only 5.1% of firms in Afghanistan have a line of credit and only 2% of firms are using banks for their funding needs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANISTAN INTERNATIONAL BANK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-37054" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Guy Mallet Chief Executive Officer Afghanistan International Bank  Shahr-e-Naw, Haji Yaqoob Square Shahabudin Watt, Post Box 2074 Kabul, Afghanistan Telephone: +93 (0) 20550255</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="AF-Afghanistan">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AIB is headquartered in Kabul, Afghanistan and is present in the major cities of Afghanistan. As of December 2014, the Bank employs about 680 people and has a large outreach with a branch network of 33 branches and 2 cash outlets, 59 ATM, and 136 POS devices, across 10 provinces in Afghanistan.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.0000000000 66.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="522110" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">O-AA - Commercial Banking - General</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $10.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-06-28"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-28">10000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-28">10000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANISTAN INTERNATIONAL BANK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/37054/aib-equity-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/37054/aib-equity-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
