<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-17/3884/R/ELSC/NGO/4957</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">project to support Iraqi Internally displaced persons (IDPs), host communities, remainees and returnees through cash-for-work activities to provide income for life-saving necessities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bothoor alkhaer seeks to implement a cash-for-work program in the Iraqi governorate of Mosul working in Quarter Zahra - quarter Tahrir - Quarter alnoor &#x2013; Al Zuhoor quarter. for a total of 300 beneficiaries 88 working days. This program will aim 
1. Providing workers with income so they can meet their basic needs 
2. Improving or repairing community infrastructure, basic services and the local economy.
Cash-based interventions, such as cash-for-work, have various advantages. 
it enables people to make their own choices and set their own priorities. For example, monitoring studies of the use of emergency distributions have revealed that aid recipients often sell their food and non-food relief packages in order to obtain money for more urgent priorities such as health care, debt payments and education
Another advantage of CFW programming is that it can be implemented far more quickly and with fewer delays than food aid. Cash payments (as opposed to in-kind distribution or aid packets) empower the beneficiaries to buy food or other necessities for immediate use and according to the priorities of the individual
. Distribution costs are usually lower than distributions of food or non-food items and CFW can be implemented quickly because it is not reliant on delay-prone shipping. CFW stimulates recovery of the local economy by creating short-term work, reintroducing income flow, supporting local businesses through the purchase of construction materials, and encouraging households to purchase food and non-food items locally. CFW programs also fund the rehabilitation of damaged community assets while maintaining the dignity of the affected population through meaningful community engagement in the selection and implementation of projects. CFW activities provide short-term employment for large numbers of the population and can be designed to encourage the integration and participation of women and other marginalized groups in the area. 
 the project will improve the community infrastructure like Schools, University, health centers cleaned and environment inside them improved by repainting of its walls And lifting the rubble
 The entrances to the cities, township organized, cleaned, painting of street&apos;s sidewalk.
 cleaning the water drainage area inside the town&apos;s streets

According to WFP assessment data was used to evaluate to evaluate the price of  food basket in the target governorate. Food basket cost about 220$ (food ampnoon food items)
And To prevent the competition with existing labour wage the daily rate will be  10$
(according to WFP assessment  the wages of unskilled labour about 11.875). Each person working for 22 days will received USD220, this amount, also it is similar to UNHCR&#x2019;s MEB (Minimum Expenditure Basket) partially fulfils the food and other prioritized requirements of a household with 6-7 family members.

Similar experience
In 2014 , Bothoor has successfully completed the implementation of two projects in Diyala governorate within the Iraq Reconstruction and Employment Programmed funded by FAO with total budget of 155,113 USD. 
Its strategic objective was to employ workers countrywide ( IDPs household ), for short periods of time in labor-based rehabilitation of both rural and urban environment, and the reconstruction of basic facilities. 
The program has made a significant and lasting change in living conditions, whilst strengthening the capacity of local administrations and communities in their ability to work together for positive changes in the overall living conditions. Also it will increase social cohesion and decrease social tension by making different Community in side Mosul work together and help each other we will target IDPs and household from different part of the city which different in (Tribes, accents, amp Education level) but this will depend our translucency in selection and using fair selecting criteria</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bothoor Alkhaer Organization for Relief and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bothoor Alkhaer Organization for Relief and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">nafee Laith</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>07705526939</telephone>
   <email>nafaa.b.a.k@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Ahmed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director of the Office of Mosul</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>07702005741</telephone>
   <email>ngo2iraq@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sondos Shah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assistant Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>07905932247</telephone>
   <email>sonds.b.a.h.o@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nineveh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.35940000 43.15280000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-05">104103.3</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-4957">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-05">104103.3</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bothoor Alkhaer Organization for Relief and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302699022">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-07">62461.98</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bothoor Alkhaer Organization for Relief and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302891356">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-18">41641.32</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bothoor Alkhaer Organization for Relief and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
