<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-17/3884/ST/H/INGO/5694</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of essential comprehensive package of primary health care services for most vulnerable population (returnees and host community) residing in out-of-camp settings in newly retaken areas in Ninewa plain. Aiming to uphold dignity, providing life-saving services and encourage safe and voluntary return.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is designed to be a part of a comprehensive package of services/assistance to vulnerable returnees and host communities residing in out-of-camp settings in Ninewa governorate.

The target number of families is 1,529 HHs and all of them will be benefiting from WASH, Health, Education and Protection services. Household size is estimated at an average of 6 members per family. The # of direct beneficiaries is based on a projected increase of population from 25% at start, to 50% of pre-crisis numbers at the end of the project period. 
Cordaid is already working in Ninewa plain providing essential WASH, Education and Health facilities.
Using own funds, Cordaid invests in the rehabilitation of two health facilities destroyed due to the crisis. Mobile health teams are deployed in the interim.  

This project will focus on equipping these two PHCCs and make them fully functional, serving the entire population. The project will therefore contribute to the revitalization of the health system in the target area and also serve as a more sustainable response that will meet the health needs of the population and support the DoH and Health system beyond the project duration.

All required procurement of the supplies and equipment for the activities will be made in country, investing in the local market.

Needs assessments have been conducted by Cordaid in 23 villages in Nimrud and Hamdania districts, these determined:
Exact non camp targeted locations
Restrictions to access/security situation
Vulnerable beneficiaries/special needs groups to be targeted 
Appropriate service package and estimated cost according to the actual need of the targeted population and in line with the guidance provided by the clusters
And more specifically established the catchment area of the two PHCCs. 


The project is designed to respond to the need of the vulnerable targeted population dis-aggregated by age group and gender: Children of different age groups (e.g. new born babies and those below 5 years) are more prone for communicable diseases and malnutrition thus necessity for nutrition analysis and availability of essential vaccines. Men and women above the age of 45 are more prone to have a chronic illness thus it is essential to have regular clinical check-ups and follow up of already established cases for any complications and drug compliance and adverse effects also responding to the need reproductive age woman and girls for promotion of their awareness of and providing requirements of reproductive health services through the services provided in the primary health clinics.
Women will be consulted and involved in project design and monitoring their social background , security and privacy during the service hour by the availability of female medical doctors and nurses at all times.
The above considerations are essential elements in project design and participative monitoring of the project. 

Local government authorities and religious leaders (both church and Imams) are consulted and liaised with. Key Informant Interviews will also take place. Coordination will take place amongst the Health Clusters and health partners.

Post activity monitoring will take place and the results to be shared with the cluster and relevant partners.
A feedback mechanism will deal with and follow up on complaints, whereas participatory monitoring through village committees will guide and adapt the project once underway, these will be directly monitored and supervised by Cordaid protection officer.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STICHTING CORDAID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STICHTING CORDAID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lavigne J. Putrus</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00964 750 743 4037</telephone>
   <email>lavigne.putrus@cordaid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nineveh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.35940000 43.15280000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-06-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-21">101015.53</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-07-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-21">98985.06</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-5694">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-21">200000.59</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STICHTING CORDAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302752424">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-03">80000.24</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STICHTING CORDAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303987186">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-15">114038.51</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STICHTING CORDAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
