<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-17/3884/R/H/UN/7191</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting  the lifesaving health care services and outbreak prevention and response facilities for the  IDPs from Hawija settling in Kirkuk, and Salah Al Din Governorates</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The military operations in the western Kirkuk governorate (Hawija) expected to displace around 60,000 people in and around the operation areas. The IDP movements are expected to be on the west towards Tikrit and in the East towards Kirkuk. The recent assessment made by health cluster partners in the two governorates revealed that there are 3-4 hospitals on both sides and there are 5 PHCs inside the Hawija, further there are 4-5 PHC centers in the IDP camps and screening/mustering points on both side serving the IDPs. The new influx would increase the case load of the existing camps and clinics and expected to cause outbreaks of common communicable diseases like, measles and cholera, shortage of medicines and medical supplies in the health facilities. The high risk for communicable disease outbreaks coupled with inadequate disease surveillance and response system will require establishment of a robust disease early warning and response system. Ensuring access and uninterrupted availability of life-saving medicines, medical consumables, emergency health kits, surgical, trauma kits and cholera kits will be a priority to support the existing health system to bear the new load. WHO Iraq will use its capacity to procure and distribute necessary standard inter agency emergency kits and medicines necessary for the emergency response. 

Under the project the WHO will  focus on reducing morbidity and mortality on the frontline and in newly accessible areas by 
1.	Strengthen the existing health facilities (including all PHCs and hospitals) with necessary additional supplies of interagency emergency kits, medicines and other essential supplies. Under the activity WHO will pre-position lifesaving medicines and medical supplies for IDPs in camps and in host communities. During the Hawija operation, WHO will support MOH, DOH and partners by providing essential medicines, medical supplies and kits through operating the main warehouse in Erbil. WHO with its privileged relationship with MoH, will procure, store and distribute medications to serve its own operation as well as that of the health cluster partners.

2.	Improve diseases surveillance and outbreak response capacity in the IDP settling locations through establishing new sentinel sites and rapid response teams. Under the activity WHO will establish the outbreak detection and response mechanisms for disease outbreaks in locations where displaced people are likely to flee and temporarily settle in. The EWARN systems will be strengthened in local communities to ensure rapid detection, treatment and management of epidemic-prone diseases given the increased public health risk including cholera and measles. Vaccination will be prioritized to deal with the expected low antigen levels of IDPs fleeing Mosul. The following vaccination response is proposed:</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wael Hatahit</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+9647510101456</telephone>
   <email>hatahitw@who.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G013">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kirkuk</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.46670000 44.31670000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="G016">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Salah Al-Din</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.45000000 43.58330000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-11-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-27">288776.86</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-27">352166.9</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-7191">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-27">640943.76</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302975201">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-01">640943.76</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
