<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-17/3884/R/F/NGO/4719</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bothoor alkhaer  project to support Iraqi Internally displaced persons (IDPs), host communities, remainees and returnees through cash-for-work activities to provide income for life-saving necessities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bothoor alkhaer seeks to a cash-for-work program in the Iraqi governorate of Diyala working in Great Khalis district for a total of 1 ,000 beneficiaries 14 working days. This program will aim to facilitate the return process to Great Khalis and improve food security in the area through two means: 1) providing cash income to returnee, and other vulnerable families in order to increase economic access to food, and 2) increasing food security though projects that improve agricultural and market conditions.
Cash-based interventions, such as cash-for-work, have various advantages. Direct cash transfers provide a flexible resource to affected households and empower individuals to spend money according to their needs and priorities. Distribution costs are usually lower than distributions of food or non-food items and CFW can be implemented quickly because it is not reliant on delay-prone shipping. CFW stimulates recovery of the local economy by creating short-term work, reintroducing income flow, supporting local businesses through the purchase of construction materials, and encouraging households to purchase food and non-food items locally. CFW programs also fund the rehabilitation of damaged community assets while maintaining the dignity of the affected population through meaningful community engagement in the selection and implementation of projects. CFW activities provide short-term employment for large numbers of the population and can be designed to encourage the integration and participation of women and other marginalized groups in the area . 

Cash-for-work projects provide men and women to earn an income, and can increase their status both within their household and in the community. The projects also have the potential to lead to greater decision making authority over household spending and other related decisions. Sensitivity to gender dynamics will be a central component of all programs,( Bothoor Alkhaer ) projects are targeting women headed households, which have increased drastically over past years. Helping these women gain access to financial resources not only helps them to improve their livelihoods, but also promotes positive attitudes in the community toward women in terms of their capacity and their contribution to economic and social development. The approach would be to engage communities, through village committees, and participation of both women and men throughout the project cycle to ensure effectiveness.


Bothoor Al-khaer seeks to implement a cash-for-work program in the Iraqi governorate of Diyala working in Diyala district for a total of,(1000) beneficiaries (14 )working days. Each group (14) days of project implementation period is run 4 months, we will divided the beneficiaries to 4 groups each group 250 individuals, the most  working age will be between 18-55 year, also we will include boys, girls (under 18 year) in special cases for example (the only member extreme vulnerable family can work)

Currently, Bothoor alkhaer efforts are focused on addressing the immediate needs of conflict-affected populations in Diyala through strengthening food and non-food distributions as well as providing assistance in sectors including Food security , shelter and water and sanitation. Bothoor alkhaer recognizes that as the security situation continues to improve in Diyala and the number of returnees increases, economic recovery activities are essential to help residents access the resources needed to purchase food, clothes and medicines, repa
ir homes, and restart businesses promoting additional returns to the area. 


Bothoor alkhaer carried out more projects then 10 through and Food security , displaced communities. Bothoor alkhaer has a proven track record of the highest</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bothoor Alkhaer Organization for Relief and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bothoor Alkhaer Organization for Relief and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">nafee Laith</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>07705526939</telephone>
   <email>nafaa.b.a.k@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Majid Khalil</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>009647735945502</telephone>
   <email>ngo2iraq@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sondos Shah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assistant Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>07905932247</telephone>
   <email>sonds.b.a.h.o@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G010">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diyala</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.88330000 45.06670000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-05">321814.5</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-4719">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-05">321814.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bothoor Alkhaer Organization for Relief and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302699022">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-07">160907.25</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bothoor Alkhaer Organization for Relief and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302891356">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-18">160907.25</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bothoor Alkhaer Organization for Relief and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
