<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-17/3884/ST/EL/INGO/5720</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve access to emergency livelihood opportunities for the conflict affected IDPs and host communities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As the crisis in Iraq carries on into its third year, social tensions continue to rise, particularly in areas in which IDPs and host communities face economic or social hardship. Displacement and its subsequent economic repercussions upon host communities directly contribute to conflict between displaced and host communities, according to a recent impact assessment conducted at the cluster. Debt is growing among displaced communities, as well as Iraqi society as a whole, creating greater reliance on a diminishing social protection floor. The ability of the protracted displaced population to find sustainable job opportunities continues to be severely limited, with income generation remaining among one of the top needs of displaced populations.

Livelihoods needs often lead to social tension erupting in conflict. Assessments have shown that both displaced and host community populations which are unable to address their needs or which struggle economically are significantly more likely to have poor relationships with other communities. This is confirmed by the fact that IDPs continue to face ethnic and socioeconomic discrimination. Host community individuals often view recent economic hardship as caused by incoming displaced populations. Where economic grievances may lead to social tensions, specific livelihoods interventions are needed to support vulnerable households. In Ninewa SIF has succeeded in developing early livelihood opportunities for the extremely vulnerable IDP with generous support from CDC, the targeted groups of this approach will be able to cover the basic living needs of their families which will result in reducing the tensions among the displaced families and their hosting communities in different manners.

The plan for this project is to improve access to emergency livelihood opportunities for the conflict affected IDPs, remainees and host communities to enable them to cope with the impact of crisis, in their chosen locations in Iraq, through immediate access to income for vulnerable families and social awareness, in areas at high risk of tensions in Haditha and Heet districts in Anbar province through immediate access to income for vulnerable families and social awareness especially in areas with high risks of tensions within the proposed locations. Through this project SIF seeks to enhance the humanitarian response by working with other clusters to increase their scope and impact, SIF will consult with CCCM, shelter, WASH, education and protection clusters to conduct joint efforts for the benefits of the targeted communities through CFW initiatives such as basic renovation for the community facilities, renovation of primary schools, kindergartens and PHCCs that serve both communities (IDPs and host) and conduct protection awareness on IDP rights, mine risk education.

SIF project proposal aims to conduct a joint rapid needs assessment in coordination with Al Mortaqa Foundation regarding social tension and conflict sensitivity as well as to confirm the identification of the potential livelihood opportunities that are selected through pre-assessment surveys that took place for the purpose of developing this proposal. SIF will also conduct community outreach initiatives to reduce and/or prevent social tensions among the targeted communities. We will also initiate temporary employment activities for the extremely vulnerable categories for four months, such temporary employments will assist in restoring the most useful facilities within the targeted geographical areas as well as to assist and help in the renovation of damaged schools and water treatment plants. Women will be consulted to identify meaningful C4W activities that are socially acceptable.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intellect organization for sustainable development (IOSD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secours Islamique France</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secours Islamique France</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammed Abdelrazzak</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>07700641920</telephone>
   <email>dep.rep.iraq@secours-islamique.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moaathe Enayet</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>07500871159</telephone>
   <email>hom.iq@secours-islamique.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G01">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Anbar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.90000000 41.60000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-21">300000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-5720">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-21">300000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secours Islamique France</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302767651">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-13">150000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secours Islamique France</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303549242">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-14">128181.26</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secours Islamique France</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400233094">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-19">5549.92</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secours Islamique France</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
