<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-17/3884/ST/H/INGO/5423</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save lives and reduce human suffering through the provision of lifesaving healthcare services to newly internally displaced persons (IDPs) in Iraq.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International&apos;s (RI&apos;s) proposed health programming will be implemented in close coordination with the MOH/DOH in each respective target governorate, as well as WHO, UNFPA and other health cluster partners. In line with the Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP), RI will focus its interventions on provision of essential lifesaving health service according to the health cluster standard package, prioritizing first-line and second line response with front-line service delivery as well as comprehensive healthcare services through the existing health facilities to meet the rapidly growing needs in the proposed project area. 

The project will look at expanding coverage and deepening RI&apos;s humanitarian response in &quot;hot spots&quot; and hard to reach locations, building on RI&apos;s past and current programming experience. This critical and life-saving health response will be carried out through support to existing primary health centers (PHCs) and expanding existing Mobile Medical Teams (MMTs) capacity in hard-to-reach, recently retaken and front-line areas where no other health actors exist, and where there are no other operational health facilities (HF). RI will support an integrated package of primary health care services with emergency referrals, disease surveillance and basic RH and mental health services.

RI is proposing to support one PHC and expand an existing MMTs in front-line locations in Anbar and Salahaldin governorates, targeting locations where displacement has increased and providing urgent medical assistance to 31,640 vulnerable and under-served IDPs. In Anbar, RI is proposing to implement further into the front-line, more remote locations where the health needs are mounting and high displacement is anticipated following military interventions in west Anbar. Therefore, RI will expand support to one flexible MMT in front-line location in Anbar where influx of IDPs is anticipated from west Anbar. RI has been operational in Al Qaim since April 2016 when RI received permission from the local authorities to roll out its humanitarian intervention following intensive networking and coordination. The proposed project is designed to build off RI&apos;s current intervention in complex context with unstable security situation, ensuring no overlap of activities and providing lifesaving and urgent health care services to compliment our existing operations for these highly vulnerable populations. In Salahaldin, RI is proposing to expand the capacity of an existing PHC in Shirqat to better respond in the location currently receiving massive numbers of newly arrived IDPs, and determine accessibility in Hawija for possible future strategies to operate inside if access and security permit. RI has been operational since 2016 in the Qad al Ashur and Jumaila screening and transit points in Shirqat and intends to stay close to the front-line, providing the newly arrived IDPs who have had limited access to chronic disease medication and other basic healthcare services. 

This approach will ensure access to essential, life-saving medicines, consumables, and equipment, including for reproductive health, for vulnerable populations. RI will also provide technical capacity and support as necessary to the medical teams in order to provide high-quality care according to international standards. By including a reproductive health component, this intervention takes into account the unique needs of women and girls. RI will ensure that this intervention is not only responsive to the unique health needs of women and girls, but also takes into account the concerns and priorities of boys and men, which may vary, and will work to ensure that the HFs and MMTs are accessible and welcoming to persons with disabilities. RI has robust remote management mechanism that will be utilized to by the health technical team to monitor and analyze the proposed pro</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jody Yasinowsky</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Development Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>++44 (0) 207 065 087</telephone>
   <email>jody.yasinowsky@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Josh Kreger</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+964 7517851248</telephone>
   <email>josh.kreger@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wardere Abdikarin</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public Health Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+964 771 796 1400</telephone>
   <email>wardere.abdikarin@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G01">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Anbar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.90000000 41.60000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="G016">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Salah Al-Din</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.45000000 43.58330000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-06">274080.77</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-06">75919.09</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-5423">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-06">349999.86</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302733454">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-20">349999.86</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="6305122450">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-13">1017.01</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
