<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-17/3884/ST/NFIs/INGO/5645</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing access to shelter and NFI assistance for displaced population in Mosul City, Ninewa Governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project will continue provision of assistance to vulnerable IDP, host and returnee families affected by the military offensive and residing in Mosul City. Most vulnerable HH living in substandard shelter and undignified conditions will be supported through provision of financial resources for small scale repairs and upgrades and to purchase basic household items, either through cash or through value-based vouchers. Where the markets have not yet emerged, the support will be provided in-kind. However cash/vouchers based support will be favored when feasible. PIN will focus on the neighborhoods in the eastern part of the city, assessed in February 2017. Expansion onto West Mosul is likely though, once the security situation permits and gaps are identified. The eastern neighborhoods are accessible at the date of this proposal from a security perspective and have seen significant influx of IDPs from the Western part of the city, on top of vulnerable HHs who stayed or returned. Exact numbers of vulnerable HH are still under assessment at the time of writing (PIN assessment, RNA, Cash Consortium/UNHCR/UNICEF vulnerability assessment), however the number is constantly growing as influx from West Mosul continues.
PIN has already well established presence in Mosul East through NFI interventions ongoing since March 2017. PIN conducted assessments in 19 neighborhoods in February 2017 and at the time of submission of this proposal is contributing to the UNOCHA RNA. Further on, PIN is conducting series of assessments in Western Mosul and once the needs are confirmed and area becomes accessible for humanitarian actors, it may adjust the intervention and extend operations to Mosul West. PIN has proven record with flexible and mobile emergency response (e.g. ongoing ECHO-funded Alliance2015 Mosul Emergency Response project, completed Second Allocation of IHPF 2016). Further on, in liaison with Cash Consortium and CWG, PIN will ensure the targeting of the most vulnerable households in terms of SNFI.
The assistance provided by PIN consists of two components:
I) Small cash grants or value-based vouchers for procurement of shelter materials and core household items for 1,000 vulnerable households (in areas where markets have not yet restored by the time implementation, PIN will provide support in-kind),
II) Small cash grants for contracting local labor for the most vulnerable 340 household among the targeted beneficiaries, who cannot conduct repair works by themselves (female-, child-, elderly headed households).
PIN will also support the beneficiaries with technical assistance through a free of charge hotline and direct technical consultancies conducted by PIN mobile teams in targeted areas. Technical teams will visit families and support them with suitable construction advises on adequate materials, designs and solutions. PIN MampE department will conduct post-distribution monitoring surveys to collect feedback and inform future programming. Moreover, PIN Complaint and Feedback Response Mechanism will be available to target population to ensure accountability.
A cash based intervention was identified by PIN as well as the SNFI Cluster and the Cash Working Group as the most appropriate approach in Mosul City. Markets in the city are available (see e.g. PIN East Mosul Key Findings, February 2017 or WFP market assessment in Mosul, March 2017). The challenge for the population is the lack of purchasing power and livelihood opportunities and it is believed that cash will provide a more dignified and appropriate assistance while simultaneously stimulating local economy. Vouchers are foreseen as the modality for SNFI in order to ensure that the identified and needed assistance is bought. PIN will follow the SNFI Cluster and CWG working group guidelines (200 USD/HH). 

The project will be closely coordinated with SNFI Cluster and with CWG to ensure the selected approach is coherent with cluster strategy and guidelines.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dominika Rypa</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+9647515104215</telephone>
   <email>dominika.rypa@poepleinneed.cz</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maciej Perczynski</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Directir</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+9647515246855</telephone>
   <email>hom.iraq@peopleinneed.cz</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nineveh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.35940000 43.15280000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-09">421464.44</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-5645">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-09">421464.44</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302733447">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-20">337171.55</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303458073">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-24">84292.89</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
