<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-17/3884/ST/WASH/INGO/5486</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of safe access to emergency WASH services and hygiene practices and more equitable access to services in hard-to-access areas of Anbar, newly retaken areas of northern Ninewa and the Qayyarah Airstrip Camp</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In order to address the critical WASH needs of conflict-affected and highly vulnerable populations in the governorates of Anbar and Ninewa, DRC proposes a two-pillared approach to emergency WASH interventions. The proposed intervention will facilitate immediate and lifesaving access to water, sanitation and hygiene (WASH) services in hard-to-reach areas in each governorate and ensure expanded, more equitable access to sanitation services in the Qayyarah Airstrip Camp.

The first phase of DRC&#x2019;s response will ensure that targeted populations in Anbar and Ninewa have access to the minimum standards of WASH services. In the informal settlements, transit sites and established camps of Anbar, this phase will consist of the rapid provision of communal water tanks, water trucking, installation of emergency latrines and hand-washing stations, quick fix rehabilitation of water supply infrastructure and distribution of core WASH items. In Anbar, hygiene promotion activities will underpin all technical interventions ensuring that installed facilities are appropriately used by the beneficiaries and will increase health awareness and prevent diseases related to poor hygiene practices through a community approach. In newly retaken areas in the Telafar and Tilkaif districts of northern Ninewa (such as Quba, Badoosh and Khawaja Kalil), DRC will immediately support water provision by undertaking emergency rehabilitation works of municipal treatment plants and networks. This component of the intervention will not only immediately improve the access to safe water of mixed conflict-affected communities and lay the groundwork for second-line refurbishment of infrastructure, but will also increase the capacity of the target communities to absorb the new influxes of IDPs anticipated from Mosul.

The second pillar of DRC&#x2019;s WASH response under this action will aim to ensure expanded, more equitable access to water and sanitation services in informal settlements in Anbar. This second line response will be implemented though DRC&#x2019;s mobile site management approach that combines (i) mobile team site visits led by DRC&#x2019;s CCCM teams (ii) the development of site profiles and multi-sector assessments through a participatory methodology and (iii) coordination of site level interventions, including liaising with all relevant stakeholders. This approach facilitates a transition between first and second line responses allowing water and sanitation networks and facilities to be improved to meet minimum standards of service provision. In parallel, DRC will address identified privacy and dignity concerns, particularly amongst women and girls, to facilitate access to sanitation facilities in the Qayyarah Airstrip Camp. In line with DRC&#x2019;s integrated approach to programming, this component of the proposed intervention will also support local industry in Qayyarah town and provide immediate access to income to camp residents and host community households.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DRC Iraq</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>allen.jelich@drciraq.dk</telephone>
   <email>Allen Jelich</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G01">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Anbar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.90000000 41.60000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="G015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nineveh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.35940000 43.15280000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-27">638555.75</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-27">205873.16</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-5486">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-27">844428.91</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302756480">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-06">675543.13</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
