<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-17/3884/ST/CCS/INGO/5543</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multi-Dimensional Risk Mitigation Information Management Centre</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since November 2016, iMMAP has been running a comprehensive and multi-dimensional Risk Mitigation Information Management (RMIM) center dedicated to Mosul humanitarian response to provide risk information during the critical emergency relief period in Iraq. This project is funded by IHPF and its six-month term comes to an end on 30th April 2017. 

The overall goal of the RMIM center is to rapidly assess the level of explosive hazards and security situation to set up safety, security and risk management systems in new contexts and rapid onset emergency response situations to Humanitarian Actors (HA) involved in the Mosul response.

The RMIM center is proving to be a critical multi-cluster response program for Mosul whereby we provide regular updated IM products on explosive contamination and the security situation. This work supports HA by ensuring they are adequately informed on safety, security, and risk information. This information feeds into cluster and institutional IM systems facilitating the emergency response. The information products produced by iMMAP have been crucial resources for the UN agencies, cluster partners, I/NGOs and government agencies responding to the crisis. Through this support, our partners have been able to prioritize and effectively implement their respective interventions appropriately. 

iMMAP proposes to continue, adapt and expand this project as the need for risk mapping continues to be vital in newly liberated areas and in areas where IDP&#x2019;s have been displaced. It is widely believed that this project can be applied to new contexts in line with the current priorities of the humanitarian response. 

As of now, there are approximately 150 organizations (UN and I/NGO and other HA) who regularly access these publications, data sources, and dashboards.

The support provided via the RMIM unit will come in the following set up:

1. iMMAP&#x2019;s security incident tracking and mapping with focus on humanitarian response:
iMMAP have a dedicated unit that gathers daily reported incidents for the whole of Iraq since 2006. The RMIM team will be zooming into areas of priority. These incidents are then analyzed and disseminated in the form of IM products/maps.

2. Timely Mobile Data Collection (MDC) of current explosive contamination through front line partners:
iMMAP will provide MDC tools to selected front line humanitarian actors, community leaders, returnees and selected government officials to collect real time explosive contamination data and share it remotely with iMMAP to store, verify, classify, analyze and disseminate IM products to the humanitarian responders.

3. Mine Action Information Management:
iMMAP provides mine action information management to mine action stakeholders helping them to maintain a clear common operating picture. iMMAP will be providing layered IM products to identify areas with the greatest need, in order to plan, prioritize tasks and manage Explosive Remnants of War (ERW) mitigation activities of the humanitarian operations.

4. Desktop survey of hard to reach areas:
A comprehensive desktop survey (Satellite Image Analysis) will be carried in hard to reach areas to allow the humanitarian community plan their aid delivery once the areas become accessible. This will provide a better picture about damage, threat, suspected hazard contamination and the scope and scale of security and safety of the areas.

The above layers of data sets will be customized and integrated to produce IM products that enhance the risk mitigation measures of the humanitarian actors and their response impact.

Additionally, iMMAP will be supporting the IM of the protection cluster members and other HA of the project area to develop efficient mobile data collection and to integrate and layer their specific data sets with the above mentioned data to produce informative IM products that informs better situational understanding and subsequently a more enhanced response.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">iMMAP France</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">iMMAP France</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Isam Ghareeb</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Representative</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+964 750 446 3318</telephone>
   <email>ighareeb@immap.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G01">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Anbar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.90000000 41.60000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="G010">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diyala</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.88330000 45.06670000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="G013">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kirkuk</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.46670000 44.31670000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="G015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nineveh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.35940000 43.15280000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="12" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coordination and Support Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-12">246300.6</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-5543">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-12">246300.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">iMMAP France</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302724528">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-15">197040.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">iMMAP France</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303102147">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-03">49260.12</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">iMMAP France</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1703754327">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-07">26390.37</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">iMMAP France</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
