<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-17/3884/ST/P/INGO/5656</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of first and second line child protection services to highly-at-risk populations in Ninewa Governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through this proposed 6- month multi-sectorial project, ACTED will provide first and second-line responses to child protection needs in Ninewa Governorate both in and out-of-camps where new displacement is expected. Through 3 mobile teams, ACTED will provide IDP, returnee and host community children with ongoing and effective specialized support (including case management and referrals) and psychosocial services in response to their differential needs. ACTED will pay particular attention to the needs of girls and adolescent girls, persons with disabilities, as well as survivors of sexual and gender-based violence &#x2013; ensuring inclusive access to, and engagement in, activities and services. ACTED will use a community-based approach, focused on building the capacity of actors who make up the protective environment of children to identify and respond to children&#x2019;s protection needs. 

ACTED will have three mobile teams, each of which will have the flexibility to respond to new needs as they arise:
	First mobile team intervening in Bawiza, Tawila, and Orta Khrab, where ACTED is currently active. Should New Zelikan Camp open, this team will be able to respond to needs rapidly by shifting its intervention to intervene in the camp. Additionally, this team will be pre-positioned to potentially provide CP support in Qaymawa Camp, should there be a sudden influx of IDPs and already present CP actors&#x2019; capacity be overstretched. This course of action was agreed upon with the Child Protection Sub-Cluster (CPSC) Mosul focal point. 
	Second mobile team assigned to Tilkaif town and more precisely four locations which will be selected through a CP Site Assessment to be conducted in the initial stage of the project. 
	Third mobile team assigned to Bashiqa subdistrict, and working in 4 locations &#x2013; also selected through a CPSA. The current number of IDP families in Bashiqa (150) is expected to increase at the end of the school year, requiring child protection assistance. Indeed, in an intentions survey conducted by UNHCR, 47% of IDPs surveyed said that they had the intention to return to their area of origin at the end of the school year. Should this anticipated influx not occur, ACTED will re-locate the third mobile team based on consultations with the CPSC and additional assessments. 

The following results will be achieved through this multi-sectorial project:
 Specialized child protection services are provided to vulnerable IDP, returnee and host community children in and out-of-camp areas
 Non-formal educational and psychosocial support for girls, boys and caregivers is provided through community-based and mobile activities
 Community-based child protection capacities to prevent and respond to child protection issues are supported and
 National and local capacity to provide sustained child protection services is strengthened. 

This project will fill gaps in protection service provision where government and humanitarian support is currently insufficient and will ensure safe and inclusive access to child protection services for vulnerable and at-risk children in Ninewa. The proposed intervention will build on the lessons learnt from the past IHPF-funded child protection projects implemented by ACTED as well as more widely its significant child protection programming throughout the country. The action was designed and will be implemented in line with the Protection Clusters objectives under the HRP 2017, as well as in close collaboration with relevant sub-national working groups, to avoid duplication and best answer the child protection needs in the areas of intervention. 

An estimated total of 3,750 beneficiaries will be reached through this multi-sectorial project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aline Milev</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+964(0)7719253543</telephone>
   <email>aline.milev@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camille Chemin</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Grant Management Unit</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+33(0)142653333</telephone>
   <email>camille.chemin@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Raphael Capony</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+964(0)7723341711</telephone>
   <email>raphael.capony@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G09">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dahuk</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.86739100 42.99885800</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="G015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nineveh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.35940000 43.15280000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-23">195827.1</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-23">33172.9</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-5656">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-23">229000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302769534">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-14">229000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
