<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5403052001-KAU-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kvinna till Kvinna framework 2015-2017 + extension 2018</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Kvinna till Kvinna ramst&#xF6;d 2015-2017 + f&#xF6;rl&#xE4;ngning 2018</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insamlingsstiftelsen Kvinna till Kvinna (KtK) har inkommit med en ans&#xF6;kan avseende en ett&#xE5;rig f&#xF6;rl&#xE4;ngning 2018 av sitt p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende ramavtal 2015-2017.

I juli 2013 beviljades KtK beh&#xF6;righet som ramorganisation inom anslagsposten St&#xF6;d genom svenska organisationer i det civila samh&#xE4;llet under CSO-strategin. Det p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende avtalet perioden 2015-2017 &#xE4;r det f&#xF6;rsta ramavtalet under CSO-anslaget. Ut&#xF6;ver detta avtal har KtK 12 p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende avtal med Sida med ett totalt avtalat belopp om 469 MSEK. Sidas &#xE5;rliga utbetalningar &#xE4;r ca 115 MSEK. Avtalen avser st&#xF6;d till verksamhet i Palestina, Rwanda, Liberia, Serbien, Bosnien Hercegovina, Makedonien, regionalt V&#xE4;stra Balkan, Georgien, MENA och Syrien samt informations- och kommunikationsinsatser i Sverige. Programmet f&#xF6;r perioden 2015-2017 och f&#xF6;r f&#xF6;rl&#xE4;ngningen 2018 har som syfte att: &quot;M&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra f&#xF6;r KtK att forts&#xE4;tta sitt arbete med att ge st&#xF6;d till partnerorganisationers arbete f&#xF6;r kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter i konfliktdrabbade l&#xE4;nder och regioner och att f&#xF6;r detta &#xE4;ndam&#xE5;l &#xE4;ven utveckla metoder f&#xF6;r kapacitetsutveckling och m&#xF6;jlighet att bilda n&#xE4;tverk&#x201D;.
Det l&#xE5;ngsiktiga effektm&#xE5;let &#xE4;r &quot;&#xF6;kad uppfyllelse av kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter inom agendan f&#xF6;r kvinnor, fred och s&#xE4;kerhet i konfliktdrabbade regioner&quot;. 

Programmet &#xE4;r indelat i fyra tematiska huvudomr&#xE5;den, varav ett &#xE4;r tv&#xE4;rg&#xE5;ende:

1. Kvinnor och fredsbyggande
2. K&#xF6;nsrelaterat v&#xE5;ld mot kvinnor
3. P&#xE5;verkansarbete
4. Kapacitetsutveckling i organisatorisk h&#xE5;llbarhet (tv&#xE4;rg&#xE5;ende omr&#xE5;den)

De f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade resultaten &#xE4;r i stort sett de samma som under p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende avtalsperiod.

Totalt ans&#xF6;ker KtK om 36 510 215 SEK f&#xF6;r verksamhet 2018. Det ans&#xF6;kta beloppet inneb&#xE4;r en &#xF6;kning om 6 569 103 SEK j&#xE4;mf&#xF6;rt med beviljat och avtalat belopp 2017, d.v.s. en &#xF6;kning p&#xE5; ca 22 procent.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Insamlingsstiftelsen Kvinna till Kvinna (KtK) has submitted an application for a one-year extension of its ongoing framework agreement 2015-2017. The extension application for 2018 is based on the application for 2015-2017 and focuses on changes and news. The expected impact of the programme is &#x201C;increased fulfilment of women&#x2019;s rights within the Women, Peace and Security agenda in conflict affected regions&#x201D;. The expected results are more or less the same as in the on-going agreement.

The programme is divided into four main thematic areas:
1. Women in Peacebuilding (WiP)
2. Gender Based Violence (GBV)
3. Advocacy
4. Sustainable women&#x2019;s rights organisations

The total amount applied for 2018 is 36 510 215 SEK. This is an increase by 6 569 103 SEK (equal to 22 percent) compared to the agreed amount 2017. In accordance with the guidelines for the CSO-appropriation the amount is divided into two categories.

The total budget for the programme 2018 is 40 266 410 SEK and this amount includes KtK&#x2019;s own contribution of 3 756 195 SEK amounting to 10 percent of the total operational costs. The grant to the administrative costs equals 8 percent of Sida&#x2019;s contribution to the operational costs. This is in accordance with the guidelines for the CSO-appropriation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the development intervention is: &quot;Kvinna till Kvinna&#xA0;and partner organisations together with targeted women have contributed to improved security and increased participation of women in conflict affected regions in the Middle East, South Caucasus, and the Western Balkans&quot;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kvinna till Kvinna</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kvinna till Kvinna</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="619" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Asia, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">453121.6115217159</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">233646.9350785952</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">453121.611521716</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">233646.9350785954</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">690294.33049</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-04-28">226560.805760858</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-10-28">226560.805760858</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-28">233646.9350785952</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kvinna till Kvinna (KtK) submitted the final report for the &quot;Women, Peace and Security Programme, 2015-2017&quot; on May 25, 2018. The report is KtK&apos;s first results report as framework organisation under the CSO-appropriation. It is the first time KtK makes a cross-regional analysis of results within its four thematic focus areas. Sida assesses that the report presents many results on an outcome level.
Regarding GBV and Peace Building, results are presented and analysed on individual, community and institutional level. KtK has also included sections about how they themselves have contributed to the achievement of results. The report reflects upon learnings and what can be developed further, and includes an analysis of what has not worked according to plan.
KtK has conducted two major evaluations during the reporting period that have provided important input to the results report:
- Keystone Evaluation of Partnership
- Process Evaluation of Kvinna till Kvinna&#x2019;s Women Peace and Security Programme, 2015-2017, January 2018
Below is an overview of the programme, including examples of results within the four different programme outcomes.
1. Gender Based Violence (GBV) 
Programme outcome 1: &#x201C;KtK and partner organisations have contributed to the prevention of and protection against GBV towards women.&#x201D;
A majority of KtK&#x2019;s partner organisations in the programme addresses GBV one way or the other. In total they give support to approximately 74 000 survivors of GBV every year (of which 90 percent are women and girls). The support provided is psychosocial support, legal support and counselling and reference to other organisations and institutions.
The results within the GBV-programme are presented under three interlinked levels; individual, community and institutional. KtK underlines that a country programme must cover all three levels but all partner organisations does not have to work on all levels.
Individual level
At individual level the support focuses on changing women&#x2019;s perception of themselves, strengthened self-esteem, increased possibilities to support themselves and progress within their court cases. Change can also be traced among targeted men.
Examples of results:
- The Women&#x2019;s Rights Centre in Armenia reports that they see increased self-esteem and self-confidence, awareness of their rights and abilities to claim rights among the women they support. The organisation&#x2019;s legal counselling hot-line have received and handled 462 calls for legal counselling during the reporting period. The counselling has resulted in 240 cases presented to court.
- In Erbil BWA provides psycho-social support to women and girls victims of GBV in three IDP (Internally Displaced People) camps outside the city. About 73 percent of the women and girls considered that the support had contributed to an improved life situation, strengthened self-esteem and a desire to change negative aspects of their lives. Five participating women have organised their own discussion groups and meeting for women in the IDP camps thus spreading the results to a wider group.
- In Palestine the partner organisation Aisha for Woman and Child Protection works to change attitudes and behaviour of men to become supportive of gender equality and contribute to the elimination of GBV against women and girls in Gaza. A core group of male ambassadors have reported changes in their view of what masculinity means, and how patriarchy affects not only women but also men negatively.
Community level
At community level the support focuses on changing the views of GBV from being a private matter, to being understood as a part of structural gender inequality. Reducing the stigmatization of GBV victims and challenging traditional and destructive norms of masculinity are also important focus areas.
Examples of results:
- Medica Kosova&#x2019;s work in awareness raising has contributed to less stigma for victims of sexual violence. The general public have started to see GBV and wartime sexual violence in a different way.
- In Palestine the partner organisation Aisha is engaging 75 men (ambassadors), from different occupations and social background. They have been trained in topics such as respectful confrontation, feminist interpretation of Islam, women&#x2019;s rights and CEDAW&#xA0;(Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination against Women) The ambassadors have become active in their local communities and circles of influence and have contributed to creating a more supportive environment for women and girls&apos; rights in their different spheres such as education, health, justice and within the community, including the religious sphere.
- Through developing contacts with the community police force, IDP camp managers, municipal councils, health centres and schools, BWA in Iraq has facilitated the creation of a referral system for victims of GBV. They have also contributed to an increased awareness among stakeholders about challenges and risks that school girls are facing.
Institutional level
At institutional level the programme strives to achieve results such as e.g. policy and legislative changes, monitoring of the implementation of laws and policies, and increased cooperation between different actors in society.
Examples of results:
- In Armenia the partner organisation Society Without Violence has successfully advocated for gender mainstreaming in the curricula for education of teachers. In cooperation with the Ministry of Education a handbook about gender equality has been adopted as educational material for social science teachers. Society Without Violence also cooperates with the National Institute of Education in the development of a training on how to integrate gender equality in education. A 51 percent increase in awareness among 76 participants has been reported so far. During the follow-up visit in Armenia May/June 2018 Sida met some of the teachers that had participated in the training. They confirmed that their awareness about gender equality had increased and that they had changed the way they perceived and treated their students. They also reported seeing behavioural changes among their students.
- In Bosnia-Herzegovina the advocacy work of Zenski Centar towards the Institute for Employment has resulted in that the institute co-finances employment and selfemployment of women victims of domestic violence. This is crucial for them to reach financial independence from their perpetrators. In the MENA-region the efforts to reach institutional change have resulted in increased networking within the women&#x2019;s movement. Through KtK&#x2019;s support organisations and networks learn from each others&apos; experiences.
Kvinna till Kvinna&#x2019;s additional contribution to results within GBV
Apart from the direct support to partners KtK highlights the following contributions to the results within GBV.
- Mapping of partners&#x2019; GBV work systematized through a baseline report and a follow up study. The work resulted in a policy on GBV and associated method material.
- An in-depth analysis of experiences and learning from the work of partners in Western Balkans that has been shared with the partners in other regions.
- Providing safe space for sharing experiences and facilitate networking within countries, between countries and between regions. This is important for learning, new perspectives and finding alternative strategies.
- Supporting networks and exchange across geographical and political boundaries is a way of breaking isolation and strengthening civil society arenas. The report presents several examples of concrete results of the networking meetings.
2. Peace Building
Programme outcome 2: &#x201C;KtK and partner organisations have improved women&#x2019;s participation in peace building initiatives.&#x201D;
Partner organisations engage to promote women&#x2019;s participation in two kinds of processes;
1) Community based peace building processes
2) Formal peace building processes
The majority of efforts focuses on the first of these. KtK&#x2019;s baseline assessment showed that peace building has been more in focus in the Western Balkans and South Caucasus than in the MENA region.
Individual level
In KtKs total programme portfolio approximately 15 076 individuals have been reached by partners&#x2019; peace building activities.
The operations can be divided into three main categories
1) Increase in confidence
KtK reports that partner organisations have contributed to targeted women to become change agents in their context, starting from the family, in safe women-only spaces and the broader community in all programme countries where POs were supported in peace building.
2) Women&#x2019;s leadership and peace building activism
An example of a result is Radio Women&#x2019;s Voice in Armenia that started as an initiative by two volunteers in the Women&#x2019;s Resource Center Armenia. It is now a 24-hour online radio channel with more than 15 200 listeners from all over Armenia and the diaspora. The channel broad castes events, local initiatives and interviews with women from&#xA0;different parts of the country. Sida had the opportunity to meet the volunteers during the follow-up visit in Armenia in May/June 2018.
Another example is the 25 round table discussions on reconciliation and UNSCR 1325 that the Palestinian Working Women Society for Development organized for young men and women in the West Bank. The participants report that they have the ability to break the silence and combat stereotypes of shame and fear to talk about their right to political participation and representation. A major outcome is the group of facilitators that include main stakeholders in the local advocacy planning.
3) Attitude changes in relation to peace building
An example of a result is the cooperation between Serbian, Albanian and Roma youth in Kosovo that has been achieved as part of the feminist festival FEMART organized by KtK&#x2019;s partner organization Artpolis.
Community level
Partner organisations have facilitated the development of community-based organizing platforms/fora which have contributed to organizing and seeking to influence community decision making processes. One example is the project implemented in cooperation between the organisations Horizonti from the Federation of BiH and Forum Zena from Republika Srpska aiming at integrating gender equality and peace building in relevant municipal policies. Through gathering young activists and women from six municipalities they have developed more trustful and normal relations and together they have managed to get peacebuilding strategies for youth introduced in relevant strategies at local level in several municipalities. Sida met these partner organisations and some of the young activists during the follow up visit in BiH in October 2017.
KtK&#x2019;s partners also work to
1) Increase acceptance for women&#x2019;s leadership in communities
2) Change the relationships to more collaborative relations across divides
An example of an organization working with the last point is the Iraqi Women&#x2019;s League. They have trained 108 university students in Baghdad, Babil and Dhi Qar on how to work for peace building. As a result, the students have formed contact groups through WhatsApp to keep in contact and support each other in the resistance to sectarian division. These groups will be followed to see the long-term effects.
Institutional/socio-political level
In KtK&#x2019;s baseline assessment 2016 17 out of 58 partner organisations reported having sought to influence formal peace building processes. Most partners tried to influence the development of National Action Plans for 1325. Constitutional reform was the second&#xA0;most common areas, while only a few partners tried to influence formal negotiations, transitional justice and national dialogue processes.
One successful example of an initiative to influence constitutional reform is the Initiative Women for Constitutional Changes in BiH coordinated by KtK&#x2019;s partner organisation Helsinki Citizen Assembly, that Sida met during the follow-up visit in BiH in October 2017. The initiative advocates for an engendered constitution within the ongoing reform process at the state level. This is done through a two-level approach, with advocacy work towards the state level, including the parliament and with mobilisation of the grass root level. The initiative has developed five priorities for the constitutional reform as well as suggestions for law text to include in a new constitution. The initiative has 35 CSO members, from both entities, and 450 individual supporters. The supporters include a pool of experts in constitutional law.
Kvinna till Kvinna&#x2019;s contribution to partners&#x2019; peace building work
KtK&#x2019;s support to partner organisations includes financial support, knowledge and skills development through trainings, workshops and networking and exchange meetings, technical support to advocacy initiatives regarding women&#x2019;s peace building participation, support to strategic development in peace building and documentation and learning. KtK also highlights the long term and strong partnerships as being extra important for peace building work.
3. Advocacy
Programme outcome 3: &#x201C;KtK and partner organisations have improved advocacy for development of adequate legislation on women&#x2019;s rights, and of monitoring of the implementation of legislation and relevant policies, in line with the Women, Peace and Security Agenda, CEDAW and other relevant international, regional and national instruments&#x201D;.
A baseline assessment was carried out in the beginning of the programme period. The identified needs regarding advocacy included financial support, capacity building, exchange and learning from other women organisations, support in constructing advocacy strategies and advocacy action plans and to move from ad-hoc towards strategic advocacy. This resulted in more focus on individual coaching and support to partner organisations. KtK has made a follow up assessment and reports e.g. the following results:
- Monitoring NAP on UNSCR 1325 in BiH. KtK has supported partner organisations in developing sustainable and effective mechanisms for continuous monitoring and implementation of the NAP 1325. After one of the trainings the advocacy activities for the adoption of the local action plans for the implementation of Resolution 1325 were initiated in 10 municipalities. Memorandums of cooperation with the mayors were signed and meetings were held with representatives of the legislative and executive authorities. Cooperation with women politicians was established, and they developed a methodology for monitoring the implementation of the NAP 1325 Action Plan in BiH and signed a platform for joint action
- An example of networking and joint advocacy can be found in MENA where women human rights defenders (WHRD) have formed the network WHRD-MENA Coalition with representatives from many countries in the MENA region. They have contributed to enhancing protection mechanisms for WHRDs in the MENA region as well as developed their capacities in the area of advocacy. The Coalition has launched a Data consortium and eight members have been using its register and documented incidents to access patterns of the violations against WHRD to serve as a basis for their advocacy.
- In the Western Balkans KtK has created a regional network for advocacy on gender mainstreaming in the EU accession process which has become a recognised counterpart for EU institutions in the accession process.
- In Iraq KtK reports that, through the support from KtK, Iraqi WHRD have obtained access to international fora for advocacy, particularly the EU and the UN, . One tangible example is that KtK&#x2019;s partners were invited to a separate meeting with the principal gender advisor of the European Untion External Action (EEAS) in connection to a civil society dialogue meeting in Brussels in 2017.
4. Sustainable Organisations
KtK&apos;s reporting in the area of sustainable organisations is extensive and is presented under the following headings:
- sustainable project management
- financial management and sustainability
- risk management
- sustainability and the contributions to women&apos;s movement
Although KtK do report many results, overall this section in the report is more focused on describing activities than the three other parts. Some examples of results follow below.
- The Regional Partnership Days in South Caucasus in 2017 had the purpose of contributing to strengthened capacity of all partners&apos; institutional and strategic capacity and to a pluralistic women&apos;s movement, especially considering that KtK is phasing out operations in the region. After the meeting partners reported having applied the knowledge and techniques gained in their own internal strategy and planning work. One partner organisation reported having acquired two new partners.
- KtK&apos;s approach Integrated Security is being used to support women human rights defenders to consider safety and well-being, to enable safe spaces and prevent burn out. Integrated Security Workshops have been held throughout the programme period. Partner organisations report that their organisations have developed in a sustainable and risk-aware way. An example is Palestine where partners report that Integrated Security has had an impact to enhance an open workplace, sustaining methods to decrease stress of the individual staff and to enable better services to the target group.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="54030520" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
