<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Sviluppo d&#x2019;impresa nelle filiere agroalimentari del caff&#xE8; e  dell&#x2019;ortofrutta in Ruanda per una crescita economica ed  occupazionale duratura, inclusiv</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">L&#x2019;obiettivo generale di questa Iniziativa triennale &#xE8; contribuire alla crescita economica duratura, inclusiva e 
sostenibile del Ruanda attraverso il supporto all&#x2019;implementazione delle politiche di sviluppo del Governo locale 
per le filiere agroalimentari in un&apos;ottica di sviluppo di impresa, contribuendo ad una occupazione piena e alla 
creazione di lavoro dignitoso.
L&#x2019;iniziativa insiste sulla crescita economica perch&#xE9; il Ruanda &#xE8; tra i Paesi meno avanzati (HDI di 160 nel 2020)
ma ad altissimo potenziale di crescita; in particolare, l&apos;agricoltura &#xE8; centrale per l&#x2019;economia, l&#x2019;occupazione e la 
riduzione della povert&#xE0; impiegando il 72% della popolazione con un contributo al 33% del PIL. Il Governo locale 
sostiene e punta alla crescita del settore grazie alla professionalizzazione e allo sviluppo di filiere agricole ad 
alto impatto e valore, e trainanti per l&#x2019;esportazione come quelle del caff&#xE8; e dell&#x2019;orticoltura, scelte 
dall&#x2019;Iniziativa in accordo con il Governo ed in linea con il lavoro del Soggetto Proponente e dei Partner e con 
le strategie dei principali donatori ed Agenzie internazionali.
Le due filiere sono particolarmente rilevanti: il caff&#xE8; occupa pi&#xF9; di 400.000 produttori e conta per il 43% 
dell&#x2019;export agricolo; l&#x2019;orticoltura occupa pi&#xF9; di 60.000 produttori ed &#xE8; il quarto settore pi&#xF9; importante fra 
quelli orientati all&#x2019;export. Il Governo ruandese punta sul caff&#xE8; per i grossi volumi e quindi aumentare le entrate 
e la circolazione di valuta estera, e punta sull&#x2019;orticoltura per migliorare la nutrizione, diminuire le importazioni, 
generare nuove occupazioni e contribuire alla diversificazione dell&#x2019;export.
L&#x2019;iniziativa ha quindi adottato come obiettivo specifico un aumento di fatturato, redditivit&#xE0; e occupazione per 
gli attori delle filiere del caff&#xE8; e dell&apos;orticoltura con una crescita economica inclusiva ad alto impatto sociale ed 
ambientale, con una partecipazione attiva di giovani e donne, e con un contrasto degli effetti negativi della 
pandemia. L&#x2019;intervento risponde ai bisogni identificati: 
- Aumento della produttivit&#xE0; e delle capacit&#xE0; di conservazione e trasformazione lungo la filiera,
introducendo l&#x2019;uso di buone pratiche agricole, le formazioni tecniche, l&#x2019;accesso a input, la fornitura di 
strumenti e tecnologie anche attraverso l&#x2019;intensificazione degli scambi commerciali con il nostro Paese 
per promuovere il Sistema Italia ed il Made in Italy nei settori della meccanizzazione ed irrigazione
- Aumento dell&#x2019;accesso al credito, migliorando le capacit&#xE0; di gestione e pianificazione finanziaria
attraverso formazione e accompagnamento personalizzato
- Rispetto di standard di qualit&#xE0; internazionali, migliorando la conoscenza e l&#x2019;allineamento alla domanda
dei mercati
- Coinvolgimento maggiore dei giovani in agricoltura e valorizzazione delle donne nei processi 
decisionali, con metodologie di coinvolgimento specifico e la formazione tecnica durante gli studi
- Riduzione degli effetti della pandemia, con una crescita che recuperi la riduzione delle entrate (-40%) 
e della forza lavoro (-60%).
I gruppi targetselezionatisono i produttori (pi&#xF9; di 18.000 persone, 27% giovani e 30% donne), aziende e ragazzi 
in percorsi di formazione professionale.
La logica di intervento si basa su 4 pilastri fondamentali:
1. Lo sviluppo d&#x2019;impresa, perch&#xE9; le filiere del caff&#xE8; e dell&#x2019;orticoltura sono rilevanti, trainanti e votate 
all&#x2019;esportazione per cui l&#x2019;Iniziativa vuole superare l&#x2019;ottica assistenzialista. Particolare rilevanza 
assumono gli strumenti della conoscenza del mercato e dell&#x2019;accesso al credito, senza i quali lo sviluppo 
d&#x2019;impresa e quindi la crescita economica ed occupazionale sono inibiti
2. L&#x2019;approccio &#x201C;pull&#x201D;, ovvero partire da imprese che hanno gi&#xE0; una domanda crescente di prodotti del 
mercato nazionale ed internazionale lavorando per soddisfarla, e non lavorare sulla produzione senza 
essere sicuri che ci sia domanda
3. La scelta di Partner strategici: rilevanti attori locali radicati &#x201C;sul campo&#x201D;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of this three-year Initiative is to contribute to Rwanda&apos;s sustained, inclusive and 
sustainable economic growth through supporting the implementation of the local Government&apos;s development 
policies for agribusiness supply chains from a business development perspective, contributing to full 
employment and decent work creation.
The Initiative insists on economic growth because Rwanda is among the least advanced countries (HDI of 160 
in 2020) but with very high growth potential; in particular, agriculture is central to the economy, employment 
and poverty reduction employing 72% of the population with a contribution to 33% of GDP. The local 
Government supports and aims at the growth of the sector thanks to the professionalization and development 
of high-impact, high-value and export-driven agricultural sectors such as coffee and horticulture, chosen by the Initiative in agreement with the Government and in line with the work of the Leader and Partners and 
the strategies of major donors and International Agencies.
The two sectors are particularly important: coffee employs more than 400,000 producers and accounts for 
43% of agricultural exports; horticulture employs more than 60,000 producers and is the fourth most 
important export-oriented sector. The Rwandan government is counting on coffee for large volumes and thus 
increasing incomes and the circulation of foreign currency, and is counting on horticulture to improve nutrition, 
decrease imports, generate employment and contribute to export diversification.
Therefore, the initiative has adopted as a specific objective an increase in turnover, profitability and 
employment for the actors of the coffee and horticulture supply chains with an inclusive economic growth with 
high social and environmental impact, with an active participation of youth and women, and with a contrast of 
the negative effects of the pandemic. 
The intervention addresses the identified needs of: 
- Increased productivity and capacity for conservation and processing along the supply chain, introducing 
the use of good agricultural practices, technical trainings, access to inputs, provision of tools and 
technologies also through the intensification of trade with our country to promote the &#x201C;Sistema Italia&#x201D;
and Made in Italy in the areas of mechanization and irrigation
- Increased access to credit, improving management skills and financial planning through training and 
personalized support
- Compliance with international quality standards, improving knowledge and alignment with market 
demand
- Greater involvement of young people in agriculture and enhancement of women&#x2019;s participation in 
decision-making processes, with specific methodologies and technical training during studies
- Reducing the effects of the pandemic, with a growth that makes up for the reduction in income (-40%) 
and workforce (-60%).
The selected target groups are producers (more than 18,000 people, 27% youth and 30% women), businesses, 
and youth in vocational training.
The intervention logic is based on 4 fundamental pillars:
1. Business development, because the coffee and horticulture sectors are important, pulling and export-oriented, so the Initiative wants to overcome the welfare perspective. Of particular importance are the 
tools of market knowledge and access to credit, without which business development and therefore 
economic growth and employment are inhibited
2. The &quot;pull&quot; approach, i.e. starting from companies that already have a growing demand for products on 
the national and international market and working to satisfy it, and not working on production without 
being sure that there is demand
3. The choice of strategic partners: relevant local actors rooted &quot;in the field&quot; (Kahawatu Foundation and 
Sina College), public bodies responsible for the implementation of agricultural policies, Italian industry 
associations</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ISTITUTO PER LA COOPERAZIONE UNIVERSITARIA ONLUS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/04/9" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="45" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="55" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Employment creation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, double the agricultural productivity and incomes of small-scale food producers, in particular women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers, including through secure and equal access to land, other productive resources and inputs, knowledge, financial services, markets and opportunities for value addition and non-farm employment</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure sustainable food production systems and implement resilient agricultural practices that increase productivity and production, that help maintain ecosystems, that strengthen capacity for adaptation to climate change, extreme weather, drought, flooding and other disasters and that progressively improve land and soil quality</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote development-oriented policies that support productive activities, decent job creation, entrepreneurship, creativity and innovation, and encourage the formalization and growth of micro-, small- and medium-sized enterprises, including through access to financial services</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote sustained, inclusive and sustainable economic growth, full and productive employment and decent work for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-08">1800000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ISTITUTO PER LA COOPERAZIONE UNIVERSITARIA ONLUS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-17">1080000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ISTITUTO PER LA COOPERAZIONE UNIVERSITARIA ONLUS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
