<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="82" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/18841" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-WH-MZ-13-18841</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cattle Development Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the World Food Program, one third of Mozambique&#x2019;s population is chronically food-insecure, and half a million of the country&#x2019;s children aged 6-23 months are undernourished. 


The UN&#x2019;s Food and Agriculture Organization reports the principal form of livestock in Mozambique is cattle, which are raised traditionally on natural pastures. However, in contrast, Mozambique has one of the lowest cattle populations in Africa and not nearly enough cows to supply the country&#x2019;s needs. 


World Hope International&#x2019;s Cattle Development Program creates a way for the rural poor to build assets in the form of cattle. The cattle, which can be used for plowing, milk, food security, or income, are helping farming families escape the cycle of poverty in Mozambique. Cattle are distributed amongst families, and owners are educated on animal husbandry. Once the cattle give birth, a certain number of offspring are passed on to another family in the community, creating a sustainable cycle.


Cattle Cluster Project: With support from Food Resources Bank, World Hope International&#x2019;s Cattle Cluster Program aims to increase cattle production, helping farming families in Mozambique become more food secure. Most importantly, the Cattle Cluster Program offers poor farmers a hand up, not a hand out since each recipient repays what he or she received while encouraging Mozambicans to also help their neighbors. 


WHI provides heifers to family groups which can be used for plowing, milk, food security, or income. In return, the new cow owner must agree to give two of the heifer&#x2019;s offspring to a neighbor or family member. Through this process, cattle multiplication continues and program staff holds groups accountable to meet their obligations of giving offspring to help others. Agreements are made on paper and before witnesses in the community so that recipients feel a strong sense of obligation. To-date, ninety percent of family groups who received a cow have passed on offspring to a waiting family.


Once a group passes on offspring to form another cluster, families may choose to sell its cows or keep them for further multiplication. With this flexibility, many families now have plows and bulls that enable them to expand their farm size and to plow for hire. In addition, famers highly value the security of having some savings in the form of livestock and only sell a cow in times of exceptional need.


Since the project began in 2003, more than 2500 cows and been distributed to poor families desiring to herd cattle.


Village Vet Training: The increase in cattle production comes with an increased need for veterinary care. Veterinary care can help to improve livestock production and contaminate the spread of disease. To address this, WHI helps to facilitate five-day training courses for new cow owners. The courses are taught by government veterinarians and include three days of classroom learning followed by two days of hands on training. The participants are also trained in prevention and treatment of common diseases for sheep, goats, pigs, and cattle.


The Village Vets become a valuable resource in their community and are increasingly utilized by government veterinarians to coordinate vaccination campaigns, which play an important role in keeping all cattle and animals in the area healthy. To date, 168 Village Vets have been trained.


Garden-Cattle Integration Project: Community vegetable gardens are another major focus of the World Hope International Cattle Cluster project. The new four year project combines the assets of cow manure with WHI drilled wells to create small-scale sustainable vegetable production. While the cattle have a long term food security impact, vegetable gardens complement the program with short-term increased food and nutrition.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1985485" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Hope International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="WH-MZ-13-18841" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Hope International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.worldhope.org</website>
   <website>https://www.worldhope.org/agriculture/gro-project</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_1046058">
   <location-id code="1046058" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza, Mozambique (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="1046058" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-23.5 33.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.worldhope.org/agriculture/gro-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
