<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="82" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/22485" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-73-22485</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Konsae Pilot Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Mondul Kiri Province of Cambodia is home to a vulnerable, indigenous population known as the Bunong people.

In 2016, WHI has conducted an initial assessment and met with various local authorities, community members, school teachers, and relevant stakeholders to get to know one of the villages there and understand the people&#x2019;s situation. This initial assessment also helped build a relationship providing WHI perspective and understanding of the Bunong indigenous people&#x2019;s group and their aspiration for the future.

Issues identified included high drop-out and high repetition rates of students in and poor school learning environments. Additionally, the community faced strong gender disparity as well as alcohol abuse and domestic violence. In Cambodia as a whole, four to six percent of boys and girls in Cambodia alike have experienced sex abuse before the age of 18&#x2013; there is an average 12 percent teenage pregnancy rate, with Mondul Kiri Province having the highest, at 34 percent.

The enhancement of quality of primary education and the strengthening of community involvement for improved school performance and standards monitoring is one of the key priorities of the Royal Government of Cambodia in its Education Sector Development Program (ESDP III, the Program). Not only was Mondulkiri identified as one of the priority provinces of the ESDP III, but World Hope believes that part of the solution for successful economic development in this community is through education. 

That is why World Hope has implemented the Project &#x201C;Konsae&#x201D; pilot; a two school-year project which aims to enhance the quality of primary education and the strengthening of community involvement for improved school performance and, hopefully, a project which will empower the community as a whole.

The project includes a feeding program, a child protection and health education aspect, English as a Second Language learning opportunities, regular community meetings, and capacity building of the School Support Committee, Women&#x2019;s Group, and the Indigenous Community Committee.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1985485" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Hope International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="73-22485" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Hope International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.worldhope.org</website>
   <website>https://www.worldhope.org/project/project-konsae/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_1830306">
   <location-id code="1830306" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mondolkiri</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mondolkiri, Cambodia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="1830306" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.75 107.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="5" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.worldhope.org/project/project-konsae/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
