<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="82" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/18843" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-WH-SL-12-18843</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pineapples and Papayas Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">During Sierra Leone&#x2019;s wet season from May through September, also known as the &#x201C;hunger months,&#x201D; Sierra Leonean farming families living on less than $1 a day can typically only afford to eat one meal a day &#x2013; if they&#x2019;re fortunate. World Hope International&#x2019;s pineapples and papayas program brings welcome relief to many farming families in Sierra Leone, year-round. Historically grown in small quantities and contained to household backyards, pineapples and papayas in Sierra Leone have provided limited food and income for farming families. Now, thanks to World Hope International, the fruits are rapidly multiplying across Sierra Leone&#x2019;s countryside, preventing poverty along the way. 


WHI supports pineapple and papaya farming cooperatives in Sierra Leone by providing smallholder farmers with agricultural inputs, extensive training and support by connecting farmers to suppliers and markets during a 1-2 year partnership with the farming cooperative. The training helps to ensure the project is self-sustaining. Farmers prepare the land, plant the fruit and attend to them until harvest, a process typically lasting 12-15 months. 


In addition, WHI helps to connect farmers to commercial markets and suppliers, both within their communities and through an international supply chain to export their goods, create profit, and improve their livelihoods. Because pineapples and papayas can be harvested year-round and demand high market prices, large-scale farming is attractive to nearly all Sierra Leonean farmers. The poorest farming families, however, lack the capital to invest in the resources required for planting. WHI bridges this gap by providing the initial inputs necessary to get farmers started, including the cost of training, agricultural inputs, irrigation and machinery. Over the course of the program and the through the profits farmers receive from their harvest, farmers gain the means to invest resources back into their farm.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1985485" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Hope International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="WH-SL-12-18843" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Hope International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.worldhope.org</website>
   <website>http://www.worldhope.org/agriculture/pineapples-project</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.worldhope.org/agriculture/pineapples-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
