<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="COP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="ES" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>CO-RUE-830053223-110454</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="CO-RUE-830053223" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="ES">Liga Internacional de Mujeres por la Paz y la Libertad</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="ES">Women Advocate for Peace (Women, Peace and Security in Colombia)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="ES">Result Area 1: Peace process
The peace process has several mechanisms and spaces created at the territorial level to
facilitate its implementation. The Peace Accord can only be implemented and contribute to
the sustainable development of territories when considering the needs, demands, and
proposals of solutions from women and their organizations. By training women and women&#x2019;s
organizations, they will be able to do Lobbying and Advocacy (L&amp;A) in order for them to

participate in decision-making and achieve the acceptance of their proposals by policy-
makers. This will contribute to strengthening the mechanisms created for the

institutionalization of peace with gender justice in order for the State to comply with the 51
gender indicators set out in the Peace Accord.
Result Area 2: Accompaniment and Protection
The internal armed conflict exacerbated unequal gender relations, racism and violence
against women and girls. Survivors often have profound psychological, physical and
emotional damage without the State, society and communities being aware of the magnitude
of the problem and being able to help eradicate GBV. Against this background we support
women human rights defenders and their organizations, who find themselves isolated and
unprotected in the face of attacks by different armed actors, to strategize and start
participating in relevant decision-making spaces where they can influence the State to
implement laws and regulations related to violence against women and carry out effective
measures against GBV in the territories, including access to survivor-centred care.
Service Delivery Component: GBV survivors have limited access to care services to deal
with the psychosocial consequences of the conflict. When authorities implement legislation
for protecting GBV survivors and women, and offer appropriate services, women are less
vulnerable to psychosocial harm and can participate more actively in social and political life.
Provision of psychosocial support will take place through the establishment of peer-to-peer
support groups (cf. IASC Reference Group on MHPSS). Stakeholders and community
gatekeepers will be sensitized to promote and build inclusive community-based MHPSS
support the evidence collected from the interventions will build the basis to support
mechanisms that promote gender and social inclusion.
Result Area 3: Women&#x2019;s empowerment
In order to lift local women out of poverty and unequal power relations, both in their family
and within their communities, we will train them in sustainable livelihoods, while at the same
time raise awareness in their families on positive masculinities. Ensuring a sustainable
livelihood within a supportive family environment where care work is equitably distributed
will enable women to claim their rights, such as land rights and the right to participate in
community life. Through sustained advocacy, women will be recognized as key political
actors within their territories.

Our ToC intervenes directly in complex and diverse civic spaces in which a wide range of
actors operate which are directly linked (either positively or negatively) to the development
and change processes to which we aspire to contribute. Annex VII details the actors with
whom the Programme will interact, using the classification established by the MoFA: public
sector institutions, knowledge institutions, NGOs, thought leaders, and clients/citizens. We
have added a new category to be able to include bilateral and multilateral entities, such as
the European Union or the United Nations system.
The most important actors are the women and their organizations in the six target
departments.

4.1. Women in the Programme areas

In the adverse contexts of the territories where the Programme will work, women have
become more organized and have consolidated their organizations as key actors in the
peace process and the defence of human rights (mainly women&#x2019;s and victims&#x2019; rights). They
are leading processes for children&#x2019;s education in the communities, capacity development
and training of women, and fundraising for emergency situations and for productive projects.
The women&#x2019;s movement in these departments, as in the rest of the country, is a broad and
diverse movement in which collectives of young women, LGBTQI+ individuals, and disability
organizations come together to fight for the inclusion of their demands in the broader agenda
of the inclusive women&#x2019;s movement.
In their role as leaders, many of these women have suffered socio-political and
sociodemographic violence. The overwhelming majority have been victims of GBV and of
violence as a consequence of the armed conflict. They demand increased governmental attention, primarily through their organizations and social movements for peace. Organized
women see themselves more and more affirmed as political heavyweights. They are
organizing actions and demanding that their rights be respected even in the midst of the
conflict. They also continue to call for guarantees for their full participation in all the decisions
relating to women&#x2019;s development and peace. As part of their responsibilities as leaders, the
women from the six departments deal with public institutions through spaces and
mechanisms such as working groups where the government and civil society participate to
monitor public policies and laws. They also participate in the state agencies in charge of
implementing the Peace Accord, such as municipal councils, peace departments, and
planning councils.

The women in the six regions where the Programme will work share the following
characteristics:
&#x25CF; The majority is from rural areas (approximately 60%) though a significant percentage of
them live in urban areas (approximately 40%). Most of them are the primary household
earners with substantial domestic and care work responsibilities besides their activism
and leadership work. Many of them live in a domestic partnership without marriage. This
is a vulnerability factor because of the often-low stability of these relationships, leaving
women to take responsibility for the household income and childcare alone. Many of the
women have limited access to knowledge and technology, work options, political
participation, recreation, and possibilities of expression.
&#x25CF; The age range is very broad, with women from eighteen to eighty years. They mostly
have a low level of formal education although there are also some that graduated high
school and continued to college. Most of the women have informal jobs or work in the
fields, and there is a tendency to focus on productive projects to address their precarious
economic situation. A significant percentage of women are artisans.
&#x25CF; They are generally religious, mostly Catholic or Evangelical Christian. For many women
religion allows them to process the physical, mental, and emotional effects of the armed
conflict; it is where they find refuge, given the lack of psychosocial attention provided by
the government. In the case of indigenous and Afro-descendent communities, their own
autochthonous worldviews prevail.
&#x25CF; All the regions are ethnically diverse, with the presence of Afro-Colombian, indigenous,
and mestiza populations.18 Indigenous and Afro-descendent women suffer triple
discrimination for being women, impoverished, and indigenous. They are also the
population group that is most affected by the structural violence in the country. In
departments with relatively large indigenous and Afro-Colombian populations, such as
Bol&#xED;var and La Guajira, women are victims of forced displacement, many have been
victims of sexual violence, and they are organized into collectives for the defence of their
land, human rights, and economic autonomy.
&#x25CF; As indicated in the section on COVID-19, the economic situation in these areas is
serious, as the public health crisis has exacerbated structural inequalities, especially
those affecting women and girls. Obligatory isolation has been imposed on families living
in precarious conditions, both in more populated and rural areas, where most of the population earns a living from the informal economy, with high and rising levels of
inequality. Because of their precarious situation, the women have to leave the house in
search of their daily sustenance in spite of the quarantine measures decreed by the
government, endangering their health.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The strategic objective of Women Advocate for Peace is to contribute to a lasting peace
process with gender justice in Colombia in which women and girls have the same rights and
opportunities as men and boys. This requires the creation of favourable conditions to
strengthen the participation, influence, and leadership of women and their organizations in
peacebuilding spaces at the local, territorial, and national levels.
Our Theory of Change describes three mutually interrelated thematic pillars/ result areas: 1.
Peace process; 2. Accompaniment and protection; and 3. Women&#x2019;s empowerment. These
are aligned with all three sub-objectives of the WPS grant instrument. The fulfilment of the
gender indicators established by the Peace Accord will influence the application and
adoption of gender-based measures to protect women, including psychosocial attention.
Compliance with the gender measures established by the Peace Accord is a determining
factor for a sustainable and inclusive peace process. By accompanying women and their organizations, they will become stronger, increase their resilience, and be able to participate
in political spaces to ensure the application and monitoring of the current laws governing
gender (including the WPS agenda and SDG-5) at the national as well as departmental and
municipal levels. Finally, encouraging their economic autonomy and a more equitable
redistribution of chores in the family context will facilitate their empowerment, the
development of their political role, and their fundamental contribution to development and
peace in Colombia.

Our ToC is guided by a series of general assumptions:
&#x25CF; There is stability and space for CSOs to function;
&#x25CF; The CSOs meet the minimal requirements for increasing mobilization and taking
advantage of existing strengths;
&#x25CF; The government and state institutions are willing to cooperate;
&#x25CF; Raising awareness about positive masculinities leads to changes in behaviour;
&#x25CF; Once women are trained in advocacy they will assume leadership roles;
&#x25CF; The participation of women and civil society organizations in decision-making spaces
influences the decisions of stakeholders;
&#x25CF; Women&#x2019;s proposals at the local level are crucial to influence those in charge of
developing policies, with the objective of improving access to services and creating
policies that take gender-related issues into account;
&#x25CF; Change agents within communities can play a crucial role in changing unequal power
relations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This programme has been elaborated by a consortium consisting of three Colombian
organizations&#x2014;Ruta Pac&#xED;fica de la Mujeres, Liga Internacional de Mujeres por la Paz y la
Libertad (LIMPAL) and Corporaci&#xF3;n de Apoyo a Comunidades Populares (CODACOP)&#x2014;
and two Dutch ones&#x2014;ICCO and HealthNet TPO&#x2014;. By letter of 29 May 2020, the Dutch
Ministry of Foreign Affairs (MoFA) informed the consortium that its proposal has been
selected for a strategic partnership within the scope of the grant instrument Women, Peace
and Security. In its letter of 30 June 2020, MoFA informed the consortium that the maximum
grant is EUR 4.989.660 for the period 1 January 2021 until 31 December 2025. This amount
will be provided under the condition that:
1. In the strategic partnership a programme will be established in consultation with the
consortium partners, local partners, and the MoFA;
2. The programme satisfies sufficiently the qualitative criteria for the programme
proposal set by the MoFA; and
3. This programme underpins this amount.
Below we present the full proposal for the programme which has been developed
collaboratively by all consortium members. Local organizations in the 6 target departments
as well as the MoFA and the Dutch Embassy in Bogot&#xE1; were consulted. Annex I Table of
fulfilment with the requirements established by the MoFA, detailing how the programme
addresses each of the criteria of the MoFA.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-56484038-110454" ref="NL-KVK-56484038" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICCO Cooperation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="CO-RUE-830053223-110454" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="CO-RUE-830053223" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="ES">Liga Internacional de Mujeres por la Paz y la Libertad</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="CO-RUE-830053223-110454" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="CO-RUE-830053223" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="ES">Liga Internacional de Mujeres por la Paz y la Libertad</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="ES"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="ES"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="ES"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="ES"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="ES">Natalia Chaves Monroy</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="ES">Programme Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>573212428500</telephone>
   <email>programawps@limpalcolombia.org</email>
   <website>https://www.limpalcolombia.org/es/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="ES">programawps@limpalcolombia.org</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="ES">Claudia Albarrac&#xED;n</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="ES">Evaluation follow-up and monitoring professional</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>573205619892</telephone>
   <email>proyectos@limpalcolombia.org</email>
   <website>https://www.limpalcolombia.org/es/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="ES">proyectos@limpalcolombia.org</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="ES"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="ES"></narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="ES">Bol&#xED;var y Meta</narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="12340" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15164" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="ES"></narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">144765</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-01">226391</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2023-01-01">214262</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2024-01-01">196762</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2025-01-01">141759</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="5- year programme commitment">
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">923939</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global amount for the program</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-56484038-110454" ref="NL-KVK-56484038" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="CO-RUE-830053223-110454" ref="CO-RUE-830053223" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="ES"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3rd Installment">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-18">50667.75</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-56484038-110454" ref="NL-KVK-56484038" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="CO-RUE-830053223-110454" ref="CO-RUE-830053223" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="ES"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="4th Installment">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-16">21714.75</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-56484038-110454" ref="NL-KVK-56484038" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="CO-RUE-830053223-110454" ref="CO-RUE-830053223" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="ES"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1st Installment">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-05">28953</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-56484038-110454" ref="NL-KVK-56484038" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="CO-RUE-830053223-110454" ref="CO-RUE-830053223" type="22"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2nd Installment">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-05">36191.25</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-56484038-110454" ref="NL-KVK-56484038" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="CO-RUE-830053223-110454" ref="CO-RUE-830053223" type="22"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Expenditures 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">110877</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Expenditures 1st trimester 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-31">7437</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Expenditures 2nd trimester 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-30">16656</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Expenditures 3rd trimester 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-30">29424</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Expenditures 4th trimester 2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">57360</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Expenditures 1st trimester 2022">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-31">41390</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="CO-RUE-830053223-110454" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-56484038-110454" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="ES">Strengthened capacity of women, women&apos;s rights organizations, CSO&apos;s, government &amp; private sector to enhance women&apos;s rights, empowerment and gender equality</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2.2 # of individuals with strengthened capacity (knowledge and skills) to advance women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality (disaggregated by type, age and gender).</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The indicator # of women and men that are trained and supported by the Programmeis linked to the indicator WRGE indicator 5.2.2 # of individuals with strengthened capacity (knowledge and skills) to advance women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="WRG049Y" indicator-uri="https://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SCS-IATI-indicator-guidelines-SRHR-updated.pdf?msclkid=826d4bc3a5d411ec950d1b0ac9308486" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-12-31" value="10" year="2020">
     <location ref="Colombia"></location>
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="ES"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="33">
      <location ref="Colombia"></location>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <location ref="N/A"></location>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the year 2021, no progress is reported in the indicator, since there was no progress in the activities that report to this indicator.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2.2 # of individuals with strengthened capacity (knowledge and skills) to advance women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality (disaggregated by type, age and gender).</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The indicator # of women and men that are trained and supported by the Programmeis linked to the indicator WRGE indicator 5.2.2 # of individuals with strengthened capacity (knowledge and skills) to advance women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="WRG050" indicator-uri="https://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SCS-IATI-indicator-guidelines-SRHR-updated.pdf?msclkid=826d4bc3a5d411ec950d1b0ac9308486" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-12-31" value="11" year="2020">
     <location ref="Colombia"></location>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60">
      <location ref="Colombia"></location>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <location ref="N/A"></location>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ES">For the year 2021, no progress is reported in the indicator, since there was no progress in the activities that report to this indicator.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">WRGE indicator 5.2.2 # of individuals with strengthened capacity (knowledge and skills) to advance women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The indicator # of women and men that are trained and supported by the Programmeis linked to the indicator WRGE indicator 5.2.2 # of individuals with strengthened capacity (knowledge and skills) to advance women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="WRG049NY" indicator-uri="https://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SCS-IATI-indicator-guidelines-SRHR-updated.pdf?msclkid=826d4bc3a5d411ec950d1b0ac9308486" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-12-31" value="86" year="2020">
     <location ref="Colombia"></location>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="97">
      <location ref="Colombia"></location>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <location ref="N/A"></location>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ES">For the year 2021, no progress is reported in the indicator, since there was no progress in the activities that report to this indicator.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
