<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5100002603-AFC-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Bank, 2009 - 2017, Transitional Demobilization &amp; Reintegration Program II</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">World Bank, 2009 - 2017, Transitional Demobilization &amp; Reintegration Program II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">TDRP &#xE4;r en efterf&#xF6;ljare till V&#xE4;rldsbankens demobilseringsprogram i Stora Sj&#xF6;regionen, MDRP, som &#xE4;gde rum 2002-2009, och som Sverige var med och finansierade med sammanlagt 60 MSEK. TDRP har vidareutvecklats i samr&#xE5;d med olika partners varibland Sverige varit mycket aktiv i dialogen i syfte att ta tillvara MDRPs erfarenheter och &quot;lessons learned&quot; och bidra till att f&#xE5; en st&#xF6;rre regional ansats. Programmet syftar till att st&#xF6;dja D&amp;R aktiviteter b&#xE5;de nationellt men ocks&#xE5; regionalt. Sverige har hittills bidragit till TDRP med 15 MSEK. Mot bakgrund av den s&#xE4;kerhetspolitiska situationen i regionen och n&#xE4;rliggande regioner har programmet f&#xF6;rl&#xE4;ngts och delvis expanderat i och med att dess tj&#xE4;nster inom omr&#xE5;det har efterfr&#xE5;gats av nya akt&#xF6;rer. Ytterligare medel beh&#xF6;ver d&#xE5; tillf&#xF6;ras och Sverige har tillfr&#xE5;gats om att bidra med 10 MSEK. Hittills uppg&#xE5;r programmets totala budget 2010-2014 till 33.7 MUSD. AfDB, Sverige, Finland, Norge, Kanada och Italien st&#xF6;djer programmet.

TDRP is the successor to the World Bank&apos;s D&amp;R program in the Great Lakes region, MDRP, which took place in 2002-2009, and that Sweden was co-funding with a total of 60 MSEK. TDRP has been developed in consultation with partners, among which Sweden has been very active in the dialogue in order to take advantage of MDRP&apos;s experiences and &quot;lessons learned&quot; in order to contribute to a wider regional approach. The program aims to support D &amp; R activities both nationally but also regionally. Sweden has so far contributed to TDRP with 15 MSEK. In light of the security situation in the region and neighboring regions, the program has been extended and partially expanded, in that its services in the field have called for new stakeholders. Additional funds will then be needed and Sweden has been requested to contribute 10 MSEK. So far, the total program budget 2010-2014 amounts to 33.7 MUSD. AfDB, Sweden, Finland, Norway, Canada and Italy support the program.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Transitional Demobilization and Reintegration Program (TDRP) is a regional programme financed by a multidonor
trust fund (African Development Bank (AfDB), Belgium, Finland, France, Germany, Italy, Norway and Sweden) aiming to enhance the prospects for stabilization and recovery in the Great Lakes Region, GLR, by supporting demobilization and reintegration (D&amp;R) and related activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Transitional Demobilization and Reintegration Program (TDRP) is a regional program financed by a multi-donor trust fund (African Development Bank (AfDB), Belgium, Finland, France, Germany, Italy, Norway and Sweden) aiming to enhance the prospects for stabilization and recovery in the Great Lakes region by supporting demobilization and reintegration (D&amp;R) and related activities.
The TDRP aims to support the Disarmament &amp; Reintegration (D&amp;R) of ex-combatants and related activities in the Great Lakes region of Africa. The ultimate strategic objective of these activities is to enhance the prospects for stabilization and recovery in the GLR.
Specific program objectives are:
a. To support the successful implementation of existing D&amp;R programs in the region through the provision of financial and technical support;
b. To expand D&amp;R programming coverage by providing emergency response financing for new or ongoing D&amp;R operations where funding gaps have been identified and the Government concerned has requested assistance; and
c. To facilitate a platform for dialogue, information exchange and learning on D&amp;R in the sub-region with a view to addressing the regional aspects of conflict, improving the quality of on-going D&amp;R efforts, reducing duplication of efforts across the GLR, strengthening coordination on D&amp;R policy and programming, and generating policy advice for future programs.
d. Enhance the capacity of African leadership to respond to (DDR) needs through operational, technical, and knowledge managemnet capacity building</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="1028" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">-19684.0191475651</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-28">-19684.0191475651</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TDRP has demonstrated positive results across all areas of the programme, including progress on enhancing institutional and organizational capacity of the African Union (AU) through the AU Disarmament, Demobilization and Reintegration (DDR) Capacity Program, and through other activities, the program has positively affected lives of over 200,000 ex-combatants.&#xA0;
TDRP has been relevant to the needs of&#xA0;the countries supported&#xA0;as well as to donor priorities and the broader work of the World Bank in fragile countries and states. In particular, the Technical Assistance of TDRP has been suited to the needs of national commissions as the assistance delivered has met the needs identified by national commissions. It also provided some standardized approaches to Monitoring and Evaluation and Management Information Systems in the Great Lakes Region. Additionally, TDRP&#x2019;s work has successfully contributed to the Research, Knowledge and Learning objective of the World Bank and donor expectations.&#xA0;
It has been noted in the TDRP donor committee meetings that the TDRP implementation period (2009-2017) has seen growing recognition that DDR activities are just one of many elements required for successful peace and stabilization process, and that they are associated in multifaceted ways to peace negotiations, to justice and security sector reform, and both peace-building and state-building. This is particularly important in contexts in which an increasing number of DDR activities take place outside a formal peace process, and in many cases, occur in contexts in which there is no legitimate government - or a government with severe capacity constraints. This reinforces the role of DDR as one of a larger nexus of activities within the broader peace building and stabilization context.&#xA0;
It should be noted that whilst all results showcased in the completion memo are associated with the TDRP portfolio, not all the deliverable or outputs were directly funded by the TDRP trust fund.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51000026" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061603" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="4725000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional Africa 2016-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt Afrika 2016-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
