<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-18/3485/RA3/Shelter-WASH/INGO/10139</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Shelter and WASH assistance to displacement affected population in Bari and Sool  regions.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is an integrated response that is framed around four sector areas, Shelter, WASH, Camp Coordination and Camp Management (CCCM) and Protection. Shelter and WASH activities will be implemented by NRC while CCCM and Protection activities will be carried out by  Danish Refugee Council (DRC) targeting the same locations and beneficiaries in Bari and Sool regions.A pre-teaming agreement has been uploaded/attached to this proposal providing further details on the approach and rationale of the collaboration. In essence, the multi-cluster, multi-sector and multi-agency approach, will maximize assistance as different sectors and actors will be able to share critical information and inform immediate programming and re-design of programs. This approach will be useful to create synergies enabling the concentration of services and expertise within the same location and same population leading to achieving a greater impact. The interventions will support the targeted communities holistically and efficiently by providing well-tailored and packaged responses in order to address different needs of the people of concern. The integrated response is in line with SHF principles by prioritization direct implementation and supporting integration of response across clusters. 

This project is designed to mitigate physical and protection consequences of drought on populations and communities directly affected in Bari and Sool regions. This overarching objective will be achieved by enhancing the overall protective environment for drought-affected population, increasing access to basic services linked to Shelter, CCCM and WASH and Protection. The integrated response will provide specialized support assistance to beneficiaries to help them address other interconnected protection concerns. The action is also conceptualized to consolidate the ongoing humanitarian response to the drought situation in the targeted locations. Through this grant, NRC will reach 6,733 HHs (40,400 individuals, 50% females) in the two regions with services and assistance in Shelter and WASH sectors. DRC will target the same beneficiaries through CCCM and Protection interventions to have an integrated and area- based approach with the maximum impact of the intervention. 

This project will be implemented in Eight (8) most vulnerable settlements of Bari and Sool regions, namely Bander Bayle, Hafun, Caluula, Bandar Bayle, Bareda, Habo, Bocame and Lascanood. The project is designed to meet the needs of 80% IDPs and 20% host communities of the total beneficiaries targeted. NRC will select Extremely Vulnerable Individuals (EVIs) through predetermined beneficiary selection criteria. Gender will be mainstreamed into the project through the specific consideration of the different needs of women, men, boys and girls during the design of activities. Assistance will prioritize female-headed households, and households with pregnant or lactating women. The project will ensure that all participants have equal access to resources and training. The project will will be guided by the IASC handbook gender checklist. Monitoring and evaluation will be based on gender, age and diversity dis aggregated data. 

Through Shelter interventions, NRC main activities will be the distribution of 3,500 NFIs through cash, construction of 300 Emergency Shelter Kits (ESKs), distribution of 300 solar lamps (same Shelter HHs) followed by Post Distribution Monitoring (PDM) exercises. Through WASH interventions, NRC main activities will be the rehabilitation and desludging of 100 latrines, distribution of 500 Hygiene kits, rehabilitation of 2 shallow wells, rehabilitation of 2 pipe line networks//distribution systems, rehabilitation of 40 water berkads coupled with 4 hygiene promotion campaigns.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-03" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-03" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Barnabas Asora</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programme</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254790205708</telephone>
   <email>barnabas.asora@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Victor Moses</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254702296001</telephone>
   <email>victor.moses@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9663">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bari</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.64800000 50.23200000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="9675">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sool</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.72400000 47.52900000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-09-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-14">324175.93</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-03"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-14">675824.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-10139">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-14">1000000.33</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303559705">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-20">800000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304304064">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-06">200000.33</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
