<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-18/3485/SA2/Nut/NGO/11057</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prevention and treatment of acute Malnourished children under five years of age, pregnant and lactating women through Outpatient Therapeutic feeding Programme with stabilization center services to avert nutrition-related morbidity and mortality in Balcad, Cadale and Mahaday districts, Middle shabelle region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is designed to provide emergency and lifesaving nutrition services to 21984 vulnerable persons (3936 men, 5204 women, 5474 boys and 7370 girls) living in Balcad, cadale and Mahaday districts of Middle Shabelle. The intervention will target pregnant and lactating women (PLW) together with children under the age of 5 years (CU5) amongst the host communities, IDPs and returnees in the Balcad district where Wocca is the primary rationalized partner in Adale where we are the secondary rationalized partner and also extend our services to Mahaday.  Wocca will operate 2 fixed/static outpatient therapeutic feeding centers (fixed OTPs) and 4 mobile outpatient therapeutic feeding programme teams (mobile OTPs) targeting 16 locations chosen on the basis of vulnerability and absence of nutrition interventions in the 3 districts. The static facilities will be established in Ceelow and Caddow Uul locations  and Cadale districts respectively while the 4 outreach teams will serve 14 locations namely Bulo Axmed Cigow, Kulmis Weyn, Buurfuule and Xudur Ciise in Mahaday Ceelka Cusub, Cisiley and Sheikh Rooble Garas weyne, Cadan gabey and Ceel Xamar in Cadale Xanlay, Muki dheere Bari, Bulo Walaal and Caro faag in Balcad. WOCCA has engaged UNICEF for backstopping during training of the project staff, community health workers (CHWs) and mothers for the &#x201C;mothers MUAC approach&#x201D;, on nutrition screening and case identification, Integrated management of acute malnutrition(IMAM),Infant and young child feeding education (IYCF-E) and Nutrition, health and hygiene promotion (NHHP).The trained staff shall be deployed to the targeted locations, mobile and static OTPs where together with the trained mothers will screen children under 5 and PLWs. Children under 5 with severe acute malnutrition (SAM) conditions and no medical complications will be enrolled to the static and mobile OTPs for treatment while the cases with medical complications will be referred by the mobile clinics and CHWs to the stabilization center (SC) in Waberi star village managed by WOCCA for nutrition and medical rehabilitation. Children under 5 and PLWs with MAM conditions will be referred to TSFP center managed by ARC. CHWs and Hygiene promoters will be trained on Nutrition, Health and Hygiene Promotion (NHHP), they will disseminate hygiene promotion messages to the communities to prevent outbreak and spread of communicable diseases like AWD/cholera during the activities as they move around with the mobile Team. Mothers will be counseled individually and in groups by trained nutrition staff and Community Health Workers (CHWs) on appropriate maternal infant and young child feeding as part of efforts to prevent malnutrition. The project will also provide micronutrient support by distributing multiple micronutrients (MNPs) and Vitamin A supplements to pregnant and lactating women and children under the age of 5years through the static and mobile facilities. UNICEF has been supporting WOCCA with nutrition supplies and technical guidance on previous nutrition projects within the targeted locations and currently supporting our SHF funded project running in Daynille/Kaxda IDP camps and in Balcad district. Therefore, in this project WOCCA will still engage UNICEF to provide nutrition supplies and technical support for management of SAM cases. To enhance effective coordination, WOCCA will provide monthly activity updates with partners including Nutrition cluster both regional and Nairobi level, Other agencies working in the field who are doing other sector projects in the project sites will also be updated to avoid duplication and promote effective and efficient utilization humanitarian fund.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Child Care Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Child Care Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-29" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joseph Mutunga</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254718992246</telephone>
   <email>livelihoods@woccaorg.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Robbert Van der Steeg</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C.E.O</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254734755122</telephone>
   <email>robbert.vandersteeg@woccaorg.om</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9671">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.82500000 45.93700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-15">253072.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-15">41715.28</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-11057">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-15">294788</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Child Care Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303801826">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-24">235830.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Child Care Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304662823">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-06">52360.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Child Care Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
