<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-18/3485/SA2/WASH/INGO/11210</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustain and expand life-saving basic WASH services for the vulnerable drought, flood and conflict displaced populations, Schools and Health/Nutrition facilities in Buloburte (Hiran), Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The majority of people living in IDP settlements and villages in Buloburte (Hiran), a cholera/AWD hotspot in Somalia, do not have access to a protected water source (41%) and their latrine have been damaged or destroyed by the floods. Moreover almost 9 out of 10 households (84%) reported that access to hygiene commodities (soap, detergent) is a challenge due to lack of cash. Save the Children is proposing a 12-month project targeting drought, flood and conflict displaced populations in Bulaburte, reaching 2,480 households (14,880 total beneficiaries, Men: 3,803 Women: 3,832, Boys: 3,506, Girls: 3,739 ).  The interventions will consist of the provision of sustained water supply, shared and community-managed sanitation facilities amp hand washing stations hygiene promotion amp commodities in communities, schools and health/nutrition facilities. The proposed intervention will link with SC&#x2019;s ongoing emergency response interventions in WASH, Education, Health, Livelihoods, Nutrition and Food Security,  all aimed at providing a combination of lifesaving and resilience building support to drought and flood affected communities in Buloburte. The proposed project activities will include: construction and rehabilitation of strategic water sources with construction of hybrid solar pumping systems pipeline extensions and distribution systems enhancement of community-led water management through capacity development of operators provision of operation and maintenance tools construction and /or rehabilitation of sanitation facilities in the target IDPs, schools and health/nutrition facilities trainings in and dissemination of hygiene best practice through IECs and the distribution of hygiene kits. The project will also conduct WASH related DRR  capacity building training for local institutions such as Government, NGOS and communities. The project beneficiaries of the sanitation facilities and hygiene kit component will be selected through a community consultative process in order to ensure that only those who meet the specified vulnerability criteria are identified for support. Female headed households, families with low income, pregnant and lactating mothers among others will be given high priority whilst accountability and transparency measures will be put in place to ensure equity within an all-inclusive aid administration process. SC will maintain and expand synergies across all the programs by ensuring that this project is implemented alongside the other emergency response programs implemented by SC as well as other partners in the area. 

The project is designed to ensure equitable access to WASH services by older people and those with disabilities, the safety of children, and dignity and privacy for women and girls. Coordination with nutrition, health, education and WASH clusters at national and state levels will be maintained, in addition to ongoing coordination with general key actors in Hirshabelle, Buloburte in particular. The project will contribute to ongoing life-saving responses in the target communities in order to strengthen  their resilience. It will address gender issues through collecting sex and age disaggregated data which will be analyzed to identify gaps, provide gender sensitive interventions and ensure the participation and empowerment of women. Accountability to affected populations will be ensured by involving communities in information sharing and engaging them in the complaints and feedback system. Protection of beneficiaries will be ensured during access and utilization of services seeking to reduce further risks. Through collaboration with community members, community education committees, parent teacher associations and students, SC will work to bring positive changes to the hygiene and sanitation situation of targeted communities and schools.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior WASH Technical Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>abdirizak.ibrahim@savethechildren.org</telephone>
   <email>Abdirizak Ibrahim</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acting Head of Program Development</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>Stephen.Mwangangi@savethechildren.org</telephone>
   <email>Stephen Mwangangi</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9667">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hiraan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.22300000 45.37600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-12-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-21">15109.91</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-19"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-21">484890.81</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1704378534">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-31">165174.83</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-11210">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-21">500000.72</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303756823">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-03">200000.29</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304157329">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-28">300000.43</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
