<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-18/3485/RA3/FSC-Nut/INGO/10125</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Food security and Nutrition project-Bari, Nugaal, Sool and Sanaag</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">North Somalia, specifically Nugaal, has faced prolonged droughts in 2016 through late 2017 with below average rainfalls, low production and loss of main livelihoods. During this time, the communities have lost their livelihoods such as the livestock, the farms, small businesses and overstretched the social copping mechanism (credit services). Over 60% of the livestock were lost to the droughts between 2016 and 2017, while the remained livestock had poor body conditions as result of limited access to water, pasture and under nutrition related livestock diseases (Adeso internal report, inter agency assessment report, Government reports, UN OCHA updates). About 65% of the North Somalia population are rural and pastoral communities (Puntland strategy document) whose main sources of income is from livestock sales, milk and livestock byproducts. We have observed in 2017, there were significant pastoral communities that lost all their livestock, and joined the internally displacement camps (IDP) or at villages within the host communities. The recent FSNAU/FEWS NET and Partners Nutrition assessment indicated serious to critical acute malnutrition among the under five children in Garowe IDP camps.  Despite the gains made as result of large humanitarian assistance and the average 2018 GU rainfall, the proposed location for this response is in IPC 3 and 4.  Target communities are pastoral and rural communities whose traditional livelihood have been livestock. Restoring the livestock for the poor households is key in providing sustainable livelihood that will increase access to food, improve nutrition status and strengthening their resilience. The target district has good pasture and water that will last till next rainy season and therefore the timing of the response is ideal of restocking. The project will reach 250 households (1500 Women, Girls, Boys and Men)
The beneficiaries will be selected through the existing nutrition referral pathways such as from the nutrition centres, health centers through community health workers, community elders to exactly identify those successfully discharged after they received nutrition treatment. The project will mainly target those poor women with children that had acute malnutrition and have no livelihood. The community will be mobilized and sensitized on the targeting process to ensure there is communal buy-in, including the men in the target area. 
The project will therefore provide 10 goats (9 lactating and one male) and 3 months&#x2019; unconditional cash transfers for 250 households. In addition, the project will provide 10KG supplement blocks to each household and vaccination and treatment services to the livestock (against PPR, SGR and worms). We have been working with Ministry of Livestock and Animal Husbandry and over time trained community animal health workers, and the Ministry has technical veterinary doctors who can provide animal health care, including inspecting the animals before being purchased.  The Animal will be purchased locally and this will enable adaptive to the local environment and no additional pressure on the resources (water, browse)
We have practical experiences in restocking for North Somalia. In 2011, we delivered Camel restocking to the droughts affected pastoral communities, in 2002 and 2003 we have delivered 740 Camels through restocking. Those camels that were distributed have multiplied and really benefited not only the direct beneficiaries but also the communities through milk sales and other livestock byproducts. 
We are local and grass route organization that work with poor in the communities, have good relation with both Puntland and Somaliland governments and have expanded competent team on the ground and can successfully deliver the project. Our direct cost for this project is over 75% and this provides value for money for SHF, we have implemented several SHF projects in 2017 and 2018 and therefore have good understanding on the SHF program delivery guideline</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Development Solutions</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Development Solutions</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Ali Sharif</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254 704828655</telephone>
   <email>mali@adesoafrica.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9673">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nugaal</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.20900000 48.84600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="90" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="10" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-09-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-18">201810.31</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-18">252734.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-10125">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-18">454544.71</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Development Solutions</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303562673">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-24">272726.83</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Development Solutions</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303902952">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-02">181817.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Development Solutions</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
