<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-18/3485/SA1/WASH/INGO/8692</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustain and expand life-saving basic WASH services for the vulnerable drought and conflict displaced populations, Schools and Health/Nutrition facilities in Baidoa Districts, Central and Southern Somalia (CSS)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children is intending to sustain the famine prevention response in Baidoa through the provision of water, sanitation and hygiene services in communities, schools and health/nutrition facilities while still meeting immediate WASH needs and easing the burden for vulnerable drought and conflict displaced populations in the target areas of Baidoa.
The proposed intervention will link with SC&#x2019;s ongoing emergency response interventions of WASH, Education, Health, Nutrition and Food Security, Livelihoods, all defined to provide a combination of lifesaving, famine prevention and resilience building support to drought affected communities in Baidoa. The proposed project activities will include construction of strategic water sources, pipeline extensions and distribution systems, provision of operation and maintenance tools, construction/rehabilitation of sanitation facilities in the target IDPs, schools and health/nutrition facilities, trainings and dissemination of hygiene best practice through IECs with and distribution of hygiene kits. 
The project beneficiaries will be selected through a community consultative process in order to ensure that only those who meet the specified vulnerability criteria are identified for support. Female headed households, families with low income, pregnant and lactating mothers among others will be given high priority while accountability and transparency measures will be put in place to ensure equity within an all-inclusive aid administration process. SC will maintain and expand synergies across all the programs by ensuring that this project is implemented alongside the other emergency response programs. 
The project is designed to ensure equitable access to WASH services considering people with disabilities and elders, safety of children and dignity and privacy for women and girls. Coordination will be maintained with nutrition, health, education and WASH clusters at national and state levels, in addition to coordination with key actors in Baidoa. The project will contribute to sustain the famine response and resilience of the target community. It will address gender issues and collect sex and age disaggregated data which will be analysed to identify gaps, provide gender sensitive interventions and ensure participation and empowerment of women. The accountability to affected populations will be ensured by involving communities, information sharing and engaging them in the complaints and feedback system. Protection of beneficiaries will be ensured during access and utilization of services seeking to reduce further risks.
Through collaboration with community members, community education committees, parent - teacher associations and students, SC will work to bring positive changes in hygiene and sanitation situation of targeted communities and schools. The team will identify respected community members (including elders, religious leaders, Women/Youth groups, teachers etc.) who are interested to work voluntarily in their communities. Then, SC will provide these community volunteers (male and female) with training on community hygiene promotion through community-based sessions. The trained volunteers will then work with SC&#x2019;s WASH staff to disseminate hygiene and sanitation related messages to all community members and school children. SC will adopt, print, and use graphic IEC materials developed by the Somalia WASH cluster to facilitate further the implementation of soft component of the project.
This project is designed to improve and sustain the quality and access to services in communities, in particular the provision of WASH services at the community level. Save the Children is therefore proposing a 12-month project for drought and conflict displaced populations in Baidoa (24 IDPs camps) 8559 households (59913 total beneficiaries, Men: 23,366 Women: 24564 , Boys: 5991, Girls: 5991</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Binyam Gebru</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Health and Nutrition</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>(+254) 731 034 501</telephone>
   <email>Binyam.gebru@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Claire Taylor</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acting Head of Program Development</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>(+254) 715 811 048</telephone>
   <email>Claire.Taylor@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9664">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bay</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.67600000 43.73800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-05-02"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-10">478606.97</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-10">238318.7</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-8692">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-10">716925.67</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303330831">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-15">573540.54</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304099778">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-15">137595.89</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
