<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-18/3485/SA1/H-Nut-WASH/NGO/8538</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated multi-sectoral and lifesaving services to drought and conflict affected communities (IDPs and Host community) in  Kahda  district of Banadir region and Wanlaweyn  and Afgoye districts of lower Shablle region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project responds to the gender and age specific needs such as through integrated  lifesaving health/wash/nutrition services to vulnerable drought and conflict  affected communities in the IDPs and host community in Kahda,Afgoye  and wanlaweyn districts and this project will be continuation of ongoing activities in target areas which will be  an end at 31 December 2017 and complement to the areas which current project not covered .The project will continue 5  (IERT)  in Kahda,Afgoye and Wanlaweyn districts. two IERTs  will be fixed another  4 will be outreach base. HIJRA will focus on ensuring access to integrated health,nutrition and WASH  services for the women, men, boys and girls along with the most vulnerable among these groups such as the youth, elderly, persons with disabilities and pregnant and lactating women. HIJRA engages the community in a sustainable and accountable manner to determine context and culturally appropriate need&#xAC; based responses. The project will use existing staff for IERT and recruit if need be. CHPs engaged to provide the community hygiene promotion sessions on good hygiene and sanitation practice. The project plans to reach 500 individuals (100 male and 400 female) from the schools, health facilities and nutrition centers. the aim is to empower communities to manage their water supply and to control sanitation &#xAC;related diseases by promoting health awareness and understanding proper hygienic breastfeeding practices , Procure and be distributed 400 hygiene kits to the families of discharged patients particularly acute watery diarrhea/cholera as well as families with acute malnutrition in internal displaced population, An orientation on how to use of the kits will be provided to the families by the hygiene promoters to ensure optimal and appropriate utilization. The hygiene kits will be comprised of essential hygiene items to ensure improved hygiene at an individual and household level. The hygiene kits will be as per stander of WASH cluster. Water sources will be protected, in the short term chlorination at sources and household level will be emphasized. HIJRA will repair/construct safe water sources at water in health facilities and schools in Kahada, Afgoye and Wanlaweyn to improve access to safe and clean water. Latrine and hand washing facilities will be repaired at school for boys, girls, men and women. Distribution of IEC materials will complement the participatory hygiene promotion sessions. The provision of chlorine and aqua tabs whose use will be extensively explained during the training sessions is critical. The IERT will provide of case management includes measles and acute watery diarrhea, capacity building of staff on proper diarrhea case management and referral of very sick patient after giving first aid to Banadir hospital and Afgoye hospital .Community health nutrition workers will detect active case of acute malnutrition and refer to IERT if without medical complication and to stabilization center if with medical complication .they will follow up progress of case. IERT will be trained on infancy young child feeding practice and Integrated management acute malnutrition (IMAM). IYF Promoter will perform breast feeding promotion and infancy young child feeding support through consulting one to one and workshop season, IERT will treat acute malnutrition case and referral with medical complication to stabilization center in Banadir hospital. The break in the provision of essential medicines and nutritional supply will have humanitarian consequences throughout the country. So HIJRA will procure essential drugs and nutrition supply and this will distribute to integrated facilities and outreach team in order to maintain running activities and to avoid stock out. This supply will be complement from supply receiving from MOH, WHO and UNICEF. The project aims to reach 49500 beneficiaries comprising of boys (11600), girls (11600), men (8400), and women (17900).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Initiative Just Relief Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Initiative Just Relief Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Dahir Fidow</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">executive director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254721840280</telephone>
   <email>m.dahir@hijra.or.ke</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamud Mohamed Hersi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Officer in charge and Program manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615057981</telephone>
   <email>m.hersi@hijra.or.ke</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9662">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banadir</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.11500000 45.46700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="9669">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.74900000 44.39100000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="34" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="33" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="33" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-05-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-05">293949.11</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-05">206039.09</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-8538">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-05">499988.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Initiative Just Relief Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303382359">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-11">399990.56</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Initiative Just Relief Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303822753">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-06">99997.64</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Initiative Just Relief Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
