<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-32491</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bekto Precisa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- On top of existing labor force of the Company, Bekto Precisa is expected to create additional direct skilled jobs until 2014 in a country where official unemployment rate is around 45%, - Moreover, the multiplier effect is estimated at 3x for indirect jobs in small-medium enterprises focused on factory &amp; machine maintenance and small mechanical workshops located mainly in Gorazde, a small remote mountain town, supporting local MSMEs, - On the back of increased sales &amp; production capacity of the Company as well as export-oriented production &amp; sales will boost the hard-currency flow to BiH with a certain positive impact on BiH&apos;&apos;s current account deficit and tax revenues; and - Finally, given that Bekto Precisa mainly sources its main processing material and services domestically, which corresponds more than 50% of total annual expenses of the Company, the Project will have a direct positive local supply chain impact.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Although the origins of Bekto Precisa d.o.o. (Bekto Precisa or the Company) stem from Bekto Internacional d.o.o. which was established as one of the first privately owned companies in the Former Yugoslavia, about 35 years ago, the Company was founded as a family business in 2005 right after the sale of Bekto Internacional d.o.o. to EMKA Beschlagteile GmbH &amp; Co (Emka) in 2004 where Emka is still the largest customer of the Company operating eight factories across Europe and China with annual turnover of 220 million.  Bekto Precisa has specialized in technical know-how and up-to-date technology in the production of highly sophisticated tools and non-ferrous metals, as well as metal-plastic combinations.  The Company is export-oriented and mainly supplies three industries, which in the importance of the turnover generation are automotive, electrical, and ski industries.  Formed with 10 employees, the Company successfully managed to grow into one of the leading companies in the Southern Europe offering turn-key production solutions covering design, engineering, precision tool making and molding, plus additional fitting and assembly services of sophisticated plastic and metal injection molding units by employing more than 350 employees currently.  The Company plans to (i) execute an expansion investment in 2013-2015 to strengthen its competitiveness and to accept multi-tool and larger tool orders for heavier and complex plastic parts, (ii) refinance and restructure its existing debt to optimize the number of relationship banks as well as (iii) improve its corporate governance practices (the Project).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BEKTO-PRECISA D.O.O</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-32491" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-06-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-07-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bekto Precisa d.o.o.  I. Popovia bb.  73000 Gorazde,  Bosnia and Herzegovina  Website:  http://www.precisa.ba    Ms. Emina Karahasan  Tel: +387 38/24 14 23  Fax: +387 38/24 14 20  E-Mail:  mailto:emina@bekto.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bekto Precisa d.o.o.  I. Popovica bb.  73000 Gorazde,  Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="BA-Bosnia and Herzegovina">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bekto Precisas headquarters and operations are based in Gorazde, a city in BiH located 100 km east of Sarajevo and 20 km from the Serbian border.  Gorazde is in the eastern part of the country which is known for its low level of development and was badly affected by the war in the 90s. However, it has since succeeded in developing an engineering hub primarily focused on the automotive sector. Current population of the city is estimated at 30,000 and Bekto Precisa is one of the leading employers in this remote town, promoting high skilled labor.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>44.2500000000 17.8333300000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="333" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">M-DB - Industrial Machinery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $10.39 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-06-14"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-06-14">10390000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-06-14">10390000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BEKTO-PRECISA D.O.O</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/32491">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/32491">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
