<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-11310</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lukavac Cement</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FCL and ALAS Bosna, a special purpose company for modernizing the cement plant for FCL, would be the co-borrowers for the project.  FCL was established in 1974 as a state owned company, and uses the dry process technology of the 1970s. It has a kiln capacity of 800 tons per day, translating to around 340,000 tons of cement a year.     The project would involve the post privatization rehabilitation and modernization of  the company. The project would consist of (i) optimization of production capacity of the existing facility of the borrowers located at Lukavac, Macan Marije bb, Bosnia and Herzegovina from its current cement output level of about 260,000 tons per year (tpy) to a full capacity level of 340,000 tpy (stage 1); (ii) expansion of the existing cement grinding capacity to 800,000 tpy (stage 2); and (iii) expansion of clinker production capacity by installing a new kiln line of 2,000 tons per day (tpd) capacity to match the cement production level of 800,000 tpy (stage 3). The first two stages will be implemented together as Phase I, while the kiln will be constructed as Phase II of the project.    The project is underpinned by strong local demand driven by the need to complete repairs to buildings, bridges and other infrastructure damaged during the war. Demand is also growing from new construction of industrial and commercial facilities, fueled by a high post war GDP growth rate and is currently being met through heavy cement imports (estimated at 900,000 tpy in 2001). The modernization will also bring down production costs and enable the company to compete with imports, thus contributing to foreign exchange savings.       The project provides an opportunity for IFC to support privatization and one of the largest and highly visible FDI in BiH.  Moreover, the underdeveloped financial system in BiH is not able to provide the sponsors with access to adequate long-term limited recourse financing.  In addition, IFCs review and approval of the project will provide confidence to other potential lenders and signal an improving investment climate in BiH, as the current perception of BiH, and its associated macroeconomic risk, by many international banks is somewhat negative.  IFCs investment, including long term funding for its own account and mobilizing commercial resources, would also play an important role in assisting a company whose modernization would have a substantial positive impact on the economic development in the area.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&apos;FCL&apos; d.d.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-11310" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2002-09-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2003-03-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Kurt Asamer   ALAS International Baustoffproduktions AG Unterthalhamstr. 2, 4694 Ohlsdorf AUSTRIA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="BA-Bosnia and Herzegovina">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The existing facilities of Fabrika Cementa Lukavac (FCL, or the company) are located close to the town of Lukavac, Macan Marije bb,   18 km   from the city of Tuzla in the northern part of BiH at a flat land between wooded hills. The location offers good infrastructure such as access at just 200 meters to the main road Doboj-Tuzla-Orasje connected to the Sarajevo transversal, railway branch to the plant, power transmission from the public grid, modern communication systems, and human resources at an urban area. The site provides good possibilities for further expansions.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>44.2500000000 17.8333300000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Cement</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $24.10 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2002-09-12"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2003-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2002-09-12">24100000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2002-09-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2002-09-12">24100000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">&apos;FCL&apos; d.d.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/11310/lukavac-cement">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
