<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012349-01-2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community-Based TB and HIV Integration Project - (CBTHI Project)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Partendo da queste carenze, gi&#xE0; incontrate nella realizzazione di programmi per la diagnosi HIV e delle malattie correlate nella Regione di Dodoma e in linea con i progetti attivi promossi dal TNCM tanzaniano, il presente progetto si concentrer&#xE0; nel distretto di Kondoa (Regione di Dodoma), in 26 villaggi selezionati particolarmente isolati, con l&#x2019;obiettivo di rinforzare il sistema sanitario locale e migliorare l&#x2019;accessibilit&#xE0; e la qualit&#xE0; delle cure per TB e HIV. Pilastri fondamentali del progetto saranno: 1) il rafforzamento delle strutture sanitarie di base in termini di infrastrutture, equipaggiamento e formazione del personale socio-sanitario; 2) il potenziamento della figura dei Community Health Workers (CHWs) attraverso la conduzione di corsi specifici e sostegno materiale per la conduzione delle attivit&#xE0; (acquisto di telefoni cellulari/tablet e biciclette).
Il progetto includer&#xE0; anche trasversalmente l&#x2019;implementazione di attivit&#xE0; per favorire la sinergia fra i programmi TB/HIV e attivit&#xE0; di ricerca operativa con focus specifico su l&#x2019;et&#xE0; pediatrica e adolescenziale (0-14) a supporto della attivit&#xE0; realizzate in tal senso dai progetti implementati dal TNCM.
Beneficiari diretti saranno le strutture sanitarie di base, gli operatori sociosanitari, i CHWs e i 115.050 abitanti dei villaggi selezionati. Le attivit&#xE0; previste si svolgeranno nell&#x2019;arco di 24 mesi.
Scopo complessivo del progetto &#xE8; ridurre il &#x201C;burden of diseases&#x201D; per la TB e HIV nelle popolazioni target, ampliando la portata dei programmi di controllo a livello locale. Per questo nel rafforzamento delle strutture sanitarie &#xE8; incluso l&#x2019;istallazione di pannelli solari, l&#x2019;acquisto di 15 microscopi standard con altre forniture diagnostiche per migliorare la diagnosi della tubercolosi e l&#x2019;identificazione delle resistenze farmacologiche al trattamento (MDR) e l&#x2019;acquisto di un apparecchio GeneXpert e relativo materiale di consumo. L&#x2019;identificazione dei casi (detection rate) &#xE8; un ambito in cui &#xE8; possibile un considerevole miglioramento vista la forbice esistente tra i casi realmente diagnosticati e le stime dei casi presenti nel territorio. Altro punto di forza sar&#xE0; la formazione e il coinvolgimento di 104 CHWs, che verranno incoraggiati a partecipare attivamente alla promozione di iniziative per l&#x2019;identificazione e la cura dei casi di TB, a favorire l&#x2019;aderenza terapeutica dei pazienti TB positivi nel seguire la corretta assunzione della terapia, a favorire l&#x2019;integrazione dei programmi nazionali TB/HIV nei rispettivi villaggi e a fornire informazioni adeguate sui diritti della popolazione per accedere alle strutture sanitarie.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will focus on the Kondoa district (Dodoma Region), in 26 selected villages, with the aim of
strengthening the local health system, improving accessibility and quality of care for TB and HIV. Fundamental
pillars of the project are therefore: 1) the strengthening of basic health facilities in terms of infrastructure,
equipment and training of social and health personnel; 2) the enhancement of the figure of community health
workers (CHWs) through the conduct of specific courses and material support for the conduct of activities
(purchase of mobile phones/ tablets and bicycles). The project will also cross-cuttingly include the
implementation of activities to foster synergy between TB/HIV programs and operational research activities with
a specific focus on paediatric and adolescent age (0-14). The direct beneficiaries of the project will therefore be
basic health facilities, social and health workers and CHWs and the 115.050 inhabitants of the 26 selected
villages. The planned activities will take place within 24 months. The strengthening of healthcare facilities
includes the purchase of 15 standard microscopes and other diagnostic supplies to improve the diagnosis of tuberculosis and the identification of pharmacological resistance to treatment (MDR), and the purchase of a
Gene Expert device and related supplies. Detection rate still seems to be an area where considerable
improvement is possible given the gap between the cases actually diagnosed and the estimates of cases present
in the territory. Another strength will be the training and involvement of 104 CHWs, who will be encouraged to
actively participate in the promotion of initiatives for the identification and treatment of TB cases, to promote
the therapeutic adherence of positive TB patients in following the correct intake of therapy, to facilitate the
integration of national TB/HIV programs in their respective villages and to provide adequate information on the
rights of the population to access health facilities. The overall aim of the project is to reduce the burden of
diseases for TB and HIV in target populations by broadening the scope of local control programmes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CMSR - CENTRO MONDIALIT&#xC0; SVILUPPO RECIPROCO ONLUS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012349/01/2" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-21" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-03-20" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="40" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12182" percentage="10" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medical research</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12263" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tuberculosis control</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.8" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achieve universal health coverage, including financial risk protection, access to quality essential health-care services and access to safe, effective, quality and affordable essential medicines and vaccines for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end the epidemics of AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria and neglected tropical diseases and combat hepatitis, water-borne diseases and other communicable diseases</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="1.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure that all men and women, in particular the poor and the vulnerable, have equal rights to economic resources, as well as access to basic services, ownership and control over land and other forms of property, inheritance, natural resources, appropriate new technology and financial services, including microfinance</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End poverty in all its forms everywhere</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.D" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthen the capacity of all countries, in particular developing countries, for early warning, risk reduction and management of national and global health risks</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.C" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Substantially increase health financing and the recruitment, development, training and retention of the health workforce in developing countries, especially in least developed countries and small island developing States</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-04-06">398677.35</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CMSR - CENTRO MONDIALIT&#xC0; SVILUPPO RECIPROCO ONLUS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012349-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012349-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012349-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012349-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012349-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012349-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012349-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
