<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-IATI-LPI-XI-IATI-LPI-0002</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-IATI-LPI" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Living Peace Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Working with Men to Increase Security and Stabilization in North Kivu, South Kivu and Ituri provinces</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Husband&#x2019;s women survivors SGBV in Community; 2. Military Men; 3. PoliceMen (PNC); 4. Men living in Community in high risk zones; 5. Ex-combatant and ex child soldiers living in Community in high risk zones; 6. Spouses of military men and policemen participating into the LP program</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Living Peace project seeks to achieve its goal by pursuing following objectives at five different levels: 1. Individuel Level: Men and women (spouses), healed of severe mental health and psychosocial problems, adopted positive non-violent coping strategies and experience greater personal efficacy to build meaningful relations with self and others. 2. Family Level: Reduced violence at home and restored peaceful partner relations create a safe and healthy environment for women, men and children. Reduction of violence use by men against their partners and children and increase gender equitable behaviours in the household create a safer environment for all members of the family. 3. Community Level: Restored community-based social support systems increase social cohesion between families, individuals and community structures resulting in higher levels of inclusion, and solidarity between community members. 4. Society Level: Congolese civil society organizations and public institutions of Police, Army and Health Care and religious leaders institutionalized the Living Peace approach in their services to adequately address the consequences of SGBV, promote positive masculinity and prevent (mainly) men getting involved in conflicts and/or (re)join armed groups. 5. Women Social and Economic Empowerment: Women, partners of male participants in Living Peace groups, enjoy greater social and economic autonomy with positive support of husbands that participated in Living Peace groups.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of the proposed intervention is to achieve sustainable, gender-equitable peace at all levels of society in provinces of South Kivu, North Kivu and Ituri in eastern DRC by: 1. The overall goal of LPI is to reduce level of violence and build trust in the community by working with men through psychosocial support programs that will help them to end violence and adopt norms and values that support gender equality at all levels; &#x2028; 2. Promoting women socio-economic empowerment with positive support of husbands through an adaptation of the Living Peace methodology, (Journeys of Transformation). LPI will partner with a local organization that is implementing VSLA groups and/or women involved in other economic empowerment activities. LPI will train the local partner in the application of Journeys of Transformation module to engage men as allies of women in economic empowerment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XI-IATI-LPI-4000003194" ref="XI-IATI-00000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Living Peace Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000003194" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Living Peace Institute</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aloys Mahwa</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director LPI</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+243970965771</telephone>
   <email>a.mahwa@livingpeaceinstitute.org</email>
   <website>http://livingpeaceinstitute.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">info@livingpeaceinstitute.org</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity is implemented in Noth-Kivu, South Kivu and Ituri provinces</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-15">2921782.96</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="DEC0869087">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-03">1601980</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">First instalment for the financial year 2020-2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000003194" ref="Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Money is disbursed directly to the implementing institution and managed through a separate bank account</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="XI-IATI-LPI-400000194" ref="XI-IATI-LPI" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <sector code="XI-IATI-LPI-0002" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://livingpeaceinstitute.org">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transaction for Living Peace Institute</narrative>
   </sector>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="DEC0983049">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-18">2035836</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Second instalment for the fiscal year 2020-2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000003194" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="XI-IATI-LPI-0002" ref="XI-IATI-LPI" type="22"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="XI-IATI-LPI-0002" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://livingpeaceinstitute.org">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transaction for Living peace Institute</narrative>
   </sector>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 2: Family Level: Reduced Violence at Home and Restored
Peaceful Partner relations in the family</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">At family level, LP project aims at reducing violence at home and restore peaceful partner relations in the family. At this level, men psychosocial support groups, the inclusion of women through weekly homework tasks and women participation in shared sessions with men work to reduce the use of violence by men against their partners and children, increase relationship quality, and increase gender equitable behaviors in the household, thus creating a safer and more equal environment for all members of the family.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 2.1.2: Improved communication in partner relationship</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Communication is an important competence in family relations and conflict management. It is through
communication that men and women can listen and identify everyone needs triggers of conflicts and positive ways of managing them. For the year 2020-2021, the number of men living in harmony with their wives increased from 29.8% at pre-intervention to 83.9 % at post intervention. The percentage of men who use dialogue to find solutions to family problems increased from 26.5% to 76.9%. The percentage of men who dialogue with their wives to get mutual consent for sexual intercourse increased from 28.5% to 85.3 %. The percentage of men who dialogue with their wives about children education increased from 37% to 83.1%.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome Indicator 2.3.1: Reports (from men and women participants) of reduced men&#x2019;s use of physical,
psychological and economical violence against women &amp; violence against children</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">LP intervention seeks to break the cycle of violence by tackling its root causes and by engaging men in the process of change. For the year 2020-2021, 37.7% of men identified to participate in LP PSSG have misunderstanding with their wives most of time. This percentage was reduced to 6.5% after the intervention. The percentage of men who were calling their wives witch or prostitute when they went angry was reduced from 45.1% to 8.7%. The percentage of men who slap their wives when they feel not respect decreased from 32% to 0.4%. The percentage of men who was used to force their wives to have sex even if they do not want decreased from 25.9% to 9.1%.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 2.1: Refer to the Output indicator 1.1.1 and 1.1.2 in the objective One</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 2.1: Refer to the Output indicator 1.1.1 and 1.1.2 in the objective One</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome Indicator 2.1.1: Reports (from men and women participants including in polygamous relations) of more gender equitable attitudes and full caregiving responsibilities for their respective spouses and children in the households of participating men.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participation in LP psychosocial support group has been revealed to be associated with reduction of harmful gender attitudes which support inequality and justify violent behaviors of men and the adoption of positive attitudes which support equality between men and women. For the year 2020-2021, men participants in LP psychosocial support groups acquired new gender attitudes to support equality between men and women and engagement in the prevention of SVBG. The percentage of men who believe that changing diapers, washing and feeding children are tasks of women decreased from 54.2% to 8.9%. The percentage of men who believe that a woman who does not dress in a decent manner is at risk of being raped decreased from 63.1% to 14.7%. The percentage of men who believe that there are times when women deserve to be beaten decreased from 51.6% to 6.8%. It is these changes in gender attitudes and the improvement of mental health conditions which can explain new behaviors among LP group participants. the number of men who was participating in household chores such as cooking and cleaning home, washing and feedings kids increased form 14.3% to 65.7% and 76.3 % respectively. Sharing salary with his wife and planning together family expending increased from 15.7% to 79.9% and 19.1% to 89.1 % respectively.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output indicator 2.2.1. Number of women spouses of men who participate in shared sessions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The LP methodology includes family-focused shared sessions of the LP Program psychosocial support groups during which targeted men and their spouse meet to discuss about how their can put their effort together to end the cycle of violence in their family. Shared sessions are 9 th, 12 th, 13 th and 15 th. Shared sessions reinforce more gender equitable attitudes and behaviors, improve communication in partner relationship and reduce men&#x2019;s use of physical, sexual, psychological and economic, violence against women &amp; violence against children. For the year 2020-2021, the average rate of participation of women in shared sessions is evaluated at 93.3% which means 14 women par shared session
and per group.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Some testimonies of beneficiaries</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x201C;My name is GJ, the spouse of UUP participant of Umoja group in Nyakasanza village. Before my
husband participated in the men&apos;s groups organized by LP, we had not had the slightest opportunity to
sit together as married couples with children. My husband came home when he wanted, drank when he
wanted, the children&apos;s problems did not concern him; he lived as he wanted and did as he wanted. With
the participation in the living peace group, I have observed important changes not only in his life, but
also in our life as a couple. My husband doesn&apos;t drink much anymore, he comes home early, now we
manage to share as a family as husband and wife, father and mother. Today, we take the time to plan
the family projects, we are comfortable and calm, the dialogue is already a reality in our family&#x201D;.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 4: Society Level: Political Engagement. Involve Congolese civil society and public institutions in order to institutionalize the Living Peace approach and influence</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">At society level LP have the objective of involving Congolese civil society and public institutions in
order to institutionalize the Living Peace approach and influence policy. Living Peace Institute transfers
the message of peace to local CSOs and Congolese government institutions to persuade them to take
responsibility and action against SGBV, starting with SGBV between uniformed men and civilians.
Living Peace builds the capacity of state actors and CSOs, by engaging them in activities and
debates, and by actively participating in all technical working groups and platforms that seek to end
SGBV.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 4.2.1: Number of training events tailored for military and police men</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the year 2020-2021, LPI in collaboration with its partner ISL identified and trained 22 military
and 26 police forces on gender equality, prevention of SGBV and LP methodology. They contributed
in the implementation of 88 LP psychosocial support group , to reach directly 1320 men in uniform and their spouses in military and police communities in north and south Kivu.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 4.1.2: Number of facilitators recruited by CSOs and trained to conduct group therapy
sessions in communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the year 2020-2021, LPI in collaboration with its partner and community leaders identified 234
facilitators to conduct psychosocial support group. Males represent 77.6% while females
represent 22.4%.  51.7% of facilitators have secondary education level, 27.6 % have the first cycle of university studies while 25.4 % have a bachelor&#x2019;s degree. Before the implementation of first phase of LP psychosocial support group, identified facilitators participation in a 3-day training on the identification of men, participants of group and a 7 day training of group dynamic and Living Peace methodology. The training on the identification of LP group participants were organized during the period from 26 January to 1 February 2021while trainings on LP methodology were organized during the period from 8 to 15 February 2021. Before the implementation of the second round of LP psychosocial support group, a refresher training were organized during the period from 14 to 18 June 2021.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 4.1.1: Number of representatives from community organizations, CSOs, trained in
gender transformative approaches to engaging men and boys in violence prevention</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For year 2020-2021, LPI trained 53 representatives of CSOs partner on the process of identification
of psychosocial support group facilitators and gender transformative approaches. The trainings
helped the participant to understand clearly that transformative approaches differs from other SGBV
prevention and response approaches in that sense that they actively seek to examine, challenge and
change rigid gender norms and power imbalances, encourage critical awareness; question the cost
of harmful and inequitable gender norms and highlight the benefits of changing them; emphasizes
the empowerment of women / girls and people and engages / empowers boys and men in the areas
of gender equality, violence prevention and sexual and reproductive health.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 4.2.3: Number of traditional and community leaders involved in all process of LP
intervention to support and promote peace, gender equality and intervene as appropriate in families
and community conflict</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Traditional and community leaders are involved in all process of  intervention to increase their capacity
to support individuals and community in presenting positive models of masculinity, preventing and
mitigating SGBV, and gender equality. For the year 2020-2021 community leaders contributed to
the identification of 234 facilitators and 2970 participants.  444 community leaders were involved in the identification of facilitators whereas 318 leaders were involved in the identification of beneficiaries.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 4.2.2: Number of religious and community leaders trained as facilitators of LP
program psychosocial groups</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training religious leaders in the Living Peace methodology helped them reach out to members of their
religious communities while applying a methodology that combines promotion of gender equality,
mental health care prevention and psychosocial support. For the year 2020-2021, LPI in
collaboration with its local partners has identified and trained 234 facilitators among them 75
community leaders. The first round of trainings took place in February 2021 while the second round
(refresher trainings) took place in June 2021.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 3: Creating and restoring social support systems at the community
level</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the community level, LP project aims at creating and restoring social support systems to support men, women and families in the target communities (both participants and non-participants in the LP psychosocial support groups) in establishing an environment that is gender-equitable, peaceful and favourable to positive social change. Restored community-based social support systems increase social cohesion between families, individuals and community structures resulting in higher levels of inclusion, and solidarity between community members.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output indicator 3.1.2: Number of community campaigns or activities resulting from LP Program participation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community celebration is one of the fifteenth psychosocial support group sessions where the member of the targeted community including community  and religious leaders celebrate the new behaviors and positive change of LP participants. Community campaigns aim at increasing the levels of social cohesion in the community and reduction of conflict in communities in the targeted areas. They contribute to the reduction of stigmatization and facilitate re-integration of SGBV survivors by husbands, families, community in target communities. They are also intended to improve perception in terms of equal right to inherit land and promote peace and gender equality among community members. For the year 2020-2021, Living Peace institute modified the ancient format of community celebration to be adapted to rules and measures against the spread of Covid-19 Virus. A total of 84 community campaigns were organized in the provinces of North Kivu, South Kivu and Ituri. During all the 84 community campaigns, 2941 LP participants and their spouses shared testimonies of change in front 3008 community members and 465 community leaders.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 3.5.1: Number of psychosocial and gender-equitable peace messages broadcasted
via Radio/TV/social media</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the year 2020-2021, LPI worked with La Benevolencija to develop and disseminate gender
equitable messages via radio and social medias. The campaign intends to disseminate living peace
messages designed to prevent sexual and gender-based violence and conflict; discuss the role of
men involved in security forces in SGBV prevention; stress the importance of support for SGBV
survivors and those indirectly affected by it; and to encourage cooperation between civilians and the
security sector.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 3.3.1: Number of ex-combatants and ex-child soldiers who participated in LP
Program psychosocial support groups</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the year 2020-2021, LPI identified 330 Ex-combatants to participate into LP psychosocial group
sessions in two rounds. The average rate of participation of ex-combatants is evaluated at 92.2%.
Among 330 ex-combatants identified to participate in LP psychosocial groups, 318 ex-combatants
which represent 96.4 % participated in more than 70% of the session.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 3.2.1: Number of military men and police men who participated in LP Program
psychosocial support groups</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the year 2020-2021, LPI identified 660 military men and  their spouses  and 660 policemen and their spouses to participate into LP Psychosocial Support Groups. The rate of participation of military and police in LP psychosocial support group is presented as follows. For  military men in North Kivu, the rate of participation is evaluated at 98.1%. For policemen in North Kivu, the rate of participation is evaluated at 95.2%. For the military men in south-Kivu, the rate of participation is evaluated at 97.4%. For the policemen in South Kivu, the rate of participation is evaluated at 88.6%.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 3.1.4: Number of mobile cinema developed to promote gender equality, positive masculinity,
SGBV prevention/ mitigation in target communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the year 2020-2021, the Covid19 context has made it difficult to stick to the initial planning,
which included a workshop to be held in DRC in October 2020, followed by filming in January/February 2021. These timeframes were premature, considering extensive lock-downs that are applicable in Europe since late 2020, the vaccination campaign that progresses but is not yet causing a &#x2018;tipping point&#x2019; for infection rates, and international travel restrictions (especially double quarantine that needs to be observed and significantly affects costs and planning). The Covid19 context also affects the way in which LPI is rolling out the cycles with the groups. There are currently no large community gatherings/celebrations, whereas those type of activities would be especially important to also capture with the filming. 
&#x2022; Consultations with LPI: After analysis of the LPI manual, online consultations were held with
key LPI staff (Aloys, Benoit, Valens) in order to grasp the order and logic of the different
group sessions, especially with regards to the main topics and messages communicated. This
allowed MCF to align the film sequences with these messages. Following these consultations
a document was prepared that captured a summary of the focus of the LPI sessions and ideas
for film content. The proposal was to develop short film sequences for most of the sessions,
to be used as an entry-point to further discuss important questions/messages under the lead
of the LPI facilitators. This document was shared with LPI for feedback.
&#x2022; Pre-edit and editing of clips: A first rough edit of the short film sequences was completed by
mid-November. In total 11 sequences were edited based on existing footage that has been
filmed in DRC by MCF (IFProductions) throughout the years. Each sequence is around 5 minutes
in length, spoken in Swahili/Lingala or French and featuring especially security staff (police,
army) on topics related to trauma, positive masculinity, gender-based violence etc. A working
session held with LPI end of November 2020 allowed to visualize the film sequences and
register feedback for improvements. During this session key staff of LPI were present. Based
on this, a second version was edited by mid-January. A second session to visualize the films
was held in March 2021. During this session all LPI facilitators were present. This once more
offered an opportunity to gather final elements of feedback. Film versions of the films were
then edited by mid-April and these were shared with LPI in order to be used for the remaining
sessions of the current cycle.
&#x2022; A short educational short film was developed, produced and broadcast during the refresher
trainings for both LPI master trainers and LP group facilitators. This film covers all topic of LP
manual. The sequences are aligned to help the audience to engage a critical thinking about
the key message and highlight the message to mitigate methodological challenges in line with
facilitator&#x2019;s role during LP group session. This film was broadcast to 223 facilitators during
the refresher trainings.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-02"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 3.5.2: Number of people reached by media campaigns</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">LPI Facebook helps to assess people who are interacting with message developed by LPI. The statistic from LP Facebook account featured the number of people from different countries and cities that
followed the LP messages during the period from the 1 st October 2020 to 30 September 2021. In
general, 507,827 people followed LP messages on Facebook in 72 countries with the most
participation in the DRC (72%) and in more than 100 cities.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lessons learned</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">LPI will continue to put more efforts in modified format of community celebration. This consists of
gathering not more than 20 people around five living peace couples to witness their process of
change and disseminate the living peace message to prevent SGBV and create more peaceful
environment. This strategy will help LPI to reach more than 8000 people with living peace and non
violence messages for the year 2021-2022.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 3.1.1: Number of men and women actively participated in LP program group sessions where they learn to mitigate obstacles to support SGBV victims within their communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The LP psychosocial support groups intervention provides to men and Women new insight and competences to not only deal with their problems at home but also to mitigate obstacles and support SGBV survivors in their communities. The 12th psychosocial support group which is the sharing group session is dealing with identifying different obstacles within the community and see how to overcome them so that LP participants will promote peace and gender equality, intervening as appropriate when there are conflicts in families and in the community while guaranteeing the inclusion and support of the most vulnerable people. The 13th psychosocial support session helps the LP participants to discuss on the way they can play an active roles to protect communities against gender based violence and together with neighbors to develop security network plan to effectively respond to fundamental needs of SGBV survivors which are healthcare, support and protection. for the year 2020-2021, 2494 men and 2434 women attended the 12th session (ex-combatant excluded) whereas 2466 men and 2428 women attended the 13th session.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Testimony of community leader</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x201C;My name is EM, I am a chief of BIKENGE and LUSHEBERE localities but also president of
the Hutu community of Masisi. I am very happy with this community celebration ceremony
and especially with your activities of engaging men for the promotion of gender equality
in my entity. A few years ago, I did not sleep because of the couples living in BIKENGE
who, most of them, came to complain to me very early in the morning because of the acts
of disorder, violence and other negative attitudes that the men were committing towards
their partners, children and members of the community. For example, the man who testified
that he regularly stole his wife&apos;s money and goats was true, but since he joined your groups,
his wife no longer complains. Since the existence of this project in these localities, I have
noticed a decrease in cases of violence and a significant reduction in complaints, which
makes me start to sleep a little. I thank Living Peace Institute and CARITAS and I ask them
to continue to support men to promote positive masculinity in several villages and localities
of my entity because peace is gradually being restored.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key Challenges and Mitigations with regard to the objective at community level</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; Especially the Covid19 context has made it difficult to stick to the initial planning, which
included a workshop to be held in DRC in October 2020, followed by filming in
January/February 2021. These timeframes were premature, considering extensive
lockdowns that are applicable in Europe since late 2020, the vaccination campaign that
progresses but is not yet causing a &#x2018;tipping point&#x2019; for infection rates, and international travel
restrictions (especially double quarantine that needs to be observed and significantly affects
costs and planning).
&#x2022; The Covid19 context also affects the way in which LPI is rolling out the cycles with the groups.
There are currently no large community gatherings/celebrations, whereas those types of
activities would be especially important to also capture with the filming.
&#x2022; Due to the measures taken by the government of the Democratic Republic of the Congo to
prevent the spread of third vague of covid-19, community celebrations were organized in
modified format. Classrooms were used to host not more than 20 persons in the strict respect
of covid-19 preventive measures such as hand washing, wearing mask and social distancing.
&#x2022; In many communities in Noth Kivu (Katindo, munzenze, Buhimba, kiziba, Kimoka, Bweremana,
Shasha and Mubambiro) community celebrations were postponed due to the Nyiragongo
volcanic eruption occurred on 22 May 2021 and earthquakes that causes the evacuation of
the population of Goma and its neighbourhoods to the small city of sake, Rwanda and
Bukavu.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 1: Individual Level: Trauma healing of individual men</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the individual level, LP aims at healing the Trauma of Individual men, ensuring that men heal from conflict and violence-related trauma in ways that are specific to their gender identities and that take into account gendered coping mechanisms. For the year 2020-2021, 198 LP psychosocial support group sessions have been implemented from February to September 2021, to directly reach 2970 men and their spouses in different community located in North and South Kivu as well as Ituri Province (see the distribution of participants per targeted groups).
&#x2022; 330 men have been reached in 22 groups psychosocial groups of husbands of women survivors of
SGBV;
&#x2022; 660 men have been reached in 44 LP groups of the military men (22 in North and 22 in South Kivu);
&#x2022; 660 Men have been reached in 44 LP groups of the Police (22 in North and 22 South Kivu);
&#x2022; 330 Men have been reached in 22 LP groups with Men Ex-Combatants;
&#x2022; 990 Men have been reached in 66 LP Groups in high-risk zones (22 in North Kivu, 22 in the South Kivu and 22 in Ituri province.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Some testimonies of LP group participants</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.I am JV, a married man and father of 5 children living in the village of Buhimba in rural area of
Goma. My participation in the LP group helped me to give new meaning to my life. The life
destroyed by many experiences of violence of which we are directly or indirectly victims.
Experiences that had made me a very violent person towards my wife. Before I met LP, my wife
had been away at her parents for over 4 years with the children. She was no longer able to handle
my behavior. I was no longer providing food for the family; I was no longer paying the rent for
the house, which caused her to be driven out of the house. I was finishing everything I earned in
alcoholic drinks. At the second session, while the others were sharing their experiences, I was forced
to share mine as well. By listening to the advice and experience of other group members in the
different meetings, until the 9th session, I took the decision to bring my wife back to my home, I
asked her to forgive me for all the insults, blows and injuries that she suffered from me innocently,
and from then on we were reconciled.&#x201D;

2.&#x201C;I am P5 participant from &#xAB;Mapendo&#xBB; group at SAIO village in Nyakasanza district. Before LP I
developed hatred towards my father for long time because when I accidentally impregnated a girl,
he cursed me and abandoned me. I struggled alone without any assistance. Today, I have 4 children but no one among them knows his grandfather. My decision was not to speak to my father any
longer, but also my children should never visit him. This group thought me to overcome the hatred.
I met my father after many years and discussed with him about the experience. I&#x2019;m now reconciled
with my father and I&#x2019;m planning to go with the children so that they can approach their
grandfather...</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome Indicator 1.2.1. Reports of men&#x2019;s reduced use and abuse of alcohol and drugs</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alcohol abuse and use of drugs are one of the harmful mechanisms used by men when they are attempting to reduce extreme stress and hiding their vulnerability. As it is shown on the figure below, the participation in LP psychosocial support group is reveled to be accompanied with significant changes of these behaviors.  for the year 2020-2021,  the use of alcohol to forget problems decreased from 50% to
7.8% among LP psychosocial groups participants. The use of cannabis to forget problems decreased from 34.1% to 4.2%.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 1.1.3: Percentage of men who attended more than 70% of sessions of LP program
psychosocial group sessions for men</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Changes in behaviors, perceptions and attitudes result in regular participation in psychosocial support
groups. The more the individual participates in psychosocial group sessions, the more the likelihood to get positive changes. For the year 2020-2021, 2788 LP participants representing 93.9% attended more than 70% of the whole program.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome Indicator 1.3.1. Reports (from men and women participants) of improved positive coping skills
among participating men</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coping strategies are different ways in which people respond to stress and are predictor of individual&#x2019;s
mental health. Differences in mental health responses are likely be influenced by differences in individuals&#x2019; use of various coping strategies. The participation in LP psychosocial group helped participant to reduce of use of unhealthy coping strategies such as fighting with other, fighting with their spouses, beating their children, getting out in the cabaret to drink alcohol with friends, looking for girls or women for sexual intercourse and the improvement of the use of health coping strategies such as seeking advice from important others, talking to the wife to find a solution and doing sport to calm down anger and frustration. For the year 2020-2021,  an improvement in coping strategies was observed among LP psychosocial support group participants. Going to church when feel distressed or frustrated increased from 28.4 % to 62.9%, seeking advice from a trustworthy person increased from 30.1% to 72.7%, talking to his wife to find a solution increased from 27.5% to 81.4%.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Identification of Partners to Implement Living Peace Program in Communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the year 2020-2021, Living Peace Institute has been partnering with local Civil Society organizations and International nongovernmental organization for the implementation of the living peace methodology, VSLA and Community Campaign. Local implementing partners are Caritas Goma, Heal Africa, Institut Sup&#xE9;rieur Du Lac (ISL), Kivu Men and Centre Rafiki. International nongovernmental organization are Mobile Cinema and La Benevolencija. A Memorandum of Understanding was signed in December 2020 between the Living Peace Institute and the local partners. The various areas of intervention were identified regarding the MONUSCO priority zone and the outstanding issues regarding the level of violence identified in the communities. For year 2020-2021 LP program was implemented in 34 communities in 11 Health zones). Five health zones in the North Kivu (Masisi,Mweso, Kirotche, Kalisimbi and Nyiragongo), four health zones in South Kivu (Bagira, Ibanda, Lemera and
Walungu) and two healthzones  in Ituri (Bunia and Nizi).</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 1.1.1: Number of Master trainers trained in delivering LP methodology</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In order to attain its objectives, LPI relays on a pool of master trainers to fulfil the assignment of Living peace project for the second phase of the implementation. For the year 2020-2021, LPI renewed the contracts of 9 master trainers and recruited 3 new ones. The overall responsibility of master trainers is to provide training, mentorship and clinical supervision to LPI local partners in different areas of interventions. LPI master trainers were trained on delivering LP methodology/approach notably the training on gender, violence and trauma, the training on LP methodology, group dynamic and group facilitation, the training on technical and clinical supervision and the training on monitoring and evaluation. Before the beginnings of the second round of LP psychosocial groups, the same refresher trainings were organized on behalf of LP master trainers.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 1.1.2. Number of targeted men attended LP program gender-specific psychosocial group education sessions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">LP psychosocial support group program is based on the principles of therapeutic groups and group dynamics. Group sessions are held on a weekly basis and extend on fifteen consecutive weeks under the guide of group facilitators. During session, different topic are discussed to help participants to gain more insight on the problems which hinder their personal, family and community life and reflection on effective ways of resolving them.  For the year 2020-2021, 2970 LP participants were identified to form 198 groups. 1650 participants who represent 55.6% are in North Kivu, 990 participants who represent 33.3 % are in South Kivu and 330 participants who represent 11.1 % are in Ituri province. The Husband of SGBV survivor represent 11,1% of all participants, the men in uniform are representing 44.4 % (Military men 22% and policemen 22% respectively), the participant living in the high-risk zone are representing 33.3 % while the ex-combatants and ex-child soldiers are representing 11.1 % of all participants. The average age of men is 40.2-year-old whereas the average age for women is 33.4year old. The statistic shows that the LP participants are responsible of 15052 children. The average child by family is 5. The average rate of participation is evaluated at 93.6%. This means on the total number of 2970 participant expected at each session, 2780 participants were present. 

*LP methodology includes a GBV focused component to help men to reflect on their own experiences of
violence as witnesses, authors or victims. GBV focused sessions are 5th, 6th, 7th and 8th session. This component helps LP group participants to get clear understating not only of different forms of violence that are happening in their families, their consequences and that they have to make the first step in behavior change if they want to contribute to the breaking of the cycle of violence. For the year 2020-2021, participant representing 84.3 % participated in the 5th session, 1394 men representing 93.8% participated in the 6th session, 1376 men representing 92.6 % participated in the 7th session whereas 1377 men, representing 92.7% participated in the 8th session. The average rate of participation in GSBV specific session is 93.3%.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="XI-IATI-LPI-0002" indicator-uri="https://livingpeaceinstitute.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 1.1.1. Number of men who reduced mental health problems</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">LP psychosocial support program includes 15 weekly sessions conducted by trained facilitators that are
members of the communities where the LPI program is implemented. Sessions include content on (1) sharing problems and experiences, (2) coping with emotions and stress, (3) dealing with problems and difficulties, and (4) restoring trust in others; all of which focus on men&#x2019;s specific needs in dealing with trauma and transforming coping strategies (including use of SGBV). Improved mental health (reduction of symptoms of depression/PTSD) among LP beneficiaries is one of the expected outcome at individual level. the participation in LP psychosocial support group is reveled to be associated with the reduction of symptoms of psychological distress and the improvement of positive mental health precursors. For example, feeling health and strong improved from 31.9 % to 61.9%, quality of sleep improved from 26.6 % to 59.6%, enjoying life improved from 27.3% to 65.9%, ability to love and take care of others increased from 16.8% to 64.1%. On the other side, persistent headaches and/or body aches decreased from 22.2% to 2.9%, bad thoughts related to pas experiences decreased from 23.4% to 8.1% and feeling stressed and restless at home decreased from 40.3% to 10.3%.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome Indicator1.4.1 Reports (from men and women participants) of improved trust and confidence in
others, stronger social cohesion in the community and a restored sense of belongingness among participating men</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trust, confidence in others, social cohesion and sense of belongingness are key elements for a successful family and social life. LP participants are feeling to be more respectful and integrated
into their community after joining LP psychosocial support group sessions. Before joining LP groups only 43% of LP participating men were filling respected within the community 45.2% of them participated with other member of the community in economic activities, 45% was consulted by the members of their communities in case of disputes. After joining Living peace psychosocial support group sessions,  76.1% of participant men said that they are feeling that they are more respectful, 73.8% said that they are now participating with other members of their communities into the economic activities while 69.9% said they are consulted by other members of the community in the event of disputes.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lessons learned</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; During the period of volcanic eruption, intense earthquakes and the evacuation of the population of
Goma, may people experienced severe emotional distress symptoms such as intense fear, sleep
disturbances, irritable mood and angry outbursts, having low or no energy, excessive drinking. The
Psychological debriefing sessions helped LPI staff to cope effectively and recover from those
symptoms. This practice was extended to LP group facilitators during refresher trainings.
&#x2022; Building the strong partnership with both military and police authorities at different level is very
helpful to face challenges of working with men in uniform.
&#x2022; LP approach built bonds of solidarity which have been helpful during the period of volcanic eruption,
intense earthquakes and the evacuation of the population of Goma. Beneficiaries of Living peace
Group who were rung away because of volcanic eruption and earthquakes were received by the
families of their fellow living peace beneficiaries of Sake city and LPI staff in Gisenyi and Bukavu.
&#x2022; The participation in security sub-cluster and reinforcement of collaboration between interveners and
other field actors helped LP staff to face insecurity.
&#x2022; Former participants of the Previous LP group sessions have become facilitators of group sessions to
help other members of their communities in the process of change.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key Challenges and Mitigations during the Implementation of the LP Groups in 2020-2021 (with
regard to Objective One: At individual level)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; The Covid -19 pandemic provoked the delay of about 3 months the launch of the activities for the
year 2020-2021. Even thought LPI was ready since October 2020 to launch activities in different
communities, this event took place in January 2021, when the cases of covid-19 contamination have
significantly decreased in almost all the provinces of the DRC. Before January 2021, LPI important
meeting with partners were organised virtually using videoconference.
&#x2022; Current security situation, which is unpredictable, is the main challenge in the implementation of the
project. For example in Kanii village located in Masisi health zone in north kivu the continuous clashes
between the APCLS rebels and the FARDC caused psychosis in the population and affected both
participant identification and group process.
&#x2022; In ngungu and St Benoit villages, during the identification of participants, some people had difficulty
accepting interviews with facilitators because of fear and mistrust in the communities.
&#x2022; In nyiragongo health zone the fear and insecurity caused by the murder of the Ambassador of Italy
in DRC on 22 nd February 2021 delayed the process of identification of beneficiaries and the
launch of psychosocial group session in that zone.
&#x2022; The insecurity in ituri delayed the launch of LP group participants identification and LP group sessions.
At iga Barriere, the 3rd group session was postponed due to a great panic and fear following the
fire of heavy weapons which are heard in the village of Lokpa 6 kilometers from Iga-barriere.
&#x2022; Due to the nature of the military and police service, military and police participants arrive in group
session with a considerable delay.
&#x2022; In communities affected by armed conflict and insecurity such as Ngungu, st Benoit, Iga barriere,
there is a fear of giving the true and complete identity. Some participants show symptoms of severe
psychological trauma and would require individual and specialized psychological support
&#x2022; The interethnic conflict and murder between the Nande and Bakumu Communities in Nyiragongo
territory which arose on 11th April 2021 and lasted about a week has affected the organisation of
technical supervision of LP groups gathering in Kiziba and Buhimba.
&#x2022; The eruption of the volcano Nyiragongo on 22nd May 2021 and the the identification of
earthquakes resulting to volcanic activities during the period from 22nd to 27th May and the decision
of the Congolese government to evacuate the whole population of Goma and its neighbourhoods to
the small city of sake, Rwanda and Bukavu delayed the Refresher Training for both Master trainers
and LP Group facilitators, thus delaying the launch of the second round of LP Psychosocial support
groups in different community.
&#x2022; Deterioration of the security situation in the areas of intervention (possible factors: activism of
armed groups, sporadic attacks, looting and theft, etc.) or even reduction of humanitarian activities following clashes between the loyalist army and armed groups in this area context of &#x201C;Etat de
si&#xE8;ge&#x201D; in Ituri and in the North Kivu.
&#x2022; In May 18, 2021, the Director of LPI took part, in an important meeting organized by the new
military Governor of the province of North Kivu with humanitarian actors, through UNOCHA. The
new Governor has promised a permanent communication with the Humanitarian Coordination team
on the temporary operational zones in which humanitarian movements will have to be limited, and
thus avoid collateral civilian / humanitarian damage during attacks of the National Army on the
militias. A communication approach is therefore being put in place to prevent humanitarians from
being taken apart or unwittingly participating in the war.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 5. Promoting women socio-economic empowerment with
positive support of husbands through women&#x2019;s participation in Village
Savings and Loan Associations (VSLAs) and men&#x2019;s participation into the
Living peace program enriched with select topics from the journey of
transformation program.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women socio-economic empowerment is achieved through the implementation on VSLA in Katindo
military camp, Munzenze and Mugunga police camps. Potential beneficiaries are spouses of military
and policemen how participated in LP psychosocial support groups. The primary purpose of a VSLA is to provide simple savings and loan facilities, in a community that does not have access to formal financial services. Loans can also provide a form of selfinsurance to members, supplemented by a social fund which provides small but important grants to members in distress. VSLAs are implemented in tree main phases. The Preparatory phase, which consists of providing general information to local leaders and prospective VSLA members covered the 3 first weeks of February 2021. The Intensive phase that lasts approximately 14 weeks started on the 22 nd of February with consecutive training meetings aiming at helping the Association elects its leaders, establishes its constitution and sets out the rules and procedures that govern financial activities. It then continues to meetings, in which the Association learns to manage social fund, share-purchase/savings and loan transactions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Some testimonies of VSLA beneficiaries</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.&#x201C;My name is LB. I am a spouse of a soldier and mother of 7 children. I received the information
of the group VSLA from my husband. Spouses of LP former participants are going to be group
into VLAS. The changes I saw in my husband were a motivation for me. I thought to myself that
the group that transformed my husband also has good things for me. I sell various articles:
Clothes, cups, dishes ...etc. before I was only selling to eat. I had no idea about saving. In the
AVEC we are taught to save. I hope that during these 9 months, I will have some money to help
me. Before my husband did not show me the money, but now he shows his salary and we plan
together. Today when I did not make more profit to find the contribution, he supports me and
gives me shares to pay into the VSLA. Before, when I had a loss, I had difficulties to find the
capital, but through this group AVEC, I ask for a credit because I know that I will not have
difficulties to pay because I am supported by her husband. I thank Living Peace because since
we are in the VSLA, we are valued. We have now an address. We, the wives of the military
and police were neglected. Everywhere we went we were called thieves. Nobody could trust us
and give us his money. Today we ask for loan in our VSLA and we pay them properly. LP made
us a family. We have found a new family, which assists us in case of problems and this
encourages me because we become one family&#x201D;.

2.&#x201C;My name is FB. I am the wife of a policeman and I am the mother of 8 children. Before joining
the VSLA I saw other women developing economically but I didn&apos;t know why. VSLA helped me
to discover that you can never develop by closing yourself up. I understood that by saving
1000 fc, I can earn a lot. I can even get a loan to do small business like other women. Before,
I used to play with money. But today I have understood that even 1000 francs is a lot of money.
The changes are really numerous. Since I joined AVEC, I saved my money little by little and I
took a credit to start the small business. Now I am independent. Before I expected everything
from my husband, if he did not come, I did not eat. Without my husband&apos;s salary, there was no
life. I am not too rich but I am well in my home and my capital is growing and helping me to
meet the basic needs of the family. Participating in the AVEC groups has many advantages:
They taught us how to be clean, clothing and body hygiene, savings, education of the children.
We have become well organized moms with a vision. My husband understands well the VSLA.
Before, he used to use the money for trivial things but now when he finds, he gives me to increase the shares in the VSLA. He asks me if I have forgotten to pay the shares if he is not close. It is
himself who reminds me and motivates me&#x201D;.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output indicators 5.1.1: Number of field officers trained in the VSLA approach to support existing and
to create new VSLAs in target communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the year 2020-2021 LPI trained 2 field officers and 6 field agents on VSLA implementation and
supervision. The trainings focused on how to undertake effective community mobilizations towards the
formation of a VSLA, to ensure that community leaders understand the intervention and its contribution
to their respective communities, to secure the commitment of the VSLA members in the communities to
form and run VSLA, equip VSLA members with knowledge and skills to effectively manage and
benefit from a VSLA, to inculcate the savings culture among VSLA members, inculcate a culture of
planning and savings for emergencies, to ensure effective functionality and operations of VSLA.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 5.3.1: Number of Men and Women members of VSLAs attending the training on
cross-cutting issues which include sexual and reproductive health and rights and sexual and gender based violence (SRHR &amp; SGBV).</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the year 2020-2021 LPI trained 60 women from 30 VSLA groups on cross cutting issues including: gender stereotypes and norms, Sexual and Reproductive Health and Rights (SRHR) and Sexual and
Gender-Based Violence (VSBG), power relations and decision-making in the home, joint management
of economic affairs and many others. Participants in this trained were reinforced in how to organize
a group communication aiming at behavior and attitude change. Those women are working with
Field Agents to engage other VSLA members in discussions to generate communication leading to
awareness of their problems, thus initiating a process of critical reflection to find effective solutions.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lessons Learned</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Military and police families have understood the benefits of VSLA. This was shown by the
fact that after the VSLA activities resumed, they suggested to verse tree shares in order to
fill the gap created by the suspension of activities.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 5.1.2. Number of VSLAs groups of women organized and fully functioning in selected
communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to the formation of VSLA groups, centre Rafiki, in collaboration with LPI and ISL organized
sensitization campaigns on behalf military and police authorities, women and their husbands to raise
their awareness on the services offered by the VSLA, and detailed description of how a VSLA works
and its link with the LP psychosocial targeting men; what people have to do to participate and the
role of the implementing organization.  8 Military authorities, 8 police authorities and 60 community
leaders were sensitized on the role of VSLA in women&#x2019;s socio-economic empowerment, poverty reduction and family well being.  375 military men and 375  policemen were sensitized about the importance of supporting women socio-economic empowerment and how the women participation in VSLA can change not only the wellbeing of the woman but also make more lighter the burden of  financial responsibilities most of time carried by husbands alone. For the year 2020-2021 LPI, in collaboration with Centre Rafiki Identified 750 spouses of military and policemen to be organized in 30 Village Savings and Loan Associations (VSLA). 375 VSLA members are spouses of military men in Katindo military camp whereas 225 are spouses of Policemen in Munzenze police camp while 150 are spouses of policemen in Mugunga police camp. The VSLA cycle started from February 2021 and will end in November 2021. Alongside with VSLA activities, members of VSLA benefit from the discussion on cross cutting issues aiming at engaging men as positive allies of their spouses&#x2019; socio-economic empowerment. VSLAs are implemented in tree main phases. For  The cycle of the VSLA in the period of 2020-2021, members were able to mobilize the amount of 73,759,000 Congolese franc as savings. These amount generated 8,171,960 Congolese francs of interest and the capacity for groups member to have access to credit. In general the reimbursement rate is satisfactory at 93 percent.  During the pre-operation period and during the whole cycle, VSLA members receive trainings on how to run and manage an income generating activity. The total sum of revenue in the treasurer of VSLA is evaluated at 92,578,660 Congolese francs. The VSLA shares cumulative values is 73 759 000 Congolese francs, cumulative solidarity value is 10557100, cumulative loans allowed to VSLA members is evaluated at 78996500, cumulative interest value is 8171960 Congolese francs and, cumulative fines value is 90600 Congolese francs. Members of VSLA (Military and Police wives), created and strengthened  business from the credit they get from their own savings. In general, 32 businesses were created: 12 by spouses of Police and 20 by spouses of Military. Their investments were target the market of Shoes, Clothes, Drink, Energy, Food and multiple articles.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key Challenges and Mitigations during the implementation of the LP Groups (with regard to
Objective 5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; The lack of trust in military and police communities, the poor understanding of military and
police spouses, the types of marriage (Yaka to fanda) and the total dependence on the
husbands&#x2019; salary are obstacles to the women&#x2019;s participation in VSLA.
&#x2022; Due to the Nyiragongo volcanic eruption occurred on 22 May 2021 and earthquakes that
causes the evacuation of the population of Goma and its neighborhoods to the small city of
sake, Rwanda and Bukavu, VSLA activities were suspended for two weeks.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
