<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-CAR-19/HCF10/SA2/HLT-NUT-PROT/INGO/14286</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Emergency health, nutrition and protection services to conflict affected communities in Birao, Central African Republic</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps (IMC) is an US-registered independent affiliate organization of International Medical Corps UK (IMC UK), with which IMC UK shares the same name and charitable objectives and mission. IMC UK will engage IMC to implement its programs in the field, with IMC UK oversight, according to the terms and conditions of any agreement that results from this proposal and the terms of the parties&#x2019; administrative service agreement. IMC maintains a branch office in Croatia, that provides administrative and operational support to IMC UK and to the programs on the ground, including but not limited to financial management, procurement management/international procurements, and logistics.
 IMC has been operating in Vakaga prefecture since 2007, providing basic primary health care including nutrition. Currently IMC has received funding from CAR EU Trust Fund (Bekou) for 24 months (from August 2018 to June 2020) to provide services in 20 health facilities in the Vakaga health Districts, working with the MOH, strengthening the health system through capacity building of the Health District Senior Management Team. 
With funding from HF, IMC intends to implement this project over a seven-month period, in Birao town, providing integrated services to estimate 11,812 displaced people as response to the armed conflicts that occurred in September 2019, and currently living in MUNISCA IDPs site (10,000 IDPs), and estimate 1312 persons located at Birao airstrip in addition to 500 people living with host families in Birao town. At present, under the Bekou funding IMC set up a clinic in the MUNISCA IDPs site in Birao to provide basic primary health care and emergency nutrition services. For the current acute phase of the emergency, IMC is providing minimum health and nutrition services in the IDP camps in Birao, therefore, HF funding is requested to continue the provision these emergency services in coordination with respective clusters:   
Health: provide life-saving primary healthcare services that include basic RH services, vaccinations against preventable diseases, prevention and treatment of communicable diseases, referral to Birao Hospital and provision of disease surveillance services as well as awareness raising on communicable diseases 
Nutrition: The proposed program falls within the key priorities of the Nutrition Cluster to provide treatment of acute malnutrition for children 6-59 months, pregnant, lactating women, and other vulnerable groups and an infant and young child feeding intervention. 
Protection: The protection sector will aim to prevent and respond to gender based violence (GBV) to save lives of survivors by providing medical services and psychosocial support to minimise the impact of trauma, raise awareness on the negative impact of GBV, conduct referrals to clinical treatment, encourage and train communities on the importance of respecting the 72 hour period benchmark to seek treatment to reduce rape impact and provide training on GBV concepts and psychological first aid.  Women friendly spaces will be set up to provide access information and services. A referral system will be reinforced, and rape survivors will have access to CMR and psychological first aid and non-medical case management from GWFS. 
Coordination: The three sector programs will coordinate with the Health District office and ACTED, and other local NGO s to ensure that activities are developed in engaging the community regarding social behaviors change focusing on the improvement in the utilization of health services and encouraging health seeking behaviors.  
Exit strategy: as security improves the emergency response of IMC will be gradually transferred to Birao Health District, the remaining displaced population in the sites will be encouraged to seek care in this hospital as long as the distance between the iDPs site and the hospital is less than 300 m (5-minute walk).IMC will encourage the Health District to take over MMU sites.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-CAR17-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-CAR17" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAR Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Christian Mulamba</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+23675795350</telephone>
   <email>cmulamba@internationalmedicalcorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="53">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vakaga</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.33330000 22.75000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-10">85141.38</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-10">516524.35</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="CAR17-14286">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-10">601665.73</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-CAR17-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-CAR17" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAR Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1800674465">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-13">240666.28</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-CAR17-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-CAR17" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAR Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1800682615">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-17">240666.38</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-CAR17-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-CAR17" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAR Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1800687149">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-26">120330.23</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-CAR17-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-CAR17" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAR Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAR BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-CAR17-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
