<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-000025</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NLO ML Gover and Acc</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The program aims to contribute to the challenge and the national effort to restore peace and stability in Mali desired by all people, especially those from 22 municipalities in the regions of Timbuktu and Gao, Mopti and Segou of more 700 000 people. The levers used in this program for a significant impact are improving local governance and strengthening groups of citizens, especially youth, to participate in political, socio-economic and cultural activities of their communities.

 Overall goal:
# Sustaining a movement (culture) of citizens active and involved in governance, peace and social justice, economic and political

 1.1. The program objectives
The program will pursue the achievement of the following three specific objectives:
# To help improve political participation and performance checks and citizens (young men and women) for accountable and transparent governance by the authorities (state, local and traditional);
# Support the socio-economic development of young people and women by spaces and devices vocational training, support for employment, entrepreneurship and securing peasant farming;
# Contribute to install and maintain a culture of peace and social cohesion in local companies by local mechanisms for conflict resolution and management of natural resources.

Through these objectives, the program aims to help change attitudes and practices of the various stakeholders who are involved in the accountable local governance, peace and security of livelihood (employment, entrepreneurship, and peasant farming).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl/Mission-and-vision">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-01-12"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
