<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-04460-02:NE</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sirba Sesame Oil Value Chain Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In November 2014, as part of the exploratory phase of the program B4D Oxfam in Niger, during a meeting of contact between the FCMN Niya and the head of B4D program, sesame was identified among cultures rents which are a niche market in Niger. Then between December 2014 and January 2015 two meetings were held to reflect on a possible project on sesame in the department Gotheye where previous projects have led to notable results in the production, marketing and processing of sesame. The idea of a project to consolidate the achievements restraint, FCMN Niyya and Oxfam have agreed to work on the sesame oil value chain, which is promising for the creation of income and employment. Thus, a diagnostic study was conducted to update the information on the sesame value chain in the area of intervention of the union Bonkaney Sirba, main peasant organization active on this CVA at the town Gotheye.

Indeed, the commune Gotheye is one of the two communes of the department of Gotheye, a young entity create at the last administrative division in Niger. Ithas a population of 93,264 inhabitants including 48,454 women and 44,810 men (Final results RGPH 2012). Located between the southwestern parts of the region of Tillabery and Eastern Gotheye department, the municipality of Gotheye has huge advantages in terms agro- pastoral sylvo-. Exploitable relatively fertile land and the Niger River and two of its tributaries Sirba and Dargol facilitate agricultural production under rainfall and irrigation.
The main crops grown in the area are: millet, sorghum, cowpea and sorrel. But women generally grouped into farmer organizations produce sesame, okra, bambara groundnut and groundnut. They also practice in the dry season gardening while most men will remain on the site Samira gold or in neighboring countries (Ghana, Ivory Coast and Nigeria).

It is in this context that the union Sirba Bonkaney was created in 2002 to promote the sesame sector for the benefit of its memberswho are more than 80% of women. Also, she has focused on increasing yields and marketing organization for producers. At the time, sesame cultivation was practiced around the boxes and was used for family consumption mainly as seasoning. The average area per farmer was 0,3ha.
With the two phases of the project PADEFS (2002- 2008) the union is well positioned in the sesame sector in the area. Two new varieties (white sudan and S42) introduced for earliness and high yields have found a prominent place near the Sesame colorful &quot;appointed Sirba&quot; and considered local variety in the area. Production techniques have improved and marketing is better organized in the union. It seems that the production of sesame has greatly increased and yields have improved significantly going from 200kg /ha to over 500kg / ha. Currently the production of sesame mobilizes 82% of women against 18% of men respectively operated 0,63ha average of 1.13 ha.
The sesame oil extraction is undoubtedly the greatest innovation of PADEFS. Started during the second phase of theproject, it has proven to be a new source of income for women. The traditional method, the transformation of sesame oil has advanced to a semi-scale technology that has helped to alleviate women&apos;s tasks. However, it seems that this activity is not profitable because of several factors including the relatively high production cost and low demand for the product because of the High oil prices (5000 to 8000 FCFA). Regarding the high cost of production, it is explained by the strong fluctuations in the price of sesame and thepoor performance of mining equipment that does not allow optimum exploitation. At market level, it should be noted that sesame oil produced by women of the union Bonkaney Sirba, because of the quality of the product and its presentation remains uncompetitive compared with exotic oils and / or imported therapeutic. However, its price is affordable compared to other oils (Moringa, Neem, ...) promoted by other local organizations.
This project aims to consolidate the achievements of earlier projects supporting women to conquer the local market by offering a higher quality production. This will undoubtedly at the economic empowerment of the union Sirba Bonkaney and promotion of the sesame sector in the area.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F&#xE9;d&#xE9;ration des Coop&#xE9;ratives Mara&#xEE;ch du Niger (FCMN-Niya)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 1994 eleven horticulture producers# co-operative set up the Association of Market Garden Producers (APROMANI), to counter the lack of attention paid to them by the National Union of Co-operatives and the marketing problems of agriculture products theyencountered.
In 1996 APROMANI became the Federation of Market Gardeners of Niger (FCMN). It was registered in 1998. Until 2001 its activitieswere based at its executive office, mainly related to structuring the co-operatives. Since 2001 it has had a cadres specialised in agriculture who provide a sustained technical assistance.
From 2001 to 2007 FCMN has worked with three-year strategic plans and annual operational plans. A self-analysis of the organisation has identified gaps in reforms for women#s leadership in the Federation#s co-operatives. It currently has 118 members from all over the country, with a total of 30,000 individual members, of whom 9,000 are women.
Since its founding the Federation has initiated structuring activities to strengthen its organisation, including 27 shops forinputs, one pilot centre for marketing fruits and vegetables in Niamey, 120 field workers and six sites for producing onion seeds. It strives to contribute actively to the development of the horticulture sector andfood security in Niger through integrated activities, like the cereal banks supporting schools and health centres, as well as school gardens/
The organisation#s mission is to contribute to improving the living conditions of market garden producers, and tostrengthening their production capacities and the guarantee of proper prices. Its vision is of an autonomous structure of, for and by market gardeners.
The institutional objects are (a) to seek solution to the problems in production, the supply of inputsand agricultural materials, product marketing, funding, and trainingof members, and (b) to promote the capacities of the market gardeners# organisations in Niger to become a force for mobilising local resources and advocacy.
In order to realise its mission FCMN organises its intervention around the following strategic themes: supply of agricultural inputs, support and advice (training, working out training materials, organisation of producers and capacity building of their organisations), production, marketing, food security, fundraising and management.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-20" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-20" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to a sustainable livelihood</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="33110" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-14">70000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-06-01">49000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">F&#xE9;d&#xE9;ration des Coop&#xE9;ratives Mara&#xEE;ch du Niger (FCMN-Niya)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-09-01">21000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">F&#xE9;d&#xE9;ration des Coop&#xE9;ratives Mara&#xEE;ch du Niger (FCMN-Niya)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-06-01">-14</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">F&#xE9;d&#xE9;ration des Coop&#xE9;ratives Mara&#xEE;ch du Niger (FCMN-Niya)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-06-01">49000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-09-01">21000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-06-01">-14</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-04460-02:NE">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007154"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Niger (SAWA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-04460"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Sirba Sesame Oil Value Chain Project"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men (small-scale crop farmers, cattle farmers, fisher folk) able to use sustainable production methods enabling them to better protect and use sustainably their livelihood resources</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">001-02</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Female AIM1 DAB 001</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="001-02" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-04-20" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="300"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-04-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">001-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Male AIM1 DAB 001</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="001-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-04-20" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="140"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-04-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men (small-scale crop farmers, cattle farmers, fisher folk) able to use sustainable production methods enabling them to better protect and use sustainably their livelihood resources</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">001-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="001-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-04-20" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-04-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
