<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-04281-02:KH</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SRK Value Chain Development in Pursat</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Srer Khmer means Field of Cambodia, a local NGO dedicated to the support of sustainable socio-economic development through research, training, education and community development by promoting participatory learning, farmer-led activities, farmers networking, sustainable agriculture, and natural resources management. Srer Khmer was established and registered with Ministry of Interior on 09 January 2002.
This year, SK receives funding from 11 donors including Sea Rice (from Philippine), NTFP, NPA, OA, CAVAC, Plan In#t, Agrisud, FAO (end), MoWA (end), CRY, and HARVEST-USAID.

Srer Khmer is currently implementing its operations in 4 provinces including Kompong Speu, Pursat, Kompong Thom and Siem Reap. Extension of SRI techniques to Improve Farmer Resilience (ESRI-IFR) is one of SK#s projects supported by Oxfam America, implementing in 2 provinces: Kompong Speu and Pursat. Based on the organization chart, the project is managed by Project Manager under the management support of Senior Program Support Officer, Head of Operations, and Executive Director from head office in Phnom Penh. There are 8 staff for the project (1 Project Manager, 3 Project Officers, 2 Farmer Trainers,and 2 part time staff).

In Pursat province, 3 project officers report to projectmanager, and project manager report to senior program support officer, while in Kompong Speu, 2 farmer trainers report directly to senior program support officer. There is only one finance function at the Head Office (Phnom Penh) to give finance and administrative support to the provinces.

Srer Khmer have initiative the project GALS application in Vegetable Value Chain in Pursat# submit to Oxfam while main focus on:

1. Gender Action Learning System (GALS) application
2. Community mobilization and empowerment
3. Agricultural Cooperative Formation
4. Initiative Businessesideas and Opportunity

The aims of project:  The existing poor women and men group are empowered to step into the entrepreneurship for particular improvement of household economic to address the issues above in two ways:

The specific objectives:

a. To empower group of women prepare the effectiveness of community enterprise for small-scale producers and selling group to set up the real business.
b. To take advantage of small-scale farmer#s income in vegetable and agriculture product through promoting better linkage and access to the local markets.

The expected results:

# 76 group members (70% are women) from 5 villages are conducted refresher and reflection on marketdemand, technical, and challenge of implementation of agriculture input selling.
# Two groups from vegetable and agriculture input selling formed as agriculture cooperative, at least one of business plan per each group are set for implementation.
# Twovegetable groups formed as saving group by used saving for change model
# Lessons learned, experiences, successes/failures related to the business model are well-documented in Khmer langue and shared with other relevant stakeholders, especially farmers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Background and Capability of Srer Khmer
Srer Khmer means Field of Cambodia, a local NGO dedicated to the support of sustainable socio-economic development through research, training, education and community development by promoting participatory learning, farmer-led activities, farmers networking, sustainable agriculture, and natural resources management.
VISION
Farming communities and community development workers must have the capacity, rights and ownership in making decision on any issues that are relevant to sustain their living.

MISSION
Srer Khmer, in recognition of farmers&apos; rights and community development workers to learn, use and manage theirown community resources and participate in any decision related to their livelihood, is committed to providing farmers opportunities to gain knowledge and strengthen their capacity to lead and manage their lives through participatory learning approaches which build on understanding the fundamental relationship between agriculture, environment and rural societies.

GOAL
Farmers and community development workers having increased control of their lives based on a mastery of ecological and social knowledge and skill.
To achieve this mission and goal, Srer Khmer works in close cooperation with relevantfarmers groups, government institutions and other NGOs based on the values of honesty, equity, positive encouragement, gender equity and responsibility. Specially, Srer Khmer works with Farmer Trainers as main partners in developing broad farmer-to-farmertraining activities in the areas of ecological agriculture and livelihood related issues. Farmer Trainers have played an important role in organizing farmer meetings and follow-up training activities. Key government district IPM trainers have been contacted to support these activities as a technical advisor to Farmer Trainers.

Establishment, Legal Status and Award
Srer Khmer was established and registered with the Ministry of Interior of the Royal Government of Cambodia and the local authorities on January 9, 2002 by a group of former staff of FAO Community IPM Program. The FAO project started in Cambodia in 1996 and ended in late 2001, therefore, to continue the activity of community based integrated pest management (IPM) Farmer Field Schools, a proven approach to successful ecological learning and farmer networking, Srer Khmer was the response to the need to further build on the work of FAO and facilitate the work of farmers-led activities.

Srer Khmer is certified by NGO Code Compliance Committeeof NGO Good Practice Project (NGO GPP) to award the NGO good practices project certificate. This award meant that NGO GPP recognizes and appreciates Srer Khmer&apos;s efforts in complying with all standards and being role model NGO in Cambodia. To learn moregoto www.ccc-cambodia.org.

Organizational Structure and Management
The basic elements of Srer Khmer&apos;s organizational structure and the management are as follows:
- A Board of Directors which oversees and sets policy including Srer Khmer Statutes, Personnel Policy, Financial Policy for the organization, meets every four months to monitor Srer Khmer#s activities and give feedback to the Executive Director who is responsible to the Board. The current Board has seven members and have 3 times meeting per year. However, the extraordinary meetings can call from any members if necessary take action on urgent matters should the need arise.

- The Executive Director is responsibility for all day-to-day activities, programs, projects and staff.

- The Management Committee consists of the Executive Director, Programme Manager and the Admin/Finance Manager has the role of coordinating and assisting the Executive Director with day-to-day activities.

- The Technical Coordination Committee (TCC) consisted of Executive Director, Programme Manager, Programme Officers, Project Managers and Admin/Finance Unit. TCC has the role of providing inputs on technical issues. TCC has at least 2 times meeting per year to set technical guideline for Srer Khmer.

Staffing
At the moment, Srer Khmer has more than 50 full time staff members including technical staff, support staff and graduate (intern) trainees. Most of them were based in the project based in the provinces. Fifteen (15) of them are women. Srer Khmer also has1Volunteer from Australia Volunteers to assist withprogram/organization development. Srer Khmer used to have more than 10 Australian Volunteers from AVI, VIDA and AYAD to work with us from the past.

Apart from staff, we also have a network of well-trained farmer trainers at the provincial, district, commune, andvillage levels where we can call upon for providing training at their respective communities.

Program Thematic Areas (2011 # 2015):
1. Sustainable Agriculture and Land Resources Rights
2.Natural Resources Management and Livelihoods
3. Climate Changes Adaptation and DRR
4. Agri-Business and Value Chains
5. Training, Research and Consultancy to support small provincial NGOs.

Srer Khmer plays a role as Service Provider. Training on topics related to FFS/post-FFS, FLS, Socio-economic analysis, living soil, integrated homestead production, insect ecology, farmer association management, business planning, participatory marketing study, project management,participatory monitoring andevaluation, knowledge management, Training of Trainers, and other topics related ecological agricultureand community/rural development, etc., Participatory research and analysis and Project review and evaluation.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Srer Khmer</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-15" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to a sustainable livelihood</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="3" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="33110" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-08-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-27">13753</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-09-01">13753</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Gov. Co-funding(MFS TFSN)</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Srer Khmer</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-09-01">13753</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-04281-02:KH">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000123" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007251"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Cambodia (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-04281"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Women in Value Chain and Agri-business"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men (small-scale farmers) using effective adaptation techniques developed by partner organisations</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">003-02</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Female AIM1 DAB 003</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="003-02" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-15" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="75"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">003-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Male AIM1 DAB 003</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="003-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-15" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="20"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men (small-scale farmers) using effective adaptation techniques developed by partner organisations</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">003-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="003-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-15" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">29</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men (women in particular) more able to protect themselves against disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">029-02</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Female AIM3 DAB 029</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="029-02" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-15" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">029-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Male AIM3 DAB 029</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="029-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-15" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">29</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men (women in particular) more able to protect themselves against disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">029-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="029-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-15" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
