<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-02582-02:LA</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policy lobby and CSOs capacity building</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the end of 2014 PADETC has achieved the following results:

Outcome I: Education for Sustainable Development
The ESD model has been further developed as a lasting contribution to development discourse in Lao PDR:
&#x95; The 6 centers and networks provide cost-recovery development services: comprising training (short and medium-term courses); practicum sites for real life demonstration and extension work; sites for exhibition and product promotion; and centers of documentation of best practices through a shared network of resource persons.
&#x95; More than 60 youth leaders from 30 youth groups have been empowered through skills training and experiential learning practices. Disadvantaged youth groups have developed leadership, life skills, English and IT competencies through cooperation with educational institutions such as SOLS/24/7 on employment skills training.
&#x95; Build capacities of 30 youth groups to produce socially relevant information for dissemination and promotion of sustainable livelihoods.
&#x95; Workshops on &#x91;sharing teaching and learning experience&#x92; among the school networks. These workshops will mainly be organized in VTE capital at least one per year for education officers (MoE, 6 provincial education offices), teachers and students from the school network.
&#x95; Organize an educational film festival event once a year.


Outcome II: Enabling Environment Support for Lao CSOs
&#x95; More than &gt;20 new NPAs (include the learning centres) are equipped with good management skills and increased awareness about good governance and accountability practices.
&#x95; Provide leadership coaching and mentoring the Lao NPAs though close collaboration with LHD &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Consortium members.
&#x95; Organize 2 forums of exchange with the networks and partners &#x91;Development Aid Effectiveness&#x92;.


Outcome III: Policy advocacy
&#x95; PADETC will develop an advocacy strategy based on its considerable experience of effective best practices to integrate the new teaching-learning method into the MoE and address issues related to land and biodiversity with the National Land Management Authority.
&#x95; PADETC participates on a regular basis in NPA/INGO sector meetings, and maintains bilateral contacts with the relevant authorities to forward its own advocacy objectives.
&#x95; PADETC, currently active in the sub-committees and National Organising Committee (NOC) for AEPF9, therefore it will monitor the implementation of outcome document of AEPF9. Similarly, PADETC will continue to support the increased ability of Lao NPAs andMO &#x91;government&#x92;  to work together.


Outcome IV: Padetc becomes a learning organisation
&#x95; Have an effective and efficient Planning,Monitoring, and Evaluation system, with the required competencies among senior management level and among field staff level.
&#x95; Havean Action Research and Monitoring unit with the capacity to analyse data and information, and capture learning for policy advocacy.
&#x95; Have a clear gender &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; diversity policy at both organisational level and in programme; with the required competencies at senior management level as well as among field staff.
&#x95; Be a role model for the emerging Lao civil society such as the Lao Youth Network, the Vientiane Youth Centre, and other similar groups that work on the empowerment of youth to promote active citizenship.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC (Participatory Development Training Centre) was officially founded in late 1996. With an initial staff of five Lao development workers (four men and one woman), PADETC#s broad objective was to promote alternative models of development aimed at helping Laos# people to find ways to improve their livelihoods in a just and sustainable way.
Prior to its founding its director and his small team of development workers had worked in various aspects of agriculture and integrated rural development in many rural communities in Laos for more than 15 years, with the support mainly from international NGOs and some UN agencies.  During the early 1980s the team#s work had focused mainly on improvement of food security in poor rural communities by promoting low-cost appropriate agriculturaltechnologies, such as use of bio-fertilisers and bio-pesticides, and integration of fish-raising in the rice fields, etc. The impetus for working on food security during that time was the need to address the problem of food shortages faced by many rural communities in the aftermath of the 30-year war of independence which ended only in 1975.  It was through working on these agriculture-related projects that the team understood that the food security of Lao rural communities could not be solely resolved through improvements in agricultural techniques, but must be systematically tackled at a multi-dimensional level.
From the early 1990s onwards PADETC broadened its work to include integrated rural development, with the emphasison strengthening the capacities of rural communities andempower them to improve their livelihoods systematically.
The main strategic approaches used included: the promotion of participatory processes for community development, especially the use of participatory processes in problem analysis and planning in collaboration with local authorities and communities; the training of multi-sector rural development teams comprising staff from the agriculture, education, health, and woman#s unions at various levels (village, district, province); the setting up of integrated rural development offices at the provincial and district levels to provide management, extension, and monitoring support; and the production of Lao language manuals and forms for village surveys, planning, budgeting, reporting, and many types of production techniques.
With the expansion of its scope of work programmatically and geographically, PADETC has grown from its original staff of five in 1996 to anorganisation with 53 staff (12 women), all of them Lao. PADETC also draws on the support from international expertise in the form of short-term technical experts, advisors and volunteers, etc. through international agencies, such as German International Aid (DED), Singapore International Foundation (SIF), Australia Volunteer Service, etc.
PADETC continues to co-operate closely with governmentagencies at all administrative levels and ensures that responsible authorities are regularly briefed on the progress of its projects. PADETC has closeco-operation with a number of NGOs, UN and bilateral agencies. After more than ten years of operation and innovative contribution to local development, PADETC is increasingly given more political and social recognition as a local development agency. Basedon its experience the vision and mission of PADETC is to promote the concept of #liveable# communities which balances economic growth with social and cultural vibrancy, environmental harmony, and spiritual development for all.
PADETC has long operatedasalaboratory both for development thinking, and for the applied-use of locally appropriate approaches. This has included not only Learning Centre and network development, but the articulation of a conceptual framework for development.  In 2009, PADETCbeganthe process of supporting each Learning Centre and Network to become independent, paving the way for eventual registration as individual NPAs.

In July 2012, the founder and long term Director of PADETC Mr. Sombath has handed over the function toMr.Khamphoui Saythalat. The last year, PADETC has focussed much of its energy and resources and the internal transformation of its organisation as well as the AEPF process. Consequently, most of the activities now take place in and around Vientiane, although contacts with youth groups in other provinces still exist.

Also for the coming programme period the institutional transition process will demand a substantial investment in time and resources from PADETC. In order to support the new director in the processa group of &#x93;Friends of PADETC&#x94; has been formed with international and national members and that provides coaching and technical advice to PADETC.


PADETC will focus on four fields of action. These are:
1. Education for Sustainable Development (ESD)
2. Enabling Environment Support for Lao CSOs (with a particular focus on Organizational Development and Management, and Small Grant Facility)
3. Policy Advocacy (mainly with reference tothe recommendations made from the Impact Assessment report in March2012)
4. Resource mobilization including the marketing and delivery of services for the general public, NPAs and iNGOs.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laos</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to a sustainable livelihood</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-01">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-01">93168</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-10-01">37500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-10-01">37500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-10-01">12500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-10-01">12500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-12-01">75000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-12-01">25000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-03-01">71741</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-09-01">21427</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-04-01">-6571</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-10-01">37500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-10-01">37500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-10-01">12500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-10-01">12500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-12-01">75000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-12-01">25000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-03-01">71741</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-09-01">21427</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-04-01">-6571</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-02582-02:LA">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007254"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Laos (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-02582"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Policy dialogue and CSO capacity buildin"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">13</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no of policy changes in internationally operating companies and international institutions on natural resources and biodiversity</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">013-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Campaigns (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="013-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2013-01-01" value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">013-D</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Civil organisations (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="013-D" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2013-01-01" value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">013-C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># International corporations (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="013-C" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2013-01-01" value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">13</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no of policy changes in internationally operating companies and international institutions on natural resources and biodiversity</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">013-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Policy changes AIM1 BB 013</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="013-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2013-01-01" value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of partner organisations better able to communicate at the national and international levels the voice of people in rural areas living in poverty</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">004-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partnerorg AIM1 MO 004</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="004-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2013-01-01" value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of partner organisations better able to communicate at the national and international levels the voice of people in rural areas living in poverty</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">004-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Local organisations of produc (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="004-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2013-01-01" value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">004-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="004-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2013-01-01" value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men (small-scale crop farmers, cattle farmers, fisher folk) able to use sustainable production methods enabling them to better protect and use sustainably their livelihood resources</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">001-02</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Female AIM1 DAB 001</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="001-02" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2013-01-01" value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">001-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Male AIM1 DAB 001</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="001-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2013-01-01" value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men (small-scale crop farmers, cattle farmers, fisher folk) able to use sustainable production methods enabling them to better protect and use sustainably their livelihood resources</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">001-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="001-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2013-01-01" value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
