<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-04381-02:XG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TDU-Indo Dutch Exchange Anti Biotics</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to reduce the use of antibiotics, improve quality of dairy products and enhance animal health and wellbeing in Indian dairy farming, by strengthening the action-learning community of actors in the dairy chain in the awareness about, use of and access to natural products.

High use of antibiotics in animal production and multi-resistant strains of microbes are a problem in animal farming in both India and the Netherlands. According to a recent scientific review study in the UK this will lead to global crises by 2050, with more deaths than cancer today &#x96; the majority in poor regions of Africa and Asia.

In the Netherlands, where numerous initiatives to reduce antibiotic use are being experimented with, with emphasis on law-enforced reduction of antibiotic use by farmers and veterinarians, animal health improvements, and milk quality control. In India age-old techniques with the use of medical plants and other natural products have been developed and &#x96; since the early 1990s &#x96; revitalized. This process of documentation, rapidassessment, propagation, and popularization of the use of medicinal plants is unique in the world, and provides important insights elsewhere.

In 2014 the exchange between experts in the Netherlands and India that combine both experiences has been very successful. This project aimed to reduce the use of antibiotics in dairy production in India and the Netherlands, by increasing the use of medicinal plants and other natural products, combined with integrated animal management and milk quality control. Within both countriesthe exchange has resulted in numerous new initiatives, strengthened networks, room for the use of medicinal plants and other sustainable practices in dairy farming, and important coverage in the press.

This E-Motive project in 2015 is the follow-up of this successful exchange. Similar to the 2014 project the program implies one visit from Dutch farmers and veterinarians to Bangalore (Karnataka) Karur, (Tamil Nadu) Thiruvananthapuram and Kottakkal (Kerala) in April 2015 &#x96; and a return visit of Indian farmers, veterinarians and representatives of the dairy industry to the Netherlands in September 2015.

The model that will be used is the 4-layer approach developed during the 2014 Emotive project:
1.	Foundation: improved animal management (breeding &amp; feeding)
2.	Second layer: promote the use of medicinal plants (both preventive and curative)
3.	Third layer: to promote safety of dairy products through effective milk quality control
4.	Fourth layer: to reward farmers through surplus payment for milk without residues, in the form of establishing an organic dairy chain within the dairy cooperatives

This year, the exchange between Netherlands and India will have four major objectives to strengthen the Indian dairy sector:
-	Strengthen the professional Ethno Veterinary (EVP) action-learning community in the dairy chain in three Indian States on ways to reduce antibiotic use and improve animal health
-	Herbal product for udder infection and related training materials developed for Indian veterinarians and farmers
-	Effective Indian support to Dutch herbal medicine
-	Up-scaling the findings to the Indian wider community of farmers, veterinarians and the ministries of agriculture and health

In addition, there will be a combination with a similar exchange between Netherlands and two African countries (Ethiopia and Uganda) with special emphasis on sustainable livestock breeding practices. Moreover, the exchange activities in 2015 will be effectively used to strengthen the network within the 4 countries and develop a joint proposal for strengthening the activities towards antibiotic-residue free milk worldwide.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Trans-disciplinary University (TDU) &#x96; formerly Institute of Ayurveda and Integrated Medicine (I-AIM) and Foundation of Revitalization of Local Health Traditions (FRLHT) founded in 1993 was legislated into an autonomous State University by the Karnataka Legislative Assembly on 14th February 2013 (L.C. Bill No.06 of 2013) and subsequently gazetted by the Karnataka Government (Karnataka Act No 35 of 2013). The term Trans-Disciplinary is defined in the Act as &quot;the interface of any of the Indian traditional health scienceswith other systems of knowledge including; biomedicine, life sciences, social sciences, engineering and management studies&quot;.

The university has the following goals:
&#x95;	Development of affordable, accessible and effective strategies to significantly enhance Health Security of communities &amp; their livestock.
&#x95;	Creation of new knowledge in health sciences through trans-disciplinary research in basic, clinical, pharmacological, pharmaceutical and social sciences.

It also has two supplementary goals:
&#x95;	Design of innovative and scalable strategies for conservation and sustainable use of natural resources (flora, fauna, metals and minerals) used by India&#x92;s medical heritage.
&#x95;	Training of high quality human resources at doctoral, PG, UG levels and including rural and urban schools, households and grass-root community workers, in selected dimensions of traditional knowledge and Trans-Disciplinary Health Sciences and Technology using as feasible the ICT platform for global reach.

TDU has a team of over 200 professionals that include traditional physicians, botanists, biochemists, computer professionals, forestry experts, education and training personnel, working full time on activities related to these objectives. In its 20 years of existence the organization has demonstrated that it has the ability to visualize and implement in a focused manner &#x91;pioneering projects&#x92; that &#x91;impact&#x92; national policies in its chosen area of operations.

TDU has been working on animal health since 2008. Since 2011 TDU-FRLHT has developed a post graduate diploma course on ethnoveterinary medicine (EVM) for veterinarians together with Tami Nadu Veterinary and Animal Science University (TANUVAS) http://updates.highereducationinindia.com/2011/tanuvas-university-pg-degreediploma-7618.php

In 2013-2014 TDU and TANUVAS have implementing a 2 year trainingproject for veterinarians on the use of medicinal plants (EVM) in 3 South Indian states &#x96; funded by Technical Training Program of TVET (Technical and Vocational Education and Training) - an UNESCO supported program. In 2014 TDU and TANUVAS have implemented the successful E-Motive exchange program between Netherlands and India on the reduction of antibiotic use in dairy farming. Both projects were designed and developed in close coordination with Dutch Farm Experience.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trans - Disciplinary University (TD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Level</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-20">52100</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-03-01">52100</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trans - Disciplinary University (TD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-03-01">52100</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-04381-02:XG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007356"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="Global: Small"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-04381"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="TDU-Indo Dutch Exchange Anti Biotics"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">44</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases revealing that methodologies developed and exchanged by partner organisations and knowledge institutes in joint knowledge processes resulted in improved access of citizens to relevant and reliable information (amongst others by providing acce</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">044-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Cases AIM4 KIM 044</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="044-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">44</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases revealing that methodologies developed and exchanged by partner organisations and knowledge institutes in joint knowledge processes resulted in improved access of citizens to relevant and reliable information (amongst others by providing acce</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">044-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners acces to information</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="044-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
