<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-000131</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sowing Diversity=Harvesting Security</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the Sowing Diversity=Harvesting Security (SD=HS) programme is that Indigenous people and small-holder farmers # men, women and youth # enjoy their Farmers# Rights and have capacity to access, develop and use plant genetic resources to improve their food and nutrition security under conditions of climate change.
SD=HS operates as a network of leading civil society organizations working in the field of plant genetic resources on national and global level. Currently the program is implemented in 7 countries (Nepal, Laos, Zambia, Zimbabwe, Uganda, Peru and Guatemala and there is collaboration with organizations in China as a linking and learning partner.  At the same time partners and Oxfam Novib are very active on global level (e.g. on the International Treaty on Plant Genetic Resources for Food and Agriculture).
SD=HS is possible to bilateral donors (e.g. Swedish Sida), public donations and private foundations.


Over the coming four years SD=HS will reach 250,000 households and at least 50% of the beneficiaries are women.

The four key outcomes of SD=HS are:

# Resilient indigenous and farming communities are better able to access and sustainably use and maintain plant genetic resources for food and nutrition security, climate change adaptation and disaster management.

# Indigenous peoples and smallholder farmers enhance their livelihoods, income and seed security though improved market access to and production of high-quality seeds of diverse crops and varieties adapted to farmers# needs and preferences

# Strengthen coping strategies of communities by increasing the intake of nutritious food based on local biodiversity and improved management of neglected and underutilised species (NUS)

# Policy makers and otherstakeholders support an enabling policy and institutional environment for farmers# seed systems and the implementation of Farmers# Rights, through improved policies and practices.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl/Mission-and-vision">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-01-12"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
