<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-00419-02:LA</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programm</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposed Lao Community Participation and Communication Support Programme builds on the pilot experience from the Khoun Community Radio, community media practices (i.e. community radio and village broadcast systems in combination with new technologies) will be scaled-up to additional poor districts in the country. The Scaling-up strategy takes into account the lessons from the first phaseof the project.
The project will help develop capacity in country to sustain community media. This includes the building of competence and partnerships in critical areas such as community media broadcasting, community building, financial and media management, broadcasting technology and peer support systems. The Programme &#x96; in cooperation with competent partners &#x96; is also well placed to assist the organizational strengthening of community radios who aspire to register as an association. Knowledge products  (manuals, reviews, studies) will be produced and disseminated to a wide range of international and local partners who are engaged in Supporting Community Organisations in the country. It is anticipated that a service-provider association will spin off the project implementation unit and thus be able to assist community media beyond the scope and life-time of the project.


By 2014, the Lao Community Participation and Communication Support Programme is expected to produce the following outcomes (see product II for statistics of beneficiaries). This component targets the most vulnerable segments of rural society: youth, women and elderly people from remote and under-served ethnic villages. The project seeks to improve access to:
&#x95; information in languages that people can understand and which they find relevant for taking informed decisions.
&#x95; communication channels to express their views, share knowledge, validate their cultureand traditions and to play an active part in society.
&#x95; Increase the voice of communities and through that empower them to become actors of their own development. Find solutions to development challenges from inside communities through community radio.


With thefollowing planned results
Scaling-up &#x96; Community media scaled up to poor and under-served districts
1. 5 (4 new established and 1 existing sustainable) community radios and village broadcasting systems operating sustainably
2. 30,000 people and remote villages benefitting from improved access to information and communication channels
3. Participation from target groups in programme-making (120 volunteers)
5. Satisfaction of listeners (in particular from key target groups)
4. &#x91;Significant change&#x92; stories reported by project target groups

Capacity for sustainability &#x96; Local organizations and companies have the knowledge and competence to scale up and sustain community media
1. Community radios, local governments, NGOs and donors make use of the project&#x92;s knowledge products
   - Training manuals and tool kits
   - Study on sustainability of community   radio in Lao PDR
   - Online resources with local best   practices
2. Support systems for community media in place (local resources and partnerships for training, resource mobilization, technical maintenance)
3. Peer-support system for exchanges between Lao community radios
4. 5 Community radio associations registered
5. Service-provider association assisting partners in scaling up community media
Community media scaled up to poor and under-served districts

Learning and Advocacy&#x96; Lessons learned will be used to inform policy-makers and contribute to an enabling environment for media, access to information and indigenous rights
1. M&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;E System to track aspects of sustainability and impacts of community media in Lao PDR.
2. Increased understanding and support from policy-makers and local authorities
3. Community media representatives contributing to policy debates (at least 2 forums per year)
4. Contributions to and from international networks (at least 4 contributions a year)

Efficient and effective programme monitoring and coordination systems and resources are in place.
1. Monthly &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; quarterly planning and coordination meetings take place and the agreed quorum is achieved.
2. Steering Committee Meetings are held twice each year
3. Programme review meetings held once per year 2009-2012.
4. Baseline monitoring data established.
5. Mid-term evaluation conducted in 2012 and lessons learned will be used for improving the programme.
6. Final evaluation conducted in 2013</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The United Nations Development Programme is the main body for coordinating the UN&#x92;s development work. Its global reach and management of more than US$ 4 billion (2005) annually makes it the largest provider of development grant assistance in the UN system. UNDP provides policy advice and helps build institutional and human capacity that generates equitable growth. UNDP helps developing countries attract and use aid effectively. It works with the public and private sector partners to make the best possible use of aid resources in confronting the challenges and opportunities offered by globalization. It is committed to promoting accountable governance at all levels of society and building coalitions for actions on issues critical to sustainable human development. An Executive Board,representing both developed and developing countries, governs UNDP.
As the leading advocate for the Millennium Development Goals (MDGs), UNDP helps bring countries and the international community together to take these efforts forward. Working with existing national plans and poverty reduction strategies, UNDP assists countries with formulating practical MDG strategies.
UNDP prepares the annual Human Development Report that focuses the global debate on key development issues, providing new measurement tools, innovative analysis and often-controversial policy proposals. It is guided by the belief that development is ultimately a process of enlarging people&#x92;s choices, not just raising national incomes.
At the country level, UNDP provides support to publish National Human DevelopmentReports (NHDR).  More than 140 countries have now published NHDRs that have served to invigorate local policy debates.
In all activities, UNDP encourages the protection of human rights and the empowerment of women, and all activities are undertaken in close collaboration with the Government, sister UN agencies and other development stakeholders.
Lao PDR has been a member of the United Nationssince 1955 and UNDP has worked in Laos since 1957. The first National Socio-economic Development Plan (NSEDP) was launched in 1975 and currently Lao PDR is preparing its 7th NSEDP for 2011-2015. UNDP works together with the government of Lao PDR on the preparation of the 7th NSEDP in order to support the government&#x92;s efforts to reach MDGs by 2015 and to graduate from Least Developed Country status by 2020. UN in partnership with Lao PDR has published its first MDG report in 2004 followed by the second report in 2008.
Since 1983 the Lao PDR has been participating in the Round Table Process, with the support from the UNDP. The Round Table Process servesas the primary platform for in-depth dialogue between the Government of Lao PDR and Development Partners on key development issues.From 1983 until 1997, the process was focused on the tri-annual Round Table Meetings which were held in Geneva. In 1999, following a global review of the Round Table Meeting, the Government of Lao PDR, UNDP and the international organisations agreed to turn the RTM into a continuing dynamic process held in-country, rather than just a one-off meeting every three years. The Government of the Lao PDR has been taking the lead in managing the Round Table Process, through the roles and responsibilities outlined in the Prime Minister&apos;s Official Development Assistance Decree no. 75/PM.
An independent country-level evaluation conducted by the Evaluation Officeof UNDP in Lao PDR in 2007 found that UNDP has contributed significantly to policy development and dialogue, including incorporation of the MDGs and pro-poor concerns into national planning. Through the National Human Development Reports and other initiatives, UNDP has contributed to capacity development in the government to carry out high-level policy and strategic research on key issues, such as regional integration and human development. In the important field of governance, UNDP has gained the status of a trusted partner of the government. During the years UNDP has increased its support to democratic governance and participation. In the areas of environment and sustainable development, UNDP has supported the country&apos;s efforts to fulfil its obligations to the international environmental agreements it has ratified. Given the importance of natural resources to the Lao economy, UNDP has emphasised the need to incorporate related issues into policy dialogue in order to optimize the sustainable use of natural resources for the benefit of thecountry. UNDP has also succeeded in establishing more efficient planning for operations related to UXO, thus ensuring continued international support to the effort.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programm</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-02-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-02-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laos</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2011-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-21">-28180</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-21">126202</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-01-01">-108900</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programm</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-01-01">-221100</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programm</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-04-01">101110</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programm</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-04-01">49800</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programm</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-01">101110</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programm</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-01">49800</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programm</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-02-01">126202</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programm</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2010-12-01">108900</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2010-12-01">221100</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-01-01">-108900</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-01-01">-221100</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-04-01">101110</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-04-01">49800</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-01">101110</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-01">49800</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-02-01">126202</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A00419-02:LA">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007254"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Laos (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-00419"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="UNDP Community Radio Program 2010-2011"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">39</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases of demonstrably improved professionalism  of southern media and citizen journalists (bloggers) (among others in gender sensitive fashion)</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">039-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Cases AIM4 MO 039</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="039-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2011-02-01" value="0" year="2011"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2011-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">39</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases of demonstrably improved professionalism  of southern media and citizen journalists (bloggers) (among others in gender sensitive fashion)</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">039-C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Media organisations (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="039-C" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2011-02-01" value="0" year="2011"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2011-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">039-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="039-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2011-02-01" value="0" year="2011"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2011-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">039-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Trainings (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="039-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2011-02-01" value="0" year="2011"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2011-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">44</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases revealing that methodologies developed and exchanged by partner organisations and knowledge institutes in joint knowledge processes resulted in improved access of citizens to relevant and reliable information (amongst others by providing acce</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">044-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Cases AIM4 KIM 044</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="044-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2011-02-01" value="0" year="2011"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2011-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">44</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases revealing that methodologies developed and exchanged by partner organisations and knowledge institutes in joint knowledge processes resulted in improved access of citizens to relevant and reliable information (amongst others by providing acce</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">044-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners acces to information</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="044-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2011-02-01" value="0" year="2011"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2011-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
