<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-04391-02:22</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Sovereignty for small scale fishers</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southeast Asia Fish for Justice Network (SEAFish). SEAFish was  established in August 2003 in a regional conference in Manila when fourteen (14) NGOs decided to combine forces to develop an international lobby, advocacy, and campaigning platform on fisheries and it development issues in the region. The network operates on the basis of a commonly defined Pool of Consensus, which describes a series of opinions, statements, and advocacy calls that any member of the network can make on behalf of the total membership. Also present at that time were Oxfams working in East Asia, who indicated their support to the Pool of Consensus.

From this platform, SEAFish  developed its capacity and expertise to provide added value to the various programs of the members at country level over the last  years. In delving into the international dimension of fisheries development issues, the network  emerged as an institutional spokesperson in international processes affecting fisheries development such as those involving ASEAN, SEAFDEC, WTO and ADB. The combination of members in SEAFish has developed  the expertise to become the acknowledged and respected advocate of small-scale fishery andpoverty issues that these international institutions need to hear.

Since the establishment of SEAFish, the vision is envisions a just and prosperous  global community  for  empowered coastal communities,  respecting indigenous  management systems, enjoying the  management  of  coastal and  fisheries resources.

To  pursue this  vision, SEAFish  will serve  as  the  voice of  artisanal  fishers in Southeast Asia and facilitate  opportunities  to  empower them, and uplift  their  quality of  life  through the  equitable, sustainable and  just  use  of  coastal and  marine  resources. SEAFISH  shall have contributed to the creation of  conducive environment  through  policy and practices  sensitive to: the rights of fishers to resources,  transboundary and use conflicts in coastal and marine areas,  gender fairness,  adaptation to climate change.

 SEAFish has fourteen (14) members from five (5) countries from within and outside the region namely: from Cambodia - FACT; from Indonesia - KIARA, Telapak, WALHI, KNTI and P3UW; from Malaysia # Sahabat Alam Malaysia; from the Philippines - CASCO, CERD, ELAC, KM, LAFCCOD, PROCESS and Tambuyog; from Vietnam - MCD; and from Mynmar # Ever Green.

The General Assembly (GA) is the highest governing body of SEAFish. It is composed of representatives from member organizations and has been conducted on an annual basis for the past three years. The GA is responsible for setting the strategic direction of the network and reviewing plans and programs.

he Program Coordinator (PC) are chosen on a per issues basis by selected members. Thus a PC gets his/her mandate from and is accountable to the members. A PC is responsible for overseeing the programs and issues development in the region, developing and promoting broad unities among members, ensuring that members benefit from SEAFish andfacilitate discussions in the region, and he/she is empowered to call for special meetings in the region based on availability of funds and time and approve/disapprove project proposals submitted to SEAFish in conference with other PCs and members.

The Regional Coordinator is responsible for implementing the programs of SEAFish, overseeing the day to day operations of the Secretariat, adopting and implementing the systems and discipline of the network, and managing the finances of the network including the drafting of budgets and checking the financial viability of the network in coordination with the Program Coordinator. He/she is tasked with calling for the GA and special meeting, is responsible for directly representing the OCs, reports to the PCs during meetings and provides updates to them upon request. The Regional Coordinator is appointed or elected by the PCs members and is accountable to them and hasa two-year tenure. He/she cannot be a PC while performing his/her tasks as Regional Coordinator.

The Secretariat is tasked with making regular updates, and providing news and relevant information to the PC and the members, providing assistance to members in accordance with the strategies and programs of the network, maintaining the list-serves and sharing information to allies and other networks, addressing information requests regarding SEAFish matters, doing regular outreach job to members and specific groups upon direction of PC, and ensuring that the annual financial reports are regularly disseminated to the members upon the approval of the PC. It is also tasked with preparing for meetings and should be part of all SEAFish meetings for documentation purposes.

The Secretariatgets its mandate comes and is accountable to the PCs and members. However, it is not member of the Program Coordinators. The Head of Secretariat is empowered to hire and fire Secretariat staff based on the review and approval of the PCs.


After the VI General Assembly of SEAFish in Yangoon, Myanmar, facilitated by Ever Green as a member host, a new regional coordinator are chosen by the members for 3 years: 2014-2018, that is KIARA (The People#s Coalition for Fisheries Justice). There#s no budget for this new period. Some source of funds which targeted by the Regional Secretariat are Oxfam, ASEAN Foundation and several organizations.

As a partner ofOxfam, SEAFish has a good and long collaboration in terms of influencing ASEAN secretariat to absorb the rights of small holders infisheries management in the region, both capture and aquaculture.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kiara</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Koalisi Ikan untuk Rakyat (KIARA), a network organization which was established in 2003 by fisherfolk groups, non-governmental organizations, and individuals who work and put their concerns on fisherfolk and coastal community. Since January 2009, based on the 3rdKIARA&#x92;s General Assembly in Ambon, North Maluku Province, acronym of KIARA has been changed with &#x93;Koalisi Rakyat untuk Keadilan Perikanan&#x94;. Initially, it focused on reviewing the relation and inter-relation impacts of international trade policies toward fisherfolk and coastal community. The organization found its moment when OGB (OXFAM Great Britain) was sponsoring a workshop on Coastal Resources and Fisheries Management. It was attendded and supported by KIKIS (Jakarta), Bina Desa (Jakarta), Eksekutif Nasional WALHI (Jakarta), JALA (Medan, Sumatera Utara), Kelola (Manado, Sulawesi Utara), JKPKP (Buton, Sulawesi Tenggra), Nen Mas Il (Maluku), Yayasan Karya Kasih (Sumba Barat, NTB), Layar Pantura (Semarang, Jawa Tengah), Yayasan Silfagama (Yogyakarta), FSNN (Jakarta), Konphalindo (Jakarta), Telapak (Bogor), APKP (Jakarta).

 The network works towards a vision that artisanal fishers&#x97;men and women&#x97;should have sovereignity to manage aquatic resources in order to enable them to play a more significant role in ensuring more just trade of fisheries products and sustainability of their livelihood. In achieving the above vision, the organization defined its mission as follows:

- To be information center for members and public on fisheries policies.
- To develop and/or support network on policy change towards more just trade for the benefit of small scale/traditional fishers.
- To become part of social movement in eliminating injustice practices international trade in fisheries sector.

 KIARA sought to occupy a specific niche on &#x93;fisheries trade&#x94; related advocacy, because at that time there was an active network in Indonesia on CB-CRM. Unfortunately that network is no longer active.

I n the first years of its existence KIARA received support by OGB and created a secretariat and appointed a general secretary in the person of Nina Dwisasanti. KIARA became in this period an active member of the regional network SEAFISH for Justice. It also managed to organize a number of events, workshops and campaigns. To mention some:
a. Facilitated and Participated in Asia Pacific Female Fishers Meeting in Medan 2004 (Joint Committee of SPPNSU-KIARA-SP)
b. Conducted One-day Seminar about NAMA Agenda in Serdang Begadai (200 people) before Hong Kong MC.
c. Conducted National Conference of Artisanal Fishers in Jakarta, September 2005.
d. Conducted Regional Conference of Artisanal Fishers in Jakarta, September 2005 (back to back with the national conference).
e. Participated in Hong Kong WTO MC, December 2005 and petition offered to WTO.
f. Participated in NAMA discussion, Pre Hong Kong MC, December 2005.
g. Involvementin Make Trade Fair campaign in Indonesia.
h. Signatures collection for Make Trade Fair by KIARA network (Bina Desa, Kelola, and JPKP Buton).
i. Discussion with local fisherfolk about fisheries globalisation issue in Cisolok, February 2006
j. Discussion with localfisherfolk about NAMA in Kamal Muara, April 2006.
k. Linked up with discussions on Public Private Partnership Indonesia- Netherlands on aquaculture

To date, Oxfam Novib has entered a total of two direct partnerships with KIARA, the first collaboration was for the period of September 1, 2008 to March 31, 2009 with a total amount of IDR 354,400,000,-(&#x80;  27,261,-  at exchange rate of 1&#x80; = 13,000,- IDR), and the one which just recently being finalized was a two-year program from April  1, 2009 &#x96; March 31, 2011 with contribution of Rp 2,312,550,000 (&#x80; 158,394,- at exchange rate of 1 &#x80;= 14600 IDR, date: May 2009).

In addition, KIARA has been collaboratingclosely and has become a key partner of the Oxfam International Economic Justice Campaign in Indonesia implemented by Alliance for the Village Prosperity (or Desa Sejahtera). In this alliance, KIARA was responsible to contribute on the aquaculture and fisheries aspects of the campaign strategies and managed a total of IDR 352 million for the period of April 10, 2009 to March 31, 2010.
At regional (Southeast Asia) level, the network joined a regional fisheries network based inthe Philippines, Seafish for Justice, and contributed the experience around the advocacy efforts in Indonesia to achieve leverage at regional level for the benefit of small scale fisherfolks. KIARA took part in two activities, in the period of January- December 2008 (EUR 7,133) and January- December 2009 (EUR 22,180).

KIARA has proven to be a determined and effective partner, within only a couple of years and with a lean staff resources, the advocacy work of the network has attracted much attention from the members, academics, mass media and most importantly has promoted policy changes through its advocacy work to the Ministry of Marine and Fisheries Affairs and the House of Representatives. As quoted from the Evaluation Report of KIARA 2009-2010, &#x93;KIARA&#x92;s campaigns have focused on cost and labour effective activities however with large impact to policy change&#x94;. One of the big-wins is the Court decision that states some articles stipulating the coastal waters management permit (HP3) provision of Law 27/2007 is against Indonesia&#x92;s Constitution. Hereby KIARA has completely satisfied the mandate of the National Assembly (highest decision making of the network) to propose elimination of the respective controversial articles.

KIARA has successfully implemented its program 2009-2011 as planned, as summarized by the Evaluation Report KIARA 2011:

&#x95; KIARA has satisfied the mandate of the National Meeting, proposing elimination of some controversial articles from Law No. 27 of 2007on Coastal Areas and Small Islands Management.
&#x95; KIARA has also fulfilled the mandate of the National Meeting to foster revision ofLaw No. 31 of 2004 on Fisheries.
&#x95; KIARA&#x92;s suggested that the Minister of Marine and Fishery should follow up its suggestion about the use of theTPI&#x92;s levy. KIARA asked the Ministry to ensure that the levy was to be used to support fisherfolks in hard times (no or small quantity of catches) and to secure sea accident insurance as was stipulated in regional government regulations on TPI.  KIARA&#x92;sadvocacy of the use of the levy was undertaken by the member in Semarang (Layar Nusantara) and in Bau-bau City (JPKP).
&#x95; At regional level, KIARA has supported its regional members, such as Layar Nusantara and JPKP to advocate for regional government regulations on Fisheries Auction Places (TPI).
&#x95; KIARA and partners launched media campaigns against oil dumping by an Australian ship entering Timor waters. According to Dr. Alan Koropitan, the opinion article and the letter sent to the President seemed to be successful inencouraging the government to take stricter measures.
&#x95; In response to the 2009 World Ocean Conference in North Sulawesi, KIARA succeeded in turning the forum into the one promoting integrated coastal and marine advocacy and mobilizingsolid cooperation with othercivil society&#x92;s organizations.
&#x95; KIARA disclosed information on five fisherfolks from North Sumatra having been imprisoned in Malaysia. In the end, the government asked KIARA to go with the government&#x92;s team to help releasing the fisherfolks.
&#x95; KIARA provided assistance for smallholder shrimp farmers at Dipasena (a large shrimp company) in Lampung. KIARA assisted the farmers to talk to the related officials, among other the Ministry of Marine and Fishery and the multisectoral team specifically formed to settle the disputes between the farmers and the company, which erupted from 2001. In defending the farmers, KIARA was actively launching media campaigns.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">East Asia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to a sustainable livelihood</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31310" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-23">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-03-01">100000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kiara</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-03-01">-22822</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kiara</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-03-01">100000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-03-01">-22822</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-04391-02:22">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007257"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="ZOA - Regional"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-04391"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Food sovereignty for small scale fishers"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">11</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no of policy changes regarding pro-poor markets and financial systems</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">011-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Lobby trajectories (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="011-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-01-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">011-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="011-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-01-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">11</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no of policy changes regarding pro-poor markets and financial systems</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">011-05</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Policy changes AIM1 BB 011</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="011-05" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-01-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
