<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-04257-03:LA</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory water use in industry</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable participatory water use in the coffee industry on the Bolaven plateau in Southern Laos.

The abundant rainfall and fertile soil makes the plateau very well suited to coffee production. Over 90% of the national crop (30,000 tons of green coffee beans) is produced in two districts (Paksong and Thatheng). Production is largely through smallholder, family owned plantations. In a country which remains heavily dependent of foreign aid, coffee makes an important contribution to the market economy. Coffee is Laos# largest agricultural export and there is a growing demand internationally for premium coffee products. Coffee is also an important livelihood and source of income, especially for women in rural communities.
Attention to sound environmental management has increased significantly in coffee producing countries over the past few years. Several studies have revealed that untreated waste from varying scales of coffee processing entrepreneurs are affecting the quality of surface waters worldwide and more severely in developing countries. This also is the case in Laos. The Arabica coffee wet-processing method requires a huge amount of water to produce the end product of clean green coffee beans, e.g. in Laos ~2-10 m3,  Vietnam 4-15 m3/ a ton of fresh cherry. It is estimated that 23 million litres of untreated coffee processing effluent flows into rivers on the Bolaven each year.
The waste water produced via the wet-process has high sugar content and depletes the value of biological oxygen demand (BOD) and dissolved oxygen (DO). Without wastewater management, it can pollute water resources, damage aquatic ecosystems and pose a threat to the health of nearby communities. This represents a drawback in the coffee production industry and undermines the economic benefits this production can bring to communities.
Thenow-famous Bolaven Plateau is the most important coffee-growing place in Laos. It is made of an ancient volcano on the west of Pakse, Champassak in the south of the country. Extensive volcanic basaltic rocks with fertile Ferralsol and Vertisol soil content are found and associated with high mineral content which is good for agriculture activities. When these factors are added to the elevated geography of the Bolaven Plateau, which is greater than 1,000 metres above mean sea level, the conditions for growing superior quality Arabica coffee (Coffea arabica) beans are nearly perfect.
Coffee is one of the main agro-industries of the Lao PDR, being the sixth largest agricultural commodity of the country. This puts Laos at the 32nd spot (all type of coffee products 87,330 tons) of the world#s coffee producers in 2012. The underlying trend of Laos coffee exports is that it has grown in the last decade from approximately 13,000 tons in 2002 to 30,000 tons in 2013. The strategy of the Lao Government is to massively increase this production, which highlights the needs for better production standards, including water management.

WWF Laos and Oxfam Novib are currently engaged in a partnership around water governance and broader natural resources management in the Mekong Region, looking in particular at the synergies of livelihood improvement and conservation, with a focus on gender. As part of this partnership, a project is being considered that would target the coffee processing industry and its impact on water and broader natural resources on the Bolaven plateau. A feasibility study was conducted in late 2014 and early 2015, and this 6-month project is intended as a short follow-up to disseminate the results of the study, conducting more research, building the capacity of local stakeholders and exploring engagement strategies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF have been working in Lao PDR since the late 1980s in cooperation with the Ministry of Agriculture and Forestry. Our country programme office was first established in Vientiane 2001. Since then, our small team has grown to over 40 Lao, international and volunteer staff working on over 15 projects countrywide with offices in Vientiane, Champasak, Sekong and Attapeu provinces.

The work of WWF in the fisheries sector has achieved the following results towards strengthening food security and alleviation of poverty in the lives of Lao people: (1) a network of communities across seven provinces are empowered with the rights and responsibilities to manage local fisheries by establishing village-based fishing regulations that are designed, implemented, monitored and enforced by local people. These regulations create freshwater protected areas that are providing long-term sustained benefits to local communities through promoting the sustainable use of fish and other aquatic animals.

Globally, WWF has proven to excel as an effective convener, bringing together partners around common goals. WWF has also progressed in establishing itself as a credible and compelling science-based organization, in many cases particularly those related to infrastructure and development projects. These distinct values have brought ONL to partner up with WWF in various countries, ONL East and South East Asia Team collaborates with WWF US in the development of Aquaculture Dialogues Standards, WWF China in community development in Natural Resources Management, Education for Sustainable Development, Agrobusiness and finally WWF Indonesia in Green Coast project (during tsunami 2005) and shrimp assessment program.

WWFGMPO mandate is to conserve the Mekong Complex&#x92;s biodiversity,to reduce the regions footprint, to strengthen the WWF brand presenceand local income generation in the region, and to ensure full compliance with network policy and standards.

Being centrally located in the &#x91;Mekong Complex&#x92;, WWF GMPO has significantstrengths and the current regional/country contexts highlight several clear opportunities:
- Leveraging existing partnerships. WWF has built trust, communication structures, and collaborative relationships with a number of important regional partners from NGO&#x92;s to government agencies;
- Pursuing strategic funding opportunities;
- Working with and benefit from WWF Network Initiatives (WWF NI&#x92;s) to ensure that network resources are brought to bear on projects as well as ensuring that NI&#x92;s benefit from on the ground contributions to global goals and by sharing of lessons learned.

WWF GMPO programme is built on four key conservation strategies that will be implemented across all the GMPO countries in response to the key threats, drivers and limiting factors. Critical strategies priorities have been defined, including the delivery of two &#x91;Big Wins&#x92; in 2011 and 2012.

WWF GMPO Strategic Framework 2011-2015 consists of four conservation strategies:
1. Securing landscape integrity and climate change resilience through integrated conservation economic development planning and implementation;
2. Ensuring sustainable hydropower development to maintain ecosystem integrity of the Mekong river, priority tributaries and other rivers in priority landscapes;
3. Strengthening law enforcement and protected area management to secure priority species and landscapes;
4. Securing sufficient sustainable and leveraged financing for conservation.

The Community Fisheries programme proposed by WWF GMPO is one cascading activity of strategy 3.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Wide Fund Laos</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laos</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to a sustainable livelihood</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-18">90217</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-07-01">90217</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Wide Fund Laos</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-07-01">90217</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-04257-03:LA">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007254"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Laos (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-04257"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Water  and Sustainable Livelihoods"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">16</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases (acedemic studies) on issues  on struggle for land, water and food</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">016-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Cases AIM1 KIM 016</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="016-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">16</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases (acedemic studies) on issues  on struggle for land, water and food</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">016-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Local organisations (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="016-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
