<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-03911-11:LA</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research to support community on environ</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Communities live in Siphandone or four thousand islands are facing challenges in sustaining their livelihood due to rapid changes socially and environmentally. For example recent development of infrastructure (bridge) that has just been completed in linking the Khong main island to the main land (national road) has improved access as well as speeding up extraction of natural resources. The proposed Don Sahong dam will affect larger part of local livelihood and environment. The proposed special economic zone in the district will also put the communities at higher development opportunities as well as risks.

Women in particularly will be affected differently than men due to cultural barriers, low education level and lack of employment opportunities. For example, women in rural areasengage in farming, food collection, fishing, and food processing in which near their home because they can perform their house keeping tasks and look after the family. If their livelihood activities were affected by any development projects, it is not easy to find alternatives for the rural women. So, it is very important to ensure that women participate actively in the Thaibaan research.

PADETC has been supporting 5 communities in Khong district to conduct action researchin 9 topics selected by communities themselves since 2013 in collaboration with provincial and district education offices and relevant local authorities. Local knowledge has been documented, shared and integrated to local teaching curriculums at primary school, while some problems identified by villagers have been addressed or discussed with relevant authorities. The past experiences, showed that Thaibaan research is an effective methods foradvocacy and development at local level.

The past collaboration with local government partners has results in trust in which allowthe team to work more on sensitive issues, the project is seeking ways to help villagers and local authorities to prepare for changes, so they can better mitigate negative impacts, defend for their best benefits and call for responsiveness of relevant organizations.

This project will support community led-research in 2 villages #Sahong and Som (in the below map) that will be the most affected by development activities (especially theDon Sahong dam) in documenting local livelihoods, monitoring environmental changes and advocating for better management of natural resource ensuring sustainable livelihood of local communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM Australia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC (Participatory Development Training Centre) was officially founded in late 1996. With an initial staff of five Lao development workers (four men and one woman), PADETC#s broad objective was to promote alternative models of development aimed at helping Laos# people to find ways to improve their livelihoods in a just and sustainable way.
Prior to its founding its director and his small team of development workers had worked in various aspects of agriculture and integrated rural development in many rural communities in Laos for more than 15 years, with the support mainly from international NGOs and some UN agencies.  During the early 1980s the team#s work had focused mainly on improvement of food security in poor rural communities by promoting low-cost appropriate agriculturaltechnologies, such as use of bio-fertilisers and bio-pesticides, and integration of fish-raising in the rice fields, etc. The impetus for working on food security during that time was the need to address the problem of food shortages faced by many rural communities in the aftermath of the 30-year war of independence which ended only in 1975.  It was through working on these agriculture-related projects that the team understood that the food security of Lao rural communities could not be solely resolved through improvements in agricultural techniques, but must be systematically tackled at a multi-dimensional level.
From the early 1990s onwards PADETC broadened its work to include integrated rural development, with the emphasison strengthening the capacities of rural communities andempower them to improve their livelihoods systematically.
The main strategic approaches used included: the promotion of participatory processes for community development, especially the use of participatory processes in problem analysis and planning in collaboration with local authorities and communities; the training of multi-sector rural development teams comprising staff from the agriculture, education, health, and woman#s unions at various levels (village, district, province); the setting up of integrated rural development offices at the provincial and district levels to provide management, extension, and monitoring support; and the production of Lao language manuals and forms for village surveys, planning, budgeting, reporting, and many types of production techniques.
With the expansion of its scope of work programmatically and geographically, PADETC has grown from its original staff of five in 1996 to anorganisation with 53 staff (12 women), all of them Lao. PADETC also draws on the support from international expertise in the form of short-term technical experts, advisors and volunteers, etc. through international agencies, such as German International Aid (DED), Singapore International Foundation (SIF), Australia Volunteer Service, etc.
PADETC continues to co-operate closely with governmentagencies at all administrative levels and ensures that responsible authorities are regularly briefed on the progress of its projects. PADETC has closeco-operation with a number of NGOs, UN and bilateral agencies. After more than ten years of operation and innovative contribution to local development, PADETC is increasingly given more political and social recognition as a local development agency. Basedon its experience the vision and mission of PADETC is to promote the concept of #liveable# communities which balances economic growth with social and cultural vibrancy, environmental harmony, and spiritual development for all.
PADETC has long operatedasalaboratory both for development thinking, and for the applied-use of locally appropriate approaches. This has included not only Learning Centre and network development, but the articulation of a conceptual framework for development.  In 2009, PADETCbeganthe process of supporting each Learning Centre and Network to become independent, paving the way for eventual registration as individual NPAs.

In July 2012, the founder and long term Director of PADETC Mr. Sombath has handed over the function toMr.Khamphoui Saythalat. The last year, PADETC has focussed much of its energy and resources and the internal transformation of its organisation as well as the AEPF process. Consequently, most of the activities now take place in and around Vientiane, although contacts with youth groups in other provinces still exist.

Also for the coming programme period the institutional transition process will demand a substantial investment in time and resources from PADETC. In order to support the new director in the processa group of &#x93;Friends of PADETC&#x94; has been formed with international and national members and that provides coaching and technical advice to PADETC.


PADETC will focus on four fields of action. These are:
1. Education for Sustainable Development (ESD)
2. Enabling Environment Support for Lao CSOs (with a particular focus on Organizational Development and Management, and Small Grant Facility)
3. Policy Advocacy (mainly with reference tothe recommendations made from the Impact Assessment report in March2012)
4. Resource mobilization including the marketing and delivery of services for the general public, NPAs and iNGOs.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laos</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="75" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to a sustainable livelihood</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="5" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to an identity</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31310" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-26">81102</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-09-01">7311</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Australia funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">32278</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Australia funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-11-01">31135</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Australia funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-01">-17649</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Australia funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-09-01">7311</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM Australia</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">32278</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM Australia</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-11-01">31135</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM Australia</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-01">-17649</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM Australia</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-03911-11:LA">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000570"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007254"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Laos (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-03911"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="OXAUS-DFAT INCLUSION"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">16</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases (acedemic studies) on issues  on struggle for land, water and food</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">016-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Cases AIM1 KIM 016</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="016-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">16</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases (acedemic studies) on issues  on struggle for land, water and food</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">016-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Local organisations (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="016-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">53</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases that show that partner organisations have more capacity with regard to gender mainstreaming during the design and implementation of programmes, lobby and advocacy initiatives (thanks to exchange of practices)</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">053-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Cases AIM5 KIM 053</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="053-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">53</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases that show that partner organisations have more capacity with regard to gender mainstreaming during the design and implementation of programmes, lobby and advocacy initiatives (thanks to exchange of practices)</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">053-D</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Exchange (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="053-D" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">053-E</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Measuring milestones (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="053-E" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">053-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners involving constituency (outpu</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="053-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">053-C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners learning networks (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="053-C" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">053-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners with evaluationstudies (outpu</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="053-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of partner organisations better able to communicate at the national and international levels the voice of people in rural areas living in poverty</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">004-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partnerorg AIM1 MO 004</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="004-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of partner organisations better able to communicate at the national and international levels the voice of people in rural areas living in poverty</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">004-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Local organisations of produc (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="004-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">004-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="004-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men (small-scale crop farmers, cattle farmers, fisher folk) able to use sustainable production methods enabling them to better protect and use sustainably their livelihood resources</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">001-02</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Female AIM1 DAB 001</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="001-02" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">001-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Male AIM1 DAB 001</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="001-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men (small-scale crop farmers, cattle farmers, fisher folk) able to use sustainable production methods enabling them to better protect and use sustainably their livelihood resources</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">001-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="001-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-08-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
