<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-02594-03:LA</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Office 506681 Country office Lao</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In order to engage the private sector to constructively contribute to some of Asia#s most urgent sustainable development and justice issues, CSR Asia and Oxfam will focus on areas where we have common interests, mutually reinforcing skills and knowledge,and whereour contributions can make the biggest impact.

Areas with the greatest potential to reduce poverty and injustice
In terms of sectors, agriculture and extractives have the highest impacts on communities and poor people in Asia, for a varietyof reasons. These include displacement of communities, depletion of common resources, lack of respect for human rights and labour rights, lack of access to value chains and employment opportunities, and many others. But these sectors also offer a potential path out of poverty if current practices could be changed and more of the population could benefit from the economic opportunities they bring in the short and long terms.

Asia is the most disaster prone region of the world, and the private sector has an important stake in reducing impacts, improving the quality of response, and speeding recovery both to protect its assets through a disaster, and to ensure the vitality ofthe communities upon which it relies. The private sector has an important role to play in building resilience in vulnerable communities, as well as skills and knowledge it can transfer to accelerate this in Asia.
Pervasive issues in Asia such as land rights, access to value chains, human rights, equality, and climate change resilience cross cut these sectors and are the key common themes thatwill be addressed through our work to share knowledge, build capacity, and convince leaders to take action.

A series of international and sectoral CSR instruments, developed through multi-stakeholder processes, are available for voluntary use by companies to address key sustainability issues. These, generally, have low traction and uptake among Asian companies, but could help provide a framework for corporate commitment and action towardssustainable development.

Maximizing Oxfam#s opportunities with the private sector
Oxfam has historically utilized a variety of avenues to engage with the private sector, from advocacy to philanthropy to project-based partnerships. To advance and deepen economic opportunities for the communities in which Oxfam works, and to advance fairness and justice for those adversely impacted by private sector practices, Oxfam seeks to engage in direct dialogue and activities with companies. A recent survey of Oxfamstaff by CSR Asia found an overall willingness to directly engage with the private sector, but capacityand confidence to do so varied widely in the country offices.

Oxfam and CSR Asia will work together in various ways to help prepare, equip and maximize the influence Oxfam staff can have on companies. This will mainly be done via training and ongoing support forOxfam staff in direct contact with companies. CSR Asia will also help with the development of engagement strategies and their implementation over the longer term to help advance Oxfam positions and change corporate behavior.

Building knowledge and fostering action for impact in the private sector
Oxfam brings a depth of knowledge about what works for sustainable development and povertyreduction.  CSR Asia will harness this knowledge and experience, and combine it with its own experience with the private sector, to influence private sector leaders toward more sustainable business practices. Main avenues will be via thought leadership campaigns, identification of champions and peer learning groups, training and capacity building, and demonstration of successful cases.

Overall, there is a need for a professionalization and integration of CSR practice into the private sector in Asia, which will be a key focus for CSR Asia#s capacity building and training work with the private sector and beyond.

CSR Asia and Oxfam in Asia have agreed on a three-year plan to advance their stated aim with the private sector that harness the experience,knowledge and skills of both organizations. The logical framework below outlines the intended activities and outcomes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib is one of the 17 national affiliates of the Oxfam International Confederation. It started life in 1956 as the Netherlands Organisation for International Assistance (Novib), and joined forces with Oxfam in 1994.  Working together in confederation, the Oxfam affiliates can speak with one clear and compelling voice on issues of global concern: climate change, health and education forall, agriculture, trade, and conflicts and emergencies.  Oxfam established this country office to support local organizations and projects.  Through this local office Oxfam Novib directly contributes towards this project&#x92;s implementation.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laos</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to a sustainable livelihood</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-25">18338</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-12-01">18338</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-12-01">18338</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-02594-03:LA">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007257"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="ZOA - Regional"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-02594"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="CSR ASIA 2013-2015"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">11</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no of policy changes regarding pro-poor markets and financial systems</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">011-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Lobby trajectories (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="011-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2013-01-01" value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">011-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="011-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2013-01-01" value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">11</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no of policy changes regarding pro-poor markets and financial systems</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">011-05</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Policy changes AIM1 BB 011</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="011-05" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2013-01-01" value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
