<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-02798-02:LA</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LWRN</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Introduction and background
Increasing influence of fisheries and farmers communities in decision making processes in water governance of the Mekong rivers basins is high on the agenda of the Southeast Asia regional strategies as well as country strategies of theMekong countries. Therefore in February 2012, ON South East Asia bureau in close consultation with Oxfam Australia as the lead of the water governance JRAS and WWF Greater Mekong Program, who has been identified as a key partner in this work bymid 2011,  submitted a concept note in response to the European Commission Call on Food Security Thematic Programme (FTSP). In this concept note, we have consulted three national rivers networks partners, two from the Mekong countries (CEPA in Cambodia asthe representative of the Rivers Coalition Cambodia and Lao Water Resources Network/LWRN) and one partner from Myanmar, representing the Salween River, the Karen Rivers Watch (KRW), officially represented by KESAN. We were unfortunately not able to include Vietnam in the concept note as the Call was restricted to the least developed countries. However at a later stage, during the full proposal development, we are able toinclude activities and linking and learning with Vietnam, regional NGO actors and academicians, based in Vietnam, Thailand and researchers from China, i.e. International Rivers, Vietnam Rivers Network, Thai People&#x92;s Mekong Network, TERRA, Burma Rivers Network, Salween Watch and Save the Mekong Coalition. The three national rivers networks partners are considered important in this proposal, both as the partners and direct target group of the proposed project. The EC proposal had a time period foreseen of 4 years, January 1, 2013 &#x96; December 31, 2016.
The title of the Action: Community Engagement in Governance of Mekong and Salween River Basins (CEGOMAS).
The objective of the Action is as follows:
To contribute to an increased influence of 513,500 poor and vulnerable farmers and fishers on the Governance of the Water Resources in the Salween and Mekong River Basins that support their food security and nutrition.
The Specific objectives are:
Specific Objective 1 (SO1): Three networks and member organizations of farmers and fishers have the  organizational capacity and knowledge to address, while representing their constituency, national and regional needs for good governance and sustainable management of water resources;
Specific Objective 2 (SO2): Improved dialogue and policy influencing space of three networks of farmers and fishersat national and regional levels related to the development of water resources.

Lao Water ResourcesNetwork (LWRN) is a newly founded network of committed individual members from national Non Profit Associations (NPAs) and locally based international NGOs. These individuals share similar vision around the importance of water resources for the food security and livelihoods of the riparian communities. While the network at present is a voluntary loose network, each individual member becomes agateway through its affiliated organisation to the established engagement with farmers and fishers groups.
Current contract is in place: A-02588-02-501623 for the period of September 1, 2012 to December 31, 2013.

The one year support for the three national rivers network and WWF GMPO will cover the following areas, for the period of November 1, 2012 to October 31, 2013. This will be done in close coordination with Oxfam Australia:
1. Full fledged baseline of the partners&#x92; influencing/advocacy and network capacities and skills to be able to engage in regional level dialogue/decision making processes.
2. Pilot work: this may slightly vary among partners, but in line to the activities proposed in the EC proposal/CEGOMAS (i.e. Xao Baan research, downstream impact research, RSAT inception/implementation workshop). The objective is to have one inspiring pilot activity or research successfully carried out and documented per country, to have a strong scale up component in our next proposal.
3. Some relevant but limitedengagement at regional level(some activities of specific objective 2, such as attending international/regional conference, which ideally will be attended by the three rivers network partners).
4. (Four monthly) internal reflection session for each network and the members and an end of yearevaluation process. The internal reflection session will inform the end-of-year  evaluation process. Some of the objectives of having these reflection moments are to share: a) the progress of data gathering/researchand influencing activities at national level; b)the needs and challenges of each network (internal and externally) and how to address these (the capacity needs of each network andthe members, how effective/sensitive is the influencing work at national level and how to best scale this up at regional level); c)how the hydropower tools help the influencing work of each network.
5. External funding activities: strengthening areas scoring lowin our proposal submission, i.e. sustainability, impact, replication. It is the hope that each of the consortium members, the threenational rivers networks including OAU, ON and WWF GMPO are proactively advocating our joint effort, however we also would like to make sure that a consultant will be committed to carry out this activities in collaboration with each partner, collating the baseline and progress to date and actively carrying out fundraising efforts. A draft ToR for the consultant will be jointly developed at a later stage, and the consultant will be housedby WWF GMPO.

Lao Water Resources Network (LWRN)
In the coming year, LWRN will deliverthe following outcomes:
Outcome 1: Three networks and member organizations of farmers and fishers have the organizational capacity and knowledge to address, while representing their constituency, national and regional needs for good governance and sustainable management of water resources.
Outcome 2: Improved dialogue and policy influencing space of three networks of farmers and fishers at national and regional levels related to the development of water resources.

Total amount of the water governance work in Laos is EUR 69,574.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC (Participatory Development Training Centre) was officially founded in late 1996. With an initial staff of five Lao development workers (four men and one woman), PADETC#s broad objective was to promote alternative models of development aimed at helping Laos# people to find ways to improve their livelihoods in a just and sustainable way.
Prior to its founding its director and his small team of development workers had worked in various aspects of agriculture and integrated rural development in many rural communities in Laos for more than 15 years, with the support mainly from international NGOs and some UN agencies.  During the early 1980s the team#s work had focused mainly on improvement of food security in poor rural communities by promoting low-cost appropriate agriculturaltechnologies, such as use of bio-fertilisers and bio-pesticides, and integration of fish-raising in the rice fields, etc. The impetus for working on food security during that time was the need to address the problem of food shortages faced by many rural communities in the aftermath of the 30-year war of independence which ended only in 1975.  It was through working on these agriculture-related projects that the team understood that the food security of Lao rural communities could not be solely resolved through improvements in agricultural techniques, but must be systematically tackled at a multi-dimensional level.
From the early 1990s onwards PADETC broadened its work to include integrated rural development, with the emphasison strengthening the capacities of rural communities andempower them to improve their livelihoods systematically.
The main strategic approaches used included: the promotion of participatory processes for community development, especially the use of participatory processes in problem analysis and planning in collaboration with local authorities and communities; the training of multi-sector rural development teams comprising staff from the agriculture, education, health, and woman#s unions at various levels (village, district, province); the setting up of integrated rural development offices at the provincial and district levels to provide management, extension, and monitoring support; and the production of Lao language manuals and forms for village surveys, planning, budgeting, reporting, and many types of production techniques.
With the expansion of its scope of work programmatically and geographically, PADETC has grown from its original staff of five in 1996 to anorganisation with 53 staff (12 women), all of them Lao. PADETC also draws on the support from international expertise in the form of short-term technical experts, advisors and volunteers, etc. through international agencies, such as German International Aid (DED), Singapore International Foundation (SIF), Australia Volunteer Service, etc.
PADETC continues to co-operate closely with governmentagencies at all administrative levels and ensures that responsible authorities are regularly briefed on the progress of its projects. PADETC has closeco-operation with a number of NGOs, UN and bilateral agencies. After more than ten years of operation and innovative contribution to local development, PADETC is increasingly given more political and social recognition as a local development agency. Basedon its experience the vision and mission of PADETC is to promote the concept of #liveable# communities which balances economic growth with social and cultural vibrancy, environmental harmony, and spiritual development for all.
PADETC has long operatedasalaboratory both for development thinking, and for the applied-use of locally appropriate approaches. This has included not only Learning Centre and network development, but the articulation of a conceptual framework for development.  In 2009, PADETCbeganthe process of supporting each Learning Centre and Network to become independent, paving the way for eventual registration as individual NPAs.

In July 2012, the founder and long term Director of PADETC Mr. Sombath has handed over the function toMr.Khamphoui Saythalat. The last year, PADETC has focussed much of its energy and resources and the internal transformation of its organisation as well as the AEPF process. Consequently, most of the activities now take place in and around Vientiane, although contacts with youth groups in other provinces still exist.

Also for the coming programme period the institutional transition process will demand a substantial investment in time and resources from PADETC. In order to support the new director in the processa group of &#x93;Friends of PADETC&#x94; has been formed with international and national members and that provides coaching and technical advice to PADETC.


PADETC will focus on four fields of action. These are:
1. Education for Sustainable Development (ESD)
2. Enabling Environment Support for Lao CSOs (with a particular focus on Organizational Development and Management, and Small Grant Facility)
3. Policy Advocacy (mainly with reference tothe recommendations made from the Impact Assessment report in March2012)
4. Resource mobilization including the marketing and delivery of services for the general public, NPAs and iNGOs.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-10-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laos</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to a sustainable livelihood</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-08">69574</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-08">4388</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-08">33697</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-08">40124</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-12-01">34787</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-12-01">34787</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-03-01">33697</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-05-01">31000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-09-01">9124</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-06-01">3626</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-06-01">762</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-12-01">34787</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-12-01">34787</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-06-01">3626</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-06-01">762</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-03-01">33697</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-05-01">31000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-09-01">9124</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-02798-02:LA">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007254"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Laos (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-02798"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Watergovernance 2012-2013"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">10</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no of policy changes regarding legislation, regulation and/or practices on access to property or inheritance rights and/or compensation mechanisms for loss, in the fields of land and water and preservation of biodiversity in particular to the benefit of w</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">010-C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Lobby trajectories (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="010-C" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2012-10-01" value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">010-E</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Organisations trained SRE (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="010-E" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2012-10-01" value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">010-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="010-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2012-10-01" value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">010-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Studies (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="010-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2012-10-01" value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">010-D</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Training seminars (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="010-D" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2012-10-01" value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">10</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no of policy changes regarding legislation, regulation and/or practices on access to property or inheritance rights and/or compensation mechanisms for loss, in the fields of land and water and preservation of biodiversity in particular to the benefit of w</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">010-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Policy changes AIM1 BB 010</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="010-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2012-10-01" value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of partner organisations better able to communicate at the national and international levels the voice of people in rural areas living in poverty</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">004-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partnerorg AIM1 MO 004</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="004-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2012-10-01" value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of partner organisations better able to communicate at the national and international levels the voice of people in rural areas living in poverty</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">004-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Local organisations of produc (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="004-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2012-10-01" value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">004-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="004-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2012-10-01" value="0" year="2012"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
