<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-04118-08:13</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADVOCACY SMALL HOLDER FARMERS WIN-ESAFF</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progressive international action on livelihoods and sustainable development dictates the need to address three inter-related objectives: Address food security, while dealing with the effects of climate change that are already being felt by the poor and vulnerableespecially small scale farmers; Ensure space for Africa#s development and in support of a just transition investing in small scale farmers and in Agricultural economy and calls for a  paradigm shift that supports strategies for achieving equitable development, realizing human rights, and the well-being of populations in the context of sustainable development. It is on the basis of these realities that intensified efforts by civil society and particularly small holders active participation in decision making and inclusion in policies to advocate for their interests.

It is against this backdrop that the efforts of ESSAF and its partners become more relevant since the impacts of investing in small scale agriculture and family farming will be felt at the local level and therefore theactive participation of the stakeholders at the local, regional and national levels is critical for the advancement of decisions reached through institutions and policy makers at all these levels.  This reality raises the question of governance within the agricultural agenda and practices.
ESSAF fills a capacity building and coordination need as small farmers increasingly feel marginalised and challenged by new agriculture trends and agribusiness for example bio fuels, carbon credit, and introduction of GMOs and seeds. This is pushing them to become organised at local level and increasingly at national level and regional level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESAFF</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The network has been actively involved in sharing of information, experiences, ideas and strategies among African small scale farmers and NGOs as a strategy for strengthening their capacity to effectively engage and participate in development processes from the national, regional, continental and with an eye on the global spaces upon realization that there is the need to keep small scale farmers  connected and in communication, in facilitating and strategizing to undertake collective actions on matters of common interest in Africa especially that which are of relevance to agriculture. The organization involves grass root men and women in their strategies mainly on; lobby, advocacy, use of communication and information technology (ICT and social media) and capacity building in its effort to advancing the rights of small scale farmers, recognition and participation in decision making processes in the target constituencies.

The partnership with OXFAM NOVIB and ESSAF has grown since 2006, boasting of the organization#s growth into a Pan African Network visible and credible asserting influence at strategic regional and global arenas. It is a strong network having mobilizedsmall scale farmer#s organizations in east and southern Africa that has brought together members in 15 countries working on a common agenda to advance the rights of farmers and sustainable family agriculture in the continent.

This project is a follow up to the previous grant for both institutional and programmatic contribution towardsESSAF#S execution of its strategic plan 2011-2014 that aimed addressed, Agro ecology, Agricultural policy advocacy and Organizational Development..
The organization facilitated member organizations and individuals to improve on their coalition building,policy and advocacy at the African Union, SADC-RAP, ECOWAS, EAC, by participating in the functions of these bodies as part of the larger CSOs in different forums. This was done through research, development of policy briefs and cross regional fora for small scale farmers from different nations to demand for their rights at these critical levels.
In Consolidating ESSAF#S institutional capacity, the 2014-2016 strategic plan seeks to respond to the past experienceand in anticipation of the incoming environment.
The Institutional capacity building proposal aims to facilitate the creation of a movement of small scale farmers in rural areas and enhancing their capacity to demand, practise, and advocate for sustainable agriculture and participation in policyand advocacy to better inform and contribute on the awareness of their  rights advocacy tools  so as to strengthen and build a strong African coalition of small scale farmers   rights movement that is actively and productively involved in engaging and influencing decision making process at all these levels.

PAP considers ESSAF a strong institution as an imperative to the success of any program the organization undertakes. Moreover the success and track record that the organization has recorded in capacity building, development of leadership among young men and women, lobby and advocacy-and participation in the CAADP process, partnership with like minded organizations, and current evidence and knowledge products, and the approach that interfaces communityand national level campaigns with global level processes through a regional platform is potential.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Horn, East and</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-22">10000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-10-01">10000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESAFF</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-10-01">10000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-04118-08:13">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007105"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="Pan Africa"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-04118"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="CAPACITY STRENGHTHENING FOR WIN"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">45</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases that show how partner organisations use new tools to measure and improve the legitimacy and risk management of organisations, with a special focus on (women) organisations in countries with repression and conflict.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">045-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Cases AIM4 KIM 045</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="045-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">45</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases that show how partner organisations use new tools to measure and improve the legitimacy and risk management of organisations, with a special focus on (women) organisations in countries with repression and conflict.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">045-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Methods and instruments (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="045-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">045-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners for knowledge exchange (outpu</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="045-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">045-C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners for trainings (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="045-C" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
