<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-04570-02:NG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Small-holder Fish Farmers Development</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fish represents an important part of the diet of people in Nigeria. Fish is a relatively cheap source of generally food-safe protein. The country has a significant aquaculture sector at a registered output of 260.000 MT of catfish alone. Despite this, estimated demand for fish still exceeds that of supply with a factor 2 to 3. An estimate of 2007 points at, at least, small 50.000 catfish farms and several thousand large farms producing for domestic consumption, and the number is assumed to have increasedsignificantly since then. The country has good environmental conditions for aquaculture as water is widely available. Nevertheless, conditions for aquaculture performance are also hindered by lack of infrastructure (e.g. electricity for cooling and ice is not widely available), lack of regulatory support mechanisms (e.g. regulation for quality, sector management information systems, technical extension servicesto farmers and vendors). Good quality brood-stock and feed is available in the country, but too expensive for most farmers.
Despitethese hindrances, catfish farming is profitable and can be pursued without intensive (expensive) training. Setting up a farm is capital intensive, but many smallholders have started either as apprentices on someone else#s farm (cheap labour but also the opportunity to save enough to start by leasing a pond) or by constructing a pond on available land and gathering ingredients (waste products)for home-based feeds.
Smallholder fish farms in Nigeria
Running a typicalsmallholder farm involves anything between 2-10 ponds (20x40-50 meters is a common pond size), at a stocking density of 5-25 fingerlings or juveniles per m2, and grow-out cycles of 3-5 months before harvest. Fish can then be between 0.7 to 1.2 kg in size. The main markets for fresh fish are restaurants. In some parts of Nigeria the preference is for larger fish (1,5-2,5 kg). Production per year per pond (2 cycles, typically) lies between 500 kg to 2500 kg. The larger farmers can employ up to 4 workers, but most farms rely purely on their own and household member labour. Overall in Nigeria it seems 10-15% of the smallholders are women farmers. More common is to see women as vendors (middle-men) and market traders. Fresh fish is preferred and is sold to traders all-over the country. Some urban markets (e.g. Abuja, Lagos) prefer larger fish (more rare but higher priced). Other markets (e.g. Ibadan restaurants) accept smaller sizes. Smoking harvested catfish is becoming more common and enables farmers to manage for shorter grow-out cycles (smaller fish is more suitable) as well as add value and shelf-life (preservation).
The single largest cost-item in growing catfish is feed; which can cost up to 70-80% of all costs incurred during grow-out. The use of commercial feed is therefore limited to, mostly, the first 1-2 months (fingerling/juvenile stages) when fishare sensitive and mortality is high. After this, fish becomes hardier (mortality is typically 10-15% for fish aged between 2-5 months) and farmers resort to home-made feed as that is cheaper to fabricate. This feed, however, is less attractive to the fish (pollutes the ponds easier) and is less efficient in nutrition (reduced growth in fish). Relying purely on homemade feed can reduce this relative cost to 30-40%.
Chemical use is limited, but not to be ignored. Phosphocide is regularly used to sterilize ponds before bringing in the fish (poisonous bio-accumulating pesticide); formalin is used as alternative (and freely flushed out to surface streams);nutrients (in water and pond bottom) are commonly freely flushed into neighboring water streams. Of note is also that maggots (grown from chicken intestines as alternative and cheaper protein source for fish) can no longer be grown from poultry discardscoming from village-level poultry growers that keep animals indoors. There are also some indications that conflicts with surrounding communities can occur. Also poaching can be a problem. There is also little to no regulation concerning aquaculture (the term itself even being absent in laws). Only farms larger than 50 ha are required to undertake an Environmental Impact Assessment. Food safety controls only exist on packaged and labeled products.
Other stakeholders desiring to come into the aid of smallholder fish farmers are faced with the challenges of near absence of farm documentation systems and absence of baseline data. In addition, is the absence of joint-venture initiatives among smallholder fish farmers/shared risk.
This pilot project aims to help smallholder fish farmers overcome some these weaknesses and develop a model that can be used by smallholder fish farmers to engage with different stakeholders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Justice Development and Peace Commi</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Democracy and Human Rights Programme is created to achieve the goal of contributing to a system of Inclusive governance process, where accountability, transparency and respect for human rights prevail in Oyo State. This programme is implemented in 28Local Government Areas; 22 in Oyo State and 6 in Osun State. The programe has two components; Democracy and Governance and Human Rights. Democracy and Governance is concerned with political re-awakening of the citizens for popular participation in politics and monitoring the democratic process in the state and nationally. Human Rights is concerned with providing legal aid and alternative dispute resolution services, promoting and enforcing human rights of the indigent members of society and inmates of theprison.
The objectives of this programme are:To see that Justices of the Peace are working effectively in an enabling environment; Police Community Relations on issues of human rights will be strengthened; the right of awaiting trial persons in Agodi Prison to fair hearing is guaranteed; Civil Coalition for Good Governance (CCGG) operational capacity is enhanced; articulated needs of the constituencies are reflected in government projects in Oyo State; infrastructural decay, human rights abuses are identified, exposed through electronic media and addressed by government.

The Integrated Development Programme seeks to improve the economic and social status, ensure food security and access to social facilities for improved rural livelihood among participating farmers in Ibadan Archdiocese. Our beneficiaries are subsistence farmers; men, women youths and the underserved within the archdiocese irrespective of religious believe and affiliation. They are offered capacity building on sustaining agriculturalpractices, promotion of group marketing initiatives, strategic lobby, advocacy, Networking and linkages. The integrated development programme covers both the rainforest zone and the derived savannah areas of the archdiocese. In the derived savannah area,wework in  Igangan 3 local government areas in Oyo state # Ibarapa north, Ibarapa East and Ido LGAs and Ayedaade and Irewole LGAs of Osun state.

The Women Development Child Rights Programme is concerned with promotion of the welfare of children and women especially the most vulnerable among them in our immediate environments with particular attention to 20 Local Government Areas in Oyo and some parts of Osun State, South West Nigeria. The Programme upholds children andwomen#s right to health, security and physical integrity, the right to be free from torture and cruel, inhuman or degrading treatment, and the right to life.
Our objective is to; facilitate the enforcement of the child rights acts for reduction of the incidence of child trafficking/labour in our immediate environment and sensitize the public on the adverse effects of these practices using themedia, street rallies and enlightenment workshops; create public enlightenment on the dangers of FGM and facilitate opportunities and access to expert counselling for FGM victims; network and collaborate with partners in relevant fields to facilitate and contribute to and enhance the chances of success in the projects# implementation.

Community Service Punishment Programme seeks to reform the criminal justice system in Oyo and Ogun States by advocating for a Bill for the use of community service punishment for minor offences to decongest the prisons, as well as to make reintegration of offenders into the society more achievable. The programme will also see to the implementation, management and Administration of the Community service law and scheme by ensuring that: the judiciary understands and applies community service sentencing for minor offences; aggrieved groups and individuals believe and accept community service punishment as satisfactory justice; the public is better aware and participate in chain monitoring of community service punishment gratefully.

The Caritas desk Ibadan is the Humanitarian and emergency response unit of the organization. It advocates peaceful coexistence of all by administering peace education to youths and establishing peace clubs in secondary schools in Oyo and Osun states; it pursues improved living conditions and physical, spiritual and social wellbeing of theinmates in Agodi prison; providesa platform for testing and counseling of people living with HIV/AIDS, Orphans and Vulnerable Children through her support group.

Justice, Development and Peace Committee-Parish operates within a particular Parish fromthegrass-root level. JDPC-Parish aims at imparting the Social Teaching of the Church to the parishioners and the members of different institutions or formation houses which are situated in those parishes in order to help them identify injustices or unjust restructures within their vicinities or raise awareness of the existing injustices such as modern slavery in terms of Child Trafficking and Labour, Female Genital Mutilation (FGM), Sexual abuse, widows# exploitation and harassment, violation of human rights, workers/farmers exploitation, conflicts and insecurity, unemployment or the vulnerable, just to mention but a few!
Having identified the injustices, JDPC-Parish members in collaboration withJDPC Headquarters address the issue(s) at hand promptly,adequately and accordingly. Thus, JDPC-Parish is a prophetic voice of the voiceless within a parish, though its voice echoes beyond parish level as it embraces not only Catholics but also non-Catholics living within a particular parish territory</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to a sustainable livelihood</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31310" percentage="80" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="33110" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-30">40000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-30">-3124</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-07-01">40000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Justice Development and Peace Commi</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-03-01">-3124</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Justice Development and Peace Commi</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-07-01">40000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-03-01">-3124</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-04570-02:NG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007155"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Nigeria (SAWA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-04570"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Small-holder Fish Farmers Development"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">17</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases by nationally and globally operating partner organisations documenting examples of alternative economic models,  together with knowledge institutes</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">017-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Cases AIM1 KIM 017</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="017-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">17</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases by nationally and globally operating partner organisations documenting examples of alternative economic models,  together with knowledge institutes</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">017-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Information products (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="017-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">017-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Local organisations (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="017-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men (small-scale crop farmers, cattle farmers, fisher folk) able to use sustainable production methods enabling them to better protect and use sustainably their livelihood resources</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">001-02</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Female AIM1 DAB 001</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="001-02" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">001-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Male AIM1 DAB 001</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="001-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men (small-scale crop farmers, cattle farmers, fisher folk) able to use sustainable production methods enabling them to better protect and use sustainably their livelihood resources</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">001-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="001-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
