<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05210-02:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UWONET- Fostering Women&apos;s Leadership Uga</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PROJECT TITLE: FOSTERING WOMEN#S LEADERSHIP TO ADVANCE WOMEN#S LAND RIGHTS AND ADDRESS VIOLENCE AGAINST WOMEN AND GIRLS IN UGANDA.
The project builds on the concluded 5-year Raising Her Voice Project (RHVP) which was conceived and designed to influence the UgandaGovernment to ratify and domesticate the Africa Union Protocol on Women#s Rights without harmful reservations; and to contribute topromoting the role of women in the decision-making processes affecting their lives. The five-year Project was launched in 2008 and ended in March 2013. This project will be part of the 2nd phase of the RHV which started march 2014. Although the 2nd phase of the project focuses on fostering Local women#s activism and leadership to advance Women#s land rights and fight against VAW, the 3rd yearof the 2nd phase of RHV will continue to consolidate gains made in advancing women#s land rights and VAW prevention and response
The project is intended to build the capacity of grass root political women leaders and women#s rights organisations to engage, influence and lobby for gender responsive programmes and interventions on land and to address VAW issues in line with the Maputo protocol.In 2010 and 2013, the Government of Uganda passed the Domestic Violence Act and the land policy respectively. This project aims therefore to expedite the implementation of these frameworks active engagement of the key stakeholders, majority of who are women (70%).
The project will also create important connections between decision making spaces at local (Sub county and district), national andregional levels. The Project consortium members will build the capacity and confidence of women and women leaders to equally influence national policy debates around implementation of the Domestic Violence Act, financing for GBV prevention and response facilitiesand the Land policy with emphasis, succession, inheritance and functionality of Land management structures at Local level. The project will build capacity of informal and formal structuresto strengthen coordination and the referral pathway for increased access tojustice.

Through the project, 2 main goals will be realised;
1) National women#s rights organisations and district coalitions working on VAW and women#s land rights will haveimproved capacity to influence government and social actors to address women#s rights violations
2) The Maputo Protocol and other regional declarations on women#s rights will be increasingly applied by national governments and traditional justice mechanisms</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-202918" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda Women#s Network (UWONET) was formed in 1993 as an advocacy network by Ugandan Women; 16 national women#s organisations, institutions and 9 individuals to steer women#s rights, gender transformation and equality agenda. The network was formed out of the East African Preparatory Conference held in Kampala in 1993 to spearhead Uganda women#s efforts which led to the participation in the UN World Conference on Women held in Beijing in 1995.  UWONET was formed to champion a untied voice and create space for women to collectively address and take action on gender based discrimination in spheres of social economic and political life of women in Ugandaat all levels. UWONET#s core mandate is policy advocacy, however for the past five years it has concentrated programmatically on specific thematic areas and focus i.e. Women#s Leadership and Democratic Governance, Women#s Rights and Access to Justice, Women#s Economic Justice and Empowerment and Institutional Development and Organisational Strengthening.
1. ACHIEVEMENTS
What have been the principal results in the past three years that contribute to significant, structural, sustained and positive improvement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?
1. Reduced tolerance and vulnerability to Gender Based Violence and most especially Violence against Women and Girls as a result of a holistic approach to GBV service delivery.
2. Policy influencing at National, regional and International levels such as engendering the NDP II, pushing for the enactment ofgender bills, policies and laws such as the Land Amendment Act, the Gender Policy, and the Marriage Bill, 2017. UWONET has also utilised global and regional processes and mechanisms to follow up on Uganda#s commitment to fulfilling gender through the CEDAW reporting and UPRM processes.
3. Increased and Improved access to justice and GBV case management as a result of strengthened individual, collective and systematic capacity of human rights and JLOS institutions such as the Police. SGBV desks have been introduced within the Police structure.
4. Increased women#s voice and influence in democratic governance and processes as a result of women#s participation in taking up leadership positions at all levels.
Enhanced capacity and voice among district based women#s organisations henceengaged in demanding for accountability for gender equality.3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE
Mission: To coordinate action among UWONET membership and targeted stakeholders through networking, capacity building, resource mobilisation, policy research and advocacy for the attainment of gender equality in Uganda.

Institutional objectives:
1) To promote women#s access to power and decision making positions in all sectorsand at all levels.
2) To improve the socio-economic conditions of women and other marginalized groups
3) To work towards the achievement of equal opportunities and rights to women in all sectors and increased access to and control of resources and benefits
4) To work towards the elimination of defilement, rape, violence against women and other forms of abuse against womenand children in society
5) To collect and disseminate information on the priority issues of concern to women.
Fields of activity:
Key thematic areas are: Women&apos;s  Leadership and Democratic Governance; Women&apos;s Rights and Access to Justice; Women&apos;s Economic Justiceand Empowerment and institutional development and Organisation strengthening.

The Geographical areas in which the organization works are Northern, Eastern, Western, West Nile and Karamoja Regions in districts of Lamwo, Kitgum, Agago, Pader, Amuru, Namutumba, Kamuli, Jinja, Buyende, Iganga, Mayuge, Kaliro, Bugiri, Moroto Kotido, Nakapiripirit, Abim, Kaboong, Amudat, Nebbi, Zombo and Mubende among others.

Social Actors are, Women, Girls, district local governments, women councillors, police, health workers, women in business, CBOs, Women groups, Local councils among others.

4. STRATEGIC POSITIONING
UWONET operatesin an environment in which there are a number of legal, policies and institutional frameworks for promotion of gender equality and increase in the number of women in politics such as the Constitution of the Republic of Uganda, National Gender Policy 2007, and affirmative Action.  However, the rights of women are continually violated and discrimination of women continues.

social Actiors are: Women, Girls, district local governments, women councillors, police, health workers, women councillors, women inbusiness, CBOs, women groups, members of parliament, ministries such as Ministry of Gender, Labour and Social Development, Ministry of Trade, Ministry of Justice and Contitutional Affairs, Ministry of Education, Ministry of Health among others.

The uniqueness is around policy advocacy and influencing at different levelsi.e. national, regional and international with views from the local levels.  In addition, available structures at the local/district levels to reach out to the communities i.e. district women networks.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda Women&apos;s Network (UWONET) UWONET</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="5" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to an identity</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="5" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-21">48454</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-01">24227</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam GB funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda Women&apos;s Network (UWONET) UWONET</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-07-01">24227</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam GB funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda Women&apos;s Network (UWONET) UWONET</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-01">24227</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-202918" ref="GB-CHC-202918">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-07-01">24227</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-202918" ref="GB-CHC-202918">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05210-02:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001233"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05210"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Fostering Women&apos;s Leadership in Uganda"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4420</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts on issues related to transformative leadership and women&apos;s political participation.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4420-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts on issues related to transformative leadership and women&apos;s political participation.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="4420-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-01-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="23"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="23"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4420</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts on issues related to transformative leadership and women&apos;s political participation.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4420-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="4420-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-01-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="23"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="23"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
