<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-04118-10:13</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergrating CSOvoices ESA-WIN-CUTS</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">They seek to contribute to national and regional policy discourses by providing technical
support and guidance to various stakeholders on national, regional and international policy issues, viz. consumer protection, trade and development, good governance, and competition and regulatory policy.
Its specific objectives include:
# To act as a knowledge center for information on trade and development, competition, consumer protection, investment and regulatory policy issues.
# To build local, national, and regional capacitiesof multiple stakeholders on areas of trade and sustainable development, competition, consumer protection, governance, investment, and regulatory policy through advocacy and dissemination of information through South-South cooperative approach.
# To promote civil society co-operation on trade, sustainable development and regulatory reforms by creating and building long term capacity of civil society representatives and civil servants to address the issues of equity and accountability in the economic systems.
# To undertakeresearch based advocacy at the national, regional and international levels on those policies that have impact on trade and sustainable development.

Their area of FOCUS is East Africa but the project will be implemented in the Southern Africa as well.

Aim 1; Better access to fair markets &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; reliable financial systems

1. To increase the opportunities for people living in poverty to takeactive part in, and benefit from, trade systems and markets.


2. Toincrease the resilience of people living in poverty in terms ofthe disadvantageous effects of the current financial and trade systems.

Outcome Indicator 4; B. local producers organisations thathave received support to strengthen their lobbying and networking capacity. [004-B]

Outcome Indicator 8; No. of globally working partner organisations with enhanced lobby-, network- and research capacity for influencing international institutions and internationally operating companies with a pro-poor agenda[*008-03]

# Global partner organisations active in fair markets and trade that have received support in order to strengthen their capacities in the field of lobbying, research and networking.
# Research reports aboutspecific themes and business activities in developing countries.
# Information products (user guides, briefing papers, toolkits, websites, etc.).
#  Networks of partner organisations that have been set up to put public pressure on the internationally operating food and drinks industry.
# Training courses and/or seminars about socially responsible entrepreneurship

Outcome Indicator 11; No of policy changes regarding pro-poor markets and financial systems [*011-05]

# Partner organisations that have sufficient knowledge and resources to effectively lobby their governments for pro-poor development.
#  Lobbying trajectories for pro-poor development developed by the IMPACT Alliance

Outcome Indicator 14; No of policy changes regarding governments, international financial and tradeinstitutions and multinational companies (via e.g. the Fair Banking Guide)

# Global partner organisations that are supported by the IMPACT Alliance in their lobbying activities for pro-poor economic policy. B.
# Lobbying trajectories to promote pro-poor economic policy that have been set up by the IMPACT Alliance.
# Campaigns to promote pro-poor economic policy ( set up by the IMPACT Alliance).
#Internationally operating companies and international institutions that have been lobbied by the IMPACTAlliance for a more pro-poorpolicy.
#  Studies about the regulation and policy of socially responsible entrepreneurship, and trade and investment.
# Campaign trajectories about the regulation and policy of socially responsible entrepreneurship, and tradeand investment</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CUTS-Centre for International Trade Economics and Environment, Nairobi http://www.cutsinternational.
org/ARC/Nairobi/ is an independent Non profit; Non Governmental
Organisation registered under Section 10 of the NGO Co-ordination Act of the laws of Kenya on 2nd November 2000. Over time it has come to be commonly referred to as CUTS,
Nairobi. It started its operations in the year 2003.

The Organization is affiliated to CUTS International (www.cuts-international.org) registered
in India in 1984 as Consumer Unity &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Trust Society, a non-governmental organisation working on public interest issues with a #rights-based# approach in different parts ofthe world with a staff strength of over 120 persons and a large international network of professionals (associated in various othercapacities, e.g., fellows, consultants, advisers, etc.) working on international trade and development, consumer protection, governance, competition policy and law and economic regulation issues. However, CUTS Nairobi is an independent legal entity with its own board and management.

The mission of the organization is to function as a resource, coordination as well as networking Centre to promote South-South cooperation for sustainable, people-centred economic and social development in Eastern Africa specifically and the Sub Saharan Africa generally.

They seek to contribute to national and regional policy discourses by providing technical
support andguidance to various stakeholders on national, regional and internationalpolicy issues, viz. consumer protection, trade and development, good governance, and competition and regulatory policy.
Its specific objectives include:
# To act as a knowledge centre for information on trade and development, competition, consumer protection, investment and regulatory policy issues.
# To build local, national, and regional capacities of multiple stakeholders on areas of trade and sustainable development, competition, consumer protection, governance, investment, and regulatory policy through advocacy and dissemination of information through South-South cooperative approach.
# To promote civil society co-operation on trade, sustainable development and regulatory reforms by creating and building long term capacity of civil society representatives and civil servants to address the issues of equity and accountability in the economic systems.
# To undertake research based advocacy at the national, regional and international levels on those policies that haveimpact on trade and sustainable development.

There area of FOCUS is East Africa but the project will be implemented in the Southern Africa as well.
As such, the partnership with CUTS contributes to the below-stated Outcomes and related Outputs.

Aim 1; Better access to fair markets &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; reliable financial systems

1. To increase the opportunities for people living in poverty to take active part in, and benefit from, trade systems and markets

2. To increase the resilience of people living in poverty in terms of the disadvantageous effects of the current financial and trade systems.

Outcome Indicator 4; B. local producers organisations that have received support to strengthen their lobbying and networking capacity. [004-B]

Outcome Indicator 8; No. of globally working partner organisations with enhanced lobby-, network- and research capacity for influencing international institutions and internationally operating companies with a pro-poor agenda [*008-03]

# Global partner organisations active in fair markets and trade that have received support in order to strengthen their capacities in the field of lobbying, research and networking.
# Research reports about specific themes and business activities in developing countries.
# Information products (user guides, briefing papers, toolkits, websites, etc.).
#  Networks of partner organisations that have been set up to put public pressure on the internationally operating food anddrinks industry.
# Training courses and/or seminars about socially responsible entrepreneurship

Outcome Indicator 11; No of policychanges regarding pro-poor markets and financial systems [*011-05]

# Partner organisations that have sufficient knowledge and resources to effectively lobby their governments for pro-poor development.
#  Lobbyingtrajectories for pro-poor development developed bythe IMPACT Alliance

Outcome Indicator 14; No of policy changes regarding governments, international financial and trade institutions and multinational companies (via e.g. the Fair Banking Guide)

# Global partner organisations that are supported by the IMPACT Alliance in their lobbying activities for pro-poor economic policy. B.
# Lobbying trajectories to promote pro-poor economic policy that have been set up by the IMPACT Alliance.
# Campaigns topromote pro-poor economic policy ( set up by the IMPACT Alliance).
# Internationally operating companies and international institutions that have been lobbied by the IMPACT Alliance for a more pro-poor policy.
#  Studies about the regulation and policyof socially responsible entrepreneurship, and trade and investment.
# Campaign trajectories about the regulation and policy of socially responsible entrepreneurship, and trade and investment</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consumer Unity &amp; Trust Society Afri</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Horn, East and</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-08">10000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-10-01">10000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consumer Unity &amp; Trust Society Afri</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-10-01">10000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-04118-10:13">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007105"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="Pan Africa"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-04118"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="CAPACITY STRENGHTHENING FOR WIN"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">45</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases that show how partner organisations use new tools to measure and improve the legitimacy and risk management of organisations, with a special focus on (women) organisations in countries with repression and conflict.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">045-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Cases AIM4 KIM 045</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="045-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">45</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of cases that show how partner organisations use new tools to measure and improve the legitimacy and risk management of organisations, with a special focus on (women) organisations in countries with repression and conflict.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">045-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Methods and instruments (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="045-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">045-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners for knowledge exchange (outpu</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="045-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">045-C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners for trainings (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="045-C" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
