<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-04398-06:AF</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAPACITY BUILDING PROGRAMME</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In order to bring about positive sustainable changes in the lives of people and their organisations, Oxfam Afghanistan will continue with capacity building interventions for its own staff, partner organizations, and other civil society/grassroots organizations (working within our geographical programme area). This is consistent with Oxfam Afghanistan#s strategic plan and Oxfam Global-CapacityBuilding Policy emphasising our continued commitment to work with and through partnerships. Oxfam has developed aconcept for a period of one year in order to roll out its capacity building mandate.

Oxfam pursues its vision through multiple sets of action agenda.Firstly, direct partnership with LNGOs and vulnerable communities for facilitating their local initiatives. Secondly, contribute towards reducing poverty and social disparities, ensuring basic services, and institution building through increasing participation inlocal governance and protecting environment. Another action agenda is to influence policy processes by promoting articulation of the perspectives of the poor and disadvantaged. This may be achieved by facilitating alliance/networks among various civil society actors.
Supporting and nurturing these agenda, Oxfam#s Programme along with relevant support functions will carry forward Oxfam#s agenda for capacity building with a view to promote self-identity, self-reliance and self-growth of marginalized communities. Oxfam seeksto strengthen and widen the process of learning across a variety of relevant themes and contexts of different stakeholders in social development at different levels. It will mainly focus on the processes of transfer and exchange of knowledge and experiences, as well as the provision of technical expertise.

MISSION:
Capacity Building Programme#s mission is to contribute to sustainable changes, poverty reduction in Afghanistan by strengthening the capacity of Oxfam and other citizen organizations. We will work to accomplish this mission through following: human resource development, institutional strengthening, organizational development, creating an enabling environment through discussion, discourse and publications.

AIM of the PROGRAMME:
Help reduce poverty by supporting Civil Society Organizations, primarily serving rural constituencies, through building managerial and technical competence so that they can realise their potential of empowering people.

MODUS OPERANDI:
# human resource development, by providing staff training and supporting personnel policy;
# organizational development by improving internal processes and structures, financial durability and the management culture within partner organizations improve their management;
# institutional strengthening by strengthening the capacities of partner organizations and networks in areas such as advocacy, institutional learning, and the formations of strategic alliances;
# building social partnerships by building bridges between the government, and NGOs;
# advocacy to create and flourish the culture of discourse, debate and critical analysis of local and national issues; also by assisting NGOs in organizing national debate on key issues or getting articles in Oxfam#s newsletter for discussion and debate;
# association-building and network development by facilitating dialogue and networking among NGOs and NGO support groups through Discussion Fora and by being members to different consortiums and forums;
# image promotion for Oxfam by working with NGOs to develop media outreach campaigns and providing training in developing public service messages;
# encourage cooperation and collaboration between grassroots organizations and intermediaries by facilitating networking and exploring opportunities for learning and sharing of ideas through forums such as forums on Issues on Social Development in Afghanistan;
# help establish a resource base for learning in the area of livelihood food security, local self governance and civil society building.
The specific programme purpose is to strengthen Afghanistani civilsociety in addressing their concerns through inclusive interventions and strategies so that they are enabled to provide services and are able to defend the interests of their members and constituencies. Additionally, civil society is being empowered to promote the improvement and maintenance of good governance as well as peace in the country and establish working relations with both state structures and the private sector.

The programme is initially formulated as a one-year programme with the broad objectives of raising awareness on the roles and responsibilities of civil society, through public awareness and advocacy, strengthening the capacity of civil society organizations to contribute to peace, development and human rights and strengthening linkages within civil society and with other actors including local authorities and the international community via trainings and publications. This programme reflects Afghanistan#s view that civil society and civic organization is best placed to bring about lasting change.

Expected Outcomes:

# Oxfam#s capacity building work willbe able to address the training needs of staff and partners.
# Oxfam CB work will be able to provide a platform to the different provincial, national and international organizations and government department for the exchange of information and experiences.
# Oxfam will be able to increase its out-reach/visibility to civil society organizations and government department and disseminate and collect updated information regarding its main areas of work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACSFo,

Afghan Civil Society Forum (ACSF) was established in February 2002 on the request of 76 participants of Afghan Civil Society Conference in Germany, 2001, as a partnership between Afghan civil society partners and Swiss Peace. In May 2002 ACSF opened its offices in Kabul. In 2010, ACSF changed its legal status to an NGO (since then called ACSFo).

The Bonn agreement induced the processtowards democratic ideals and participatory political structures of which the Loya Jirga (June 2002) and the constitution (January 2004) were the first big steps. ACSF promoted the development of civic education (culture of peace, democracy and justice) among theyoung and undefined civil society in Afghanistan with partner organisations across the entire country in the context of these important events.

ACSF&#x92;s mission is to strengthen civil society and its countervailing power in stabilising the country, so that citizens are aware and committed to participate in the development of a just and equitable society; disarmament and security being prerequisites for democratic development.

From 2002 to 2005 civic education became ACSFo&#x92;s main strategy to prevent human rights abuses andto promote a culture of peace, democracy and justice. ACSF works as a network organization and organized Nation-wide campaigns (with support of DFID, UNOPS/JEMBS and USAID). About 10-15% of the Afghan population was reached leading to 31% women participation in the presidential elections (2004) and 34% in the parliamentarian elections (2005). These projects educated over 11 million Afghans. Since 2002 ACSF also has been able to publish 68 editions of Jamea-e-Madani civil society magazine have been brought out.

F rom 2006-2009 ACSF carried out a country-wide civic education programme financed by Oxfam Novib, contributing to awareness creation on civilrights and democratic processes amongst young and not yet &apos;defined&apos; civil society.
ACSFo also added advocacy and research, peace-building/governance and institutional capacity building to its activities consisting of:

&#x95; Facilitation of National Consultations/Dialogue: collecting public opinion concerning the by the government claimed achievements on security, poverty reduction, health, education, transparency and fighting poppy cultivation.

&#x95; Institutional Capacity Building: ACSFo works with Counterpart Inter&#xAC;national (CPI) to implement the &#x93;Initiative to Promote Afghan Civil Society&#x94; (I-PACS) &#x96; a nationwide approach that supports the development ofa civil society friendly legal framework.

&#x95; Advocacy/Research: ACSFo has set-up advocacy committees on topics such as youth, womenand people with disabilities, environment and transparency and accountability. Concerns of the citizens are advocated at national level and the organisation of National youth conferences (2002, 2004 and 2005).

ACSFo has implemented a research project &#x84;How Peopledefine Violence and Justice&#x93;, examining the people&#x92;s understanding of violence in the past five decades. Results were used to strengthenpeace initiatives via local and people-driven justice and reconciliation processes.

&#x95; Peace-building/Governance: ACSFo is member of the Afghan Civil Society Organisations Network for Peace (ACSONP). Peace-building training manuals have been produced aNational Peace Day was celebrated throughout the country in 2007.

In 2009, ACSFo piloted a Community Policing project in 31 districts of five Northern provinces, bridging gaps between the governmental/law enforcement institutions and the civil society, reducing local conflicts and improving capacities and accountability of the Afghan National Police.

&#x95; Networking/Coordination: ACSFo has expanded its civil society network across Afghanistan, comprising 320 partner organisations and 130 members othermembers.

In recent strategic repositioning discussions it was concluded that ACSFo should continue emphasising rural areas and as organisation try to form an important &#x91;internode&#x92;/cross-point for synergic sharing and strengthening of qualities of individual members (horizontal linkages) and for analysing and forwarding of information originated at central government level and organisations active in the context of local government institutions and structures (vertical linkages). In the current development of the government decentralisation and devolution of government towards provinces, districts and further downwards to grass-root levels civic education, awareness creation in combination with mobilisation and are very important co-processes for empowering communities and strengthening of the democratic basis in Afghanistan, wherein ACSFo plans to play a catalysing role.

ACSFo  is one of the few NGOs that really have added value to civil society development in Afghanistan. Projects of most NGOs areactually to a large extent service deliveries and relief activities, which often use traditional social and political power structures to reach the communities and therewith confirm and consolidate thesepower relations. Critical analysis if activities are reaching the most vulnerable people are lacking in many organisations and perhaps some activities are even counterproductive. Oxfam Novib has endeavoured to strengthen NGOs capacities and to develop insights. ACSFo has been an important player in this CS strengthening process and is in the current local governance programme showing it can also bring the countervailing power function of CSOs in practice.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Civil Society Forum</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-15" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-17">20000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-03-01">20000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Civil Society Forum</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-03-01">20000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-04398-06:AF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007201"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Afghanistan ASIA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-04398"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="CAPACITY BUILDING PROGRAMME"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">40</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of partner organisations with stronger capacity for monitoring governments and private sector on obligations and duties in their budget (income and expenditure) with specific attention to impact on women</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">040-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners AIM4 MO 040</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="040-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-15" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">40</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of partner organisations with stronger capacity for monitoring governments and private sector on obligations and duties in their budget (income and expenditure) with specific attention to impact on women</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">040-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners course budget (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="040-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-15" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
