<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05027-02:ML</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Every Child needs a Good Teacher</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project Each child need a good teacher is part of the support of the objectives of the Emergency Programme On EFA and the orientation of the Mali new PRODEC-Programme Decennal pour Education through the implementation of the policy national initialtraining and continuing master and its long-term strategic plan. It must help to consolidate the achievements of the initial and continuous training by capitalizing on modules, operational strategies implementation and partnership dynamics between actors.His chances of success depend largely on the inclusion in this dynamique. The framework of the implementation of the training of teachers, the project &quot;Every child needs a good teacher&quot; played a decisive role in improving the quality of education in the Segou region. More than 3,000 teachers in the primary I have been trained and monitored.
Indeed, the supervision of the Academy showed tremendous difficulties in some educational consultants in performing their monitoring mission especially, coaching and management training workshops.
In orderto safeguard the achievements, the Academy of San request the financial and technical support of the project &quot;Every child needs a good teacher&quot; for the training of 20 newly appointed education consultants in their roles and responsibilities.
In order to give every child a good teacher and where as steering comity are essential links in the pursuit of this objective, it is necessary to train them in their roles and responsibilities so that they can perform their missions desired height.
Strengthening of 20 educational consultants SAN capabilities of AE through their training on their roles and responsibilities to support the monitoring of train teacherwith introduction of new technology
1. Train 20 Educational Consultants on their roles and responsibilities
2 .Organize audit of project accounts
Description of activities:-reinforcement of the partnership at the turn of the project: the project will continue to develop a fruitful collaboration framework based on the participation of all actors at the local, regional and national levels. Capacity-building Training: The project will use the cascade training approach, pledge for the sustainability of the project activities.The national trainers form pools of regional trainers who will in turn train teachers ECOM.    the training sessions for teachers ECOM for lasting 21 days: the practical organization of the training courses is an important activity which planning requires the involvement of important players suchas managers of schools, teachers &apos; unions and teachers. It will involve 500 community  teachers ina single cohort. During training, it will be made available to participants the required documentation.  pedagogical follow-up...
The project will supportalso the logistic of programme to access in field by a new car. The funding with comic relief supports a costof salary of driver but did support means of displacement.This project a part of Program quality educator for all in Mali is the result of a partnership between Oxfam novib, international education EI, the Ministry of Education of Mali national and civil society organizations: National Union of Education and Culture SNEC and the Association of youth for the endogenous development in the SahelAJDES Children receiving quality education will have better opportunities to decent jobs and will participate actively in their society. Oxfam and Education International with the help of Comic Relief have joined forces to improve the quality of the education system since 2012 in Mali.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Association des Jeunes pour le D&#xE9;veloppement Endog&#xE8;ne au Sahel (AJ</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Endowed with legal and moral entity, the Association of the Young for Endogenous Development in the Sahel (AJDES) is created February 7, 1989. It received its accreditation from the Malian Government in May 8 following receipt of declaration n&#xB0; 0411 / MATDB.DRUCT. DAG of February 11, 1989. It is non-profit and is apolitical. AJDS signed its agreement centers with the Government of Mali October 3, 1989 (Agreement centers n&#xB0; 148 of October 3, 1989). It has therefore sixteen (16) years of existence.
Statutes and Internal Regulation
AJDES has written statutes and internal regulations applicable to all members.
Mission :
Contribute to the lasting improvement of living conditions of populations though empowerment of the most vulnerable layers (women and youth) by supporting the organization, initiation and implementation development actions.
Vision :
A reference NGO concerning support - advice, of convenient training for communal development by 2020.
 Objectives :
As an organization that supports community based initiatives, AJDS objectives are:
# Reinforce autonomy and build capacity of women and the youth by facilitating their access to resources, information and training.
# Address desertification by supporting actions aiming to reforest and creating a green belt.
# Promote the combination of modern and traditional technologies through sensitization, animation training of communities.
# Favor the reinsertion of youth their community by initiating and implementing development actions.
# Contribute to enhancing health condition of communities through behavior change (BCC, activities and by supporting the decentralization of the health system
# Contribute to the promotion of basic education by supporting the establishment and animation of literacy center.
# Serve as implementing body and relay for other development partners in common interest fields.

 Methodology:

The principle that guides AJDES is that on the one hand, there is not a real development without a conscious and active involvement of the concerned populations and that on the other hand the programs must stretch toward the satisfaction of the important needs of these populations
In other words, AJDES aims to promote an endogenous and inspired auto-centered development of communities.
In this consideration AJDES helps the concerned populations to put in place and to enliven structures that auto promote and self-manage to take in charge their own development needs.

AJDES brings its support to communities, municipalities and vulnerable groups (women, youth disabled) committed and mobilized to achieve development micro-projects, Income Generating Activities of (IGA), information, education and communication (BCC) activities to the profit of family planning, reproductive healthand the promotion of the child rights (good nutrition, schooling). AJDS stresses on the necessity to promote accessible and easily controllable technologies by populations.
AJDES collaborates to this effect with all development stakeholders operating inits impact area (decentralized bodies, political organizations of mass, technical services, NGO#)
Address et Representation.
AJDES isheadquartered at : Hamdallaye ACI 2000, Rue 390, Porte : 1734 Telephone: 79  06 8756 / 67 67 56 02  and has representatives in the regions of Koulikoro ,Sikasso, Segou ,Gao)
Field of Expertise
AJDS intervenes in the files of: Education, Literacy, Health, Environment, Training ,Agro #sylvo-pastoral , Micro- finance.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ML" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mali</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="10" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-08">51833</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-06-01">51833</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Association des Jeunes pour le D&#xE9;veloppement Endog&#xE8;ne au Sahel (AJ</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-06-01">51833</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05027-02:ML">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007153"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Mali (SAWA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05027"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Support Each Child need a Good Teacher"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2320</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts against extreme inequality and poverty.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts against extreme inequality and poverty -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2016-06-01" value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="3"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2320</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts against extreme inequality and poverty.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas  -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2016-06-01" value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="3"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
