<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-04398-14:AF</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAPACITY BUILDING PROGRAMME</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In order to bring about positive sustainable changes in the lives of people and their organisations, Oxfam Afghanistan will continue with capacity building interventions for its own staff, partner organizations, and other civil society/grassroots organizations (working within our geographical programme area). This is consistent with Oxfam Afghanistan#s strategic plan and Oxfam Global-CapacityBuilding Policy emphasising our continued commitment to work with and through partnerships. Oxfam has developed aconcept for a period of one year in order to roll out its capacity building mandate.

Oxfam pursues its vision through multiple sets of action agenda.Firstly, direct partnership with LNGOs and vulnerable communities for facilitating their local initiatives. Secondly, contribute towards reducing poverty and social disparities, ensuring basic services, and institution building through increasing participation inlocal governance and protecting environment. Another action agenda is to influence policy processes by promoting articulation of the perspectives of the poor and disadvantaged. This may be achieved by facilitating alliance/networks among various civil society actors.
Supporting and nurturing these agenda, Oxfam#s Programme along with relevant support functions will carry forward Oxfam#s agenda for capacity building with a view to promote self-identity, self-reliance and self-growth of marginalized communities. Oxfam seeksto strengthen and widen the process of learning across a variety of relevant themes and contexts of different stakeholders in social development at different levels. It will mainly focus on the processes of transfer and exchange of knowledge and experiences, as well as the provision of technical expertise.

MISSION:
Capacity Building Programme#s mission is to contribute to sustainable changes, poverty reduction in Afghanistan by strengthening the capacity of Oxfam and other citizen organizations. We will work to accomplish this mission through following: human resource development, institutional strengthening, organizational development, creating an enabling environment through discussion, discourse and publications.

AIM of the PROGRAMME:
Help reduce poverty by supporting Civil Society Organizations, primarily serving rural constituencies, through building managerial and technical competence so that they can realise their potential of empowering people.

MODUS OPERANDI:
# human resource development, by providing staff training and supporting personnel policy;
# organizational development by improving internal processes and structures, financial durability and the management culture within partner organizations improve their management;
# institutional strengthening by strengthening the capacities of partner organizations and networks in areas such as advocacy, institutional learning, and the formations of strategic alliances;
# building social partnerships by building bridges between the government, and NGOs;
# advocacy to create and flourish the culture of discourse, debate and critical analysis of local and national issues; also by assisting NGOs in organizing national debate on key issues or getting articles in Oxfam#s newsletter for discussion and debate;
# association-building and network development by facilitating dialogue and networking among NGOs and NGO support groups through Discussion Fora and by being members to different consortiums and forums;
# image promotion for Oxfam by working with NGOs to develop media outreach campaigns and providing training in developing public service messages;
# encourage cooperation and collaboration between grassroots organizations and intermediaries by facilitating networking and exploring opportunities for learning and sharing of ideas through forums such as forums on Issues on Social Development in Afghanistan;
# help establish a resource base for learning in the area of livelihood food security, local self governance and civil society building.
The specific programme purpose is to strengthen Afghanistani civilsociety in addressing their concerns through inclusive interventions and strategies so that they are enabled to provide services and are able to defend the interests of their members and constituencies. Additionally, civil society is being empowered to promote the improvement and maintenance of good governance as well as peace in the country and establish working relations with both state structures and the private sector.

The programme is initially formulated as a one-year programme with the broad objectives of raising awareness on the roles and responsibilities of civil society, through public awareness and advocacy, strengthening the capacity of civil society organizations to contribute to peace, development and human rights and strengthening linkages within civil society and with other actors including local authorities and the international community via trainings and publications. This programme reflects Afghanistan#s view that civil society and civic organization is best placed to bring about lasting change.

Expected Outcomes:

# Oxfam#s capacity building work willbe able to address the training needs of staff and partners.
# Oxfam CB work will be able to provide a platform to the different provincial, national and international organizations and government department for the exchange of information and experiences.
# Oxfam will be able to increase its out-reach/visibility to civil society organizations and government department and disseminate and collect updated information regarding its main areas of work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Rights Research and Advocacy Consortium</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Human Rights Research and Advocacy Consortium (HRRAC) was formed early 2003 and brings together eight Afghan and six international organisations committed to promoting peace and human rights in Afghanistan. The member organisations contribute a wealth of experience, from the fields of humanitarian relief, rehabilitation, human rights, women&apos;s rights, peace promotion, research and advocacy. They include some of the most experienced and respected agencies working in Afghanistan, and their extensive programme experiencesgives HRRAC an unrivalled access to communities. HRRAC is therefore a unique initiative for Afghanistan, and for other countries emerging from conflict and insecurity.

HRRAC engages in research, training and collective and pro-activeadvocacy activities on human rights in Afghanistan. The first phases of HRRAC (2003-2005) were co-funded by USIP (United States Institute for Peace) and (Oxfam) Novib with contributions of the consortium members. The third and fourth phases (2005-2007 and2007-2011) were funded by Oxfam Novib with member contributions.


HRRAC intends to influence the development and implementation of policies, to promote peace, security and human rights, by motivating people to voice their opinions, concerns and priorities, and give their input to human rights-based policy changes. HRRAC focuses on issues related to social (mainly education), economic- and political rights.
The different projects concerned research to generate information on what Afghans think aboutkey human rights issues, including security rights, political rights, and the right to quality education in the country. HRRAC intends to collect the opinions and voices of Afghans from all parts of the country, without any distinction in sex, gender, education, occupation, ethnicity or location. The research findings will be communicated to the government, donor agencies, civil society organisations, and participating communities from all over the country. It will also use this research to advocate for positive policy changes.

During the four earlier phases HRRAC has published a number of documents on education, civic education, disarmament, governance issues and women rights. These publications were widely spread and appreciated.

In the last years HRRAC&#x92;s core programme addressed the political and development environment. These were optimum for advocacy activities (young democracy/parliament, decentralisation in development, strong donor attention for good governance,education, etc.). HRRAC gathered strengths and opportunities of the members in a joint advocacy approach, which functioned as an important feed back to many national NGOs. This joint/network approach also has contributed in avoiding &#x93;re-invention of the wheel&#x94;, especially with active/effective participation of AREU and ACBAR. This puts HRRAC in a rather unique position.

Since 2010 HRRAC is concentrating its efforts in the following:
The right to political participation (with a special emphasis on women&#x92;s participation)
Access to justice
Rights to livelihood and economic security
Freedom of expression
The right to peace and physical security
The rightto education
Countering traditional practices that are incompatible with human rights

Considering the current political environment in the country, women&#x92;s political and public rights will continue to be a prioritized objective of the organization during the coming years. This forms the main subject for HRRAC&#x92;s current partnership with Oxfam Novib, which aims at strengtheningof the enabling environment for equitable and independent participation of women in national and provincial peace- and reconciliation processes at the national and provincial level via public action.
This will be tackled by a three fold strategy consisting of the components: Research, advocacy and awareness-raising.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-15" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-30">20000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-03-01">20000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Rights Research and Advocacy Consortium</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-03-01">20000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-04398-14:AF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007201"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Afghanistan ASIA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-04398"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="CAPACITY BUILDING PROGRAMME"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">40</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of partner organisations with stronger capacity for monitoring governments and private sector on obligations and duties in their budget (income and expenditure) with specific attention to impact on women</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">040-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners AIM4 MO 040</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="040-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-15" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">40</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of partner organisations with stronger capacity for monitoring governments and private sector on obligations and duties in their budget (income and expenditure) with specific attention to impact on women</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">040-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners course budget (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="040-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-15" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
