<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-04589-02:LA</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting Gender Equality Through Film</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTRODUCTION:
Urban population is growing in Laos as economic reforms offer work and education opportunities amidst complicated social and cultural trends. Many young men and women from rural areas relocate to the Capital to look for work, education andlife changing opportunities. Their lives have faced a lot of challenges. These challenges can be grouped economically, socially and culturallynot limited to low income, and sexual identity and sexual orientation.

Economic, Social &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Cultural Challenges:
The Lao population is scattered unevenly throughout the country (Laos Guide 999, 2014). Approximately one third (27%) of the country#s populationcurrently lives in urban areas, while the rest of the population (73%) lives in rural areas, depending onfarming, fishing and natural resources for survival (Laos Guide 999, 2014). According to UN Human Development Report 2009, only 73% of Lao#s adult population can read and write, and that there are more illiterate woman than men (United Nations, 2009). Causes of female illiteracy fluctuate across provinces and among the different ethnic groups, but poverty, distance, costs and traditional beliefs tend to be the main factors (United Nations, 2009). Other factors consist of the affliction of household chores,early marriage or pregnancy (United Nations, 2009). There are also gaps in terms of education between high income and low income earners. Income disparities have widened in recent years, and populations living in remote areas are the most disadvantagedfrom services (Poverty Equality &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Reduction, 2015)

Sexual Identity &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Orientation Challenges:
As Lao is a socialist country with a small population (just over 6 million), it has no public or commercialized sex scene, whether it be #gay# #lesbian#, #bisexual#, or #transgender# (UNESCO Bangkok, 2008). While there are numerous influence on popular display of sexuality, which are both locally and internationally driven, individuals that consider themselves #lesbian#, #gay#, #bisexual#, or #transgender# inevitably poses challenges living in a heterosexist society (UNESCO Bangkok, 2008). Many lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender people face social stigma, heterosexism, violence and discrimination (American Psychology Association, 2015). According to the American Psychology Association 2015, stigma is defined as #a negative social attitude or social disapproval directed toward a characteristic of a person# and heterosexism is defined as #the ideological system that denies any non-heterosexual form of behaviour, identity and behaviour#.
Social stigma, heterosexism, violence and discrimination not only confirms the society#s negative attitude towards non-heterosexuality and transexuality, but also causes minority social stress, such as verbal and physical abuse, that can ultimately lead to low self-esteem, depression, psychological distress, physical health, intimacy, relationship quality and career development (American Psychology Association, 2015).
SUMMARY:
DOKLAO Center in partnership LNWC (Lao New Wave Cinema Production) would like to produce a romantic drama film on lives of six young people that are weaved together through a conflict of their culture, beliefs and gender orientation. The film will reflect cultural differences and gender inequality through the lives of these young people from different ethnic backgrounds working in the capital, Vientiane. The film will also shed light on the underlying perception and sensitivities that society has towards the life decisions and actions the six young people make.

This fictional film is estimated length of 90-100 minutes, shooting in High Definition format, produced and directed by crewmembers from DOKLAO Center and Lao New Wave Cinema Productions, and Lao people play the cast.

DOKLAO ORGANISATIONALBACKGROUND:

Established in 2008, DOKLAO is a Media Centre operating in the support of Participatory Development Training Center (PADETC). PADETC being an indigenous and all-Lao organisation operates with the objective of Education for Sustainable Development for the population of Laos. Focused on encouraging changes towards a #Livable Society# in Laos through holistic education development, PADETC is DOKLAO#s main supporting agent.

Highly experienced in developing media productions, DOKLAO aims to distribute pressing issues associated with the impact of human activities on the natural environment, and critical surroundings related to the quality of life and standards of living in Laos. DOKLAO allows rural populations in Lao access to knowledge on these topics. DOKLAO also provides training on the subject of Media Production to students, youth and government officials. Networked throughout Laos, DOKLAO has theability to channel information through twelve provincial television channels across tendifferent companies.  Along with DOKLAO#s experience in organizing mobile screenings with rural communities and schools, DOKLAO also is experienced on  #Climate Change awareness for youth though film making# supported by #ProcEEd# GIZ. And the experiences working with OXFAM on awareness raising, by Filming Women in leadership role to Promote Gender Equality to 7 provinces in schools.  PADETC strongly believes in the impact of media and discussion in awareness rising.

PADETC ORGANISATIONAL BACKGROUND:

PADETC grew out of a group of five Lao development workers, who had spent over ten years working on agriculture and participatory processes in rural development sector throughout the country. In late 1996 the Lao Government approved an application by the group to establish the Participatory Development Training Centre (PADETC)as an independent and non-profit organisation aimed at strengthening human resources for sustainable development.

PADETC cooperates with government agencies at different administrative levels and with a number of international aid agencies such as International NGO#s and UN agencies. In the early years, PADETC focused on facilitating sustainable agricultural practices and integrated rural development, and in recent years it has expanded its activities to focus on building the capacity of Lao civil society to undertake integrated participatory rural development revolving around agriculture and forestry through youths. It now mainly promotes young people as agents of change and promotes education as a tool for sustainable development in the country. PADTEC recently received Megasaysay award for its outstanding work engaging with youths for promoting sustainable development in the country.

Under the umbrella ofPADETC, the Doklao center, Suanmai Lao center and Education development units will bring in their respective extensive expertise and experience to work in collaboration with #ProcEEd project# GIZ. By building on local wisdom and working at school, family and community levels,they contribute to raising awareness on environmental issues and sustainable development as well as to develop sustainable environmental-friendly practices.
PADETC has a good working relationship DEQP and ProCEEd and will closely collaborate with theminthe preparation and implementation stages.

Lao New Wave Cinema Production # LNWC BACKGROUND:

Lao New Wave Cinema Productions is a film production company co-founded by a collective of young filmmakers residing in Laos. Our primary aim is to change the face of the Lao movie industry to reflect current trends and ideas. Our team consists of both native and international members, whom all share a common passion to produce quality images and stories. In order to survive in the business world, wehaveexpanded our products and services to cover more than just our own movie projects. We offer our technical expertise and inside knowledge of Laos and its culture to help local and international clients -- be it for documentaries, commercials, TV programs,TV series, corporate videos, musicvideos or fiction.

The Ministry of Information, Culture and Tourism
Cinema Department, within The Ministry of Information, Cultureand Tourism.
The Cinema Department will be a key government partner in the screening of this film. The Cinema Department within theMinistry of Information, Culture and Tourism will play an important role in be holding responsibility for censorship, filming authorization and film screening consent and approval. The department will also coordinate the scouting location process and filming time.

OBJECTIVES:
The main objectives of film are to the following:
# To facilitate and encourage the audience to develop a deeper understand life situations of marginalized young people (Among Ethnic Minority groups in Laos)
# To raise a more profound awareness to viewers from key themes such as respect, compassion and general kindness in regards to gender inequality, gender identity/orientation, cultural, economic and social differences through a romantic drama film.
# To show impacts and effects of abuse, discrimination, victimization, misjudgments and misconception to individuals and communities.

PROJECT Target Group
- Lao Young people including all ethnic minorities group and peoplewith all gender identities from 10-25 years old
- Adult groups of audience from 25 # 45 years old
EXPECTED OUTCOMES

# The film is expected to reach 10,000 youths and adults (5,000 women) and raise awareness on the themes of economic, social culturaland gender identity/orientation.
# The film will be developed as a platform to inspire youth and views that #everyone is different and has a different story#, and to encourage compassion and understanding amongst youth and adults.
# The collaboration of DOKLAO andLNWC will mark future partnerships, as a strong network will be formed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC (Participatory Development Training Centre) was officially founded in late 1996. With an initial staff of five Lao development workers (four men and one woman), PADETC#s broad objective was to promote alternative models of development aimed at helping Laos# people to find ways to improve their livelihoods in a just and sustainable way.
Prior to its founding its director and his small team of development workers had worked in various aspects of agriculture and integrated rural development in many rural communities in Laos for more than 15 years, with the support mainly from international NGOs and some UN agencies.  During the early 1980s the team#s work had focused mainly on improvement of food security in poor rural communities by promoting low-cost appropriate agriculturaltechnologies, such as use of bio-fertilisers and bio-pesticides, and integration of fish-raising in the rice fields, etc. The impetus for working on food security during that time was the need to address the problem of food shortages faced by many rural communities in the aftermath of the 30-year war of independence which ended only in 1975.  It was through working on these agriculture-related projects that the team understood that the food security of Lao rural communities could not be solely resolved through improvements in agricultural techniques, but must be systematically tackled at a multi-dimensional level.
From the early 1990s onwards PADETC broadened its work to include integrated rural development, with the emphasison strengthening the capacities of rural communities andempower them to improve their livelihoods systematically.
The main strategic approaches used included: the promotion of participatory processes for community development, especially the use of participatory processes in problem analysis and planning in collaboration with local authorities and communities; the training of multi-sector rural development teams comprising staff from the agriculture, education, health, and woman#s unions at various levels (village, district, province); the setting up of integrated rural development offices at the provincial and district levels to provide management, extension, and monitoring support; and the production of Lao language manuals and forms for village surveys, planning, budgeting, reporting, and many types of production techniques.
With the expansion of its scope of work programmatically and geographically, PADETC has grown from its original staff of five in 1996 to anorganisation with 53 staff (12 women), all of them Lao. PADETC also draws on the support from international expertise in the form of short-term technical experts, advisors and volunteers, etc. through international agencies, such as German International Aid (DED), Singapore International Foundation (SIF), Australia Volunteer Service, etc.
PADETC continues to co-operate closely with governmentagencies at all administrative levels and ensures that responsible authorities are regularly briefed on the progress of its projects. PADETC has closeco-operation with a number of NGOs, UN and bilateral agencies. After more than ten years of operation and innovative contribution to local development, PADETC is increasingly given more political and social recognition as a local development agency. Basedon its experience the vision and mission of PADETC is to promote the concept of #liveable# communities which balances economic growth with social and cultural vibrancy, environmental harmony, and spiritual development for all.
PADETC has long operatedasalaboratory both for development thinking, and for the applied-use of locally appropriate approaches. This has included not only Learning Centre and network development, but the articulation of a conceptual framework for development.  In 2009, PADETCbeganthe process of supporting each Learning Centre and Network to become independent, paving the way for eventual registration as individual NPAs.

In July 2012, the founder and long term Director of PADETC Mr. Sombath has handed over the function toMr.Khamphoui Saythalat. The last year, PADETC has focussed much of its energy and resources and the internal transformation of its organisation as well as the AEPF process. Consequently, most of the activities now take place in and around Vientiane, although contacts with youth groups in other provinces still exist.

Also for the coming programme period the institutional transition process will demand a substantial investment in time and resources from PADETC. In order to support the new director in the processa group of &#x93;Friends of PADETC&#x94; has been formed with international and national members and that provides coaching and technical advice to PADETC.


PADETC will focus on four fields of action. These are:
1. Education for Sustainable Development (ESD)
2. Enabling Environment Support for Lao CSOs (with a particular focus on Organizational Development and Management, and Small Grant Facility)
3. Policy Advocacy (mainly with reference tothe recommendations made from the Impact Assessment report in March2012)
4. Resource mobilization including the marketing and delivery of services for the general public, NPAs and iNGOs.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laos</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-29">43538</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-07-01">43538</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PADETC - Participatory Development Training Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-07-01">43538</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-04589-02:LA">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007254"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Laos (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-04589"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Promoting Gender Equality Through Film"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">56</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men that are legally empowered through increased awareness about their rights</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">056-02</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Female AIM4 DAB 056</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="056-02" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">056-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Male AIM4 DAB 056</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="056-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">56</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men that are legally empowered through increased awareness about their rights</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">056-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Organisations understand&amp;claim (outp</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="056-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">056-C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners human rights (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="056-C" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">056-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners legal aid (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="056-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-07-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
