<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-27849</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CG Togo Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ContourGlobal Togo S.A. (the Company or CG Togo) is the local subsidiary of ContourGlobal which develops and operates electric power and district heating businesses around the world. CG Togo has entered into a 25-year concession and power purchase agreement to develop, construct and operate a 100 MW thermal power plant on a brown-field site in Lom&#xE9;, Togo (the Project). The Project will be the first substantial foreign investment in Togo in over a decade and will be one of the most significant investments in the West African power sector in over twenty years. CG Togo will be capable of producing up to ~780 gigawatt hours (GWh) of electricity per annum which it will sell to the Togolese electric distribution company, Compagnie Energie Electrique du Togo (CEET).  Construction began in May 2009 and is expected to be completed and operational in April 2010.  

The plant will be powered by six W&#xE4;rtsil&#xE4; 18V50DF engines (16.6 MW each), with tri-fuel burning capability to operate on natural gas (NG), heavy fuel oil (HFO), and distillate diesel oil (DDO). HFO will be the primary source of fuel until NG becomes available via the West African Gas Pipeline.  

In December 2008, the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC) signed a US$146 million nonrecourse loan agreement with CG Togo. Financial closing was reached in May 2009. IFC is considering a 20% equity stake in the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In addition to representing one of the largest sources of Foreign Direct Investment (FDI) to Togo in recent years, the project will help improve the sustainability of Togos power sector by: 
Providing energy security through reliable power supply.  Acute power shortages meant that in recent years Togo has had to institute a power rationing program with daily electricity cuts of up to 4-6 hours. Major industrial customers have had substantial cutbacks in operations due to inadequate and unreliable power supply and are having to develop expensive off-grid power supply arrangements.
Diversifying power source: By adding thermal power to Togos and the regions hydro-dominated electricity sector (mostly imported from Ghana), the project will improve the long-term security of energy supply within the region.
Leveraging private sector to support countrys infrastructure needs: After more than a decade of isolation from the development community and with little private investment, Togos essential infrastructure is in a very poor state.  With large infrastructure financing needs, Togo will need to leverage private sources where possible. 
Improved Health &amp; Safety.  Load shedding reduces road safety (particularly at night) and interrupts the proper functioning of medical centers.  The project will help avert power shortages. 
Contributing to fiscal revenues: The project will generate concession revenues for the Government of Togo.
Reducing Togos carbon emissions:  The project will help displace diesel generated electricity with HFO and eventually with natural gas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ContourGlobal Togo SA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-27849" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-03-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-06-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lee Muller

ContourGlobal Exec. VP, Business Development
650 Madison Ave, 22nd Floor 
New York, NY 10022 
Tel: +1 212 610 9142

Fax: +1 212 610 9144
Email: Lee.Muller@ContourGlobal.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Togo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="TG-Togo">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will be located in Lom&#xE9;, Togo, on the existing site of Centrale Thermique de Lom&#xE9;  (CTL) which is about 7 km east of Lom&#xE9; and 800 meters north of the Gulf of Guinea. Developed in the 1970s and 1980s, CTL is an existing oil-fired thermal power station with 90MW capacity. CTL is no longer operational due to technical problems. The CTL brownfield site is adjacent to water, fuel storage and CEBs switchyard. CG Togo is constructing the project on a vacant portion of the CTL site.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.6666698000 1.0833300000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="2211" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AE - Multi Fuel - Thermal Power Generation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $14.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2010-03-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-03-31">6000000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2010-03-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-03-31">8000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-03-31">8000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ContourGlobal Togo SA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-03-31">6000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ContourGlobal Togo SA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/27849/cg-togo-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
