<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-43339</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zener SA, Togo</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the World Health Organization (WHO) in 2019, only 9.3% of the Togolese population consumed clean technologies for cooking. Firewood represents 99% of primary energy production , where more than 36% of the firewood is used by households for cooking.  Heavy reliance on biomass fuels for household consumption entails severe negative health effects. These fuels are inefficient energy sources and produce a range of pollutants associated with detrimental health outcomes. While replacing biomass with LPG remains a switch to fossil fuels, this change represents an important step in the countrys move towards cleaner energy sources. The current use of biomass in Togo is unsustainable and contributes to the countrys high levels of deforestation. 

The most significant expected project-level outcomes are increased access to LPG products, with improvements in households air quality and resultant health effects, especially for women and children, especially in undeserved rural areas. Beyond the Project, IFC anticipates the Project will further promote Competitiveness of LPG production in the market through demonstration effects in other market players in improving LPG access, in particular to undeserved rural populations as an energy transition fuel.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zener SA (Zener or the Company) is a full-service, integrated energy provider operating in Togo, across the LPG full value chain with the only seaborne LPG import facility for end-user distribution to industrial, commercial, and residential (urban and rural) markets, as well as export. The proposed investment is up to EUR 7 million (m) IFC A loan and mobilization of up to EUR 14m in Parallel loans, to finance (i) Zeners LPG terminal capacity expansion and (ii) support the establishment of five gasoline retail stations for the distribution of white products, solar kits, and LPG bottles exchange (the Project).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZENER SA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-43339" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0.0000         &#xA0;  Zener SA,   Lome (TOGO) Zone industrielle de Lome, route   dAneho  , 08 BP     8535.</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zener SA  Mr. Jonas A. Daou  President/Chief Executive Officer  +228 22 27 2000  jonas@zener.tg  Lome (TOGO) Zone industrielle de Lome, route dAneho, 08 BP 8535  https://www.zener.tg/</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Togo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="TG-Togo">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project will be sited next to the existing&#xA0;operation of Zener in the industrial zone in Lome, while the filling stations will be across Togo at Ago&#xE8; Deux lions (in lome) and Ny&#xE9;konakpo&#xE8;, Kpalim&#xE9;/ Kp&#xE9;ta, Ts&#xE9;vi&#xE9;/Kpali, and Atakpam&#xE9;/Av&#xE9;t&#xE8;.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.6666698000 1.0833300000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="331" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">I-AF - Other Steel Products (Including Wire, Metal Sheets etc.)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/43339">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/43339">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
