<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10293A0101-SOM-16030</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Innovativa l&#xF6;sningar f&#xF6;r f&#xF6;rflyttade befolkningar i Somalia</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Innovative solutions for displaced in Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To improve housing, land and property rights (HLP) protection to allow for longer/term local urban integration of internally displaced persons (IDPs) who express willingness to participate in the project. To facilitate return of refugees from Dadaab/Kenya to Kismayo/Somalia through an integrated planning approach which is in line with strategic and sustainable urban development and durable solutions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">F&#xF6;r att &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rda det &#xF6;kande antalet f&#xF6;rdrivningar av internflyktingar samt att m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra en s&#xE4;ker repatriering och &#xE5;terintegrering av &#xE5;terv&#xE4;ndande somaliska flyktingar fr&#xE5;n Dadaab flyktingl&#xE4;gren i Kenya, avser projektet att skapa innovativa l&#xF6;sningar med m&#xF6;jlighet till uppskalning. Det &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let f&#xF6;r insatsen &#xE4;r att inr&#xE4;tta h&#xE5;llbara l&#xF6;sningar f&#xF6;r de olika f&#xF6;rflyttade befolkningarna (flyktingar, internflyktingar och &#xE5;terv&#xE4;ndande), och i synnerhet f&#xF6;r att bidra till en h&#xE5;llbar, s&#xE4;ker och varaktig &#xE5;teranpassning av internflyktingar i stadsomr&#xE5;den i Mogadishu och Kismayo.

Pilot 1: Mogadishu:
Ett pilotprojekt f&#xF6;r hyressubventioner &#xE4;mnar att finna kreativa l&#xF6;sningar till problemet med vr&#xE4;kningar av f&#xF6;rdrivna internflyktingar. Projektet kommer att uppn&#xE5; detta genom att skapa ett system med incitament f&#xF6;r f&#xF6;rdrivna familjer och hyresv&#xE4;rdar som syftar till att formalisera hyresrelationen mellan internflyktingar och land&#xE4;gare under en period som &#xE4;r tillr&#xE4;ckligt l&#xE5;ng f&#xF6;r att skapa och uppr&#xE4;tth&#xE5;lla framg&#xE5;ngsrika f&#xF6;rs&#xF6;rjningsstrategier.

Pilot 2: Kismayo:
Ett pilotprojekt f&#xF6;r att underl&#xE4;tta flyktingarnas &#xE5;terintegrering i Kismayo / Somalia genom en integrerad strategiplanering som &#xE4;r i linje med strategisk och h&#xE5;llbar stadsutveckling och h&#xE5;llbara l&#xF6;sningar, som kan st&#xE4;rka den gemensamma handlingsplan som lanseras i december av FN och Kismayos administration.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat has applied to Sida for funding of 10 million SEK to carry out the &quot;&quot;Innovative Solutions for Displacement in Somalia&quot;&quot; in Mogadishu and Kismayo (Somalia) during the period Dec 2016 to Dec 2017. 

The intervention which includes two Components has the overall objective to establish durable solutions for the displacement-affected populations, and particularly to support a sustainable, safe and durable reintegration of IDPs in urban areas in Mogadishu and Kismayo.
Pilot 1: The Mogadishu-initiative aims at setting up cash transfers and livelihood schemes for 100 IDP households that will make them secure one year of rent, preventing the risk of being evicted.
Pilot 2: The Kismayo- initiative aims at facilitating the return of refugees from Dadaab refugee camp in Kenya to Kismayo in Somalia through an integrated planning approach which is in line with strategic and sustainable urban development and durable solutions. 

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 10 million SEK, and Sida is the sole donor. Approximately 5 million SEK  of the intervention budget will be forwarded from UN-Habitat to the implementing partner; Norwegian Refugee Council.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41120" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat/United Nations Human Settlements Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41120" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat/United Nations Human Settlements Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="16030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Housing policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-30">1168702.156255</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key results achieved are:&#xA0;
1. Selected IDP families at risk of evictions secure a housing solution by committing to engage in livelihoods activities, participate in saving schemes and training.&#xA0;
Improved access to housing and land rights through rental subsidies: In Mogadishu, 80 households were targeted with a rental subsidy of up to 80 USD per month for one year and an income generating activity instalment of 1000 USD (500 USD in two instalments) and a 7-month food basket. The food allowance was separate of the small-scale business trainings, which along with the Income generating activity (IGA), consisted the livelihood element of the scheme.&#xA0;
Tenure security: A formal rental agreement was signed between the landlord and the beneficiary IDP, but facilitated by the BRA, the relevant district authorities and NRC&#x2019;s technical teams.&#xA0;Throughout the project, only three households faced risk of evictions. The other 77 households completed the 12-month duration without any fears of being evicted. Therefore, the project was able to improve the tenure security. The capacity of beneficiaries to focus on building their livelihoods, as opposed to the threat of eviction, contributed to the longer-term sustainable reintegration of the IDPs into the communities.
Access to justice for violations of HLP rights: &#xA0;Through the mediation and legal counseling services, a network of paralegals was engaged to conduct community outreach activities and identify HLP cases in the target areas. A total of 10 HLP cases have been resolved through legal counseling and assistance provided. With a strong mechanism in place including the land tenure agreements and inclusive discussions around the sustainability of the financial model this intervention ensured trust and transparency between the landlords, tenants and the local authorities and mitigated potential violations of HLP rights.
Access to livelihoods: In order to ensure sustainability of the rental model, a livelihoods component was incorporated. The project conducted the livelihood training of the targeted eighty households. The IGA activities were conducted in two phases: first, beneficiaries were provided with startup cash of USD 500 to begin a business initiative; second, a scale-up was provided to beneficiaries who successfully established a business based on their idea. Through support to the IGAs beneficiaries were able to make a significant income that allowed them to continue to pay their rent. As a result, the project was able to improve the resiliency of the beneficiaries with 78 of the households supported identifying as self sufficient and no longer in need of humanitarian assistance.
2: Capacity of the government authorities is built in view to create and administer a rental subsidy scheme at the level of the municipality
The training was critical to building a foundation of understanding for the local administration on the capacity to administer rental subsidy schemes at the municipal level. While a simplified version of the financial module was utilised in the end, the local administration was still able to benefit from greater understanding on financial modules for renting schemes and benefit from deeper knowledge and capacity on how to adapt and administer such modules specific to their local context going forward.
While the BRA provided oversight, leadership and guidance, their role was primarily limited to devolving the level of engagement to the district level. Thus, the role of the local government in supporting durable solutions for housing became irrefutable. These were central to addressing key issues as they arose and provided critical mediation support to ensure the successful implementation of the project.
3: By-laws at municipal level to regulate and manage rental schemes and to comply by the eviction guidelines are in place
A formal rental agreement, written in English and translated to Somali, was issued to each beneficiary household. The agreement outlined the terms and conditions of the tenancy relationship, and clearly stipulated the rights and obligations of each parties. The rental subsidy scheme was operationalized considering adequate tenure security for beneficiaries. The district level administration led the processing of the rental agreements, while the BRA and district authorities oversaw the issuance of the individual agreements. This approach was intended to prevent or at least minimize the risk of contractual disagreement resulting in forced evictions.
4: Strategic spatial plans guide rapid urbanization process in Jubaland
The initial premise of the spatial plan was to pioneer and establish the layout of reintegration for Kismayo, however delays in the early months of the project meant that by the time the spatial planning exercise had begun, other settlements had already been established in the same vicinity. As a result, the planning teams developed an approach that would mould the innovative settlement in the context of the surrounding new settlements.
The project builds on a spatial planning exercise funded by the Midnimo project. The Kismayo Urban Profile provided a basis for analyzing the city&#x2019;s resources and how they are shared.&#xA0;The approach and the preliminary area plan for Midnimo neighborhood were endorsed by the Ministry of Public Works in November 2018. The area plan is complementary to the existing site plans for the new IDP settlements and can be used as tool for further area coordination as envisaged by NRC and UN-Habitat under Midnimo and Danwadaag Programs.
5: Returns and local reintegration effectively managed based on agreed upon reintegration framework 
The draft reintegration framework was developed based on interviews with key stakeholder but also from the knowledge accumulated through the experiences of returnees and partner organizations operating in the field. As a result, the framework outlines the key priority areas for engagement; governance, livelihoods and housing, social cohesion and access to basic services. The framework also hinged all future development of public, private development, stabilization and humanitarian actors on area-based planning.
As such a comprehensive plan for the adoption of the framework led and established by the Jubaland authorities is also included in the framework along with key common indicators derived from the Regional Durable Solutions Secretariat and the Interagency Standing Committee Framework on Durable Solutions.
6: Urban identity campaign increases social cohesion
A critical component of this project was social cohesion, namely the development of two activities; a body mapping and a photo voice. These facilitated dialogue between different demographic groups, young women to have a platform to speak to the male dominated community elders, the elders would be able to speak to the young men. displacement affected communities, IDPs and returnees would find an avenue to tell their stories and be heard.
7: Provision of an innovative housing scheme with livelihood opportunities for 100 households
The initial project was designed to develop 4 prototype houses, 1 community centre and 100 houses in Kismayo. Based on the design/prototypes chosen, NRC and UN-Habitat worked together to revise and approve the technical documents (design and BOQ). NRC launched the implementation of the shelters, latrines and the community Centre. By the end of the project, 5 prototypes, 1 community centre and 74 houses were built, a comprehensive site plan was developed, beneficiary selection was carried out and returnee and IDP families moved in to the housing units on March 2019. Each of the household was provided with a permanent title deed to make sure that they were the sole owner of the property handed to them. The difference in numbers were primarily due to the change in specifications that were made by the MoI into the project.
Challenges and unexpected results:
1. The project had initially envisaged the development of a set of legal tools related to rental in the form of municipal by-laws. However, in discussions with local partners and BRA, and during the course of the project implementation, it became evident that such by-laws would require an evidenced based approach that demonstrates the potential effectiveness of these laws across all districts. Given that the project was a pilot, and still testing the applicability of the financial modules and the integrated approach to rental housing scheme, it was not feasible to develop full scale by-laws based on 80 households. Such laws would require broad and inclusive dialogues across all districts of Mogadishu as well as an assessment of the impact of the project that fully captures the successes and challenges before comprehensive municipal laws can be drafted and adopted.
2.&#xA0;There were several challenges that resulted to the change in the final housing model in Kismayo to accomodate the government&apos;s suggestions to construct bigger houses given the size of the average Somali household. Therefore the price per unit increased from $3,791.75 to $4,109 and the number of units came down from 85 to 79.&#xA0;The government standard in the long-term would lead to a reduction in the number of persons in need of support.
3. In relation to the point above (2), there was an expectation that all IDPs and returnees could potentially be supported with housing to this scale assumed that the land would be available, and that tenure could be secured. However ensuring land tenure was secured and resolving claimant issues was something that the Jubbaland authorities struggled extensively with despite their ambitions and goodwill thus delaying the construction of the houses in Kismayo.
4. The business kiosks and urban agriculture to supplement household income that had been built in to the original prototype designs were removed in the last design in favour of larger rooms. Moreover, livelihoods had not been featured strongly in the design of this project and as such the loss of what little had been included was significant for the households that were moving in to the units and were now relocated to sites further from the business districts and the centre of town. It is thus crucial to undertake further advocacy for more housing solutions to enhance social cohesion and livelihood opportunities adapted to the specific location context.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10293" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
