<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5127001602-SOM-15110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r att konstruera MOF kontor i Mogadishu</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to construct MOF offices in Mogadishu</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">M&#xE5;len med insatsen &#xE4;r att bygga en ny och funktionell finansdepartement f&#xF6;r somaliska federala regeringen i Mogadishu. Med en f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad arbetsmilj&#xF6;, s&#xE5; &#xE4;r insatsens fr&#xE4;msta f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntning att detta kommer att leda till en f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad offentlig finansiell kontroll och styrning samt &#xF6;kade m&#xF6;jligheter f&#xF6;r tillg&#xE5;ng till offentliga tj&#xE4;nster. 

Insatsen &#xE4;r ett samarbete mellan FN organisationen (UNOPS) och den somaliska federala regeringen. Det totala budgeten f&#xF6;r insatsen ber&#xE4;knas att uppg&#xE5; till cirka 14.8 miljoner svenska kronor och Sverige planerar att bidra med hela summan.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNOPS has applied to Sida for funding of 14 800 000 SEK to carry out the project &quot;Support to Construction of Ministry of Finance (MOF) offices in Mogadishu, Somali&#x201D; during the period 2014-12-01 to 2017-07-31. 

The intervention aims at constructing a new and improved Ministry of Finance headquarter building that will provide a quality working environment and thus increase the capacity of the ministry to support the needs of the Somali community, thereby permitting increased access to financial services. Specifically, the intervention will: 1) Perform a detailed structural audit of the existing building to establish whether it can be rehabilitated or whether a new facility should be constructed to replace the existing; 2a) In the event that the structural audit deems the existing building fit for rehabilitation, the objective shall be to rehabilitate the basement, ground floor and the first floor of the MoF building in Mogadishu Somali; OR 2b) In the event that the structural audit deems the building unfit for rehabilitation and needs to be completely demolished, the objective shall be to construct a new two floor office building to house the core ministry requirements; 3) Capacity build the local contractors through technical training; 4) Undertake an assessment of the operation and maintenance requirements for the new facility and prepare a proposal for future funding, inclusive of an outline operation and maintenance plan. 

UNOPS will implement the intervention in collaboration with the Somali Federal Government through the Ministries of Finance Health, Planning and Public Works. The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is estimated at 14.8 million SEK and Sweden will fully support the budget. The government will provide land for the construction.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main goal of the project is to construct a new and improved Ministry of Finance headquarters that will provide a quality working environment, in order to increase the capacity of the Ministry of Finance, thereby permitting increased access to financial services to the people of Somali.
The specific outputs are as listed below:
1) Perform a detail structural audit of the existing 6-storey building to establish whether it can be rehabilitated or require a new facility to replace the existing one. The audit found that the building was beyond refurbishment thus prompt the need of new building facility.
2) A complete design and cost estimation for new 4-storey building.
3) Procurement activities and construction Management.&#xA0;
4) Demolition of existing building and the construction of new building.&#xA0;
5) Design and implementation of renewable energy source.
6) Capacity building of local contractor through technical on the job training during the course of construction.
7) Capacity building of national engineers who were appointed by the ministry through job training during the course of construction</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41502" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNOPS/United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41502" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNOPS/United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">373848.3678483678</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">373848.3678483678</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-31">465791.338066</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">373848.3678483678</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall, a new four story Building for Ministry of Finance with renewable energy source was constructed and handed over to the government during an inauguration ceremony on 2018-10-30. It has however, not yet been occupied by the Ministry of Finance officials.
Specifically:-
1) A detailed structural audit of the old building was performed to establish whether it could be rehabilitated or required a new facility to replace the old one. The audit found that the building was beyond refurbishment thus prompted the need of a new building.
2) A complete design and cost estimation for new building was developed
3) Construction services were procured and construction process managed to ensure adherence to architectural and structural designs as well as the required safety standards.&#xA0;
4) Demolition of existing building and the construction of new building was carried out
5) Renewable energy source was designed, procured and installed. The wind energy has not been installed yet but the materials and equipment are on site and will be installed by the ministry.
6) Capacity of local contractor was built through technical on the job training during the course of construction
7) The project built the capacity of two national government engineers (one female) through job training during the course of construction.
8)&#xA0;Reviving of the government properties sends a positive and strong message to the public that the government is committed towards the country&#x2019;s development.
9) The construction of the building also attracted economic activities and further improving the security conditions; number of restaurants and shops have opened since and are now operating in the area.
10) The project attracted and encouraged diaspora investment; For example, Malayka Hotel and restaurant located 100 m away from the newly constructed ministry building is built and owned by diaspora investors.
11)The project area was relatively abandoned prior to the construction due to the high security risks, but the start of this project prompted faith, ultimately assuring the community that the security situation has improved.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51270016" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
