<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5215000301-SOM-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EISA Somalia programme 2013-2017 (Transition, Stability &amp; Democratization)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">EISA Somalia programme 2013-2017 (Transition, Stability &amp; Democratization)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Electoral Institute for Sustainable Democracy in Africa (EISA) har inkommit med en f&#xF6;rfr&#xE5;gan om ytterligare medel om 11,3 MSEK f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rdjupa och ut&#xF6;ka sitt p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende demokratiseringsprogram i Somalia under perioden 1 december 2013 till 30 november 2017. F&#xF6;rn&#xE4;rvarande finansierat med 40 MSEK. Det totala bidraget fr&#xE5;n Sida uppg&#xE5;r nu till 51,3 MSEK. De ut&#xF6;kade medlen kommer att anv&#xE4;ndas till att: i) ut&#xF6;ka kapacitetsbyggandet och medborgarutbildningen (&#x201D;civic education&#x201D;) f&#xF6;r civilsamh&#xE4;llet och &#x201D;Let&#x2019;s talk elections dialogues&#x201D; till 10 regioner utanf&#xF6;r Mogadishu, ii) anst&#xE4;llning av en konstitutionsexpert till Justitie- och konstitutionsministeriet f&#xF6;r st&#xF6;d till konstitutions&#xF6;versynen, iii) Tekniskt st&#xF6;d till Inrikesministeriet f&#xF6;r att utveckla lagar och institutioner f&#xF6;r val och st&#xF6;d till ministeriet f&#xF6;r att arbeta med valfr&#xE5;gor innan valkommissionen &#xE4;r etablerad, iv) f&#xF6;rl&#xE4;ngning av kontraktet f&#xF6;r den seniora valkonsulten (initialt kontrakterad f&#xF6;r fyra m&#xE5;nader) till och med slutet av 2016 och v) uppr&#xE4;ttande av en flexibel fond f&#xF6;r att hantera strategiska f&#xF6;rfr&#xE5;gningar fr&#xE5;n federala regeringen inklusive den nyligen genomf&#xF6;rda utbildningen av interimsadministrationer i nyligen tillg&#xE4;ngliga distrikt.  
     
EISAs Somaliaprogram fokuserar p&#xE5; fem omr&#xE5;den: i) EISA har etablerat sin verksamhet i Somalia, ii) Civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer &#xE4;r b&#xE4;ttre organiserade, representerar deras respektive intressegrupper b&#xE4;ttre och har f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrat sitt engagemang med nationella intuitioner och myndigheter, iii) politiska partier har etablerats samt det legala ramverket f&#xF6;r politiska partier har utformats, iv) parlamentet fungerar mer effektivt och har en st&#xE4;rkt roll i konstitutionsprocessen och v) st&#xE4;rkt kapacitet f&#xF6;r valakt&#xF6;rer f&#xF6;r att hantera, leda och administrera valprocesser samt bidra till att &#xF6;ka transparens i valprocesser samtidigt som konflikter motverkas. 

Sammantaget syftar programmet till att bidra till ett b&#xE4;ttre politiskt och socialt klimat i Somalia, vilket bidrar till &#xF6;kad stabilitet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Electoral Institute for Sustainable Democracy in Africa (EISA) has applied to Sida for additional funding amounting to 11.3MSEK to deepen and expand the ongoing EISA Somalia programme supporting transition, stability, and democratization in Somalia during the period 1 December 2013 to 30 November 2017 currently funded at 40MSEK. The total funding will now total to 51.3MSEK. This additional support will go towards: i) the extension of capacity building and civic education for civil society and the Let&#x2019;s Talk Elections Dialogues to 10 regions outside of Mogadishu, ii) Hiring of a constitutional building consultant to provide expertise and technical assistance to the Ministry of Justice and Constitution on the process of constitutional review, iii) Technical assistance to the Ministry of Interior and Federalism in the development of a legal and institutional framework for elections and in its caretaker role to create an enabling environment for the smooth take off of the electoral process, iv) extension of the contract for senior elections consultant (which was earlier budgeted for four months) until end of 2016 and v) Flexible funding pool to fulfill important requests from the federal government including to pay for the recently conducted training of Caretaker Administrations for newly accessible areas.
The Intervention has five outputs: These are i) EISA is operational in Somalia,  ii) Civil Society organizations are better organized, can represent their constituencies and constructively engage with national institutions and authorities, iii) Political parties and rules governing them are established, iv) Parliament is more effective in its general functions and its role in Constitution building  and v) Key electoral stakeholders are exposed to electoral processes, management and administration and contribute to the transparency of the electoral process while preventing and managing conflicts. These outputs taken together seek to contribute to the impact of improved social and political environment for key stakeholders to contribute to a more stable Somalia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To complement ongoing initiatives in support of the democratization and stabilization process of Somalia from a conflict-ridden and undemocratic state with a fragile central authority to a more stable and democratising state. Specifically, EISA intends, through capacity building activities for Civil Society Organizations (CSOs), political parties and Parliament, to make a modest contribution towards laying the foundations for a more stable Somalia and a successful democratic transition, including the electoral process.
This relates to i) more progress towards a stable and peaceful federal Somalia through inclusive political processes and ii) Key Somali stakeholders, including women, supported by EISA, better perform and deliver on their duties, and complement ongoing stabilization initiatives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EISA/Electoral Institute for Sustainable Democracy in Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EISA/Electoral Institute for Sustainable Democracy in Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1535343.6098998955</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1093310.3981107597</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1856619.1735968587</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">2123552.1235521236</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1035625.5178127589</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1535343.6098998953</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1093310.3981107597</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1856619.1735968585</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">-2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">2123552.1235521236</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1035625.5178127589</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-11-01">9258121.967696</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">1535343.6098998955</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-28">1093310.3981107597</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-07-28">889753.5975703795</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-11-28">966865.5760264791</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-28">1228501.2285012284</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">895050.8950508949</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-28">1035625.5178127589</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This programme achieved the following results:
&#x2022; Supported the Technical Selection Process for the establishment of the National Independent Electoral Commission (NIEC) and the Boundaries and Federalism Commission (BFC). These two commissions are today operational, and they are currently working towards the 2020 elections;
&#x2022; Played a pivotal role in supporting the National Consultative Forum (NCF) for the 2016 electoral process. EISA facilitated five dialogues in five regions to discuss the NCF electoral options.
&#x2022; At Federal Member State (FMS) level EISA played a key role in the management of the constitution-making process for the Interim Jubbaland Administration. The key outcome of this process was the drafting and adoption of a provisional Jubbaland Constitution based on the fundamentals of human rights and democratic principles which reflect the views of the citizens of Jubbaland as they have been gathered through a representative outreach process and passed through the Jubbaland Constitutional Convention. While this programme was supported by the Somalia Stability Fund (SSF), it provided an excellent opportunity for the Institute to expand its reputation beyond Mogadishu and deliver on key activities in support to Somalia&#x2019;s transitional goals and complemented the activities undertaken through the Sida supported interventions.
&#x2022; EISA supported the Federal Member State formation process by ensuring full and relevant participation of all segments of communities. This was effected by the expansion of the project to more regions across Somalia i.e the Interim Galmudug Administration (IGA), and Hiraan and Middle Shabelle , The organisational development training provided in Adaado and Balcad regions capacitated more than 200 civil society members to better administer their organisations, engage with authorities and contribute to the state-building process in 2016.
&#x2022; EISA provided support to gender engineering and empowerment of women&#x2019;s participation in the 2016-2017 political process in Somalia. In this regard, EISA has been working with the Somali Women Leadership Initiative (SWLI). A core group of 15 women from the SWLI network were trained on how to fund raise, develop proposals and develop and use a logical framework approach. This has enabled SWLI to secure funds from UNDP for their lobbying, advocacy and capacity building activities for the 2016-2017 electoral process.
&#x2022; Cognisant of the importance of the Electoral Law in the current democratisation process toward the 2020 universal suffrage elections, EISA provided support to the Ministry of Interior, Federal Affairs and Reconciliation (MoIFAR) by capacitating staff of the Electoral Law Working Group (ELWG). With the skills acquired by the 37 participants at the workshop, the ELWG was able to draft its road map for the Electoral Law drafting process and develop a public outreach programme. Reinforcing the gender dimension of the ELWG&#x2019;s work through a workshop on &#x2018;&#x2019;mainstreaming gender in Electoral Law Drafting process&#x2019;&#x2019; for 37 participants from the MoIFAR, the Ministry of Women and Human Rights and the Office of the Prime Minister and COSs.
&#x2022; In support to federalism and decentralisation the capacity of commissioners and staff of the Banadir Regional Administration was developed through a series of workshops.
&#x2022; EISA supported CSOs, focusing on women and youth trained in internal and external communication and project management to ensure a better visibility of their organisations and be able to engage with stakeholders such as government&#x2019;s agencies, the donor community and the population at large.
&#x2022; EISA has been one of the main partners of the Ministry of Constitutional Affairs (MoCA) through various activities including capacity building workshops, the facilitation of stakeholders&#x2019; dialogue sessions and study tours. With EISA&#x2019;s support The MoCA was able to convene consultative meetings, providing thus the ministry with a unique opportunity to gather views and opinions from the various segments of the population on the CRP. One of the success stories of this support is the organisation of the MoCA four-day strategic retreat that led to the two-year public outreach strategy of the ministry.
&#x2022; Building on the opportunity of the registration of political parties, EISA conducted a series of induction workshops in August 2018 to enable newly partially registered political parties to perform their duties as key actors of the scheduled 2020 universal suffrage elections.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52150003" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
