<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-14486A0101-SOM-12220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 UNICEF Somalia 2021-2022 tematiskt st&#xF6;d h&#xE4;lsa &amp; skydd av barn</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 UNICEF Somalia 2021-2022 thematic support health and protective environment</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New/additional funds to address COVID-19
Sida will support United Nations Children&apos;s Fund (UNICEF) in&#xA0;Somalia with thematic funding for Health and Protective Environment, with an additional support to the Covid vaccination campagin. The contribution has the overall objective to contribute to:

- That more newborns, infants and children survive and thrive, and fewer women and girls die during pregnancy and childbirth.
- That children and women are safer and better protected from violence, exploitation, abuse and harm.

The proposed contribution will contribute to the following objectives in the Strategy for Sweden&#x2019;s development cooperation with Somalia 2018&#x2013;2022:
- Greater and equitable access to health and medical care, focusing on women 
and children;
- Strengthened systems and institutions that promote and guarantee respect 
for human rights, democracy and the rule of law; and
-  Strengthened capacity to prevent and counter violent extremism and radicalisation.

Sida will contribute with 75 million SEK over the period 2021-2022 to the thematic areas, health, including an earmarked support to the roll-out of the Covid-19 vaccination campaign, and protective environment, as stated in UNICEF&apos;s Country Programme for Somalia 2021-2025. During the same period UNICEF proposes to implement the equivalent of 520 million SEK from regular and other resources to the same thematic programmes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Nya medel/medeltill&#xE4;gg f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Sida kommer att st&#xF6;dja FN:s barnfond (UNICEF) i Somalia med finansiering av de tematiska programmen H&#xE4;lsa och Skyddande milj&#xF6; f&#xF6;r barn, och ett extraordin&#xE4;rt till&#xE4;gg f&#xF6;r att st&#xF6;dja utrullningen av vaccinationskampanjen av covid vaccin. Insatsen har de &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;len att bidra till:

- Att fler nyf&#xF6;dda, sp&#xE4;dbarn och barn &#xF6;verlever och utvecklas och att f&#xE4;rre kvinnor och flickor d&#xF6;r under graviditet och f&#xF6;rlossning.
- Att barn och kvinnor &#xE4;r s&#xE4;krare och b&#xE4;ttre skyddade fr&#xE5;n v&#xE5;ld, exploatering och &#xF6;vergrepp.

Den f&#xF6;reslagna insatsen kommer att bidra till f&#xF6;ljande m&#xE5;l i Strategin f&#xF6;r Sveriges utvecklingssamarbete med Somalia 2018 - 2022:
- &#xD6;kad och j&#xE4;mlik tillg&#xE5;ng till h&#xE4;lso- och sjukv&#xE5;rd med fokus p&#xE5; kvinnor och barn;
-  St&#xE4;rkta system och institutioner som uppr&#xE4;tth&#xE5;ller och garanterar respekt f&#xF6;r m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter, demokrati och r&#xE4;ttsstatens principer, och;
-  St&#xE4;rkt kapacitet att f&#xF6;rebygga och motverka v&#xE5;ldsam extremism och radikalisering

Sida kommer att bidra med 75 miljoner kronor under perioden 2021 - 2022 till de tematiska programmen H&#xE4;lsa, inklusive ett &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkt st&#xF6;d till utrullningen av Covid-19 vaccineringen, och Skyddande milj&#xF6; f&#xF6;r barn, s&#xE5;som de &#xE4;r f&#xF6;reslagna i UNICEF:s landprogram f&#xF6;r Somalia 2021 - 2025. UNICEF kommer under samma period att finansiera samma tematiska program med motsvarande 520 miljoner kronor.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The contribution is focused on two areas: health and protective environment
Health: 
UNICEF states that the overall purpose of its support to Somalia&#x2019;s health programming is to ensure that more children aged 0-18 years and women benefit from quality comprehensive health services and healthy life practices.
Programming will, UNICEF informs, therefore focus on strengthening evidence-based planning, budgeting and monitoring for maternal, neonatal, child and adolescent health (MNCAH), improving quality MNCAH services as well as family care practices for health and nutrition and institutionalizing community health approaches.
As part of Somalia&#x2019;s strategy, to reduce neonatal mortality, UNICEF&#xA0;aims &#x2013; with the contribution from Sida - to provide continued support to evidence-based low-cost high impact interventions to mothers and babies to reduce new-born mortality and still births.
UNICEF support includes trainings of midwives, nurses and doctors on early essential new-born care, which UNICEF with Sida support seeks to roll out in two federal member states: Hirshabelle and South West States.
Complemented with supplies and equipment, competency-based training will - according to UNICEF - target health professionals, primarily midwives, nurses and doctors from regional hospitals, health centres and peripheral health units (PHUs) to deliver quality interventions for pregnant and lactating women and their babies.
In terms of actual activities, UNICEF&#xA0;states that these are derived from the essential package of health services (EPHS) with primary focus to establish quality care targeting pregnant and lactating women and their babies using community, health facility and mobile clinic platforms.
This includes:
-Cascade (already prepared) various forms of&#xA0;competency-based training to build skills and knowledge of health professionals (midwives/nurses/doctors) and other front-line health cadres (e.g. community health workers).
-Provision of new-born care and other related mother and new-born supplies and materials.
-Monthly performance monitoring meetings to review indicator trends.
-Complementary resources to NGO partners in targeted areas to accelerate mother and new-born health service delivery, emergency referral and community accountability mechanisms (e.g., community health committees).
-Develop an integrated health and nutrition &#x201C;first pregnancy&#x201D; strategy for UNICEF; and, conduct a detailed assessment and roadmap for gradually supporting the state MOHs to manage managing their own cold chain to enable deliver safe, effective vaccines.
-Prepare contingency plans, capacity development and pre-positioning of supplies to enable the different&#xA0;state ministry of health&#xA0;to prepare and respond to regular cyclical shocks (floods, drought)- given chronic humanitarian needs (annual cyclical shocks) affecting the two states.
Examples of indicators that will measure progress and results for Health:
- Percentage of deliveries attended by skilled health personnel
- Percentage of pregnant women who attended at least four times for antenatal care during their pregnancy
- Percentage of children under 1 year receiving measles-containing vaccine
Protective environment:
The humanitarian crisis in Somalia is among the most complex and longstanding emergencies in the world. The protective environment for children has been weakened due to more than two decades of conflict resulting in the collapse of institutions at all levels. The perpetration of grave child rights violations including the recruitment and use of children by armed forces and groups remains a major concern in Somalia.
Under the programme for protective environment&#xA0;UNICEF will provide technical support to the Ministry of Women and Human Rights Development and the Ministry of Justice to develop an effective child protection system. UNICEF will support the Government in accelerating the domestication of the Convention on the Rights of the Child through building a stronger legislative and policy environment. The Child Protection Information Management System will be rolled out nationwide, providing case management tools that reinforce accountable services and follow-up.
UNICEF will furthermore in the area of child protection/protective environment:
-Strengthen the protective environment for girls and boys in school.
-Support children affected by armed conflict (including maintenance of the monitoring and reporting mechanism on grave child rights violations).
More specifically, the contribution will help to support the retention of girls and boys in school by contributing to a wider safe schools initiative that is being developed between the UNICEF education and child protection teams.
The broader program includes the development of school councils, teacher codes of conduct, improved pre- and in-service teacher training, higher female teacher ratios, as well as empowerment self-defence and &quot;your moment of truth&quot; violence prevention norm change programming for students.
Examples of indicators that will measure progress and results for Protective Environment:
-&#xA0;Outcome indicator: Number of schools and adolescent students (by sex) engaged in a safe schools&#x2019; programme incorporating adolescent empowerment
-&#xA0;Outcome indicator: % of girls and boys recruited and used by armed forces and groups that have been released and reintegrated with their families and provided with adequate care and services
For both Health and Protective Environment&#xA0;UNICEF&#xA0;has provided a results framework with indicators, baseline and targets&#xA0;allowing for a results oriented approach and close follow-up and dialogue on the progress of implementation. Examples of those is presented above under each thematic area.&#xA0;
COVAX&#xA0;vaccines and the roll out&#xA0;of Covid-19 vaccination campaign&#xA0;
The first batch of COVAX vaccines (300 000 doses) arrived to Somalia on March 15, 2021. &#xA0;The Covid-19 vaccination campaign is&#xA0;of vital importance as a critical public health intervention&#xA0;to help contain further spread especially amongst the vulnerable populations.
The COVAX facility will provide vaccines for 20% of Somalia&apos;s total population. In this regard, Somalia will receive vaccines to cover 3,134,106 individuals, taking into consideration the population of Somalia being approximately 15,670,529 persons. Each eligible individual will receive 2 doses of the vaccine so, meaning that 6,268,212 million doses are expected to be administrated.&#xA0;&#xA0;
In close collaboration with the Federal and State Ministries of Health,&#xA0;UNICEF&#xA0;and WHO developed a plan and budget to cover for the operational costs for the vaccination campaign. To cover the operational costs for the 6,2 million&#xA0;doses that are expected, it is calculated to cost approximately 25 MUSD, or per doses administrated 4 USD.
The plan developed includes the following key activities&#xA0;planning and coordination, logistics and vaccine management; human resources; training and meetings; supplies and equipment; transportation; social mobilization and communication; and M&amp;E tools and biometric data collection; intra- and post-campaign monitoring; AEFI (adverse events following immunization) surveillance; and other forms of necessary technical support.&#xA0;&#xA0;
The expected outcome of the Covid-19 campaign is vaccine induced immunity to protect against&#xA0;Covid-19, which will protect vulnerable groups and detain further spread of the virus. The proposed 5 million SEK&#xA0;will cover full vaccination (2 doses) of approximately&#xA0;74 000 Somalis.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF/United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF/United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="122" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.a - Strengthen relevant national institutions, including through international cooperation, for building capacity at all levels, in particular in developing countries, to prevent violence and combat terrorism and crime.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.a - St&#xE4;rka ber&#xF6;rda nationella institutioner, bland annat genom internationellt samarbete, i syfte att bygga upp kapacitet p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er, i synnerhet i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna, f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rebygga v&#xE5;ld och bek&#xE4;mpa terrorism och brottslighet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2 - By 2030, end preventable deaths of newborns and children under 5&#xA0;years of age, with all countries aiming to reduce neonatal mortality to at least as low as 12 per 1,000 live births and under-5 mortality to at least as low as 25 per 1,000 live births.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.2 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att inga sp&#xE4;dbarn eller barn under fem &#xE5;r d&#xF6;r av orsaker som hade kunnat f&#xF6;rebyggas. Alla l&#xE4;nder b&#xF6;r str&#xE4;va efter att minska den neonatala d&#xF6;dligheten till h&#xF6;gst tolv d&#xF6;dsfall per 1 000 levande f&#xF6;dda och d&#xF6;dligheten bland barn under fem &#xE5;r till h&#xF6;gst 25 d&#xF6;dsfall per 1 000 levande f&#xF6;dda.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3 - By 2030, end the epidemics of AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria and neglected tropical diseases and combat hepatitis, water-borne diseases and other communicable diseases.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.3 - Senast 2030 utrota epidemierna av aids, tuberkulos, malaria och f&#xF6;rsummade tropiska sjukdomar samt bek&#xE4;mpa hepatit, vattenburna sjukdomar och andra smittsamma sjukdomar.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B033" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">4080728.4683277174</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">4080728.4683277174</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">4080728.4683277174</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">4080728.4683277174</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-01">8161456.936655</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-28">4080728.4683277174</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-07">4080728.4683277174</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/somalia/14486_14486-UNICEF-SwedenAgreeement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">14486 - Unicef-Sida Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/somalia/14486_14486-DecisiononContributionUnicefSomalia.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">14486 - Decision on Contribution Unicef Somalia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="14486" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060903" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3000000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Somalia 2018-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Somalia 2018-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
