<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5127003102-SOM-15190</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LAW - access to justice gender based violence in Somalia</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">LAW - tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa k&#xF6;nsrelaterat v&#xE5;ld Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Den internationella organisationen, Legal Action Worldwide (LAW), har ans&#xF6;kt om finansiering om 9 miljoner kronor f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra pilotprojektet &quot;,&quot;Building &quot;legal Agency&quot; for IDPs through increased accountability for human rights violations, with a focus on GBV in Somalia&quot; under perioden 2017-2019. Projektet syftar till att &#xF6;ka ansvarutkr&#xE4;vandet och tillg&#xE5;ngen till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r internflyktingar som blivit utsatta f&#xF6;r v&#xE5;ldsbrott av s&#xE4;kerhetsstyrkor, med fokus p&#xE5; k&#xF6;nsrelaterat v&#xE5;ld, genom att st&#xE4;rka kapacitet hos civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer och r&#xE4;ttsektorn att utreda och &#xE5;tala fall av k&#xF6;nsrelaterat v&#xE5;ld samt inr&#xE4;tta oberoende &#xF6;versynsmyndigheter f&#xF6;r den somaliska polisen i omr&#xE5;den med mycket internflyktingar. Projektet syftar &#xE4;ven till att &#xF6;ka medvetenheten och behovet av &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder mot k&#xF6;nsrelaterat v&#xE5;ld b&#xE5;de p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; och p&#xE5; s&#xE5; s&#xE4;tt bidra till en starkare r&#xE4;ttighetskultur inom s&#xE4;kerhetssektorn. Projektet kommer att genomf&#xF6;ras i samarbete med akt&#xF6;rer i civil samh&#xE4;llet, ber&#xF6;rda ministerier och polisen i Mogadishu men med m&#xF6;jlighet till expandering till de s&#xF6;dra och centrala delarna av Somalia under projektperioden. Pilotprojektet kommer genomf&#xF6;ras i n&#xE4;ra samarbetet med UNHCR och andra relevanta akt&#xF6;rer och p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende program.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The international civil society organisation, Legal Action Worldwide (LAW) has applied to the Embassy for funding of 9 million SEK to carry out the pilot project on &quot;building &quot;legal Agency&quot; for IDPs through increased accountability for human rights violations, with a focus on GBV&quot; in Somalia, during the period 2017-2019. 

The project is focusing on building &quot;legal agency&quot; for IDPs by increasing accountability and access to justice for violations of human rights with a focus on gender based violence (GBV) committed by the security forces.  It will build a skill set amongst IDPs to document and advocate on human rights violations against their community(ies), both at the national and international level. The project will work with Somali actors to create a cadre of human rights enablers within the IDP community itself and those that provide legal representation to them.  An independent Civilian Oversight Board (COB) over the Somali National Police Force will be established in areas containing the highest number of IDPs. The project will be commenced in Mogadishu and expanded in the southern and central regions of Somalia over three years. 

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 10 167 500 SEK (1 089 689 USD) , out of which approximately 1 million SEK is supposed to be contributed by another donor (discussions are ongoing with UN WOMEN). Approximately 1 300 000 SEK (142 290 USD) of the intervention budget will be forwarded from LAW to the Somali NGO Witness Somalia for the coordination of the establishment of civilian oversight boards.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LAW/Legal Action Worldwide</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LAW/Legal Action Worldwide</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15190" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Facilitation of orderly, safe, regular and responsible migration and mobility</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">351000.351000351</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">172604.2529687932</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">-1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">351000.3510003509</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">172604.2529687932</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-02-01">526500.5265</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-03-28">175500.1755001755</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-28">175500.1755001755</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-28">172604.2529687932</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Result 1: Improved documentation and preparation of cases of gender-based violence (GBV) committed against IDPs in pilot areas.The intended impact of this result area is to increase access to justice for survivors of GBV in IDP communities by both up-skilling lawyers and activists who work with IDPs and improve linkages between the IDP communities, lawyers, police and prosecutors.
There are now nine paralegals operational in Mogadishu (the Geedole, Dhagaxweyn and Midnimo IDP camps) and seven in Kismayo (the Maanamuufo, Halgan and Dharkeynley IDP camps). Of the 16 paralegals, ten are women. The paralegals visit each camp weekly, perform community awareness sessions, and receive reports of crime from the IDP communities.Theparalegals then either assist the IDPs through referrals to local medical or psychosocial services,assist them in reporting the matter to the police, or mediate the issue directly as necessary.
The paralegals have now been doing their visits for almost a year, there is a developing amount of data regarding the issues they are contacted about. The most common violations and abuses reported to the ICM are:&#x2022; Domestic violence;&#x2022; Sexual violence (most commonly rape by men unknown to the survivor);&#x2022; Forced marriage;&#x2022; Land disputes;&#x2022; Forced evictions from IDP camps; and&#x2022; Exploitation (people refusing to pay after getting IDPs to do house work).
SGBV is the focus of the paralegal&#x2019;s work and they will particularly follow up on these cases.They have been met with significant resistance from the survivors about pursuing any accountability &#x2013; very few are willing to even speak to police about the incidents (see LAW&apos;s respons below under main challenges).&#xA0;
Result 2: Cadre of human rights enablers in the law and justice sector created. Impact: The intended impact of this result area is to improve access to justice for all Somalis, including the most marginalised, through the strategic efforts of a core group of Somali civil society activists who document violations, conduct advocacy and agitate for change.
The Somali Legal Aid Network (SLAN) is intended to be an umbrella organisation for legal aid providers across Somali and Somaliland and was started by LAW in 2014.&#xA0;Its roles have included advocacy on key legal issues such as the Sexual Offences Bill, as well as coordinating activities to reduce duplication, sharing or resources, and avoiding conflicts over territory or funding. A key challenge with developing the SLAN has been the constant turnover of key staff.&#xA0;To mitigate this, LAW is funding a coordination position who will organise meetings and enhance coordination between SLAN member organisation projects in Mogadishu .LAW sees great potential in the SLAN and will focus on building its capacity for the duration of the project. A formidable voice for the legal aid sector is vital to increasing access to justice and the rule of law across the country.
A key aspect of this result is to involve IDPs in the programs designed to benefit them. As such, LAW employed three community leaders from IDP communities in Mogadishu and one in Kismayo to assist in the development of the program and to act as a conduit of information between service providers and the communities. These community leaders, hired in October 2018, work closely with the ICM paralegals, regularly refer cases, and attend meetings and trainings with the ICM. Perhaps most importantly, they are a permanent presence in the IDP camps and have become a contact point between paralegal visits. Since their involvement began, they have been involved in approximately 85 percent of cases referred to the paralegals.
Result 3: Independent oversight (COB) of the police with a focus on police operations in IDP communities established.Impact: The impact of this result is to strengthen the ability of Somali civil society to hold the police to account, particularly for violations committed against IDP communities.
The Civilian Oversight Board (COB) created by this project is the first civilian police oversight mechanism established insouth central Somalia since the Police Advisory Committee was disbanded in 2011. It has been effectively overseeing and reporting on the activities of police inside the two pilot police stations since November 2017.&#xA0;
The COB also coordinates with ICM paralegals to make sure that serious cases are investigated and prosecuted, rather than resolved at the clan level, or by threats or bribes. This has been perhaps the most effective role of the COB as the likelihood of cases being forgotten or resolved outside the formal justice system is very high and this is a key reason why the publicdoes not want to pursue cases. Key results of the COB&#x2019;s visits include every visit reporting concerns about cleanliness in thecells. Detainees at one station reported the reason for this was that the police officers required them to clean the cells (including the bathroom) without any cleaning materials. This was raised with the commander who assigned the duties to the police officers instead. Another issue was police officers requiring complainants fund the food for anyone arrested as a result of their complaint. This was reported a number of times but after intervention from the COB, and other organisation, the practice has seemed to end. The Ministry of Internal Security now seems to be funding the purchase of food fordetainees consistently in Mogadishu.
Result 4: Increased awareness and commitment to meaningfully address GBV by key international and national stakeholders.
The work done towards achieving this result again focusses on the passage of the Sexual Offences Bill which is currently stalled before parliament. LAW has heard that religious objections to the bill seem to have had the desired effect of removing it from the government priority list and is in the process of working with civil society to identify ways to work aroundthis impasse. LAW is also conscious that a key aspect of the criticism received from religious scholars to the bill is that it is a tool of Western influences, and as such is keen to ensure that it is not seen to be overly visible on the issue.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51270031" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
