<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5210013001-SOM-15110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM Diaspora Project</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">IOM Diasporaprojekt MIDA Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Den 2013-16 Projektet genomf&#xF6;rs  genom IOM och fokuserar p&#xE5; att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra kapaciteten hos den somaliska regeringen i 3 sektorer (dvs. offentlig finansiell styrning samt r&#xE4;ttsliga och h&#xE4;lsa), genom rekrytering och placering av den somaliska diasporan i dessa sektorer.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2013-16 project is implemented through IOM and focuses on improving the capacity of the Somali government in 3 sectors (i.e. Public Financial Management, Justice and Health), through recruitment and placement of the Somali Diaspora in these sectors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The collapse of the government in 1991 destroyed completely Somali institutions. Since the formation first transitional national government in 2000 and subsequent governments with the support of the donor community have tried to reestablish government institutions as part of Somalia&#xB4;s reconstruction and statebuilding efforts. In contrast to the war-torn south, northern areas have established functioning institutions that have succeeded in sustaining stability, albeit considerable challenges, including resources constraints.
The 2012 peaceful and legal transfer of power from the transitional to a full-fledged federal government accelerated the need to build viable institutions. The end of the transition generated domestic political momentum and triggered international re-engagement with Somalia. The Somali New Deal Compact in 2013 highlighted this new reengagement. With the end of transition, an incremental state formation within a federal model began, starting with the formation of the Interim Juba Administration. Similar process followed with formation of additional three states, namely South West, Galmudug and Hirshabelle. Hence, the state formation was completed with the formation of Hirshabelle in 2016. However, the weak institutional capacity and a challenging security situation have complicated Somalia&#xB4;s reconstruction and statebuilding efforts. Most basic services having been provided by non-state actors and NGO during the last three decades and this continues to be the case to a large extent. The ability of the federal and states governments to cover the expenses of its institution and provide basic services to its citizens are still limited due limited financial resources.
The New Deal Somali compact emphasized the need for laying &#x201C;strong foundation for building reliable, transparent, accountable and functioning state institutions, respectful of the fundamental rights, freedoms and equality of its citizens&#x201D;. Institution building has been a cross-cutting issues across the five Peacebuilding and Statebuilding Goals (PSGs) of the New Deal Compact. Strengthening core government functions within the public service is an integral part of reconstruction, peace building and recovery (stabilization). A core element of building a functioning state in Somalia is ensuring that local, regional and national government respond to the needs and expectations citizens. The Among other things, citizens expect of their government the provision of basic services. Support institutional capacity-building in human resources remains an important area for donor support.
The overall objective of the project was to contribute to the ongoing process of stabilization and state-building of Somalia by developing the capacities of government institutions through the mobilization of Somali diaspora professionals in key public sectors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="47066" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM/International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47066" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM/International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1573727.200147393</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">2558346.3315791776</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">2553096.0088821365</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1696614.8356148356</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1573727.200147393</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">2558346.3315791776</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">2553096.0088821356</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1696614.8356148356</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">-9e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-09-01">9848696.953878</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-10-28">1573727.200147393</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-07-28">517500.2551057596</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-09-28">2040846.0764734182</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-28">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-28">1384393.852626658</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-28">1696614.8204048201</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the course of this project (September 2013 to October 2019), Somalia made significant reform progress in key civil service reform policy areas to improve the quality of public services with the support of Somalia&#xB4;s development partners. Currently although having comparatively small public service, the FGS devotes more than 50% of its spending and 70% of domestic revenues to its wage bill. Throughout the span of six years, the project has achieved key outcomes that have resulted in improvement of the capacity of the targeted institutions for function.
The project has supported a total of 35 government and public institutions across the whole of Somalia, through the placement of 124 MIDA experts, comprising of 84 diaspora professionals, 38 interns and 2 local experts. Out of the 124 experts, 19 per cent were women (24 women, 100 men), representing 10 different nationalities (UK, US, Sweden, Somalia, Norway, Italy, Kenya, Djibouti, Canada, Australia). In total, IOM supported 172 MIDA assignments (total number of contracts and extensions). These experts played important role for the government institutions in fulfilling their mandate. This included transferring injecting key competencies within the scope of the targeted institutions by putting in place operational plans, system, procedures, policies and legal frameworks in order to enhance the overall capacity of the institutions. According implementing Partner, IOM, 90 per cent of the staff interviewed in the beneficiary institutions indicate that they can fulfil their mandates as a result of the diaspora placements.
Through the MIDA secondment to the Ministry of Women and Human Rights Development (MoWHRD), a number of key legislations and frameworks safeguarding women&#x2019;s rights and protection have been developed and endorsed by the FGS cabinet although these legislations are pending at the parliament.
The MIDA experts under the Public Financial Management (PFM) sector have significantly contributed to sustainable public expenditure by promoting transparent and accountable fiscal policies and procedures, improving accounting and internal/external audit systems and controls and developing essential management skills to foster good governance practices. Key fiscal policies that have been developed and endorsed through this secondment, include the Anti-Money Laundering Policy and Combating the Financing of Terrorism (AML/CFT), Mobile Money Providers Regulations and the Anti-Corruption Law. The latter, which is a major milestone, was signed into law in September 2019, and has played critical part in the establishment of the independent Anti-Corruption commissions at the federal levels. In addition, the introduction of systems from International Standards of Supreme Audit Institutions (ISSAI) is a significant progress in the path towards restoring public trust in the financial institutions.
The macroeconomist and monetary policy analyst placed at the Central Bank of Somalia (CBS) contributed towards the Central Bank Strategic Plan 2013-2018 as well as important international conferences and frameworks in the path towards Comprehensive Debt Forgiveness making Somalia debt-free.
The Public Sector Advisor placed at the Office of the Auditor General (OAG) in Puntland was able to build the capacity of OAG staff to ensure that the OAG is following the general acceptable audit standards. Through the introduction and implementation of a standardized audit system, the audit team of the OAG are now able to properly audit government transactions. The advisor also contributed towards the Audit Law in Puntland as well as the Auditor General Strategic Plan and 2014-18 in guiding the OAG to implement the general accepted audit standards and compliance with financial rules and regulations. The Taxation Law and Revenue Reform expert at the Puntland Ministry of Finance (MoF) directly contributed to the Puntland Taxation Framework, which was later endorsed. Significant accomplishments made by the expert include the implementation of sales taxes, employment taxes on non-state employees as well as the land and property tax, in Puntland. In addition to the expert&#x2019;s contributions to the Ministry, the advisor lectured on taxation law at the Puntland State University.
The Senior Planning Advisor attached to Ministry of Planning, Planning and Economic Development (MoPIED) was engaged in reviewing the National Statistics Bill as well as leading the preparations for the National Monitoring and Evaluation (M&amp;E) policy and the Non-Governmental Organizations (NGO) Act. While the first two have been endorsed, the latter is pending approval.
Another important achievement though the secondment is the development of an innovative digital performance management tool, dubbed the &#x201C;Performance and Delivery Management Roadmap System&#x201D;, that was launched in 2019 by the MIDA expert at the Office of the Prime Minister as an Operations and Systems advisor. This highly efficient and user-friendly software system has led to optimizing the government&#x2019;s procedures and contributed towards realizing the National Development Plan (NDP). This has been made possible through proper planning and monitoring of targeted deliverables in the government&#x2019;s roadmap, with over 90 per cent of senior leadership (including the Prime Minister himself, Ministers, Director-Generals and roadmap leaders) who are now using this fully operative system.
The finance advisor, placed at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation (MoIFAC) focused on supervising and improving the performance of 14 junior staff in the Ministry (7 males, 7 females) through capacity building trainings in basic accounting, budget review and preparation, and financial reporting. As a result of the continuous capacity building carried out by the MIDA advisor, the junior finance staff in the Ministry are able to undertake common practices in accounting and apply the introduced accounting software programmes. The assistance and on-the-job training from the finance advisor have enabled the junior staff to properly apply budget guidelines and to prepare financial reports, which has resulted in improved quality of the financial reports submitted both internally and externally. Another advisor placed at MoIFAC was able to reform the organizational structure of the procurement department at the Ministry, through clear procurement guidelines. The expert supported the establishment of a fully functioning procurement committee that has enabled clear mandates and roles between MoIFAC&#x2019;s procurement department and the finance department in order to avoid overlaps and has contributed to reduced corruption and mismanagement of stocks and assets of the institution. The advisor&#x2019;s contributions in developing procurement policies and procedures, facilitating workshops and seminars on public procurement and procurement regulations, have led to improved institutional understanding of robust and transparent procurement procedures that ensure internal control of purchases and the maintenance of institutional assets. With the support of the logistical advisor, placed at MoIFAC, a new logistics and protocol system was put in place to guide all department staff within the Ministry. This included monthly checklist with department heads on logistical and protocol matters and introducing more efficient procedures for reporting and processing of requests and documents. In addition to this, all diplomatic paperwork such as Duty waiver, Visas, residence permits, and diplomatic IDs are processed between seven to ten business days. This has in turn contributed towards more efficient mechanisms to handle diplomatic crisis and conflict mediation.
The secondment of a MIDA expert to the Kismayo General Hospital as a senior surgeon, has contributed to improved surgical outcomes at the hospital through his leadership and guidance in critical decision-making and timely interventions of all surgical and medical matters. The MIDA senior surgeon led the establishment of a well-functioning surgical outpatient clinic, which is now fully operating. The staff at the hospital are now able to work under the guidance of Standard Operation Procedures (SoPs) and templates, as well as following a clear referral mechanism system. The templates include a pre-operative checklist, standard treatment sheet and a theatre workload registry. Through the trainings provided by the expert as well as his leadership role at the hospital, the MIDA senior surgeon managed to strengthen infection prevention and control mechanisms to reduce post-operative and hospital acquired infections. The expert&#x2019;s overall support has ultimately led to improved quality of treatment as well as decreased morbidity and mortality rate at the hospital.
Achievement of a MIDA expert seconded to the Ministry of Humanitarian Affairs and Disaster Management (MoHADM) include: the significant leadership and coordination efforts in the development and launch of the Disaster Management Policy in 2019, as well as laying the groundwork for the Emergency Coordination Centre that is to be established in Mogadishu, through building the capacity of the MoHADM staff that have been assigned to run the center.
Further impactful contributions to the health sector have been supported by the MIDA senior health sector policy advisor, placed under the Office of the Prime Minister, in supporting the development of a National Road Map for the Social Sector which sets to coordinate and prioritize key health interventions. The advisor also supported in providing technical input in the development of the National Health Professionals (NHP) Act, a comprehensive legal framework covering the required criteria for health professionals, including their registrations as medical practitioners, clinical licensing and medical conduct. The NHP Act when enacted by the parliament will lead to overall improved quality and formalized health care by ensuring that medical practitioners operate under clear legal frameworks.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52100130" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
