<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5210011901-SOM-15110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">FNs JPLG, fas II</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Joint Programme on Local Governance and ServiceJPLG II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">FNs gemensamma program f&#xF6;r lokalt samh&#xE4;llsstyre och decentraliserad   samh&#xE4;llsservice fas II (JPLG II), 2013-2017.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The UN Joint Programme on Local Governance and Service Delivery Phase II (JPLG II), 2013-2017</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">7676718.049499477</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">5102115.191183546</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2076091.727664219</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">4090457.546894174</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">2047502.0475020474</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">7676718.049499478</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">5102115.191183545</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2076091.7276642187</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">4090457.546894174</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">2047502.0475020474</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">23797825.953448</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-06-28">5373702.634649634</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">2303015.4148498434</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-07-28">5102115.191183546</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">2076091.727664219</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-28">2045228.773447087</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-28">2045228.773447087</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-28">2047502.0475020474</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2017 annual report is yet to be submitted since the programme implementation period was extended to June 2017 pending the roll-over to JPLG III. The report is expected at the end of October 2018.
The 2016 annual report highlights progress which includes the progress made to implement the decentralization strategies in Somaliland and Puntland and the finalization of a basic package of legislation which supports the devolution of functions from central to local government. The programme fruitfully conducted an assessment and review of the decentralization policies, that included a review of the Service Delivery Models and the Participatory Planning and Public Expenditure Management framework in JPLG target districts (at the end of 2015 and the beginning of 2016). The assessment and review identified a series of gaps in national legislation (Somaliland and Puntland) which led to the production of a list of policies, laws and regulations that require amendments (to address the gaps) and in support of the devolution of authority. In May 2016, the programme managed to adopt a Fiscal Decentralization Strategy to attain operational inter-governmental-transfer system in 2017. 
The programme achieved finalization and/or endorsement of the following key technical policies that support districts to perform their key functions: 
i) Local Government Finance Policy (LGFP), which covers financial management, budget preparation and execution, revenue generation, expenditure management, accounting and control, fixed asset management, and financial reporting; 
ii) Urban Regulatory Framework which covers urban planning and management; 
iii) A review of the road sector legislative, institutional and policy framework was conducted. This will inform the decentralization strategy for the roads sector to be developed in 2017; 
iv) Solid Waste Management bylaws, that define the role of municipality and public, use of municipal revenue and public-private partnership arrangements in the delivery of the service; 
v) Natural Resource Management (NRM) strategy that defines the procedure of functions transfer, the role of the central government, municipality and public in the delivery of the service. 
&#xA0;At the end of 2016, all target districts have functioning planning, procurement, social affairs, revenue generation and public works departments that have been equipped with tools, guidelines and systems that facilitate effective public service delivery. Tools such as district planning and public procurement are now extensively used outside JPLG projects areas and are mostly funded by a district&#x2019;s own revenues. Another significant achievement in 2016, was the improvement in the capacity of districts; for example, there has been a significant annual increase in revenue from property tax collection in JPLG target districts in Somaliland and Puntland. The increase is attributed to programme reform and technical assistance, the implementation of property numbering, constant updating property and building databases. Though the programme has achieved significant progress in public works, urban development and an increase in revenue there is a need to put more efforts into strengthening the capacity of the social affairs departments. 
In 2016, the programme continued supporting Service Delivery Model pilots in the following sectors: education, health, roads, natural resource management, solid waste management and water. All Service Delivery Models were implemented as planned in Borama, Berbera, Burao and Odweine in Somaliland and Bosaso, Eyl, Garowe and Gardo in Puntland. However, there were delays in launching pilots in Puntland, where service delivery models were initiated in the water sector in Eyl and plans developed for implementation of the education model in Garowe. Local governments in target districts in Somaliland increased their contributions to sector budgets, with contributions to education budgets from local revenues rising by 92%. There is a recorded increase of utilization of health and education services as a result of the improved service delivery mechanisms as well as improved public-private partnership arrangements in roads and water management. The programme closed outstanding payments from 2014 - 2015 under Local Developments Funds component but due to funding constrains was not able to support 2016 LDF projects, though they were approved and finalized. 
&#xA0;Early 2016, state and federal Ministries of Interior worked together to finalize and agree on a principled document to guide local governance formation - the Wadajir framework, which is aimed to to advance the establishment of the third level of government. The representatives of MoIFA and state Ministries of Interior during different forums and meetings that took place in 2016 repeatedly stated that &#x201C;the strong local governance is fundamental to stabilization, peace building and development in Somalia&#x201D;. It became a crucial task for the programme to intensify supporting the state Ministries of Interior on institutional development and advancing LG reforms. 
In 2016, the programme supported Jubbaland State and South West State to undergo the initial phase of Local Government Law development, which will enable district council formation to commence. The process has its own significance as the new Federal Member States were simultaneously able to compare their bills and under the leadership of MoIFA to review and propose revisions to the Federal Local Government Law #116. Jubbaland State, South West State, and Galmudug State are establishing state level structures with the mandate for local governance and decentralization and JPLG supported state building by creating common planning and vision for a uniform local government structure. South West state and BRA were the focus of large-scale civic education efforts which resulted in improved understanding among citizens of local governance process, brought them closer to local government, and build trust between them. The programme has subsequently produced a contextualized civic education resource pack that is aligned with the Wadajir framework and that can be taken forward by Federal Member States.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52100119" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
