<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5215001601-SOM-12220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Additional contribution to CHF 2013</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Kompletterande bidrag till CHF 2013</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Den f&#xF6;reslagna &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rden uppfyller de krav som det p&#xE5;g&#xE5;r och det extra bidrag p&#xE5; 17 miljoner kronor kommer att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att interventionen motverkar den framv&#xE4;xande humanit&#xE4;ra och utvecklingsm&#xE4;ssiga utmaningar i Somalia. Interventionen &#xE4;r i linje med Sveriges strategi f&#xF6;r Somalia, den nya aff&#xE4;ren och flera svenska politiken.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia still faces one of the worst humanitarian crises in the world. Despite having made progress in the humanitarian situation, needs still remain vast and the gains could be reversed without continued timely and appropriate interventions. Nearly two decades of conflict have weakened the country&#x2019;s ability to cope with complex emergencies and recover from the associated economic impacts. The country&#x2019;s humanitarian challenges include: food insecurity; poor access to health services; inadequate access to water and sanitation services; sexual and gender-based violence; internally displaced persons among others. Somalia still stands as one of the most challenging and dangerous environments in the world to deliver both humanitarian and developmental assistance hence collective efforts are required to meet the needs of Somalis especially in South Central that is hardest hit and requires more support yet access is most difficult.
An estimated 870,000 people require urgent humanitarian assistance while an additional 2.3 million require livelihood support. Malnutrition rates remain among the highest in Somalia, with 206,000 children under the age of 5 years acutely malnourished. About two-thirds of the acutely malnourished children are in southern Somalia. Internally displaced people in Somalia constitute more than two-thirds of the 870,000 people in crisis. Humanitarian access remains critical, especially in south central where high levels of malnutrition persist and most urgent humanitarian needs are concentrated.
Access to health services was worsened by the recent withdrawal of M&#xE9;decins Sans Fronti&#xE8;res (MSF) from Somalia. After working continuously in Somalia since 1991, the international medical humanitarian organization announced the closure of all its programs in Somalia in August 2013. MSF closed its medical programs across Somalia, including in the capital Mogadishu and the suburbs of Afgooye and Daynille, as well as in Balad, Dinsor, Galkayo, Jilib, Jowhar, Kismayo, Marere, and Burao. This decision was reached after review of incidents that involved MSF including death and kidnapping of staff. More than 1,500 staff provided a range of services, including free primary health care, malnutrition treatment, maternal health, surgery, epidemic response, immunization campaigns, water, and relief supplies. In 2012 alone, MSF teams provided more than 624,000 medical consultations, admitted 41,100 patients to hospitals, cared for 30,090 malnourished children, vaccinated 58,620 people, and delivered 7,300 babies. 

The pull out of MSF therefore, leaves a huge gap in health service delivery that unless bridged immediately will have severe consequences to the target population and Somalia in General. An analysis carried out by the health cluster and the health authorities indicates that an estimated 1,500,000 Somali population will lack access to essential, including life-saving, health services. Specifically, about 15,000 pregnant women with complicated deliveries per year may die due lack of access to Basic Emergency Obstetric Care (BEmOC). Similarly, an estimated 30,000 acutely ill children under 5 years may die due to lack of specialized health services and the case could be complicated by failure of newly born children to access preventive health services such as immunization. The MSF withdrawal also indicates that over 20,000 patients in need of life-saving surgical interventions, such as gunshot wounds, will lose their lives due to lack of access to emergency/casualty care. The withdrawal implies that Somalis will travel or walk up to 150 km, with good possibility of no access, in search for medical care.

A few facilities have already closed down following the withdrawal and some more are likely to close once the 3-6 months supplies and staff salaries left by MSF run out of stock. Some facilities in Benadir have reported increased patient number of patients hence increased work load and likelihood of the available medical supplies not meeting the increased demands. There are reported doubled numbers of Antenatal Care (ANC) and deliveries in health faccilities in Balcad signifying urgent need for drugs and vaccines. Several development partners expressed interest in taking up the facilities vacated by MSF. The Health Cluster and the Somali Health Authorities hence allocated facilities, following an agreed upon consultative process, to various development partners. However, their capacities are thwarted by the inability to timely access the required resources. It is estimated that a total of USD 16.55 million is required to cushion the Somalia from the impacts of MSF withdrawal.

Tied to the health challenges above is outbreak of the Wild Polio Virus that hit Somalia in May 2013 after six years of eradication. As of November 2013, there were 200 cases confirmed in Somalia, Kenya (14) and Ethiopia (6). The origin of the polio outbreak is Somalia. The outbreak was enabled by the very low immunization coverage in Somalia driven by highly mobile populations and insecurity. An estimated 600,000 children in the least accessible parts of Southern and Central Somalia have not received polio vaccination and are at a high risk of contracting the polio virus.

In the month of November 2013 a tropical cyclone struck the northeast coast of Somalia killing more than 100 people and thousands of head of livestock. Around 300 people were unaccounted for. The cyclone also destroyed important infrastructure and predisposed the affected population to waterborne diseases. Many wells in the provinces of Eyl and Dangorayo collapsed during the storm hence there is dire need for safe drinking water in some of the remote villages where the storm destroyed all sources of potable water. In Jowhar town Middle Shabele, flash floods damaged hundreds of homes affecting more than 200 families, among them elderly women and children. The joint multi-cluster rapid assessment mission carried out from 7-10 November, identified 33 villages affected by the flooding and corroborated the approximately 11,000 households displaced reported by the local authorities, while FSNAU has a more conservative number of 7,000 household distributed along 28 villages. To add to those affected by the floods, it is estimated that up to 1,000 HH have been displaced from ten villages due to clan conflict in the area, though estimates by local authorities run closer to 4,800 HH.  The Jowhar floods have contaminated water sources, including shallow wells, and damaged latrines across the affected area, leaving the population without access to safe drinking water and at risk to disease. There is also need for food aid as well as NFIs (Non-Food Items) in the affected regions.  

Sexual and gender-based violence is a critical concern in Somalia. More than 800 cases of sexual and gender-based violence were reported in the first half of the year in Mogadishu alone. Many more cases were likely not reported due to the stigma of sexual violence and the lack of access to justice. Women and girls living in settlements for displaced people are especially vulnerable.

An estimated 1.1 million people are internally displaced in Somalia, with high concentrations in Mogadishu and other urban centers. There are concerned about wide-spread insecurity in the settlements where internally displaced people reside, as well as ongoing evictions. Between June and mid-October tens of thousands of very vulnerable people were evicted from central Mogadishu. Most are now in makeshift settlements along kilometers 7 to 13 on the road from Mogadishu to Afgooye.

Life-saving assistance is required to meet the immediate needs of the people and address resilience so that the citizens can cope with looming humanitarian crises. While the gap in health service delivery cannot be adequately addressed in the short term, humanitarian partners are in need of funding to provide services for the most vulnerable. Prevention of conflict-related sexual violence is a key part of Somalia&#x2019;s peace-building and state-building processes.

A lack of adequate humanitarian support may exacerbate the situation. The requested 17 MSEK will be channeled through the CHF to support interventions that will mitigate impacts of the above mentioned challenges in Somalia. It is expected that the contribution will contribute to the CHF funding gap and contribute to strengthened capacity to respond to immediate life-saving needs as well as disaster risk management and strengthened resilience.

Since Somalia is a protracted crisis with a need of strengthening preventive measures and disaster risk management it is regarded useful to use funds from the Somalia country frame to complement funds from the humanitarian budget to increase the possibility of the CHF to allocate funds for disaster risk management and resilience as well as closing the gap between humanitarian funding and long-term development funding.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="122" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B04" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">2610084.1368298223</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">2610084.1368298223</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">2610084.136829</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">2610084.1368298223</value>
  </transaction>
  <contribution contributionid="52150016" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
