<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-20/3420/SA1/WASH/NGO/17927</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Restoring/maintaining sustainable and emergency WASH services to support the most affected people  in high priority districts in Maqbanah (parameter 1) and At Ta&apos;iziyah (parameter 2) in Taiz Governorate.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through this project 11 months, GWQ aims at increasing access of the targeted HHs of IDPs and the vulnerable host communities clean and safe water and suitable and appropriate sanitation facilities and to enhance hygiene practices of the targeted of HHs of IDP and host community in two high priority districts (61933 BNFs in Maqbanah and 2100 BNFs in At Ta&apos;iziyah) in Taiz gov. This goal will be realized following a gender-sensitive approach i.e., the unique needs of women, girls, boys, and men will be identified and reflected in the project activities, such as constructing latrines and involving women in training volunteers on hygiene promotion and in community committees formation.
The main objective will be achieved through a series of activities planned and would be implemented to be in line with the WASH cluster&apos;s objectives and the WASH cluster strategy for the 2020 SA of YHPF. The increased and equitable access to safe drinking water for HHs of IDPs and vulnerable host communities in the said districts will be reflected by rehabilitating 2 water schemes in Ad Darah and As Solaif of Maqbanah districts and powering them by solar energy, conducting water quality testing and monitoring in collaboration with LWSC for the targeted water network, providing water trucking to 2100 HHs of IDPs in hosting sites for 3 months and connecting the targeted HHs&apos; water tanks to sustainable water supply schemes as an exit strategy in At Ta&apos;iziyah district, and providing water storage containers to 7000 HHs ( 6700 HHs in Maqbanah and 300 HHs in At Ta&apos;iziyah) and water filters to 500 SAM HHs in Maqbanah. Improving access to the sanitation for HHs of IDPs in the host sites and communities will be achieved through constructing 100 emergency latrines with consideration of the needs of women and children and old people, and providing them with light in IDPs collective sites in At Ta&apos;iziyah district and through providing support for solid waste management in collaboration with the cleaning fund in urban areas with high SAM prevalence and open sewage in Maqbanah district. Regarding enhancing the knowledge of the targeted HHs of IDPs and host communities about hygiene practices, this will be reflected through distributing WASH cluster standard hygiene kits to 7000 SAM HHs (6700 HHs in Maqbanah and 300 HHs in At Ta&apos;iziyah), distributing  sanitation kits for 100 HHs of in At Ta&apos;iziyah, training 26 CVs on hygiene promotion to be responsible for conducting hygiene promotion/community mobilization in areas with high SAM prevalence (for 3 months) in the targeted areas of Maqbanah district, and printing and distributing IEC materials.
In addition, the current project was planned in coordination with GARWASP-Taiz to meet the essential needs of people in acute needs in hard-to-reach and malnutrition areas. Moreover, to provide comprehensive intervention in the targeted areas, this project comes to complement other actors&apos; and partners&apos; efforts across sectors working to reach YHRP 2020, WASH cluster, and YHF SA1 2020 objectives. For instance, GWQ will focus on targeting malnutrition cases in areas where UNICEF, IMC-OFDA, and IYCY are currently providing interventions in the nutrition sector. Besides, UNICEF will provide GWQ with CHKs and jerrycans to distribute for targeted BNFs. 
Based on the project&apos; context and GWQ&apos;s experience, some low and medium risks are expected and procedures to mitigate them are stated in the assumptions and risks tabs. Regarding the exit strategy, it is explained in the exit strategy tab.
Being a partner of WASH cluster and carrying out some projects in the targeted district and having sub-offices that can be used to run the project closely, GWQ has strong access to the targeted districts. Besides, GWQ will maintain coordination with stakeholders, WASH cluster, the local authorities, GARWASP, LWSC, Health Office, OCHA, and other actors in the targeted areas to ensure implementing the project activities smoothly and successful.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generations Without Qat</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generations Without Qat</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-18" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-18" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Layla Alfaqeeh</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Organization</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>967771230664</telephone>
   <email>layla.alfaqeeh@gwq-ye.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mesk Alabsi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>967770115919</telephone>
   <email>misk.absi@gwq-ye.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-09">340407.82</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-09">48347.78</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-17927">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-09">388755.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generations Without Qat</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304915014-5015">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-16">155502.24</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generations Without Qat</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305219993">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-05">116626.68</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generations Without Qat</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305460098/99">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-07">116626.68</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generations Without Qat</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
