<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-20/3420/SA1/Protection/INGO/17855</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive response to specialised protection services needs for 3600 vulnerable adults and children with disability, with injury and survivors of explosive remnants of war, affected by the conflict in AL Mokha district, Yemen / Priority 1</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing a comprehensive response to specialized protection services needs for vulnerable persons affected by the conflict in Al Mukha disctrict(Taizz Governarate) in Yemen, the proposed action contributes to mitigating the impact of the Yemen crisis on vulnerable groups. In a context of conflict, famine and poverty, persons with injury and/or disability among the most vulnerable. 

Reaching 3600 beneficiaries the proposed action will be implemented in AL Mokha District Hospital in Taizz governorate (AL Mokha district) with 3 expected results:

1. Persons with disability and/or injuries have increased access to available, accessible and quality comprehensive rehabilitation services  in AL Mokha district.
2 Humanitarian actors in Al Mukha district have increased knowledge on the inclusion of persons with disability and/or injury and have improved inclusive practices in their humanitarian responses.
3. Communities returning to and residing in contaminated areas have improved knowledge of the risks posed by mines/ERW/IEDs 

The proposed project is a comprehensive response to the identified needs of persons with disability and/or injury in the hard-to-reach area of Al Mokha district and is based on three complementary pillars: prevention, service provision and inclusion. While several factors lead to temporary or permanent disability, conflict is a main one in Yemen. 
The proposed project aims at preventing disability through the communities&#x2019; education to the risks of landmines, explosive remnants of war and improvised explosive device. HI will seek to strengthen communities&#x2019; capacity to promote Risk Education and safety through training community safety focal points (CSFPs) that are able to reinforce Risk Education messages. IEC materials for Risk Education will be developed and updated by HI during the project duration in a participatory and non-discriminatory approach.
The second pillar is implemented through the provision of protection specialized services to adults and children with disability and/or injury. HI will deliver direct and comprehensive rehabilitation services to adults and children with disability and/or injury as well as ensure that these services include the necessary psychological support required by persons with injuries and disabilities. Increasing the capacity of humanitarian actors and service providers will ensure a more sustainable impact of the action.
The third pillar aims at promoting the inclusion of persons with disability in the humanitarian responses and the accessibility of services, HI will raise awareness on the barriers faced to meaningful participation and access to humanitarian aid of persons with disabilities in protection amp health clusters and the humanitarian country team, through the promotion of the IASC Guidelines on the inclusion of persons with disabilities in humanitarian action. HI will support DPO representatives in attending cluster meetings by covering transport costs to a central place set aside for training, training of trainers for community representatives of persons with disability on inclusive humanitarian action and facilitate launching activities of the Arabic Language version of the IASC guidelines with organizations of persons with disabilities.
While HI will be in charge of the direct implementation of the activities, capacity building will as well ensure sustainability of the intervention and increased coverage of the services. To do so, HI will partner with Al Mokha hospital  in Al Mokha district. HI will focus on AL Mokha District Hospital which is a central facility and serves the population from Mokha District. Activities will complement already existing primary Healthcare in the location in order to maximize impact.

The project targets 864 persons with disability and/or injury 3600 persons in awareness activities and 30 professionals in trainings.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Handicap International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Handicap International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caroline Dauber</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967776404907</telephone>
   <email>c.dauber@hi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Florence Mesa</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967730518121</telephone>
   <email>f.mesa@hi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mike Kosgey</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operation Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967730010794</telephone>
   <email>m.kosgey@hi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-12">602199.99</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-12">190260.29</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-17855">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-12">792460.28</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Handicap International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304918197">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-23">316984.11</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Handicap International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305465036">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-09">316984.11</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Handicap International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
