<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-20/3420/SA1/WASH/UN/17943</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Emergency WASH Services for Hard Reach Locations and IDPs sites in Ad Durayhimi district.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen has now suffered for five years at the hands of a brutal conflict that has left close to 80 percent of the population in need of some form of humanitarian assistance. Nearly 18 million people, including 9.2 million children, do not have regular access to safe water, according to UNICEF, and only a third of the population has access to piped supplies. More than 12 million children need humanitarian assistance Acute child malnutrition rates have reached record levels in some parts of the country, marking a 10 per cent increase just this year. Nearly 325,000 children under the age of five suffer from severe acute malnutrition and are fighting to survive. More than five million children face a heightened threat of cholera and acute watery diarrhea.

UN-Habitat and Taybah Foundation for Development (TFD) will be to form a partnership under the umbrella of an UN-Habitat led to undertake the Provision of Emergency WASH Services for Locations Hard Reach and IDPs sites in Ad Durayhimi district. Both UN-Habitat and TFD have many years of experience implementing successful WASH projects, have strong relationships with the local authorities, both are members of the WASH Cluster. 
Access to clean and safe drinking water remains crucial for the good health and survival of children and their caregivers. Hostilities in Al Hudaydah Governorate have escalated in recent months. In October, While WASH needs remain substantially high due to the increasing number of displaced people as a result of the escalation of conflict along coastal areas of Al Hudaydah and other frontlines natural disasters, food insecurity and epidemic outbreaks. Notoriously, Ad Durayhimi had been particularly uncovered partially due to proximity to the front lines.
UN-Habitat will respond to the needs of the population in the WASH sector under the 2021 1st Standard Allocation with this intervention.
This specific intervention focuses on improving the access to WASH services for highly vulnerable families (host communities and Internally Displaced Persons (IDPs)) in risk of malnutrition, famine (in line with the Integrated Famine Risk Reduction (IFRR) programming) and/or infectious disease outbreak. UN-Habitat will provide a full WASH package composed of emergency and more sustainable solutions in order to adapt to the different needs of the populations targeted. Considering the gender gap in Yemen, this project will also rely on community based interventions, tailored to the specific needs of the communities, allowing to take into account the specific needs of women and girls especially in terms of adaptability and access to services. UN-Habitat will increase access to latrines for women. In addition, while this particular activity specifically addresses a protection concern, UN-Habitat will mainstream protection in all its activities. In general, the assistance will be provided while paying attention to the context and sociocultural norms, to prevent any unintended negative effects of the intervention and work towards equality, impartiality, accountability and empowerment.
UN-Habitat will work in communities to restore, construct key community water points, training WASH Management Committees (WMCs) to maintain them once the activity is over. Whilst the UNICEF will provide hygiene kits for most vulnerable households, UN-Habitat will provide alongside it the essential training and awareness sessions. Specifically, in order to contain and prevent the spread of COVID 19, cholera and other water-borne diseases in vulnerable communities within affected areas in Ad Durayhimi district, Al Hudaydah GOV, 
UN-Habitat and TFD have a good relationship of working with local authorities, EXU of IDPs, government offices, and community groups to implement core activities of their projects UN-Habitat maintains a team of highly experienced and skilled field engineers in Yemen who have in-depth knowledge and familiarity of the local communities&#x2019; specific challenges.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taybah Foundation for Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Human Settlements Programme (UN-HABITAT)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Human Settlements Programme (UN-HABITAT)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jorge Albizu Fierro</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wash Specialist Yemen Program</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+962 797501071</telephone>
   <email>jorge.albizu@un.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Hudaydah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.00062889 43.04031959</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-02">405601.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-02">146162.57</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-17943">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-02">551763.69</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Human Settlements Programme (UN-HABITAT)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304941830/31">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-11">551763.69</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Human Settlements Programme (UN-HABITAT)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
