<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DE-CR-VR9971-4000002514</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DE-CR-VR9971" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Applied Research in Partnership with the Orient e.V.</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rethinking Yemen&#x2019;s Economy &#x2013; Towards a Sustainable Future</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Rethinking Yemen&#x2019;s Economy initiative aims to contribute to peacebuilding and conflict prevention, (economic) stabilization and sustainable development in Yemen by building consensus in crucial policy areas through engaging and promoting informed Yemeni voices from all backgrounds in the public discourse on development, economy and post-conflict reconstruction in Yemen and by positively influencing local, regional and international development agendas. The project is implemented by CARPO &#x2013; Center for Applied Research in Partnership with the Orient, DeepRoot Consulting and the Sana&#x2019;a Center for Strategic Studies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main target group of this action are national and international policy-makers working on Yemen. This includes the internationally recognized government, other Yemeni experts and professionals working in the fields of economy and development, and regional and international policy-makers and representatives of organizations working in the respective fields in Yemen. All of these policy-makers, whether local, national or international, are constrained in their work by a lack of reliable data on pertinent issues on the ground as well as knowledge and expertise on the wide range of complex issues they need to address. The publications and the briefing meetings conducted during the ongoing project have thus always been very welcomed by all stakeholders invited as it provides them with the rare opportunity to speak to Yemeni experts on detailed matters relating to the conflict, development and economy in Yemen. The government of Yemen has also been represented by representatives during the final sessions of the DCFs and has also regularly kept informed on project outcomes through conversations with the project partners as well as through the publications. This target group will also be addressed through publications and briefing meetings both at the DCFs as well as in separate meetings with Champions organized in relevant capitals both in the region and in Europe and the US. As during the ongoing project, these briefing meetings will have public components where we partner up with a local think tank to organize panel discussions as well as non-public components through in-house briefings at relevant institutions in the respective capital in order to ensure a broad inclusion of relevant and interested stakeholders as well as room for detailed and confidential discussions.
The Yemeni society at large is not only a final beneficiary, but also a target group in this project as certain outputs are designed to ensure the Yemeni population is kept informed on the Champions&#x2019; recommendations and can interact with them through social media</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective is to contribute to peacebuilding, conflict prevention and stabilization in Yemen.

Specific Objectives:
SO1: To contribute to confidence-building and mediation through dialogue and knowledge transfer on the ongoing economic crisis.
SO2: To build the collective identity of the Development Champions as the advisory body on economic issues and development.
SO3: To build consensus on crucial policy areas.
SO4: To positively influence local, regional and international development agendas.
SO5: To highlight local needs and priorities and engage local expertise.
SO 6: To build the capacities of Yemeni researchers in researching and advocating for social and economic change.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DE-CR-VR9971" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Applied Research in Partnership with the Orient e.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DeepRoot</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sana&apos;a Center for Strategic Studies</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to contribute to peacebuilding and conflict prevention, (economic) stabilization and sustainable development in Yemen</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
