<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-17/3559/SA2/H/NGO/7010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support IDPs and Host Communities Through Provision of Primary Health Care Services in Jarablus, Al-Bab and Atareb Sub-district</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project will address the emergency winterization plan of the cluster and primary health care needs of the most conflict-affected vulnerable groups in hard to reach areas in Northern Aleppo Governorate &#x2013; Syria for 6 months. 

The proposed project aims to improve equitable access to quality primary health care services including reproductive and child health and referral services will principally focus on people in hard to reach the area and will be on ensuring that those already vulnerable will be able to survive winter conditions through a package of material assistance and services. Furthermore, the proposed project focuses on providing immediate primary health services with a specific focus on the vulnerability of the displaced populations, particularly the most vulnerable such as children, women, elderly and people suffering from chronic diseases. 

The proposed project serves a catchment population of 146000in 3 different districts in northern and western Aleppo governorate, which will allow to 87600 women, 64240men, 67160boys and 73000 girls.

The proposed project will work to improve the capacity and run
- 3 PHCs, level 2, located in Jarablus city- Jarablus district and Kafr Karmin sub-district- Jabel Saman district, and Sandrah city, Alraee sub-district
- 1 mobile clinic located in Zograh camp. 

Delivery of services per essential Package of primary health care, free of charge medicine, community outreach awareness services will reduce the morbidity and mortality among most vulnerable groups caused by hard winter session. IDA will contact SIG and WHO to include the suggested facilities under EPI program to provide routine vaccination to children and PLWs. 

Basic equipment, consumables, diagnostic kits and medication will be available according to the standard list. Sampling sets and surveillance kits for Type A diseases and RDTs will be available in the PHC Units as the staff will be responsible for the sample referrals to the surveillance laboratories and reporting on the priorities diseases under the early warning system. 
IDA will implement its HIMS system in the 3 PHCs and 1 mobile clinic for data collection and reporting, patient records will be kept by the medical team and reports were done.

IDA has signed MoU with Jarablus local council to implement this project in Jarablus district. Also, MoU has signed with Sandrah local council to run the proposed PHCs. IDA will ensure to obtain the approval form Kafr Karmin local council before starting implementing in this location. These PHCs are chosen to be supported after need direct coordination with AHD.

Considering the accessibility, Within a continuous coordination and meetings with Turkish authorities and local authorities in Jarabulus, Al-bab, and Jabal Samaan, IDA had managed to secure an official access to Jarabulus through Karkamish gate with for the commodities, materials and IDA&apos;s staff to cover the eastern rural area of Aleppo, and similar access through Bab Alhawa border gate to reach western rural side of Aleppo governorate, through this accessibility, IDA is capable of provided the necessary requirements to the activities in the region and facilitate the entrance the supply chain for the medical support in Jarabulus and Jabal Samaan. 
The other contingency option, IDA had the accessibility through Bab Al Salama gate where we have an alternative channel to support the activities in Jarabulus through A&apos;zaz district, but still, this alternative option will be used in the case of Karkamish gate have any issues in terms of security or safety of the supplies as well the staff.

The proposed project will improve the resilience of the local targeted community through improving the health service, building the capacity of local medical workers and coordinate with health local authorities in the targeted area. The proposed facilities are already staffed, So, Existing medical staff will be evaluated and contracted to run the facil</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-07">54554.39</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-07">274590.45</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-7010">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-07">329144.84</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303057099">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-15">263315.87</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303599834">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-11">51147.81</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
