<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-17/3559/SA2/E/NGO/7111</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving access to protected education environments for affected students in Ehsem Sub-District</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MWL proposed project seeks to provide protective education environment opportunities to vulnerable children (both boys and girls) in Ehsem Sub-District (Ariha district Idelb Governorate) as a response to the ongoing conflict, by availing inclusive protective learning spaces, through provision fuel for heating (diesel) to ensure that no children absent or drop out of schools&apos; due to severe cold weather and to protect the children from physical health effect. Because the selected area is very cold and Directorate of Education has no economic capacity to provision the heating fuel.
Ultimately, the communities in these areas shall have some measure of education access to ensure continuity of education.
MWL proposed project aim to support education facilities through provision of amenities (fuel for heating, etc.), as well as winterization kit for children in schools. MWL proposed project will provision the fuel for 46 school, (707) class room, that including 17.111 children (8.205 boys 8.905 girls) and 1.265 Teachers (882 Men , 383 Women) in Ehsem Sub-District. The fuel will cover three months of schools` heating needs, and provision Winterization Kits for 4.806 children (2.395 boys 2411 girls) consist of IDPS (479 boys 482 girls) and Host Community (1.916 boys 1.929 girls) for most vulnerable communities in Ehsem Sub-District. The fuel will cover three months of schools` heating needs. While these interventions represent more temporary than long term interventions.
MWL proposed project will supporting the rehabilitation of winterization like stoves and accessories, and fuel tanks. MWL will consider the protection mainstreaming as a priority by distributing fire extinguishers, first aid kit and communication material that sensitization about the fuel amp fire risks to protect themselves from any accident.
The distribution of Fuel will target 14 community in Ehsem sub-district (Ehsem, Balyun, Kansafra, Marata, Bsames, Arnaba, Balshun, Abdita, Ablin, Bara, Marayan, Jousef, Maghara, DeirSunbol), and winterization kits will target 5 most vulnerable community (Marata, Bsames, Balshun, Abdita, Jousef) in Ehsem sub-district.
The distribution of fuel and winterization kits will be through Voucher Scheme to ensure the safety and security for the children amp schools, prevent the fraud amp corruption in procurement process, and increases the resilience of local markets.
MWL has a good experience in design, developing and implementing education projects inside Syria Pre-University Support (Schools amp Education Directorates), University Education through full financial supporting (Running Cost, teacher incentive, administrative staff and expanding the laboratories) for 20 colleges (north of Syria) for Aleppo university, printing 45000 books in Rural Damascus and full support (Running Cost, teacher incentive, and administrative staff) for 28 schools in Aleppo. MWLA has good access and acceptance in selected area though implementation many projects before particularly in education. Last intervention was in Ehsem amp Marat al numan through distributing fuel for 50 Schools amp stationery for 90 schools. one of MWL biggest project had implemented last winter through distributing fuel in 9 province inside Syria that covering 2216 schools / 2090 classroom / 600 000 children for one month that funded though MWL USA office.
MWL will monitor the market during the project period to analyze the mechanisms of local markets supplying, check vouchers redeeming, ensure that the project does not disrupt markets systems and conduct spot checks visits at the local shops to discourage any forms of corruption. MWL will identify, verify and profile targeted schools through education directorate. MWL will also share its complaint mechanism to ensure that beneficiaries can quickly report any complaints that they have on a specific supplier to mitigate the risks of fraud. And all project activities will adhere to &#x201C;Do no harm&#x201D; approach.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-22">61660.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-22">184980.14</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="6305957799">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-09">7023.66</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-7111">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-22">246640.18</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303040643">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-05">147984.11</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303253869">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-03">98656.07</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
