<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-17/3559/RA2/WASH/NGO/7655</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency response to address the causes of water source contamination in South Idleb in two locations via sewage system rehabilitation and support most effected vulnerable people with lifesaving WASH intervention.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HIH through this proposed project aims to Respond to the emergency Situation in Joseph and Bara, as after receiving multiple reports from WASH Cluster and WHO in August 2017 indication the death of 4 of children from water Born diseases WBDs which were received from different Medical facilities in Ehsem sub-discrete. HIH in August and September after receiving those reports conducted water quality test by using portable Delagua kits to the water source in Joseph which is the Hometown of the 4 death cases and in Bara which is the source of the springs and wells of the trucked water to many locations in Ehsem sub-discrete like Joseph, Balun, and Bara itself.
The water tests result in Joseph and Bara showed traces to Bacterial infection. Indicating huge contamination to water sources, mainly from Sewage water leaks into the underground water body.
HIH after conducting KII with local council in Joseph and Bara started technical assessment to the sewage networks and drafted the scheme of the water networks.
HIH designed this project to rehabilitate the Sewage network in Josepha and Bara, by changing lines of the sewage networks which is causing the leaks. The project will replace the damaged pipes and the implementation will ensure the pipes to be protected by a layer of soft sand of thickness10 cm underneath it, and of thickness of 30 cm above the pipes, then reaching to road level by crushed stones and soft excavations outcomes. the project will replace the existed damaged concrete pipes with new concrete pipes. Concrete pipes will be connected together via concrete rings which will be plastered around the joining section of the pipes to Limit leaking risks. The total lengths of the sewage networks which will be rehabilitated in Joseph will be 1885 meters and in Bara will be 1570 meters.

The project will also conduct Hygiene promotion sessions in Schools and or collective centers and or informal settlements in the targeted locations, to raise the awareness of IDPs and children. The Hygiene Promotion Materials which will be used will be the standard IECL materials with special focus on water quality issues and water treatment in emergency situation. 

The project will also provide chlorinated trucked water to IDPS families and Female headed house from both host communities in Joseph and Bara for two months. The distribution of the trucked water will provide 40 liters per day per capita to the targeted families to meet the minimum context standard in daily water consumption. 

HIH will also conduct training sessions for both Local councils and trucked water well operators on the water augmentation technics by using powdered chlorine. The training session will provide details on the usage of powder chlorine and chlorine concertation in drinking water. The session will as well teach the trainees how to use pool testers to check the residual free chlorine value in the chlorinated water. 

HIH will allocate one team leader and two supervisors to supervise the rehabilitation works of the sewage networks, distribute the water tucking and facilitate and ensure the success of the project. Team leader will be in charge of communication with the respective local councils. 

The hygiene promotion sessions will be done by four hygiene promoters, who in the beginning will be trained on hygiene promotion Principles and presentation skills by a local capacity and training development agency.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-07-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-11">347430.07</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400243815">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-09">17900.3</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-7655">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-11">347430.07</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303118176">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-17">277944.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303458558-63">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-23">69486.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
