<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-17/3559/SA 2017/FS/NGO/5308</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting Livestock Owners in Idleb and Hama Governorates</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the Syrian crisis entering its 6th year, FSL sector has witnessed a notable decline (major food resources have changed from sustainable local production resources to insufficient emergency ones without the necessary quality to achieve food security, thus the number of people in need of food assistance has increased as the amount of available food items decreased while their quality dropped and their prices skyrocketed as a result of the sharp decline in the purchasing power of the local currency. According to (HNO2017), 1 in 3 people are food-insecure. Based on the above problem description, development projects have been adopted in an attempt to achieve stability in food security, as development projects contribute to the investment in natural resources and creation of employment opportunities as a step towards achieving food security. Civilians can rely on such projects to meet their food needs, even partially, instead of relying entirely on provided assistance which generally lacks continuity and can be impeded security- and accessibility-wise. In addition, such projects do not drain humanitarian aid resources which can be utilized during an emergency response. This project will target two districts, AlMara district (including Kafrnbel, Heish, Altamanaah and Sanjar Sub districts) in rural Idleb and Alsuqaylabiyah district (Madiq castle sub district) in rural Hama.

The project activities will provide the veterinarian coverage for about 50,000 sheep in the targeted locations. This number is based on the last survey conducted by the local council&#x2019;s agriculture offices IHR will implement four vaccination campaigns in the targeted where these activities will be implemented through a veterinarian center located in Kafr Ouied which will cover the needs for all nearby areas and a mobile clinic that will take care in the rest of the areas.

This clinic will act as the main center where it will provide assistance to the closest breeders in surrounding area for 4 hours every day and for the other 4 hours it will conduct field visits to the breeders in close distance according to a developed plan. In emergency cases the vet will amended the plane according to arising situation. In addition, the center will be supported with a mobile clinic that will reach to and provide vet services (including vaccination, treatment and training) to the sheep herders on a regular basis.

In addition, the project , through the vet center and the mobile clinic, will provide training and field sessions to the local herders in the area . these training will reach about 2000 herders in the targeted locations and will focus on the protection and sustaining of the livestock. The vet center will host the training in the center&apos;s location and the nearby area while specific field location will be holding the field ones - this can be standard spaces or barns that can set an example to other herders in the area.  

This project aims also to support the livelihoods and food security situation in the targeted areas to help secure their needs and reach the level where they used their resources and assets to increase livestock production. This will be achieved by supporting vulnerable and previous herders to raise livestock where the priority will be given to female-headed HHs to promote and support women&#x2019;s role and participation in the development of society. In Al-Madiq castle and Kafranbel sub districts IHR will be distributing 2 sheep for each vulnerable family as IHR will be targeting  the women by rate 30% minimum and those families will be supported by fodder sufficient for 5 months so every breeders will receive 300 KG of fodder while receiving necessary treatment and vaccinations by the veterinarian center or the mobile clinic.
   
IHR will be conducting a number of training for the grants recepients concerning the best methods to raise the livestock where the training will divided into both lectures and practical training field</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hama</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.13374200 36.76129100</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-22">201039.19</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-22">98871.73</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400244566">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-19">36552.2</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-5308">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-22">299910.92</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302675660">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-25">179946.55</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303288158">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-20">119964.37</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
