<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-17/3559/SA 2017/NFI/NGO/5350</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rehabilitating, Repairing and Upgrading Damaged Private Houses for Returnees  IDPs People in Bazagha and Qabasin communities.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SRO seeks through this project to meet the needs of people through provision of housing rehabilitation services for returnees amp IDPs people for both owners and tenants and this depend on the needs where the project and the beneficiaries criteria will be advertised and explained within the community and Silk Road program team will receive an application from the population. This project aims to improve the shelter and living condition for approximately 500 HHs within the targeted location, who are in acquit need for shelter or shelter rehabilitation services after their homes were destroyed partially and the selection criteria will divide into 2 part the first one will be technical criteria which mean we will target the damaged houses where the damage is slight and medium and less than 30% in addition to the vulnerability criteria which will be used to select beneficiaries, including prioritization of female-headed HHs, HHs with disabled or elderly family members, HHs comprising of more than six members, and HHs where the majority of working-aged members are unemployed.All activities of the project will implement in Bazagha and Qabasin communities, where we will target 250HHs in each community, and the priority will for the returnees and IDPs people so, Silk Road will target 500 HHs in rehabilitation works for private shelters and 100 individuals in training. The project activities will implement/coordinate between two offices &#x2013;Silk Road Turkey office in Gaziantep, and Silk Road Office in Al-Bab district and this project will start with signing an agreement with the local council and conducting meetings on the level of directors to review the project documents, roles, and responsibilities of the parties, Silk Road team, and local council.
Silk Road will start actual shelter activities with the humanitarian standards and Sphere standards in the shelter sector with identification of the beneficiaries where SRO program team will receive an application from the population and then the field survey will aim to verification for the registered beneficiaries with BOQ&#x2019;s to ensure the selection criteria(technical and vulnerability) and will enable the engineers to identify basic and essential needs of each shelter in the rehabilitation process ,and the type of service that will be provided for each shelter also this activity will be important to apply the criteria to benefit from the project. After that SRO will select the contractor and construction service providers by announcing through its website and its page on Facebook and local councils and all available media to implement the tenders or quotations according to SRO&apos;s procurement, technical conditions approved and financial policies, then a final beneficiaries list will produce where the vulnerability of the population and technical criteria for rehabilitation of shelter is confirmed.After that, we will start rehabilitation works for eligible houses/beneficiaries which mainly includes, as our SRO plans Supply and install Concrete work ,Block works, Plastering, Carpentry, and Joinery works, Metalworks,Electrical works, Sanitary and Plumbing works, and Supply and install 500 Galvanized steel water storage tank 1m3 (for more details see the BoQ).Each rehabilitated shelter will hand over to their owners according to official documents in the presence of representatives from the local council. 
It is estimated that each of the households is in need of 450-600$ worth of materials and work to fit the SPHERE minimum standards.Silk Road will work on the capacity building of the responsible parties (Local Council), we seek through this trainings to train responsible parties on the modus operandi of a field survey professionally for damaged shelter and buildings and establish a database to collect information and archives them for use in future projects. Also, Silk Road will ensure that each of the above-mentioned activities and works will be always under continuous monitoring</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-24">362665.8</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-5350">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-24">362665.8</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302695145">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-05">217599.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302982146">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-06">145066.32</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
