<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-17/3559/SA2/P/NGO/7066</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contributing to Improving the Protective environment and access to Comprehensive Child Protection Support for conflict-affected Syrians</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Orange, in partnership with Syria Relief (SR), aim at improving the protective environment and access to comprehensive child protection support for conflict-affected Syrians in Idleb and Aleppo governorates.
Orange and SR will harness their experience in humanitarian and development programming, in particular with Child Protection service delivery and will mobilize their technical expertise to provide proper response and preventive services for children, girls and boys, in northern Syria. The expected outcomes of the project will be: 
1) Reduced child protection concerns through improving access to response and preventive services girls and boys at risk from violence, abuse, neglect and exploitation 
2) Enhanced access to protective environment for girls and boys through the provision of focused and non-focused psychosocial activities, awareness raising, skill building through static community hubs and mobile outreach teams
3) Enhanced local capacity to provide child protection services through building the capacity of child protection teams, service providers including school personnel, staff from other organizations, and the establishment of local child protection committees/ networks and building their capacity on Child Protection.

The project aims to reach about 2,875 unique beneficiaries, 1,200 through five static child friendly spaces, 1,000 through two mobile child protection teams, 150 through case management, 75 through capacity building, 300 through awareness raising and 175 through parenting sessions.

The project will take the form of technical partnership with SR, where both teams implement the activities together and provide technical capacity to Orange team during implementation.

SR will be sub-grantee partner to Orange for this proposed project. The main responsibility of SR will be leading the implementation of the project and provide technical child protection capacity building for Orange to implement child protection interventions and strengthen long-term capacity of the organization to deliver quality child protection actions. SR will enhance Orange&#x2019;s team on three key components 
1- Assessing and designing child protection programming according to child protection minimum standards and accumulated experience implementing child protection programming
2- Implementing child protection programming through embedding SR&#x2019;s Child Protection field teams and technical insights from SR&#x2019;s senior programme team. 
3- Ensuring adequate monitoring and compliance of UNOCHA&#x2019;s rules and regulation with regard to any related project management, monitoring, evaluation, procurement, logistics, finance and human resources management of the project fund. 
SR will be leading the implementation of the project activities along with Orange through its Technical Programme Manager, Project Manager, Officers, Team Leaders and MEAL Officer provide technical support, mentoring and coaching and on-the-job trainings and oversight throughout the project cycle working together with the Orange staff to design and conduct needs assessments, design and implement child protection activities, identify suppliers and support procurement processes, and monitor progress of project activities. SR Protection Project Manager and their staff will support Orange in designing and modifying the Bills of Quantities (BoQs). SR&#x2019;s staff will be involved in all the project activities and processes to ensure quality activities delivery. 
Overall, there will be two parts of implementation and supervision, one management and technical capacity oriented from SR, and a second from Orange. The implementation of main project activities will be carried out mutually by Orange and SR staff who will lead the child protection teams in the field. The project staff will be trained by experienced staff on different child protection topics. SR will support Orange to monitor and produce monitoring and performance reports to monitor and ensure quality.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-22">30994.8</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-22">219029.96</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-7066">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-22">250024.76</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303040644">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-05">125012.38</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303441177">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-12">125012.38</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
