<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-16/HSD20/RE/RMS/UN/4152</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency RH and GBV Response to South Sudanese Refugees in Al Nimir, East Darfur</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New arrivals of South Sudanese refugees were reported in East Darfur as a result of outbreak of fighting in Raja town, Western Bahr al Ghazal state which erupted on 15 June. Unverified reports indicate more than 7,000 families were displaced as a result of the fighting, but that some have returned. The population previously in Abu Sinadira has dispersed to various different locations including, El Ferdous town, Ed Daein town and Raja old camp (also Ed Daein town). 
While the exact figure is unknown the Inter-Agency Initial Rapid Assessment (HAC, UNHCR, OCHA, UNICEF, WFP, IOM, UMCOR, SRCS and ARC) conducted on 3 July to Abu Sinaidira highlighted that the identified priority needs were in the areas of protection, nutrition, food, water and sanitation, and shelter. As per updated information provided by UNHCR on 9 October 2016, there are now around 8,400 South Sudanese in Al Ferdous and Raja and this population will be relocated to a newly developed site &#x2013; Al Nimir. There were 4 nurses, 2 mid wives, a dentist, EPI technician and 4 health assistants among the South Sudanese refugees. Al Nimir is around 13 kms away from ElDaein and has very little infrastructure or resources to respond to the needs of the newly arrived South Sudanese refugees. Basic infrastructure including for health will be constructed while referral for more complicated health cases would still need to happen toward the general hospital in ElDaein. 
UNFPA was tasked to provide the core pipeline materials for reproductive health and personal hygiene kits. UNFPA will procure various reproductive health emergency kits to be used at community and primary health care level in Al Nimir. A set of kits for complicated deliveries requiring caesarian section or other surgical interventions at referral level will be provided to the hospital in ElDaein to be able to provide life-saving assistance. Health service provision should not discriminate between refugees and host community and thus the items would benefit both groups while a small part of the PHKs should also be distributed to host communities where feasible and appropriate.   
While UNFPA had received funding under the Core Pipelines to provide RH Emergency Kits and Personal Hygiene Kits (PHKs) to IDPs and refugees respectively, no extra funds were available to accommodate the needs of the newly arrived South Sudanese refugees in East Darfur. UNCHR also confirmed the presence of Global Aid Hand (GAH) and ARC to provide GBV prevention and response and RH services. This project, hence, limits itself to procurement of RH kits and PHKs, UNFPA does not currently have any staff presence in East Darfur. Considering the importance for technical assistance, UNFPA will recruit and deploy an RH/GBV technical officer to be working alongside the Ministry of Health and in close coordination with UNHCR to support the provision of RH services especially with regard to monitoring the RH response and providing technical support for the efficient utilization of RH kits. The technical officer will also follow-up with GAH on the monitoring of distribution of PHKs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elke Mayrhofer</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Programme Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0912167715</telephone>
   <email>mayrhofer@unfpa.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU27">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">East Darfur</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.37827470 24.90422080</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-30">19155.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-30">57785.82</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-27">76941.34</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-4152">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-30">76941.34</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
