<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-16/HSD20/S1/P/UN/1715</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social support for extremely vulnerable displaced people and community-based protection in South Kordofan and Blue Nile</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to ensure that vulnerable people (or people with specific needs - PSN) among communities affected by displacement in Roseires and Bau (Blue Nile State) and Dilling and Delami (South Kordofan State) are able to access essential services, assistance or utilities, in conditions of dignity and non-discrimination. The project foresees two approaches. Social workers will be deployed in the targeted areas, to assess the vulnerability of people with specific needs, and their capacity to access relevant services/assistance. Based on these assessments and a list of vulnerability criteria endorsed by the targeted communities, the social workers will be responsible for providing direct support to PSN, through information, councellling, accompaniment, and advocacy with local communities or service/humanitarian aid providers. In a small number of cases, social workers will be able to provide direct material assistance to extremely vulnerable people, for example walking aid, transportation fees for urgent needs to access essential services, NFIs, etc. The focus will be primarily on people newly displaced (from 2015 mostly) and their host communities. 

In parallel, the social workers will strengthen the capacities of the targeted communities to support their vulnerable members. Based on a mapping of existing community structures, and through a participatory process, social workers will design a plan of action, so as to ensure that these structures enable key components of the population (based on the gender and age composition of the communities, and other vulnerability criterias) to participate in decisions and their implementation. Support provided to these community structures will include facilitation and mobilization, training and awareness raising on key issues, support to community infrastructures (meeting/multisectoral places). Also, small scale projects will be implemented by the communities with the view to improve the well-being and dignity of their vulnerable members. These projects will provide an opportunity for communities to mobilise its members inclusively. The impact of the project will be measured by assessing the communities&apos; perception of their improved and sustainable capacity to provide essential support to vulnerable people and ensure their access to basic services in conditions of dignity.

The project will be implemented through the Ministries of Social Affairs in the two targeted States, with the view to strengthen the humanitarian capacity and expertise of these institutions. Through the project, operational policies/standards for the protection of vulnerable people in line with international standards will be promoted and disseminated among  key social/humanitarian governmental stakeholders. The choice of the Ministries of Social Affairs as partners for this project will also contribute to strengthen acceptance of protection activities by the Sudanese authorities, and thereby also facilitate access for other humanitarian partners implementing similar activities in the targeted States.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Social Affairs Blue Nile</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Social Development Women amp; Child Affairs South Kordofan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-21" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-21" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Steven O&apos;Brien</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">External Relations Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0912179443</telephone>
   <email>OBRIEN@UNHCR.ORG</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Blue Nile</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.58600780 34.15319470</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Kordofan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.19901920 29.41793240</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-05-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-05">116648.82</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-05">73755.54</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-1715">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-05">190404.36</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-07">190404.36</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
