<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-16/HSD20/RE/P/NGO/3670</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Services and community support to vulnerable new IDPs with special needs from Jebel Marra in South Darfur</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project proposal is designed based on the Rapid Inter-agency needs assessment findings conducted in Otash IDP camp (July 2016) and Kass supported with OCHA and IOM verification figures for July 2016 including ASSIST and ElRuhman field assessments findings, which all confirms protection needs among vulnerable people in newly displaced communities from Jebel Marra.

Based on average estimates used by the Protection Sector in Darfur, the project will ensure that vulnerable people among new IDPs from Jebel Marra in South Darfur (an estimated 15 percent of the total IDP population) receive counseling,  and that the extremely vulnerable IDPs (about 2% of the IDPs) receive direct protection support. The project will also ensure that  15% of women and girls at reproductive age receive personal hygiene kits (PHK).. In total 8472 persons with special needs (PSNs) out of 25930 newly displaced IDPs from Jebel Marra Crisis in South Darfur mainly in Kass, Otash Camp, Mershing, Menawashi, and El-Malam by undertaking the following

Provision of direct protection material support to 600 extremely vulnerable IDPs mainly Persons with Special Needs, The project will also provide support to community structures, to as to ensure that  communities protect  vulnerable members. Three community structures will be supported with the rehabilitation of exiting community meeting places or construction of temporary meeting places) or equipment. Also, 3 small-scale community projects will be implemented to promote community mobilization. Nine  awareness raising events on eg. GBV, IDP rights, Mine-risk education, peaceful coexistence, HIV) will be conducted . 

In Otash camp, the project will support the Women Empowerment Centre , through the El Ruhama, so as to provide a protective environment for women at risk among the newly arrived IDPs in the camp.  Through the centre, 40 male and female IDPs will be trained on GBV prevention and response, identify and referral of cases to service providers, conduct outreach for 3055 community members to raise awareness on GBV prevention during the 16 days of activism, conduct rapid assessment on GBV through h 6 focus group discussion, ,  and provide basic counseling and skill development.

The project aims to use  a community-based approach to  promote the active involvement of people of concern, The project will be conducted in a conflict-sensitive manner, with due attention to conflicts as causes of original displacement,  and relations with surrounding communities and local authorities, and other IDP communities in existing camps. Such fora, e.g. in the form of committees, are not only intended to become independent and self-sustained after the project, their existence is also to be connected to concrete projects that can give momentum to its work and translate efforts into tangible and lasting results. However, the core strength of these community-based efforts will come from the identification and effective integration of persons with special needs, especially in relation to age, gender and diversity, designed to work towards an increase of livelihood and other options sustaining the effects of individual assistance given to PSN in form of this project.

Therefore ASSIST will support the reactivation and training of community-based protection committees to reduce Persons with special needs &#x2019; vulnerability and promote a favorable social care environment, enhanced by supporting 3 community projects to be designed and selected by the communities. The project staff will also conduct community mobilization to ensure social care protection through support to women center and community meetings places in Otash camp and provide skills training and livelihoods options for vulnerable Persons with Special Needs, including awareness raising on GBV, Mine Risk Education (MRE).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">El-Ruhama</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Voluntary Humanitarian Assistance Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Voluntary Humanitarian Assistance Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mubarak Abdalla</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection Focal Person</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249-913888817</telephone>
   <email>kafei124@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Darfur</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.64886390 24.90422080</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-09-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-10">83054.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-10">188618.68</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-3670">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-10">271673</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Voluntary Humanitarian Assistance Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="188912">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-17">108669</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Voluntary Humanitarian Assistance Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="0000">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-09">0</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Voluntary Humanitarian Assistance Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="192955">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-09">163004</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Voluntary Humanitarian Assistance Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
