<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-14273A0101-SDN-16010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">V&#xE4;rldsbanken Sudan Family Support Program 2020-22</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Bank Sudan Family Support Program 2020-22</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Development Objective

The objective of the intervention is to &quot;deliver cash transfer support to Sudanese households affected by expected economic reforms and other short-term shocks&quot;.&#xA0;The contribution will support the Government-led Sudan Family Support Programme, and intends to help create fiscal and political space for economic reforms.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Bank has applied to Sida for funding to carry out the &quot;Sudan Family Support Program&quot; (SFSP) during the period 2020-2022. The objective of the intervention is to &quot;deliver cash transfer support to Sudanese households affected by expected economic reforms and other short-term shocks&quot;. Under the SFSP, 80 % of the Sudanese population will receive cash transfers (5 USD a month over 12 months), in order to create political and fiscal space to implement the economic reforms. The economic reforms, primarily lifting of subsidies on fuel, are expected to have an adverse impact on the Sudanese economy, and the cash transfers under the SFSP will mitigate the economic shock of the subsidy removal. Further, the SFSP will also constitute an important step for Sudan towards debt relief under the Heavily Indebted Poor Countries (HIPC) Initiative, and will also help stabilize the Sudanese economy. Sida&apos;s support to the SFSP will also be an important endorsement of Sudan&apos;s current transition towards democracy.  

The World Bank will implement the Sudan Family Support Program together with the Ministry of Finance and Economic Planning and the Digital Transformation Agency. 

The total budget of the intervention is 2.07 billion USD, out of which the World Bank contributes with approximately 410 million USD. Donors have currently pledged around 415 million USD to the SFSP, and further funding rounds are to be expected. Other donors include Germany, the UK, the EU, Norway, Ireland, Italy, France, Spain, Canada, the Netherlands, Malta, the UAE and Saudi Arabia. 1.9 billion of the total budget will be forwarded from the World Bank to the Ministry of Finance and Economic Planning. Sida plans to support the Sudan Family Support Program with a contribution of 200 MSEK. In addition, approximately 25.5 MSEK from Sida&apos;s, the Ministry for Foreign Affairs, and the Ministry for Environment&apos;s respective Donor Balance Accounts have been reallocated to SFSP. The Swedish contribution to the SFSP thus totals approximately 225.5 MSEK.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">V&#xE4;rldsbanken har ans&#xF6;kt till Sida om finansiering f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra &apos;Sudan Family Support Program&apos; (SFSP) under perioden 2020-2022. Insatsens m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att &quot;distribuera kontantst&#xF6;d till sudanesiska hush&#xE5;ll negativt p&#xE5;verkade av kommande ekonomiska reformer och andra chocker&quot;. Inom ramen f&#xF6;r SFSP kommer 80 % av den sudanesiska befolkningen att mottaga kontantst&#xF6;d (5 US-dollar per m&#xE5;nad &#xF6;ver tolv m&#xE5;nader), med m&#xE5;let att skapa politiska och ekonomiska f&#xF6;rus&#xE4;ttningar f&#xF6;r att implementera de ekonomiska reformerna. De ekonomiska reformerna, framf&#xF6;rallt eliminering av br&#xE4;nslesubventioner, f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntas ha negativa konsekvenser p&#xE5; den sudanesiska ekonomin. Kontantst&#xF6;det under SFSP kommer d&#xE4;rmed att mildra de ekonomiska konsekvenserna av n&#xE4;mnda eliminering av subventioner. St&#xF6;det till SFSP kommer &#xE4;ven utg&#xF6;ra en viktig milstolpe f&#xF6;r Sudans str&#xE4;van att n&#xE5; skuldavskrivningar inom ramen f&#xF6;r HIPC-initiativet (&quot;Heavily Indebted Poor Countries Initiative&quot;), och kommer &#xE4;ven att vara ett viktigt led f&#xF6;r att stabilisera Sudans ekonomi. Slutligen bed&#xF6;ms Sidas st&#xF6;d till SFSP vara ett starkt och viktigt st&#xE4;llningstagande f&#xF6;r Sudans demokratiska transition.

SFSP kommer att implementeras av V&#xE4;rldsbanken i samarbete med Sudans Finansministerium och Sudans Myndighet f&#xF6;r Digital Utveckling.

Den totala budgeten f&#xF6;r SFSP uppg&#xE5;r till 2,07 miljarder US-dollar. V&#xE4;rldsbanken &#xE4;mnar bidra med uppskattningsvis 410 miljoner US-dollar och bilaterala givare har gett utf&#xE4;stelser om 415 miljoner US-dollar. Ytterligare finansieringsrundor &#xE4;r att v&#xE4;nta fram&#xF6;ver. Andra givare inkluderar Tyskland, Storbritannien, EU, Norge, Irland, Italien, Frankrike, Spanien, Kanada, Nederl&#xE4;nderna, Malta, F&#xF6;renade Arabemiraten och Saudiarabien. 1,9 miljarder US-dollar av den totala budgeten kommer att vidaref&#xF6;rmedlas fr&#xE5;n V&#xE4;rldsbanken till Finansministeriet. Sidas planerade st&#xF6;d till SFSP omfattar 200 miljoner kronor. I till&#xE4;gg har Sida, Milj&#xF6;departementet och Utrikesdepartementet &#xF6;verf&#xF6;rt totalt cirka 25,5 miljoner kronor fr&#xE5;n givarbalanskonton hos V&#xE4;rldsbanken till SFSP. Det totala svenska bidraget till SFSP uppg&#xE5;r d&#xE4;rmed till cirka 225,5 miljoner kronor.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-26" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2029-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan (the)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="1.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3 - Implement nationally appropriate social protection systems and measures for all, including floors, and by 2030 achieve substantial coverage of the poor and the vulnerable.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">1.3 - Inf&#xF6;ra nationellt l&#xE4;mpliga system och &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder f&#xF6;r socialt skydd f&#xF6;r alla, inklusive grundskydd, och senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att de omfattar en v&#xE4;sentlig andel av de fattiga och de utsatta.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="10.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10.4 - Adopt policies, especially fiscal, wage and social protection policies, and progressively achieve greater equality.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">10.4 - Besluta om politik, s&#xE4;rskilt finans-, l&#xF6;ne- och socialskyddspolitik, och successivt uppn&#xE5; &#xF6;kad j&#xE4;mlikhet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">14658457.930225741</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">7578495.726894332</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">14658457.93022574</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">7578495.726894331</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-26">21716233.970704</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-28">14658457.930225741</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-28">7578495.726894332</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/sudan/14273_034106-20VarldsbankenSudanFamilySupportProgram2020-20222762930_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut V&#xE4;rldsbanken STARS  Sudan</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/sudan/14273_SwedishAA26.09.2020.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Avtal V&#xE4;rldsbanken STARS Sudan</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/sudan/14273_Amendment2ndsigned.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Avtals&#xE4;ndring 2 V&#xE4;rldsbanken STARS Sudan</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/sudan/14273_Amendment1stsigned.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Avtals&#xE4;ndring V&#xE4;rldsbanken STARS Sudan</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This report is based on the progress report for the World Bank (WB) Sudan STARS (Sudan Transition And Recovery Support) Trust Fund. The progress report covers the period from when STARS was first launched in May 2020 up to December 2021.

After the military coup on 25 October, the WB triggered their &apos;Operational Policies 7.30&apos; (OP 7.30) clause on dealing with de facto governments, and have since paused all operations in Sudan, including the STARS Trust Fund. The decision on when/if STARS will resume operations will be based on an internal WB assessment. This assessment will be initiated once a permanent government is in place. 

This CoP will cover three sections. Firstly, a recapitulation of the progress made from when the Administrative Agreement between Sida and the WB was signed in September 2020 up to the military coup in October 2021. The second section will focus on the current state of STARS and FSP, including a discussion around ways forward. The third and last section focuses on lessons learnt and reflections from the process, including the economic reforms.

Progress from Sep -20 to Oct -21

In September 2020, Sida entered into an agreement of 200 MSEK with the World Bank, earmarked for the Family Support Program (FSP). The FSP is a cash transfer programme, providing $5 a month over a 12 months period for the poorest 80 % (in total 32.5m people) of the Sudanese population. The FSP was initially costed at $2.02bn, and would in equal parts be funded by bilateral donors and the WB. 

The Swedish contribution to FSP served several parallel purposes. However, the paramount objective was to support the civilian-led government&apos;s ambitious economic reform package, including the facilitation of a record-breaking debt relief package under the HIPC initiative, amounting to more than $60bn. Supporting this endeavour would underpin Sudan&apos;s (at the time) nascent democratic transition. In addition, FSP had important secondary objectives, including providing a financial cushion for the short-term economic shock expected to follow on the economic reforms, as well as strengthening Sudan&apos;s financial systems.

Sweden signed an agreement with the WB for support to the FSP on 26 September 2020 - ahead of WB&apos;s internal project approval. In line with internal regulations, the WB require a minimum level of funding to be secured prior to board approval of new projects. On 8 October 2020, bilateral donors had committed sufficient funding, and the project was subsequently declared effective on 7 December 2020. However, due to a delay in the exchange rate reform, the FSP was only launched on 24 February 2021. (The discrepancy between the official and parallel exchange rates would have reduced the cost-efficiency of the FSP by 80%. Thus, donors together with the WB made the exchange rate unification a requirement prior to the launch of the FSP.)

Additionally, due to an initial funding shortfall, the WB decided to divide the roll-out of the FSP into four phases, based on the below geography and timeframe:

-Phase 1: 4 pilot states for the initial six months (400 MUSD)

-Phase 2: An additional 12 states for the initial six months (420 MUSD)

-Phase 3: The remaining 4 states for the initial six months (300 MUSD)

-Phase 4: All 18 states, for the remaining six months (1.19bn USD)

In reality, the WB never expected phase 4 to be funded, and have instead been advocating for a transition towards a more focused permanent social safety net. As of March 2022, phase 1 and 2 have been launched, whereas another $300m are still required to fund and subsequently launch phase 3. Phase 4 still remains completely unfunded. Before the military coup, several donors (chiefly the US, but also NO, DE and NL) were in advanced talks around contributing the required funding for phase 3 to be fully financed. 

When the programme was paused shortly after the 25 October military coup, the FSP had made some significant progress. This progress includes a roll-out in 14 of Sudan&apos;s 18 states, enrollment of 9.6 million people, with at least a first disbursement reaching around 4.8 million people. By 25 October, a total of around $80m had been paid to beneficiary households, of which 37 % were women-headed. Importantly, the FSP had recently seen an exponential progress in the roll-out after a slow start. 

To date, a total of $760m have been committed to the FSP; $350m from bilateral donors and $410m from the WB&apos;s IDA allocation. An additional $137m of donor funds allocated to STARS are yet to be committed to FSP (phase 3 needs to be funded in its entirety for these funds to be committed). At the time of the pause, $181m of the $760m had been disbursed to the Government&apos;s Designated Account (DA), out of which $101m had been spent on FSP operations. Thus, a balance of $80m remains on the Government&apos;s DA. 

Financial status in summary:

-A total of $487.9m of bilateral funding have been allocated to STARS, earmarked for FSP.

-Out of which $350m have been committed to FSP through an agreement between the WB and the Government of Sudan.

-A balance of $137 in uncommitted funds thus remains in the STARS TF.

-An additional $410m have been committed from the WB&apos;s IDA allocation, taking the total amount of committed funds to $750m. 

-Out of these $750m, $181m have been disbursed to the Government&apos;s DA ($100.6 of WB&apos;s funds and $80.8m from bilateral donors&apos; funding)

-Out of which $101m have been spent on FSP operations, with $80m remaining on government accounts.

In which accounts donors&apos; respective funds are located is currently unknown. Any refund is done according to the pro rata principle.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="14273" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061002" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1600000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Sudan 2018-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Sudan 2018-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
