<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="XOF" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="FR" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SN-NINEA-621108990A0-CI-Awareness workshop of editors-in-chief and/or publication directors of media mainstream</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SN-NINEA-621108990A0" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Panos Institute West Africa</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Raising awareness workshop of editors-in-chief and/or publication directors of media mainstream in Cote d&apos;Ivoire</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">(i) increasing their sense of their social responsibilities towards the women&#x2019;s rights of expression, their female audiences rights to access to information; (ii) developing their knowledge about what gender sensitive journalism is; iii) strengthening their capacity to coach their journalists on gender-sensitive journalism, (iv) disseminating the gender sensitivity methodology of their teams within the editorial newsroom</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13 editors-in-chief from 13 mainstream media</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As results. 13 editors-in-chief sensitized on gender sensitiv reporting. 85% of them had a better knowledge of the general framework of women&apos;s rights in C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire. All the participant significantly improved the level of knowledge and understanding of gender-sensitive journalism. They validated the follow-up plan for productions produced by journalists during their training</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">The training workshop was conducted by journalism and gender experts, and had two components: A thematic session was held about the general context of Violence against women and women political participation in Cote d&apos;Ivoire; and a technical section on gender-sensitive journalism, its issues and characteristics.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Ministery of Foreign Affairs of The Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SN-NINEA-621108990A0" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Panos Institute West Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CI" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
