<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="XOF" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="FR" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SN-NINEA-621108990A0-SN-Promoting GSJ-in-unbrella-media-organisation</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SN-NINEA-621108990A0" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Panos Institute West Africa</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting the internal institutional sensitivity and capacities of he Community Radio umbrella association in Senegal to GSJ</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(i) developing the capacity radios members of the Union for critical analysis, under a gender perspective, of content produced by radios, (ii) contributing to the emergence of producers (and consumers) of critical media content on gender approach (media litteracy), and (iii) sustainably strengthening institutional capacities within the URAC, to the critical analysis of the gender dimension in the content produce by its members.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">12 Journalists, representatives of URAC</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The sessions, facilitated by PIWA staff, were divided into two components: a component on understanding gender-sensitive journalism and its characteristics, and another component on methodology and tools for analyzing radio content. Practical exercises were organized to enable the participants to better understand on one hand the fields of application of gender-sensitive journalism, and on the other hand the analysis grid, as well as its weighting system</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the training: - all participants (100%) know the different criteria and gender indicators for the analysis of media content. - The 12 participants of the workshop can now evaluate the magazines or the debates using a grid of criticizing analysis, and based on globally accepted criteria and indicators</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Ministery of Foreign Affairs of The Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SN-NINEA-621108990A0" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Panos Institute West Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-26" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" vocabulary-uri="http://www.panos-ao.org"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
