<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="XOF" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="FR" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SN-NINEA-621108990A0-ML-SUPPORT OF TRAINED RADIO FOR THE PRODUCTION OF CONTENT</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SN-NINEA-621108990A0" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Panos Institute West Africa</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Technical and financial support of trained radio for the production of content in Mali</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As Results: - 18 content (9 magazines and 9 debates) were realized by 9 radios, on the cohort of 15 having benefited from the training, - 70% of the topics developed in productions were related to violence against women and girls in Mali, and more specifically the schooling of girls, and domestic violence. - 58 people participated both in magazines and debates. Among these participants, 35.19% were CSOs&#x2019; representatives, 22.22% were decisions-makers, 7% were religious leaders, and 27.28% were school supervisors. - Local radios are raising public debate between local authorities (mayors and sub-divisional officers), teaching staff and grassroots organizations, by initiating discussions on the challenges of schooling girls in rural Mali. - The participation of local decision-makers in these public conversations demonstrates their interest in addressing with local organizations delicate or even taboo issues, such as girls&apos; education and domestic violence, in a context dominated by the radical conservatism that advocates inequality between girls and boys, men and women</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the framework of the partnership with Studio Tamani, local radio stations trained in March 2019 continued to produce magazine and debate-based productions about women in Mali. This is a total of 30 broadcasts (15 debates and 15 magazines) that were to be produced by the 15 radio stations benefiting from the training.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Ministery of Foreign Affairs of The Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SN-NINEA-621108990A0" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Panos Institute West Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-20" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ML" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" vocabulary-uri="http://www.panos-ao.org"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
