<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="XOF" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="FR" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SN-NINEA-621108990A0-CI-CSOS&apos;-IN-MEDIAMEANSTREAM</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SN-NINEA-621108990A0" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Panos Institute West Africa</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training of WCSOs on traditional media use in Cote d&apos;Ivoire</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results: - 80% had a better knowledge of issues related to the context of women&apos;s rights in C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire. - The 15 participants have a better understanding of women&apos;s rights issues - including the contribution of women in public life and the role and mobilization of women in politics, as well as economic issues. They are therefore able to document and argue in radio and TV debates on issues of violence against women and women&apos;s participation in public life.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthen the capacity of these CSOs to promote and protect women&apos;s rights and to engage a conversation through mainstream media on women&apos;s issues, including violence against women and political participation, with decisionmakers</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">The workshop was built on two components: (i) a thematic session, focused on the women&apos;s rights national laws and policies, and the national, regional and international instruments provisioned to promote and to protect women&#x2019;s and girls&#x2019; rights. (ii) The technical component, focused on the experiences of the participants in the traditional media, and the attitudes to have during a radio or television debate on the other hand.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and mainstream CSOs&apos; Leaders</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Ministery of Foreign Affairs of The Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SN-NINEA-621108990A0" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Panos Institute West Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-21" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CI" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" vocabulary-uri="http://www.panos-ao.org"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
