<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="XOF" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="FR" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SN-NINEA-621108990A0-ML-CSOs&apos;-in-MediaMeanstream</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SN-NINEA-621108990A0" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Panos Institute West Africa</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training of WCSOs on traditional media use in Mali</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- 98% of participants had a better knowledge and understanding of the legal framework for the protection of women&apos;s rights in Mali. - 93% of the participants are able to participate with relevance in the TV and radio debates.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthen the capacity of these CSOs to promote and protect women&apos;s rights and to engage a conversation through mainstream media on women&apos;s issues, including violence against women and political participation, with decisionmakers</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WCSOs&#x2019; leaders</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">he agenda of the workshop was built on two components: (i) a thematic section focused on national laws and policies to promote women&apos;s rights, and regional and international instruments for the promotion and protection of the rights of women and girls. The technical section, focused on the experiences of participants in traditional media, and the contribution of the media to the promotion of women&apos;s rights. A session on media literacy through a review of the print media and exchanges around Social Media, fake news and digital security</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Ministery of Foreign Affairs of The Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SN-NINEA-621108990A0" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Panos Institute West Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-17" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ML" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" vocabulary-uri="http://www.panos-ao.org"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
