<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://data.mcc.gov/" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:mcc="https://data.mcc.gov/ns#" xmlns:usg="http://foreignassistance.gov/iati#">
  <iati-identifier>US-18-GE2-2750BXCOMD-EDU</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-18" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Georgia II - Education Project: this project aims to improve the quality of general education through rehabilitation of deteriorating schools, training for educators and school managers and support for education assessments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-8" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Account - Georgia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States of America</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="GE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Georgia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://data.mcc.gov/evaluations/index.php/catalog/151">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving General Education Quality</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/evalbrief-121420-geo-ii-stem">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upgrading STEM Education at Universities in Georgia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-GE2-2750BXCOMD" type="1"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-GE2-2750BXCOMD-EDU-0394" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-GE2-2750BXCOMD-EDU-0395" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-GE2-2750BXCOMD-EDU-0396" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-GE2-2750BXCOMD-MON &amp; EVAL" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-GE2-2750BXCOMD-NA" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-GE2-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-GE2-2750BXCOMD-TEP" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-GE2-2750BXCOMD-VOC EDU" type="3"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PIA Schedule 2.2 a (i): Prior to the initial Disbursement of Program Funding for the initial tranche of schools to be rehabilitated under the Improved Learning Environment Infrastructure Activity, ESIDA must have hired or designated at least one permanent, dedicated and technically qualified staff member, satisfactory to MCC, to develop and implement the forthcoming School O&amp;M Plan.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PIA Schedule 2.2 a (ii): Prior to the initial Disbursement of Program Funding for the initial tranche of schools to be rehabilitated under the Improved Learning Environment Infrastructure Activity, MCA-Georgia must have hired an O&amp;M consultant to coordinate development of the eventual School O&amp;M Plan.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PIA Schedule 2.2 b (i): Prior to the initial Disbursement of Program Funding for the second tranche of schools to be rehabilitated under the Improved Learning Environment Infrastructure Activity, and to the initial Disbursement of Program Funding for the O&amp;M incentive fund, MCA-Georgia must have developed the School O&amp;M Plan, satisfactory to MCC, that is ready for adoption by the Government.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PIA Schedule 2.2 b (ii): Prior to the initial Disbursement of Program Funding for the second tranche of schools to be rehabilitated under the Improved Learning Environment Infrastructure Activity, and to the initial Disbursement of Program Funding for the O&amp;M incentive fund, ESIDA must have maintained a staff member dedicated to development and implementation of the School O&amp;M Plan, and will have identified the staff team responsible for implementation of the School O&amp;M Plan.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PIA Schedule 2.2 b (iii): Prior to the initial Disbursement of Program Funding for the second tranche of schools to be rehabilitated under the Improved Learning Environment Infrastructure Activity, and to the initial Disbursement of Program Funding for the O&amp;M incentive fund, the Government must be in substantial compliance with an Implementation Letter to be issued by MCC regarding the framework for the O&amp;M incentive fund (the ?O&amp;M Implementation Letter?).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PIA Schedule 2.2 c (i): Prior to the initial Disbursement of Program Funding for the third and any subsequent tranches of schools to be rehabilitated under the Improved Learning Environment Infrastructure Activity, and for any subsequent Disbursements of Program Funding for the O&amp;M incentive fund: the Government must be in substantial compliance with the School O&amp;M Plan</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PIA Schedule 2.2 c (ii): Prior to the initial Disbursement of Program Funding for the third and any subsequent tranches of schools to be rehabilitated under the Improved Learning Environment Infrastructure Activity, and for any subsequent Disbursements of Program Funding for the O&amp;M incentive fund, ESIDA must have maintained adequate staffing levels to implement the School O&amp;M Plan.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PIA Schedule 2.2 c (iii): Prior to the initial Disbursement of Program Funding for the third and any subsequent tranches of schools to be rehabilitated under the Improved Learning Environment Infrastructure Activity, and for any subsequent Disbursements of Program Funding for the O&amp;M incentive fund, the Government must be in substantial compliance with the O&amp;M Implementation Letter.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
