<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10612A0102-AHO-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">IGAD &#xF6;verg&#xE5;ngsst&#xF6;d 2017</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IGAD, 2017, Bridging Support</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective(s) of the Institutional Strengthening Action Programme (ISAP) is to strengthen IGAD&#x2019;s capacity to deliver on its mandate of peace, prosperity and regional integration by improving it management systems and processes (including procurement), its communication systems and services and enhancing its IT.&#xA0;
The supported activities of IGAD&#x2019;s Peace and Security Division (PSD) relate to all core intervention areas including CEWARN, Preventive Diplomacy and Mediation, Peace Support Offices, Security Sector Program and Political Affairs Programme.&#xA0;As this support is an earmarked support, it especially regards activities related to IGAD&#x2019;s Conflict Early Warning and Response Mechanism (CEWARN); Preventive diplomacy and mediation; the IGAD Office on Sudan; Transnational Security Threats; Governance, Democracy and Human Rights in addition to Crosscutting issues: Gender and Programme coordination/management.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bridging support for IGADs institutional development program and their department for Peace and security.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">&#xD6;verg&#xE5;ngsst&#xF6;d till IGADs institutionsutvecklingsprogram och avdelning f&#xF6;r fred och s&#xE4;kerhet f&#xF6;r 2017.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="47000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IGAD/Intergovernmental Authority on Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47000" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IGAD/Intergovernmental Authority on Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eastern Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">387621.3876213876</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">387621.3876213876</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">-57739.2950433063</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">387621.387621</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-28">387621.3876213876</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-28">-57739.3426326421</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Firstly, regarding ISAP results, IGAD has managed to develop and adopt a procurement manual which was approved by partners, set up a new HR and internal audit software and initiated the process of implementing a web-based procurement system, operationalised VPN connectivity between HQ and some of its specialised institutions and prepared the regional data centre to meet IPSAS (International Public Sector Accounting Standards) requirements. &#xA0;
Regarding the PSD, IGAD adopted the IGAD Mediation Protocol which is an important milestone in strengthening IGAD&#x2019;s capacities in mediation and preventive diplomacy as it outlines general principles on how mediation is initiated, conducted, concluded as well as the post-mediation processes. IGAD also held several workshops were the IGAD Roster of Mediators could share experiences with similar regional and continental mechanisms, including from the AU Panel of the Wise, EAC, EU, SADC, ECCAS and others. On a similar note, IGAD together with the African Union High-Level Implementation Panel for Sudan (AUHIP), participated in several negotiations and mediations with the government of Sudan in the follow-up of implementation of Post Referendum Arrangements, Sudan National Dialogue and democratization of Sudan.
Moreover, IGAD has worked on promoting women&#x2019;s participation in peace processes in the region and in light of the UNSCR1325 and 1820. For example, IGAD commissioned an assessment of the implementation of the resolutions in three of its member states, namely Somalia, South Sudan and Sudan. In addition, IGAD conducted workshops for member states where participants were engaged to provide support for the implementation of UNSCR1325, promote the adoption of national action plans, in addition to serving as a platform for experience sharing and consultation on the development of NAPs.
In its work on governance, democracy and human rights, IGAD conducted two election observer missions to the parliamentary, presidential as well as the rerun of the presidential election in Kenya 2017. IGAD has also initiated the process of developing a framework and rules of procedure for the IGAD Governance Forum (IGF) and IGAD Governance Architecture (IGA). The draft framework and rules of procedure for IGA and IGF was presented to participants from all IGAD MS from 7 democratic and governance institutions, ultimately resulting in the unanimous support for establishing IGA and IGF from technical experts.
IGAD has also worked on becoming a more gender mainstreamed organisation, organising a training for the Peace and Security Division Staff on gender mainstreaming and gender indicators.
Moreover, IGAD has commissioned a study to assess and identify the presence and scale, vulnerability factors or causes and risks of cross border security threats as well as mapping criminal networks, in addition to investigating member states&apos; capabilities to address the threats in the border areas of Djibouti, Ethiopia-Somalia.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10612" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061603" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="4725000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional Africa 2016-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt Afrika 2016-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
