<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13268A0101-AHO-41010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IGAD/IDDRSI 2019-2022  Strengthening Coordination and Implementation of IDDRSI</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">IGAD/IDDRSI 2019-2022 Strengthening Coordination and Implementation of IDDRSI</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall goal of the proposed projects to enhance resilience to drought of communities, institutions and ecosystems in the IGAD region.
Building on the on-going support from Sweden and other development partners; and with the benefit of the experiences and lessons learnt from implementation of the first phase of the IDDRSI Strategy (2013 &#x2013; 2018), the IGAD Secretariat will use the proposed project to consolidate its work in the promotion and coordination of resilience-building activities in the IGAD region by focusing on the following areas:(a) Optimising the implementation of IDDRSI;(b) Scaling up resilience-enhancing technologies and innovations in cross-border areas;(c) Gender mainstreaming, capacity development and partnership needed to achieve the objectives of IDDRSI and(d) Improving IGAD&#x2019;s capacity to monitor, analyse and evaluate the process of attaining resilience-enhancement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Detta bidrag bygger p&#xE5; ett p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende st&#xF6;d fr&#xE5;n Sverige och andra utvecklingspartner. Det syftar till att konsolidera IDDRSIs (IGAD Drought Disaster Resilience
and Sustainability Initiative)  uppn&#xE5;dda resultat vad g&#xE4;ller fr&#xE4;mjande och samordning av motst&#xE5;ndskraft (resiliens) i IGAD-regionen genom att fokusera p&#xE5; f&#xF6;ljande omr&#xE5;den: 
(a) Optimera genomf&#xF6;randet av IDDRSI; 
b) F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra teknik f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra resiliens och innovationer i gr&#xE4;nsomr&#xE5;den, 
c) Integrering av j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsperspektiv, kapacitetsutveckling och partnerskap som beh&#xF6;vs f&#xF6;r att uppn&#xE5; m&#xE5;len med IDDRSI, och 
d) F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra IGADs f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;ga att &#xF6;vervaka, analysera och utv&#xE4;rdera processen att uppn&#xE5; st&#xE4;rkande av motst&#xE5;ndskraft. 

Det f&#xF6;reslagna projektet l&#xF6;per &#xF6;ver 3 &#xE5;r (oktober 2019 - september 2022) och har en sammanlagd kostnad p&#xE5; 56 500 000 kronor varav 23 200 000 kronor &#xE4;r avsedda att genomf&#xF6;ras &#xE5;r 1 (oktober 2019 - september 2020), 17 400 000 kronor f&#xF6;r &#xE5;r 2 (oktober 2020 - september 2021) och 15 900 000 kronor f&#xF6;r &#xE5;r 3 (oktober 2021 - september 2022).</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This contribution, which builds on the on-going support from Sweden and other development partners; aims to consolidate IDDRSI&#x2019;s (IGAD Drought Disaster Resilience and Sustainability Initiative) achievements in the promotion and coordination of resilience-building activities in the IGAD region by focusing on the following areas: 

(a) Optimizing the implementation of IDDRSI; 
(b) Scaling up resilience-enhancing technologies and innovations in cross-border areas; 
(c) Gender mainstreaming, capacity development and partnership that is needed to achieve the objectives of IDDRSI and 
(d) Improving IGAD&#x2019;s capacity to monitor, analyze and evaluate the process of attaining resilience-enhancement 

The proposed project has a duration of 3 years (October 2019 &#x2013; September 2022) and has a total cost of SEK 56 500 000 of which SEK 23 200 000 is for implementation in year 1 (October 2019 &#x2013; September 2020), SEK 17 400 000 for year 2 (October 2020 &#x2013; September 2021) and SEK 15 900 000 for year 3 (October 2021 &#x2013; September 2022)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="47000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IGAD/Intergovernmental Authority on Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47000" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other multilateral institution</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eastern Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="410" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Environment Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="13.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">13.b - Fr&#xE4;mja mekanismer f&#xF6;r att h&#xF6;ja f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;gan till effektiv klimatrelaterad planering och f&#xF6;rvaltning i de minst utvecklade l&#xE4;nderna, med s&#xE4;rskilt fokus p&#xE5; kvinnor, ungdomar samt lokala och marginaliserade samh&#xE4;llen.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13.b - Promote mechanisms for raising capacity for effective climate change-related planning and management in least developed countries and small island developing States, including focusing on women, youth and local and marginalized communities.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1 - By 2030, end hunger and ensure access by all people, in particular the poor and people in vulnerable situations, including infants, to safe, nutritious and sufficient food all year round.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">2.1 - Senast 2030 avskaffa hunger och garantera alla m&#xE4;nniskor, i synnerhet de fattiga och m&#xE4;nniskor i utsatta situationer, inklusive sm&#xE5; barn, tillg&#xE5;ng till tillr&#xE4;ckligt med s&#xE4;ker och n&#xE4;ringsrik mat &#xE5;ret om.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.4 - By 2030, ensure sustainable food production systems and implement resilient agricultural practices that increase productivity and production, that help maintain ecosystems, that strengthen capacity for adaptation to climate change, extreme weather, drought, flooding and other disasters and that progressively improve land and soil quality.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">2.4 - Senast 2030 uppn&#xE5; h&#xE5;llbara system f&#xF6;r livsmedelsproduktion samt inf&#xF6;ra motst&#xE5;ndskraftiga jordbruksmetoder som &#xF6;kar produktiviteten och produktionen, som bidrar till att uppr&#xE4;tth&#xE5;lla ekosystemen, som st&#xE4;rker f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;gan till anpassning till klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar, extrema v&#xE4;derf&#xF6;rh&#xE5;llanden, torka, &#xF6;versv&#xE4;mning och andra katastrofer och som successivt f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrar mark- och jordkvaliteten.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">2453494.6435558754</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2529941.257587109</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">2453494.643555876</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.6985352398</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2529941.2575871097</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-01">5975105.489694</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-28">2453494.6435558754</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-28">1085811.69853524</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/amendment-to-the-agreementbetween-igad-and-iddrisi.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment to the Agreementbetween IGAD and IDDRISI</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/signed-grant-agreement-between-sweden-and-igad-iddrsi2-20190906.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Signed Grant Agreement between Sweden and IGAD-IDDRSI2</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/decision-igad-iddrsi-2019-2022.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut IGAD-IDDRSI 2019-2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The COVID-19 Pandemic that has caused substantial slow down globally has affected the implementation of the project because of restrictions on travels and face to face meetings and conferences. Nevertheless, IGAD has reverted to online options to implement some of the activities planned for the year. Given the context in which the partner was operating, it can be concluded that IGAD&#x2019;s performance was satisfactory. Some of the achievements include: Progress was made in persuading member states to align their national development plans with their resilience Country Program Papers. During the reporting period, IDDRSI National Steering Committee has held meetings and also established sub-national committees. Moreover, National Expert Panels for M&amp;amp;E have been established. Identification of technologies for scaling up is in progress with an inception report ready on this particular outcome. Gender and Resilience Working Group (GRWG) was established and held its first meeting in July, 2020. The purpose of the meeting is to operationalise GRWG. Because of the pandemic it was decided to replace the planned Gender and Resilience Share Fair by a Community Radio Program since face-to-face meeting is difficult to hold under the context. In addition, it was not possible to meet the target of&#xA0; 30% female participation in the National Expert Panels (for M&amp;amp;E) formed by the project. It was only possible to achieve an average participation of 22%. The reason for this is lack of female senior experts in the relevant government ministries. IDDRSI was able to harness partnership with other resilience initiative - CILSS (Permanent Interstate Committee for Drought Control in the Sahel). A joint fair share is planned to take place in October 2020. IDDRSI was also selected to participate in Dubai Expo 2020 representing the African Union. This event was eventually postponed to 2021 due to COVID-19. The contribution also supported the Regional IDDRSI coordination platform to maintain key staff. On communications and Knowledge Management, several briefs and publications were produced among which the production of a web version of the Resilience Focus Magazine is one. According to reports from Member States at the 11th IDDRSI Steering Committee Meeting (July 2020), impressive results have been achieved in the countries in terms activities that contribute to resilience building at community level. Examples can be cited from Ethiopia and Kenya on the progress they have made since the previous steering committee meeting that was held a year earlier. IDDRSI continues to provide a regional platform for the member states to share experience and agree on recommendations on which they would be reporting at the next steering committee meeting. In addition to the risks identified during the appraisal phase, an additional risk has been identified in the course of implementation. This risk is the spread of COVID-19 in the region and the related restriction on travels and meetings which might cause delays in implementation. Other observations include, it was not possible to implement the project in Eritrea as Eritrea has not rejoined IGAD. For this and also because of some changes in the form of implementation, budget reallocation was discussed and agreed between IGAD and Sweden. Finance:Budget utilization was at around 42% of what was planned for the year. As presented in the narrative report assessment above, this low utilization rate was due to the lock-down in the region because of the pandemic (COVID-19). Most of the meetings, workshops and travels were cancelled and most activities were done virtually. While there was a 100% utilization rate for salaries, the other budget lines were utilized between the range of 0% to 57%.&#xA0; &#xA0; Audit: Narrative Report IGAD submitted the annual narrative and financial reports for year one on time. The report is clear and provides the status of activities that were planned in the project document. Despite the on-going pandemic and the resultant restrictions on travels and meetings, IGAD has made progress in implementing the project - Strengthening the Coordination and Implementation of IDDRSI. Some of the achievements as per the report include: Progress made in persuading countries to align their national development plans with their resilience Country Program Papers. During the reporting period, IDDRSI National Steering Committee has held meetings and also established sub-national committees. National Expert Panels for M&amp;amp;E have been established. Identification of technologies for scaling up is in progress with an inception report ready on this particular outcome. Gender:Gender and Resilience Working Group (GRWG) established and held its first meeting in July, 2020. The purpose of the meeting is to operationalise GRWG. Gender and Resilience Shair Fair to be replace by a Radio Program as face-to-face meeting is difficult to hold under the current context (the pandemic).Therefore, decision has been made to revert to Radio Programs instead. In addition, it was not possible to meet the target 30% female participation in the National Expert Panels (for M&amp;amp;E) formed by the project. It was only possible to achieve an average participation of 22%. The reason for this is lack of female senior experts in the relevant government ministries. IDDRSI was able to harness partnership with other resilience initiative - CILSS (Permanent Interstate Committee for Drought Control in the Sahel). A joint fair share is planned to take place in October 2020. IDDRSI was also selected to participate in Dubai Expo 2020 representing the African Union. This event was eventually postponed to 2021 due to COVID-19. The contribution also supported the Regional IDDRSI coordination platform to maintain key staff.&#xA0; Several briefs and publications were produced among which the production of a web version of the Resilience Focus Magazine is one. In addition to the risks identified during the appraisal phase, an additional risk has been identified. This risk is the spread of COVID-19 and the related restriction on travels and meetings which might cause delays in implementation. Other observations include, it was not possible to implement the project in Eritrea as Eritrea has not rejoined IGAD. For this and also because of some changes in the form of implementation, budget reallocation was discussed and agreed between IGAD and Sweden. In conclusion, IGAD has done a commendable job in implementing the planned activities despite the limitations posed by the pandemic. It is important to note that implementation of activities was assessed to be between 21% and 51% of the planned activities according to the assessment by IGAD. FINANCE Budget utilization was at around 42% of what was planned for the year. As presented in the narrative report assessment above, this low utilization rate was due to the lock-down in the region because of the pandemic. Most of the meetings, workshops and travels were cancelled and most activities were done virtually. While there was a 100% utilization rate for salaries, the other budget lines were utilized between the range of 0% to 57%. The annual financial report states that there is a balance of USD 1298376 at the end of the reporting period. After reviewing the narrative and financial reports of the first six monthly report, it was decided to withhold a disbursement of SEK 7 400 000 (Seven Million Four Hundred) that was planned for April 2020. In total, IGAD was to receive a grant of SEK 17 400 000 (Seventeen Million Four Hundred) in 2020 including the second installment of 10 Million that was planned to be disbursed in November 2020 after receipt and approval of narrative and financial reports for year 1. Recommendation: It is recommended to approve both the narrative and financial reports and make a disbursement of only SEK 10 000 000 (Ten Million) considering the unspent balance and year 2 annual budget of SEK 17 400 00. Audit Report The audit report which was prepared based on the ToR approved by Sweden was submitted on time and was unqualified. The report did not flag any significant or control deficiency but some observations were indicated. The observations fall in the category of other matters, which is defined by the auditor as matters that do not meet the criteria of a significant deficiency or control deficiency. IGAD has responded adequately to the observations. With that remark, the audit report for year one of project implementations is hereby approved.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13268" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061603" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="4020000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional Africa 2016-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt Afrika 2016-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
