<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5105008303-AEA-33144</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM (Int Federation of Organic Agriculture Movement), 2014-2019, EAC, OTEA II</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">IFOAM (Int Federation of Organic Agriculture Movement), 2014-2019, EAC, OTEA II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project was implemented from December 2014 to July 2019 with an Agreement between Sida and the International Federation of Organic Movements, IFOAM, that in turn partnered with the regional African Organic Network (Afronet) and the National Organic Agriculture Movements (NOAMs) in EAC;&#xA0;Kenya, Rwanda, Tanzania, Uganda and Burundi.&#xA0;
The overall goal was&#xA0;to contribute to improved&#xA0;income and livelihoods of rural communities in East Africa through the development of market-oriented organic production. The specific project objective was&#xA0;to increase trade with organic products, by supporting development of enabling regional policies, organic production and trade environment, and an increased consumer awareness.
The project had five specific project components: 
1. A well-functioning Organic Guarantee System in East Africa and increased consumer awareness
2. Increased capacity of local producers to access and supply local and regional markets
3. East African government policies, strategies and plans support the organic agriculture sector. EAC and AU policy makers are supportive of organic agriculture and ecological organic agriculture
4. The National Organic Movements in Kenya, Tanzania, Burundi, Rwanda and Uganda have increased capacity and skills to further develop the organic sector. The Regional Organic Network (Afronet) is strengthened and able to address issues of regional importance at EAC and AU levels.
5. Increased availability of reliable information and statistics on production, trade and multi-functional benefits of organic agriculture and their contributions to the challenges and needs in East Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Det f&#xF6;reslagna projektet &#xE4;r en forts&#xE4;ttning p&#xE5; tv&#xE5; tidigare faser, som &#xE4;ven f&#xE5;tt st&#xF6;d av Sida under 2006-2007och 2010-2013. De tidigare faserna har framg&#xE5;ngsrikt utvecklat en standard f&#xF6;r &#xF6;stafrikanska ekologiska produkter (EAOPS) och det regionala ekologiska varum&#xE4;rket &quot;Kilimohai&quot; (EAOM), samt utarbetat ramverk f&#xF6;r utvecklingen av en formaliserad lokal ekologisk marknad i &#xD6;stafrika.

Den f&#xF6;reslagna insatsen syftar i sitt &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;l till att bidra till att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra inkomsterna och f&#xF6;rs&#xF6;rjning p&#xE5; landsbygden i &#xD6;stafrika genom utvecklingen av marknadsorienterad ekologisk produktion. Det specifika projektm&#xE5;let &#xE4;r att &#xF6;ka handeln med ekologiska produkter, genom att st&#xF6;dja utvecklingen av en regionalpolitik, en st&#xE4;rkt produktion och f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar f&#xF6;r handel, samt en &#xF6;kad medvetenhet bland konsumenterna. Projektm&#xE5;let ska n&#xE5;s genom fem sammanh&#xE4;ngande delar: 1) Organiskt garantisystem i &#xD6;stafrika, 2) st&#xF6;d till v&#xE4;rdekedjor f&#xF6;r lokala, regionala och exportmarknader, 3) Policyutveckling och st&#xF6;d i fr&#xE4;mjande av ekologiskt jordbruk i &#xF6;stra Afrika; 4) Utveckling av den ekologiska sektorns paraplyorganisationer och regionalt n&#xE4;tverk f&#xF6;r organiskt jordbruk i &#xD6;stafrika, och, 5) dokumentation av sektorns utveckling och data samling.

Projektet &#xE4;r en stor intervention f&#xF6;r produktionen och exporten av ekologiska jordbruksprodukter i &#xD6;stafrika och har potential att bidra till &#xF6;kade inkomster och d&#xE4;rmed till att minska fattigdomen i regionen. Projektet kommer att bidra till &#xF6;kad regional integration mellan medlemsl&#xE4;nderna i EAC och harmonisering mellan initiativ av organiskt marknadsf&#xF6;ring i medlemsl&#xE4;nderna. Det kommer att ytterligare st&#xE4;rka exportpotentialen f&#xF6;r ekologiska produkter fr&#xE5;n regionen. Det f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntas att projektet kommer att leda till skapandet av nya arbetstillf&#xE4;llen, fr&#xE4;mst bland sm&#xE5;brukare jordbrukare som producerar f&#xF6;r de nyskapade marknaderna, och att en betydande andel av dessa kommer att vara kvinnliga lantbrukare.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project is a continuation of two previous phases, also supported by Sida during 2006 - 2007 and 2010 - 2013, which successfully developed the East African Organic Products Standards (EAOPS) and the regional organic trade mark &#x201C;Kilimohai&#x201D; (EAOM), and elaborated framework for the development of a formalized local organic market in East Africa.

The proposed activity aims in its overall development goal to contribute to improving the income and livelihood of rural communities in East Africa through the development of market oriented organic production. The specific project objective is to increase trade with organic products, by supporting the development of enabling regional policies, a capacitated production and trade environment, and an increased consumer awareness.

The project objective will be achieved through five interrelated components: 1) Organic Guarantee System in East Africa; 2) Value chain support for local, regional and export markets; 3) Policy development and support in promotion of organic agriculture in East Africa; 4) Development of the organic sector umbrella organizations and the regional Organic Agriculture Network in East Africa; and, 5) Documenting the development of the sector and data collection.

The project is a major intervention in the production and exports of organic agriculture products in East Africa and has the potential to contribute to increased income and thus to poverty alleviation in the region. The project will contribute to enhanced regional integration between the member countries of EAC as well as to harmonization between initiatives of organic promotion in the member countries. It will further strengthen export potential for organic products from the region. It is expected that the project will lead to job creation, mainly among small-holder farmers producing for the newly created markets, and that a significant proportion of these will be female farmers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM/International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM/International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eastern Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="331" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Policies &amp; Regulations</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="33110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">409045.7546894174</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">351000.351000351</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">546580.1344011783</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">409045.7546894174</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">351000.3510003509</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">487204.2713799134</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-01">1639965.597166</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">409045.7546894174</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-28">351000.351000351</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-02-28">143836.8774739943</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-28">343367.3939059192</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of efficient and sustainable certifications bodies (component A) operating in the region has partly been achieved. Both local and international certifications bodies are actively engaged in Kenya, while local bodies remain absent in Rwanda and Burundi and Tancert operates at very low capacity in Tanzania. In Uganda, UgaCert is being revived. The use of East African Organic Product Standards and East African Organic Mark was most popular in Kenya, Uganda and Tanzania. In Rwanda and Burundi, it has not yet been used extensively.&#xA0;Results from the consumer awareness survey conducted in 2017/2018 showed a 10% increase in consumer awareness compared to 2013.
The World Organic Agriculture Statistics reports a 9% increase in the number of organic farmers in East Africa between 2014 and 2017, a period that coincides with the OTEA project. The project has effectively facilitated linkage of organic producers/groups to local markets (farmers markets, selling points, processors, traders, and restaurants/hotels). Expected results of such linkages would normally be improved sales contracts from a number of buyers, increased volumes of sales, better prices and improved profit margins. This has however not been the case in many instances within the project. The disconnect between the created linkages and actual business has been attributed to either limited volumes supplies, breach of agreements or lack of quality certificates.
Through NOGAMU, farmers in the dried fruits value chain were reported to be linked to export markets in Gulf countries. Such linkages are deemed to have substantial impact on farmers&#x2019; incomes resulting from consistency and reliability of the markets. However, sustainability of these market linkages is in doubt following the institutional troubles with NOGAMU.
With the OTEA intervention new forms of markets (farmers markets, selling points, niche markets organic restaurants, organic basket) have been established in some countries. These have in turn given farmers access to more targeted markets where the probability of receiving premium prices for their produce is relatively higher that in conventional markets. In local markets where premium prices are hard to come by, farmers have focused on economies of scale by targeting more consumers at same prices as those of conventional products.
By 2018, six non participatory guarantee system value chains (honey, dried fruits, ginger, macadamia, coffee, sesame and chia) were fully functional.&#xA0;Farmers trainings on organic production (including seed sourcing, pest and disease management, post-harvest handling, crop diversification and sustainable land use) can be linked to increased production.&#xA0;
Increased organic trade (component B) is&#xA0;evident in some key product value chains such as spices from Tanzania to other EAC countries, garlic from Rwanda to Uganda and tree-tomatoes from Rwanda to Congo. At least the Rwandan exports are attributable to the initiatives under the current project.&#xA0;A total of 130 Participatory Guarantee System (PGS) groups were supported over the project period and farmers were linked to local markets, processors and traders. There is a considerable expansion on number of PGS-groups or emerging PGS-groups and thus more producers and traders are now involved, which in turn suggest expansion of better land management practices.
A general conclusion on increased market linkage for organic products in the region can be made. However, verifiable data on actual number of organic farmers linked to processors, buyers, traders, or other outlets, volumes of products traded and prevailing market prices still remains a challenge.
In relation to government policies, strategies and plans supporting the organic agriculture sector on national as well as regional (EAC) and pan-African level (AU) (component C) the national organic agriculture movements&#xA0;have successfully engaged policy makers to support organic agriculture in their countries. Most governments prefer to have organic agriculture mainstreamed in other aspects of agricultural development rather than as a stand-alone policy or programme.
Regional organic policy forum has been conducted with support of IFOAM&#xA0;and the United Nations Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD) brought together 60 organic stakeholders, government representatives and policy makers as well as supporting organisations from five countries. Policy briefs and studies explaining current status of organic sector, successes, and challenges of the organic sector in East Africa were presented. EAC representative inaugurated the forum. At EAC level, support was seen on the endorsement of the revised East African Organic Product Standard&#xA0;at the 2018 EAC&#xA0;Annual Forum. At AU level, organic agriculture is claimed to be embedded in the Comprehensive Africa Agriculture Development Programme (CAADP).
An important part of the project was also increased capacity of the national and regional&#xA0;organic movements (component D). However, the results have been highly variable.&#xA0;NOGAMU&#xA0;(Uganda) has been drastically damaged by mismanagement and had to close down the business. ROAM (Rwanda) faced repeated issues of mismanagement and is currently an organisation run by volunteers but with institutional improvements. KOAN&#xA0;(Kenya) and TOAM&#xA0;(Tanzania) both face staff reduction as a result of that the project funding from Sida ended in 2018 and with that loss of experienced personnel. BOAM&#xA0;(Burundi)&#xA0;remains small, but reports to have been strengthened considerably by OTEA-project. The strengthening may, however, be limited to a few individuals rather than to systems.&#xA0;
Afronet&#xA0;at the regional level remains with limited staff and institutional capacity. It can still be regarded as the leading regional organic movement even though its capacity is constrained. Its operation is heavily donor dependent.
Lastly, in relation to availability of reliable information and statistics on organic agriculture trade (component E) still involve many challenges. Training and efforts to create a system for uniform data collection has resulted in a system being in place. National organic movements&#xA0;report data to IFOAM for use in the yearbooks on organic production published by the Research Institute of Organic Agriculture.&#xA0;It remains difficult to find data relevant for East Africa. NOAMs have additional data but it is not availed on their websites. There are several constraints to collection of trade data. These include among others, no dis-aggregation of organic from other produce; companies do not want to disclose their business details; much of the produce is sold together with other produce on local markets, or via specified local market linkages. In either case there will be no reporting to any form of public statistical data bases.
OTEA suffered from setbacks in implementation in both Rwanda and Uganda due to mismanagement in the national partner organisations. These events reduced efficiency. When some actions were taken the governance systems and administrative routines were strengthened in the Rwandan organisation, while the participation of the Ugandan organisation in OTEA was discontinued. Organisational assessments conducted revealed that several of the partner organisations had weak systems and with that high risks.
According to the final evaluation &quot;the impact varies considerably between components and countries, from near failures to considerable achievements. From a pedagogical point of view, it would be desirable to give one &#x201C;opinion&#x201D; on the overall performance, but an average of extremes is not useful.&quot; The project main strengths have been related to group formation and support to organic production. Maintaining and to some extent developing further the East African Organic Product Standards and East African Organic Mark. Also, engagement with policy makers even though policy advancement at national levels was not significant. The project&#xB4;s weaker areas include institution building making organisations more sustainable and making data available for East African audiences.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51050083" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061603" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="4725000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional Africa 2016-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt Afrika 2016-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
