<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5100012401-AEA-14040</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NELSAP-Mara,Kagera,SMM transboundary rivers</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">NELSAP-Mara,Kagera,SMM vattenresursf&#xF6;rvaltning</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">NELSAP &#xE4;r ett av tre center under Nileninitiativet. Projeketet        arbetar f&#xF6;r f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad vattenresursf&#xF6;rvaltning och utveckling genom   f&#xF6;rstudier f&#xF6;r infrastruktur f&#xF6;r bevattning och sm&#xE5;skalig vattenkraft i flodomr&#xE5;dena Mara, Kagera och Sio-Malaba-Malakisi.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Nile Equatorial Lakes Subsidiary Action Program (NELSAP) works    within the frame work of Nile Basin Initiative. The project is        managed by NELSAP and works for improved water mangement and to       prepare infrastructure investments in water storage, in the Mara      (between Kenya &amp; Tanzania), Kagera (Burundi, Rwanda, Tanzania &amp;       Uganda) and Sio-Malaba-Malakisi (Kenya &amp;Uganda) river basins.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="47000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NBI/Nile Basin Initiative</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47000" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other multilateral institution</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eastern Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="14040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">River basins development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">4432034.747152418</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">2149481.0538598537</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">4432034.747152418</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">2149481.053859854</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-11-01">6500317.629156</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-28">4432034.747152418</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">2149481.0538598537</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2015Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: (i) Formalized transboundary sub-basin cooperation: NEL countries agreed to enter into legally binding Memorandums of Understanding (MoUs)/Inter-country agreements to facilitate implementation of joint interventions at the three sub basin levels. The MoUs were finalized, submitted to the respective country legal departments for review and are currently at the level of ratification. 
(ii) Improved access to knowledge products for effective river basin planning and management
 - Water Resources Monitoring Systems Enhanced: NELSAP and the three sub basin projects now have high quality, reliable and comprehensive data available to facilitate WRM and investment planning. In this regard, the three Projects, together with national departments responsible for hydrology and water resources monitoring, designed, procured and installed equipment at strategic locations. The installed hydrometric stations have enhanced the monitoring of water resources and reliable data is being generated for improved investment planning. The data is shared and exchanged in line with the NBI Interim data and information sharing procedures and this has contributed to the uniformity of information systems in the NEL basin.
 - Sub basin Development Plans and Water Allocation Models Developed: These are used to guide the riparian countries in rational planning and prioritization of projects from a basin-wide perspective and give a holistic understanding of their benefits, costs, risks and cumulative impacts. The tools have strengthened the coordinated planning of the basin&#x2019;s water resources, in order to optimize the resultant economic and social welfare in an equitable manner without compromising ecosystem sustainability. As a result of the pre-investment work, there is thus: increased use of an IWRM approach as a basis for land and water management in the sub basins; awareness of resource availability constraints and options for development in RBM plans;  improved water resources planning (sub basin development plans), investment strategies and use of impact assessment procedures &#x2013; including SEA.

 (iii) Enhanced Participatory Integrated Land and Water management in selected critical watersheds:
Through this result area, there has been strong community awareness and greater ownership of watershed scale plans of action. Emphasis was placed on public participation in decision-making at all levels. Community based organisations, in transboundary catchments were also empowered through awareness raising and exchange visits, which contributed to improved local awareness of river basin management issues in the basin community. Through pilot catchment management planning, a bottom up planning approach with strong community level management was achieved. This is being scaled up in the three sub basins for catchments of transboundary significance.
As a result of the policy and institutional work undertaken in the three projects: 
-  there is integrated action across natural resource issues, which means sub basin agencies do not look for singular solutions but look at impacts across the spectrum of natural resources sectors; 
 - fora have been created for regional coordination arrangements which include civil society (e.g. Nile Basin Discourse), joint technical teams and joint programs of action (for instance in catchment planning) between states participating in each of the RBM projects; 
 -  there is consensus-based decision-making in sub basin planning and management to balance user needs for water Resources, and; 
 - rules of procedures for the steering committees have streamlined decision making at the sub-basin level.

(iv) Increased pipeline of investments prepared to address water and food security 
The 3 sub projects and the NELSAP CU supervised projects preparation studies for regional water infrastructure and watershed management. The studies built on previously identified areas from investment strategies and monographs of the 3 sub-basins (developed through financing from Sweden /Norway), and had final outputs of technical designs for prepared water infrastructure and watershed management programs. Among the water infrastructure projects prepared include Maira and Bulusambu in SMM sub basin, Taba Gakomeye, Bigasha, Buyongwe and Karazi in Kagera sub basin and Borenga and Norera in Mara sub basin. The projects, in collaboration with the NELSAP CU, also supervised integrated watershed management projects in the three sub basins. When implemented, the projects will directly contribute towards poverty reduction, food, water and energy security, overall socio-economic development as well as climate adaptation which will boost the proximate local economies.
Three out of the seven regional water infrastructure projects prepared under this program have been taken on by national Governments for implementation (Maira in Kenya being implemented within the Kenya Enhanced Water Security and Climate Resilience Program, Amoni-Kocholia in Kenya under the National Irrigation Board, and Bigasha in Uganda under Water for Production). Malaba and Busia Pollution Control Projects prepared under the SMM have also been taken up by Lake Victoria Basin Commission with funding from KfW. The three sub projects of SMM, Mara and Kagera have prepared an investment program portfolio with a value of US$ 1.2 billion by 2015.

Livelihoods of sub basin communities have been improved through the piloting of irrigation development on 172 acres (110acres at Lukhuna in Uganda and 62 acres at Sitabicha/Suswo in Kenya) with possibility for up scaling and aquaculture development. This is currently benefiting over 1,000 people directly and with scaling up irrigation development with over 10,000ha expected to be developed will benefit over 100,000 people in the three sub basins. The capacity of farmers in farm technology has increased following exposure visits and demonstrations on the irrigation development
(v) Strengthened Project Management and coordination.
The NELSAP CU has managed and coordinated the three different sub-programs. The management of the programme has been efficient and professional. All audits have been clean and with only minor issues pointed out in the management letters for the annual audits. Substantial audit recommendations have always been swiftly implemented.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51000124" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
