<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="KES" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>KE-NCB-OP-218-051-9994-1329-HAKI2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="KE-NCB-OP-218-051-9994-1329" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Rights Education and Awareness</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">USAWA NA HAKI</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bi-annual progress report of interventions implemented in Kilifi and Meru counties. Funded by the Netherlands Embassy, the Haki Yetu Jukumu Letu project was an accountability project that was implemented  in Meru and Kilifi Counties in Kenya. The Goal of the project was for women and girls in Kilifi and Meru counties to be protected and able to better exercise their right to life, health, dignity, non-discrimination, and education as enshrined in the Constitution of Kenya 2010. The project&apos;s high-level outcomes sort to ensure increased gender sensitivity, responsiveness, and coordination of GBV services by public authorities and increased capacity and action by Women-led accountability groups and community-based organizations to demand accountability of duty bearers on GBV service providers on implementation of laws and policies that address gender violence against women and girls. The project design was informed by various GBV studies and reports from multi-sectoral GBV convening which identified root causes for the prevalence  of GBV and poor accountability for the implementation of National GBV laws and policies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To improve access to justice for women and girls by strengthening institutional response of state and actors to promote and protect the rights of women and girls in Kilifi and Meru Counties by September 2021: The project  facilitated engagements between SGBV sector stakeholders including the County CEC for gender, state department of gender, civil society organizations, women champions, and representatives from women and girl led accountability groups to strengthen SGBV referral pathway including coordination of prevention and response mechanisms. This  included linkages of SGBV to the county specific COVID 19  coordination unit to ensure gender responsive action by state and non-state actors to attend to emerging needs of gender-based violence survivors.

To champion positive social cultural norms, attitudes and practices that promote the rights of women and girls by September 2021: The output will enabled CREAW engage in mass awareness forums with different sets of community members (Women and Men) and build their knowledge base and understanding of what constitutes SGBV and the referral pathway of care and support for those affected by violence. Information was shared using virtual platforms as well as physical spaces with strict adherence to the COVID 19 measures. Peer to peer learning model was used to ensure information is cascaded to households and to reach a wider population and especially those living in far to reach areas. Interventions  targeted print and electronic media including social media and CREAW website in printing timeless information on public spaces on where to receive care and support. Webinars and Facebook live with record live engagements with duty bearers where they share critical information on how the public can directly engage with government officials regarding access to comprehensive care services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and girls: At national level, Kenya&#x2019;s commitment to combat violence against women and girls is evident from the domestication of various regional and international conventions, treaties and human rights standards and programmes of action that seek to prevent or eradicate gender inequality and discrimination which are the major causes of gender-based violence . These laws and policies are spread across different sectors which include but are not limited to education, criminal justice system, the judiciary and health.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="KE-NCB-OP-218-051-9994-1329" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Rights Education and Awareness</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned implementation end date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned implementation start date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Coordinator</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leah Mutumbu</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254721127729</telephone>
   <email>leah.mutumbu@creawkenya.org</email>
   <website>https://home.creaw.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Rights Education and Awareness &#x2013; CREAW
Elgeyo Marakwet Close off Elgeyo Marakwet Road , Hse No. 1 (on the Left), Kilimani.
P.O. Box 35470 - 00100, Nairobi, Kenya.
Mobile. 254 720 357664  | Office Tel. 254 020 2378271   |  Email. info@creaw.org
Website: www.creawkenya.org
Satellite Offices: Kibera | Kilifi | Meru | Isiolo | Narok  | Mombasa</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="12264" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funded by the Netherlands Embassy, the Haki Yetu Jukumu Letu project was an accountability project that was implemented in Meru and Kilifi Counties in Kenya. The Goal of the project was for women and girls in Kilifi and Meru counties to be protected and able to better exercise their right to life, health, dignity, non-discrimination, and education as enshrined in the Constitution of Kenya 2010. The project&apos;s high-level outcomes sort to ensure increased gender sensitivity, responsiveness, and coordination of GBV services by public authorities by 2019 &amp; increased capacity and action by Women led accountability groups and community-based organizations to demand for accountability of duty bearers on GBV service providers on implementation of laws and policies that address gender violence against women and girls. The project design was informed by various GBV studies and reports from multi sectorial GBV convening&#x2019;s which identified root causes for prevalence of GBV and poor accountability for implementation of National GBV laws and policies.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project was an accountability project to endure women and girls in Kilifi and Meru counties are protected and are exercising their right to life, health, dignity, and non-discrimination.</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pro bono lawyers and counselors network established to support legal aid, legal representation, and psychosocial support for women and girls survivors of SGBV.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved confidence  and emotional stability of survivors  by the support offered Pro bono  lawyers Legal   services continue to be provided for survivors of Gender Violence. 47 clients have been given legal advise while out of those 28 have received court representation.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of women and girls receiving pro bono legal assistance, advice, representation on GBV cases, and counseling services.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total number of survivors who have benefitted from the psycho social and legal services offered.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="A localised CREAW hotline where survivors of violence can report cases and be supported with legal and psychosocial support in place.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </target>
     <target value="A virtual online platform within CREAW offices where survivors are able to virtually attend to their court cases and listen to the proceedings online established.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </target>
     <actual value="1 forum held 28Pax (8M;20F). Collaboration especially in referals was encouraged where lawyers would examine their cases and refer those that need counselling to the counsellors while the counsellors in will as well refer their clients needing legal assistant to the Lawyers.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </actual>
     <actual value="Probono Leagal services continue to be provided for survivors of Gender Violence. 47 clients have been given legal advise while out of those 28 have received court representation.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public authorities (Police and local administration) in Kilifi and Meru Counties are equipped with knowledge and skills to improve institutional response and prevention of VAW/G.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sub County Commanders have the capacity to continue to mobilize and show support for the police sensitization on NPS SOPs. The police stations that did not have gender desks officers  committed to always assist with an office or an empty room to conduct interviews and record statements for the survivors of GBV, they also directed that no survivor of Sexual Violence would be charged for PRC or P3 filling.                                                                                                                 The trainer allocated by the County Commander mentored all the gender  desk Officers in the county.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nature of coordination measures put in place ie. 
   -TWG convenings, 
    -Functional SOP, 
    -Information sharing system, 
    -Budgetary commitments/allocations by the county public authority.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This are the contributions made by duty bearers to create awareness and  support the women and girls survivors in seeking justice by following and adhering to the GBV reporting pathways.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8 quarterly multi sectoral County and Sub County GBV technical working group (TWG) meetings held">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technical working groups held with the aim of reducing GBV cases and supporting survivors of violence.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="Convened 1 GBV TWG Meting 30 Pax (23F;7M). Members of the TWG gave their reports since the last meeting; GVRC welcomed all to refer GBV survivors to them for free services and applauded CREAW, and the Gender Department for referring Cases to them; increased partnership and collaborations for referrals was called upon and toll-free numbers were shared by CREAW, GVRC and ICL.  Working with CEC gender office to develop County Specific SOPs on sexual harassment at the workplace. This will be an output in the deliverables from the Meru County SGBV Policy 2019-2024 to reduce Sexual Harassment at Workplace.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nature of coordination measures put in place ie. 
   -TWG convenings, 
    -Functional SOP, 
    -Information sharing system, 
    -Budgetary commitments/allocations by the county public authority.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This are the contributions made by duty bearers to create awareness and  support the women and girls survivors in seeking justice by following and adhering to the GBV reporting pathways.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4 lobbying meetings between women led accountability groups and members of the county assembly and the Gender CEC held.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Meetings held with women accountability groups and members of CEC</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <target value="8 quarterly multi sectoral County and Sub County GBV technical working group (TWG) meetings held">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technical working groups held with the aim of reducing GBV cases and supporting survivors of violence.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <target value="4 women led accountability groups participates in decision making platforms including public participation forums (virtual or physical) at county level">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">meetings organized with women accountability groups with support with participation in public participation forums</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <target value="16 Quarterly Court Users Committee Meetings in Magistrates courts supported.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men and women equipped with knowledge and skills on the rights of women and girls and take action to support access to justice for women and girls survivors of SGBV.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The gender champions  have improved   capacities to identify and assist the survivors of Gender based violence especially those in need of  psycho social  and legal support. They also have gone to an extend of  accompanying   survivors to seek seek services and to keep track of  their progress.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of individuals (disaggregated by type, age, and gender) with improved knowledge and skills towards the elimination of all forms of violence</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of project beneficiaries who are aware of GBV, types of GBV and the referral pathways.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="Support 20 community led accountability groups to hold 40 community conversations in 40 villages encouraging nonviolent resolution of conflict between intimate partners as well as facilitate survivor support for those living in far to reach areas."></target>
     <actual value="20 forums  conducted reaching 778 (181M;597F) Participants The women continue to accompany the GBV Survivors through the referral chain; as well as call for local administrators and other duty bearers to be accountable. They continue to encourage women and girls to seek justice and referring them to legal and counselling services offered by CREAW  The Community requested that the local administrators in charge of handling AJS and mediation be taken through mechanisms to arbitrate over those cases effectively, without favor or biasness on one side. There was also a call to conduct sensitization on laws and legal instruments protecting people against GBV to address the issues of widows and widowers being denied their spouses properties after they have passed on.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced collaboration and partnerships in eradicating GBV.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is continued Multi-Sectoral partnerships and cordination between the duty bearerers with the aim of ersdicaying   GBV. Referals have been made ; for instance, the Police, the Judicary, the ODPP, GVRC, the Gender Champions and the childrens deparment have been refering survivors of GBV for probono Couselling, legal Aid, rescue and medical assessments .                                                                                                                                           The Police in the other hand  continue to collaborate  the ODPP in ensuring proper filing of charge sheets, non delay of court files, and diversion of petty cases to the Probations department especailly for minor scases.   There is also  continued collaboation between  the Judiciary , the police and the Probations department are working together to settle AJS Cases especially those touching on intimate partner Violence and land Issues.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved multisectoral coordination and monitoring of SGBV in Kilifi and Meru Counties.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stakeholders are working together towards addressing a common goal</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="Support 16 Quarterly Court Users Committee Meetings in Magistrates courts and influence adjudication of sexual and gender based violence to use survivor centered approaches in adjudicating cases of SGBV">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </target>
     <actual value="Supported 1 CUC Meeting; 36 Pax (26M;10F).The meeting addressed the issue of missing files including SO cases files was discussed. The challenge was cases were being given a forward date after the file was not produced in court, and at that time the Survivor, witnesses and the accused were in court and this eas seen to lead the delay of justice.  Members agreed to; task the OCSs and hold them accountable for any file that does not get to the court on the date agreed, 3 days to hearing date; form a WhatsApp group with the OCS, IOs, the Prosecutors (ODPPs office), and the Court Administrator to share the course lists for better preparations and delivery of files in court.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number and nature of demonstrable contributions  made by duty bearers to better provide access to justice for women and girls</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">State actors demonstrate improved response (better knowledge, attitude and practice) to SGBV and other human rights violations on women and girls in Kilifi and Meru Counties.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="36 chiefs  in Kilifi and Meru were sensitized and they supporting in reporting and referring of GBV cases.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved positive socio-cultural norms and practices that promote the rights of women and girls by September 2021.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WGLs continue to be beacons of Justice for SGBV survivors in the communities; they have shown more commitment by continuing to champion the rights of women ang girls by accompanying them through the case  management process and holding duty bearers accountable for their actions. they have also been doing referrals for survivors to the various duty bearers and stakeholders who can assist survivors of SGBV (this included to physically accompanying the survivors) like CREAW, GVRC Meru, Ripples, Children&apos;s Department, as well as holding brief in court during case hearings. one care giver to a child survivor of defilement.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proportion of men and women reporting to have acquired new knowledge and skills to engage and support access to justice for survivors of SGBV.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project beneficiaries to report to have benefitted by acquiring new information regarding GBV</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="Develop and send bulk messages on hope and healthy living and information on where to seek support for GBV violations to community members sourced from the existing database of persons who have interacted with CREAW interventions in the counties.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </target>
     <actual value="10,000 people reached with bulk messages on hope and healthy living and information on where to seek support for GBV violations to community members sourced from the existing database of persons who have interacted with CREAW interventions in the counties.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
