<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="KES" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>KE-NCB-OP-218-051-9994-1329-FINAL</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="KE-NCB-OP-218-051-9994-1329" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Rights Education and Awareness</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SW">USAWA NA HAKI</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End of project narrative report of interventions implemented in Kilifi and Meru counties. Funded by the Netherlands Embassy, the Haki Yetu Jukumu Letu project was an accountability project that was implemented in Meru and Kilifi Counties in Kenya. The Goal of the project was for women and girls in Kilifi and Meru counties to be protected and able to better exercise their right to life, health, dignity, non-discrimination, and education as enshrined in the Constitution of Kenya 2010. The project&apos;s high-level outcomes sort to ensure increased gender sensitivity, responsiveness, and coordination of GBV services by public authorities and increased capacity and action by Women-led accountability groups and community-based organizations to demand accountability of duty bearers on GBV service providers on implementation of laws and policies that address gender violence against women and girls. The project design was informed by various GBV studies and reports from multi-sectoral GBV convening which identified root causes for the prevalence  of GBV and poor accountability for the implementation of National GBV laws and policies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To improve access to justice for women and girls by strengthening institutional response of state and actors to promote and protect the rights of women and girls in Kilifi and Meru Counties by September 2021: The project  facilitated engagements between SGBV sector stakeholders including the County CEC for gender, state department of gender, civil society organizations, women champions, and representatives from women and girl led accountability groups to strengthen SGBV referral pathway including coordination of prevention and response mechanisms. This  included linkages of SGBV to the county specific COVID 19  coordination unit to ensure gender responsive action by state and non-state actors to attend to emerging needs of gender-based violence survivors.

To champion positive social cultural norms, attitudes and practices that promote the rights of women and girls by September 2021: The output will enabled CREAW engage in mass awareness forums with different sets of community members (Women and Men) and build their knowledge base and understanding of what constitutes SGBV and the referral pathway of care and support for those affected by violence. Information was shared using virtual platforms as well as physical spaces with strict adherence to the COVID 19 measures. Peer to peer learning model was used to ensure information is cascaded to households and to reach a wider population and especially those living in far to reach areas. Interventions  targeted print and electronic media including social media and CREAW website in printing timeless information on public spaces on where to receive care and support. Webinars and Facebook live with record live engagements with duty bearers where they share critical information on how the public can directly engage with government officials regarding access to comprehensive care services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and girls: At national level, Kenya&#x2019;s commitment to combat violence against women and girls is evident from the domestication of various regional and international conventions, treaties and human rights standards and programmes of action that seek to prevent or eradicate gender inequality and discrimination which are the major causes of gender-based violence . These laws and policies are spread across different sectors which include but are not limited to education, criminal justice system, the judiciary and health.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="KE-NCB-OP-218-051-9994-1329" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Rights Education and Awareness</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned implementation end date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned implementation start date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Coordinator</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leah Mutumbu</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254721127729</telephone>
   <email>leah.mutumbu@creawkenya.org</email>
   <website>https://home.creaw.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Rights Education and Awareness &#x2013; CREAW
Elgeyo Marakwet Close off Elgeyo Marakwet Road , Hse No. 1 (on the Left), Kilimani.
P.O. Box 35470 - 00100, Nairobi, Kenya.
Mobile. 254 720 357664  | Office Tel. 254 020 2378271   |  Email. info@creaw.org
Website: www.creawkenya.org
Satellite Offices: Kibera | Kilifi | Meru | Isiolo | Narok  | Mombasa</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="12264" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funded by the Netherlands Embassy, the Haki Yetu Jukumu Letu project was an accountability project that was implemented in Meru and Kilifi Counties in Kenya. The Goal of the project was for women and girls in Kilifi and Meru counties to be protected and able to better exercise their right to life, health, dignity, non-discrimination, and education as enshrined in the Constitution of Kenya 2010. The project&apos;s high-level outcomes sort to ensure increased gender sensitivity, responsiveness, and coordination of GBV services by public authorities by 2019 &amp; increased capacity and action by Women led accountability groups and community-based organizations to demand for accountability of duty bearers on GBV service providers on implementation of laws and policies that address gender violence against women and girls. The project design was informed by various GBV studies and reports from multi sectorial GBV convening&#x2019;s which identified root causes for prevalence of GBV and poor accountability for implementation of National GBV laws and policies.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project was an accountability project to endure women and girls in Kilifi and Meru counties are protected and are exercising their right to life, health, dignity, and non-discrimination.</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <document-link format="TEXT/PLAIN" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Usawa-Na-Haki-Annual-Report-2021-20220421070445.docx">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Usawa na Haki end of project report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final end of project implementation progress and achievements narrative report.</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2021-12-23"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public authorities (Police and local administration) in Kilifi and Meru Counties are equipped with knowledge and skills to improve institutional response and prevention of VAW/G.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sensitization forums at police stations reached 432 (247M;158F) officers who were sensitized on the National Police Service Strategic Operating Procedures on Gender violence. Out of this, the NPS reaffirmed the strategies stipulated in the SOP and are working to cover the gaps existing before to ensure filing of prosecutable cases; timely investigations and conclusion of cases; and proper documentation to reduce appeals. The NPS has incorporated the below strategies;
&#x2022;	Strengthened the chain of custody of  DNA samples by working closely with the MOH to store DNA samples collected from survivors and suspects of GBV before they can be taken to the Government Chemist for analysis.
&#x2022;	Liaise with the ODPP to ensure proper drafting of charge sheets to limit instances of mistrials and appeal for cases as well as ensure court files are present and witnesses are well bonded before hearing of Cases. The Magistrates and the ODPP have reported a change of attitude by investigating officers and minimal defective charge sheets, mistrials, or appeals emanating from police filing errors.
&#x2022;	Gender desk officers are accompanying Sexual Violence Survivors to Hospital and assist them to have the required procedure followed and collecting relevant evidence to support their case
&#x2022;	In the police stations where there are no Gender Desks, the station heads provide alternative safe space for reporting and recording of statements of GBV Cases.Sensitization meetings with Local Administrators reached 676 (423M;244F) that included chiefs, Sub-chiefs, and Nyumba Kumi representatives. This team is now in a better position to empathetically listen and support reported cases accordingly reducing chances of the criminal offenses going unreported to the police. Unlike before, when even cases of defilement were being settled by the chiefs.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of public authorities (police, health, local administration) sensitized as TOT&#x2019;s on GBV related laws, policies, and efficient handling of GBV cases.
(Disaggregated by sector/sex)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Awareness creation initiatives to stakeholders to support to increase their knowledge in handling and supporting survivors.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-12-30"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="&quot;24 sensitization forums held in 24 police stations/sub county stations - 96 police officers sensitized&quot;">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </target>
     <actual value="Sensitization meetings with Local Administrators reached 676 (423M;244F) that included chiefs, Sub-chiefs, and Nyumba Kumi representatives. This team is now in a better position to empathetically listen and support reported cases accordingly reducing chances of the criminal offenses going unreported to the police. Unlike before, when even cases of defilement were being settled by the chiefs.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved multi-sectoral coordination and monitoring of SGBV in Kilifi and Meru Counties.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TWG Joint Campaigns.
In Meru County, in line with the SGBV policy to create awareness in ending all forms of violence against women and girls, the Gender department is conducting joint anti-FGM campaigns in collaboration with State &amp; Non-state agencies drawn from the GBV TWG in the most affected sub-counties of Tigania and Igembe. The inclusion of the Njuri Ncheke council of elders and reformed practitioners has played a big role in sending a strong message that FGM is an outdated cultural practice that has no place in the 21st Century. Practitioners are hence coming out openly and abandoning the practice. Further CREAW and one of the reformed practitioners was incorporated into the National government County anti-FGM intergovernmental committee creating a platform for continuous advocacy and in line with the presidential declaration on ending female genital mutilation (FGM) in the Country by 2022.  

The Meru County Anti sexual harassment guidelines.
Being free from sexual harassment is a basic human right. In recognition that all County government employees have a legal right to live and work free from sexual harassment, the gender department has developed County Specific workplace anti-sexual harassment guidelines for all the staff. As a key to preventing sexual harassment, the guideline defines sexual harassment and outlines unacceptable behavior and its consequences. The guidelines once adopted will also encourage prompt reporting of incidents and immediate action on any complaints that involve sexual harassment. 

The push for the Women&#x2019;s Agenda
The Meru County Assembly Women Caucus has lobbied for the allocation of more funds to fight FGM in the 2020-2021 budget; piping of water from the boreholes for easy access by women and girls, they have also tabled a health bill that among other things seek allocation of resources to address cancer which is affecting many families in Meru County. Members of MEWOLA are also mentoring, supporting, and encouraging other women to vie for elective seats at the county to boost women&#x2019;s leadership and to ensure that the women&#x2019;s voices and agendas are pushed for at the legislative level. The Women Caucas can now actively lobby for finances to champion and expand women&apos;s rights since they have a strategic plan and there exists SGBV policy which other counties are benchmarking with.

Kilifi TWG Constitution and Terms of Reference
In Kilifi, the County TWG has developed a constitution and terms of reference. This has improved the functionality of the technical working group by providing a point of reference and governing its activities. The TORs will among other things help coordinate planning with all members to avoid duplication of activities and maintain the updated mapping of SGBV-related services within the
County.

Creation of an information-sharing system
In Kilifi, the GBV TWG has developed a Prototype GBV Reporting toolkit purposely to generate universal information on GBV case reporting. This is to promote uniformity in the mode of reporting by the stakeholders who currently use different toolkits. This will improve documentation and monitoring of GBV cases in the county thus enhancing a better feedback and learning opportunity during the  TWG meetings. The tool will also help to inform the persistent GBV cases and violations of human rights for discussion at TWG meetings for actioning and shaping future programs at the County Level. 

During the project cycle, CREAW supported 4 GBV TWG convening&#x2019;s where members had an opportunity to share more about their programs and available reporting mechanisms including toll-free services offered by CREAW and Nairobi Women GVRC. This increased reporting by survivors seeking post-violence care and response including medical, counseling, and legal aid. Further, the Kilifi County referral hospital increased the number of health officers at the GBVRC from 2 to 4. This has brought about timely and efficient delivery of services as compared to beforeThrough the engagements and support for the CUC Meetings and training, the coordination of GBV response has been enhanced where the stakeholders hold each other accountable for their responsibilities as well as work to complement each other to ensure that the referral pathway works better and efficiently to the benefit of the survivors. Judiciary, the National police service, and the Probations department are working together to offer an alternative Justice system AJS/ADR for petty offenders and those touching on intimate partners, child maintenance thus giving the parties another chance to live harmoniously in the community.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nature of coordination measures put in place i.e. 
   -TWG convening, 
    -Functional SOP, 
    -Information sharing system, 
    -Budgetary commitments/allocations by the county public authority.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stakeholders working collaboratively with the aim of eliminating GBV</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-12-30"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="8 quarterly multi sectoral County and Sub County GBV technical working group (TWG) meetings held">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </target>
     <actual value="supported 4 GBV TWG convening&#x2019;s where members had an opportunity to share more about their programs and available reporting mechanisms including toll-free services offered by CREAW and Nairobi Women GVRC">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved positive socio-cultural norms and practices that promote the rights of women and girls by September 2021.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is a notable increase in gender responsiveness and support for survivors to access justice by community members in Kilifi and Meru Counties. By creating awareness at the community level through dialogues, sensitization forums, and local media stations, the community members are now aware of their rights and are also able to identify and support those who are violated to seek justice.  This has brought about positive socio-cultural norms and practices for instance help-seeking behavior and demand for specialized legal and counseling services has increased over time during the implementation period. 
Gender Champions, Women Group Leaders, and paralegals continue to be beacons of Justice for SGBV survivors in the communities, they have shown more commitment by continuing to champion for the rights of women and girls by accompanying them through the case management process and holding duty bearers accountable for their actions.  This is evidenced by the high number of clients received at our offices where 80% confirmed to have been referred by people who have interacted with CREAW in different forums.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proportion of men and women reporting to have acquired new knowledge and skills to engage and support access to justice for survivors of SGBV.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">beneficiaries who testify they have gained and improved knowledge on how to support survivors</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-12-30"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="80% of clients confirmed to have been referred by people who have interacted with CREAW in different forums.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">State actors demonstrate improved response (better knowledge, attitude, and practice) to SGBV and other human rights violations on women and girls in Kilifi and Meru Counties.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Timely and seamless response to SGBV cases
There is continued collaboration between state actors and other SGBV responders as a result of changed attitudes towards issues of gender violence in Meru and Kilifi Counties. In turn, timely and seamless services to survivors along the referral pathway and preventative measures have been incorporated in the respective agencies. The police, ODPP, Judiciary, Probations Department, County Gender Department, WROs, and the local Administration are working together as a response unit and have also incorporated awareness creation as part of their work. To further enhance access to justice, the courts facilitate survivors to attend court through poor man&apos;s kitty as is the case of Kilifi law courts and Tigania Law courts in Meru County. In Kilifi County, the Local administration has developed a committal document where community members sign committing not to hold disco matanga when they are berieved to curb teenage pregnancy. Disco matangas have in the past been cited Timely and seamless response to SGBV cases
There is continued collaboration between state actors and other SGBV responders as a result of changed attitudes towards issues of gender violence in Meru and Kilifi Counties. In turn, timely and seamless services to survivors along the referral pathway and preventative measures have been incorporated in the respective agencies. The police, ODPP, Judiciary, Probations Department, County Gender Department, WROs, and the local Administration are working together as a response unit and have also incorporated awareness creation as part of their work. To further enhance access to justice, the courts facilitate survivors to attend court through poor man&apos;s kitty as is the case of Kilifi law courts and Tigania Law courts in Meru County. In Kilifi County, the Local administration has developed a committal document where community members sign committing not to hold disco matanga when they are berieved to curb teenage pregnancy. Disco matangas have in the past been cited as grounds where young girls are lured into pre-marital sex many resulting in unwanted teenage pregnancies. 

Uptake of diversion by the courts
In Kilifi and Meru Counties, the courts have taken it upon themselves to train and implement diversion of matters to better address SGBV matters, especially those involving minors (The Romeo and Juliet cases). Diversion has been given offenders a second chance in life, assisting them to reintegrate into the community and reduce the risks of re-offending.  It has further ensured that individuals avoid a criminal record but atone for their mistakes, more so in Romeo and Juliet cases where both the survivor and perpetrator are minors posing a challenge for both prosecutors and judicial officers to make careful judgments about who should be prosecuted and what punishment if any is appropriate. The courts have taken it to themselves to train the members of the CUC and those involved in the administration of criminal justice on Diversion Policy, National Prosecution Policy, Article 159 of the Constitution of Kenya, and International Legal Framework that emphasizes the use of diversion as an alternative to prosecution. In Meru County, the Nkubu Law Courts CUC members have been trained with support from the United States Department of Justice. The courts are using the CUC&#x2019;s platform to sensitize their members on the importance of diversion. The uptake of diversion has lessened the burden of cases in courts as reported by Nkubu CUC Secretary.

Commitment by the County commanders to mobilize and support police training on GBV SOPs
The commitment by County Commanders on Kilifi and Meru Counties to support the delivery of the training on NPS GBV SOPs is a clear indication of the need by the agency to effectively and efficiently deliver the services from their end. This shift of attitude in collaboration between CSOs and police has enabled survivors to get services in a more dignified way from the police stations.
Further in Meru, the County commander allocated a Trainer from NPS well versed with the GBV SOPs to conduct the training making the uptake of the training. In Kilifi Couty, the training was delivered by an advocate of the high court from the ODPP  a good practice in collaboration between NPS and ODPP in addressing SGBV and human rights violations on women and girls.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number  and nature of demonstrable contributions made by duty bearers to better provide access to justice for women and girls</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support  offered offered by the local administration towards eliminating GBV by adhering to the GBV referral pathways mechanisms.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-12-30"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1.1.1. Carry out 8 quarterly multi sectoral County and Sub County GBV technical working group (TWG) engagements meetings (4 in Meru, 4 in Kilifi)">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </target>
     <actual value="There is continued collaboration between state actors and other SGBV responders as a result of changed attitudes towards issues of gender violence in Meru and Kilifi Counties. In turn, timely and seamless services to survivors along the referral pathway and preventative measures have been incorporated in the respective agencies. The police, ODPP, Judiciary, Probations Department, County Gender Department, WROs, and the local Administration are working together as a response unit and have also incorporated awareness creation as part of their work. To further enhance access to justice, the courts facilitate survivors to attend court through poor man&apos;s kitty as is the case of Kilifi law courts and Tigania Law courts in Meru County. In Kilifi County, the Local administration has developed a committal document where community members sign committing not to hold disco matanga when they are berieved to curb teenage pregnancy. Disco matangas have in the past been cited as grounds where young girls are lured into pre-marital sex many resulting in unwanted teenage pregnancies.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">20-member Pro bono lawyers and 20-member counselors network established to support legal aid, legal representation, and psychosocial support for women and girls survivors of SGBV.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">To ensure comprehensive access of services to Survivors, CREAW employed different strategies that included working with a team of full-time &amp; pro bono lawyers and Counselors (3 full-time &amp; 2 pro bono) to offer legal and psychosocial support, contracting two shelter facilities, launching a toll-free line (0800-720-186) and issuance of dignity kits to women and girls to meet their immediate hygiene needs. This facilitated:
Restoration of dignity to women and girls
The dignity of survivors of SGBV has been restored through counseling in a survivor-centered approach that has enabled their healing process. This was achieved through tele-counseling, one-on-one sessions as well as group therapies. Counseling has fostered psychological resilience to a new state of life where survivors heal from trauma and can live their lives normally after the counseling sessions. Pro bono counseling has reached 177 (80 girls, 97 women) through group therapy sessions and  87 on one-on-one sessions (82F; 5M). The clients suffered psychological trauma from cases of Physical Violence as the lead cause of trauma; Sexual Violence (Rape/defilement, emotional and economic Violence. Other cases were Suicidal, missing Child; depression cases; HIV Adherence Counseling cases; cases of Compassion fatigue (caregivers). Therapy is ongoing for 21 clients while 61  have been concluded our clients are doing well. Cumulatively, 255 (250,5M) benefited from in-person (Group &amp; one-on-one) counseling services during the project cycle while 528 survivors got immediate relief through online counseling from CREAW&#x2019;s hotline.

Fostered a sense of security and safety to survivors 
Through the provision of shelter support, the survivors were assured of a temporal safe accommodation and refuge when their homes were no longer safe for them. Through the shelter support, survivors were able to access good nutrition, security, and linkage to medical, counseling, and legal services. The support came in handy to the shelter service providers and enabled the rescue of more survivors and smooth facilitation of survivors&apos; access to other response-related services. Ripples international Tumaini center reported an increase of 5% in the admission of survivors while Okoa Sasa in Kilifi reported an 11 % increase in admission of survivors to their shelter facilities. During the project cycle 418 (338 under 18yrs, 80 women), Kilifi County accounted for the highest number of survivors at 62% of the total survivors supported with temporal shelter.
Further, the hotline provided an avenue to reach a wider population with legal, psychosocial, referral services, and general information remotely. This instilled a sense of security, confidentiality, and support to the survivor without fear of the stigmatization that a survivor can face while reporting in person. It as well minimized contact with the service provider thus minimizing the spread of the COVID 19 virus.

Access to Justice for Survivors
The support has ensured retributive justice for major crimes while remedial measures were instituted for those seeking care and protection of children as well as reconciliation through alternative dispute resolution. The legal team gave legal advice to both survivors and witnesses participating in GBV related proceedings and monitored the cases to ensure that the survivors are receiving appropriate legal support including legal advice and representation in court. 68 (7 girls, 61 women) clients benefitted from legal services relating to Inheritance rights; separation of marital properties; succession matters, illegal eviction of the clients from their property; children matters, and sexual offenses matters with 21 matters still ongoing in different courts in Kilifi and Meru. CREAW Hotline registered 1,948 clients seeking legal support across and not limited to Kilifi and Meru Counties.

Improved hygiene and wellness of the women and girls
The provision of the dignity kits aimed at meeting the basic hygiene needs of women and girls of reproductive age. However, the beneficiaries have reported a ripple effect from the dignity kits. &#x201C;I decided to save the money I would have otherwise used to procure the sanitary pads, masks, soap, pants, and sanitizer contained in the dignity kit to start up a business. Now I have a business that gives puts food on the table and in a good day, I make a profit of Ksh.300&#x201D;, Susan* reported during an evaluation exercise in July 2021. The project reached 1,500 beneficiaries with dignity kits in the two target counties.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of women and girls receiving pro bono legal assistance, advice, representation on GBV cases, and counseling services</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total number of beneficiaries who benefitted from the pyscho- social and legal support offered.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-12-30"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="A localised CREAW hotline where survivors of violence can report cases and be supported with legal and psychosocial support in place.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </target>
     <actual value="Pro bono counseling has reached 177 (80 girls, 97 women) through group therapy sessions and  87 on one-on-one sessions (82F; 5M). The clients suffered psychological trauma from cases of Physical Violence as the lead cause of trauma; Sexual Violence (Rape/defilement, emotional and economic Violence. Other cases were Suicidal, missing Child; depression cases; HIV Adherence Counseling cases; cases of Compassion fatigue (caregivers). Therapy is ongoing for 21 clients while 61  have been concluded our clients are doing well. Cumulatively, 255 (250,5M) benefited from in-person (Group &amp; one-on-one) counseling services during the project cycle while 528 survivors got immediate relief through online counseling from CREAW&#x2019;s hotline">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">10,000 men and women (7000 women, 3000 men) equipped with knowledge and skills on the rights of women and girls and take action to support access to justice for women and girl&#x2019;s survivors of SGBV.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">To equip men and women with knowledge on the rights of women and girls, CREAW adopted different strategies
Community engagement
Community dialogues were conducted to create awareness at the community level with the ultimate goal of creating awareness on the rights of women and girls as well as how the community members can play the role of an active bystander to support survivors&apos; access to justice. The dialogues focused on creating awareness on GBV issues, including the types of GBV and the referral pathways, available services, advocating for the need to use their voice to fight GBV, and responding to GBV during the COVID-19 pandemic. Community Conversations were held directly reaching 3,086 (798M; 2,288F). Further, during the distribution of dignity kits,1,500 ( 1,350 Girls, 150 young women) were reached with messages on menstrual hygiene and management and how lack of this basic human right to women and girls can be a trigger to abuse.
International celebrated days
In March 2021, CREAW in collaboration with TWG members and the Department of Gender in Kilifi and Meru celebrated International Women&#x2019;s day with the theme  &#x201C;Women in To equip men and women with knowledge on the rights of women and girls, CREAW adopted different strategies
Community engagement
Community dialogues were conducted to create awareness at the community level with the ultimate goal of creating awareness on the rights of women and girls as well as how the community members can play the role of an active bystander to support survivors&apos; access to justice. The dialogues focused on creating awareness on GBV issues, including the types of GBV and the referral pathways, available services, advocating for the need to use their voice to fight GBV, and responding to GBV during the COVID-19 pandemic. Community Conversations were held directly reaching 3,086 (798M; 2,288F). Further, during the distribution of dignity kits,1,500 ( 1,350 Girls, 150 young women) were reached with messages on menstrual hygiene and management and how lack of this basic human right to women and girls can be a trigger to abuse.
International celebrated days
In March 2021, CREAW in collaboration with TWG members and the Department of Gender in Kilifi and Meru celebrated International Women&#x2019;s day with the theme  &#x201C;Women in leadership: Achieving an equal future in a COVID-19 world&#x201D;. It celebrated the tremendous efforts by women and girls around the world in shaping a more equal future and recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic that culminated in awarding 2 gender champions by the Kilifi County government for championing women&apos;s rights and fight against GBV. Approximately 500 people were sensitized on the importance of upholding gender equity to achieve an equal future for women which cannot be realized if they continue to be denied their basic human rights. During the day of the African Child, CREAW held joint activities with the children&#x2019;s department and other stakeholders reaching to 385 children from selected schools to amplify the voice in ensuring structures are put in place to safeguard and protect children in the target counties and beyond for the successful implementation of the Africa Children&#x2019;s Charter.

Social Media Messaging
During the project implementation period, we kept our audience up to date with activities happening in both Kilifi and Meru counties like dignity kits distribution, community engagements as well as court users committee various meetings. Some of the social media engagements equally include resourcing National Police Service gender desks with dignity and menstrual hygiene management kits to ensure the health and dignity of survivors seeking police services. The hashtag used is: #UsawaNaHaki

HashTag	Link

	https://bit.ly/3EniT7k

	https://bit.ly/3stCMr8

	https://bit.ly/3H496Vp

	https://bit.ly/3yRaRSY

	https://bit.ly/32cRVlW

	https://bit.ly/3Jc8jDL

	https://bit.ly/32cjHPv



Radio and TV Talk shows: 
CREAW held four(4) Radio talk shows to discuss human rights and gender-related topical discussions reaching approximately 1,000,000 listeners. During the talk shows, CREAW engaged different panelists including community activists, the department of gender officers, office of the director of public prosecution to discuss the referral pathway, the legal process of  GBV cases, the impact of COVID 19 on the justice system, and what the government is doing to mitigate those challenges.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of individuals (disaggregated by type, age, and gender) with improved knowledge and skills towards the elimination of all forms of violence</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">beneficiaries who report to have the capability and information on GBV and its preventive measures</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-12-30"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10,000 men and women (7000 women, 3000 men) equipped with knowledge and skills on the rights of women and girls and take action to support access to justice for women an girls survivors of SGBV.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </target>
     <actual value="Community dialogues were conducted to create awareness at the community level with the ultimate goal of creating awareness on the rights of women and girls as well as how the community members can play the role of an active bystander to support survivors&apos; access to justice. The dialogues focused on creating awareness on GBV issues, including the types of GBV and the referral pathways, available services, advocating for the need to use their voice to fight GBV, and responding to GBV during the COVID-19 pandemic. Community Conversations were held directly reaching 3,086 (798M; 2,288F). Further, during the distribution of dignity kits,1,500 ( 1,350 Girls, 150 young women) were reached with messages on menstrual hygiene and management and how lack of this basic human right to women and girls can be a trigger to abuse.">
      <location ref="Kilifi and Meru"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
