<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-CACITNO57289-Activity2.1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-57289" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental Centre for Oil Spills and Gas Flaring (NACGOND)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Round Table for Policy Briefings (Civil Society, State and Local Governments, Academia and Community Groups)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The roundtable event took place at Swiss Spirit Hotel, Stadium Road, Port Harcourt with participants coming across the Niger Delta. Two policy brief documents titled &#x201C;Addressing Oil Theft and Artisanal Refining: Exploring Sustainable Policy Options&#x201D; and &#x201C;Alternative Livelihood for Repentant Oil Theft and Artisanal Refining in Nigeria&#x2019;s Niger Delta: Community-Based Policy Options&#x201D; developed and presented. Emphasis was laid on: (1). Agriculture and agro-allied should emphasise more on fish farming, food processing, preservation and storage as well as related activities. (2). Capacity building and empowerment briefs should place emphasis on skill acquisition and entrepreneurship development with availability of micro credit facilities to fund start-ups and related economic activities. (3). Tri-sectoral peace-building approach which involves government, Multinational Oil Companies (MNOCs), and communities should be the desired approach to be used in penetrating Niger Delta communities because of its peculiar development challenges.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="Activity 2.1" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute for Niger Delta Studies, Bayelsa State, Nigeria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-19" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Venue: 1. Swiss Hotel, Port Harcourt Rivers State, Nigeria.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Cordination</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coordinator&apos;s Office</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rev. Fr. Edward Obi, MSP</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coordinator of NACGOND</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>08132795461</telephone>
   <email>edyobi@gmail.com</email>
   <website>https://nacgond.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">17 Ndashi Street, D/Line, Port Harcourt</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Venue: 1. Swiss Hotel, Port Harcourt Rivers State, Nigeria.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1. One (1) communiqu&#xE9; produced and endorsed by participants in the event 2. Two (2) national Newspaper covered the event with publications of the event communique 3. TV Coverage of all the sessions of the event by AIT 4. Policy Brief was produced and circulated among the stakeholders 5. Radio news relayed of the event(Nigeria info FM, 92.3) Outcomes The youths of the Niger Delta embraced other income generating options</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-06-19"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-06-20"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2019-06-19">4228587</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitments from Stakeholders</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Buy-in of government officials at the caliber of Permanent Secretaries, Commissioners, members of State Houses of Assembly, Community Opinion Leaders, Traditional Leaders, Youth Group Leaders, Women Group Leaders and People Living with Disabilities (PLWDs) present at the round table. Buy-in will further instigate policy and legislative action to bring about other income generating options for the youths of the Niger Delta. This will significantly reduce chances of oil theft, pipeline vandalism and artisanal refining of crude oil which is causing increase in the number of oil spill incidences responsible for environmental pollution in the entire Niger Delta.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is significant indication that, available number of youths taking up alternative sources of livelihood are going to increase geometrically provided such sources are made available with entrepreneurship training and start up grants or subventions for youths in project communities.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022;Participants at the round table were made to commit to personal and institutional commitments to advocate and implement resolutions agreed upon by stakeholders in their various states and communities. &#x2022;Participants also committed to ensure that, heads of relevant government agencies and other critical stakeholders invited to the round table dialogue followed up closely to ensure that, people of decision making level in various agencies of state and communities were present during the round table dialogue and not representatives. &#x2022;Round table events of this nature require more days of intensive deliberations to arrive at stakeholder most informed actions. &#x2022;Subsequently, there should be adequate community representation in the event to escalate results at wider levels.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-06-19"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-20"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
