<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-CACITNO57289-Activity 5.3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-57289" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental Centre for Oil Spills and Gas Flaring (NACGOND)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conduct environmental education and training of club members and mapping out action plan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental tailored education trainings were conducted in eight school environmental clubs that were established in Community Secondary School, Mogho Gokana LGA, Rivers State, Comprehensive High School, Aking, Akamkpa LGA, Cross River State and Mkpanak Community Secondary School, Ibeno LGA, Akwa Ibom State. Others include New Apostolic Model Secondary School, Owaza, Abia State, Immanuel international school,Owaza, Abia State, Dean of wisdom Christian Model Group of Schools, Owaza, Abia State Owaza Sec-ondary School, Owaza, Abia State and Community Senior Secondary School, Akpajo-Eleme, Eleme L.G.A, Rivers State. At the end of the trainings, club members acquired new knowledge on environmental science and developed an action plan for their clubs to cover one year ending December, 2019.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="5.3" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment Human Rights and Development (CEHRD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="5.3" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Environmental Right and Advocacy (FENRAND)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="5.3" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for the Conervatonof the Earth</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="5.3" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GREEN CONCERN FOR DEVLOPMENT (GREENCODE)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="5.3" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peace Point Development Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-25" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activities took place as planned within the reporting period in parts of Rivers, Akwa Ibom, Cross River and Abia States.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inquiries are usually directed to the National Coordinator of NACGOND.</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coordinator&apos;s Office</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rev. Fr. Edward Obi, MSP</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>08132795461</telephone>
   <email>edyobi@gmail.com</email>
   <website>https://nacgond.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">17 Ndashi Street, D/Line, Port Harcourt</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity was implemented in the South South region of Nigeria.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policy areas covered in this activity include environmental education and climate change aimed at building leadership skills in youths of the Niger Delta region.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-05-29"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-10-02"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2019-12-31">1764906</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is increase in the number of Secondary School Students with adequate environmental knowledge in project communities across the Niger Delta.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Club members record increase in the level of environmental awareness evident in the spirit of competition among them.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Club members&#x2019; quest for more environmental awareness has significantly increased as evident in the spirit of competition recorded during the 2019 NACGOND essay and quiz programmes. Community Secondary School, Mogho in Gokana LGA of Rivers State which was one of the newly inducted schools with environmental club came out 3rd position in the essay competition. This competition is also evident in the increasing number of club members taking independent actions in sharing acquired environmental knowledge among their peers at school and in their various communities among friends and parents. Of note is the ongoing work by environmental club members of Ken Saro Wiwa Polytechnic Secondary School, Bori in Khana LGA of Rivers State where club members have incorporated outreach environmental awareness creation in other communities. The students visited Buan community in Khana LGA and Mogho community in Gokana LGA for environmental awareness outreach. This outreach has attracted the attention of the Rivers State Commissioner of Environment who has pledged to assist the students expand the environmental outreach programme to penetrate other communities and LGAs around Ogoni axis where oil theft, pipeline vandalism and artisanal refining of crude is significantly high at the moment.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is improved environmental performance and livelihood security in the Niger Delta.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The students have acquired the intended environmental education as planned in various schools across the Niger Delta focusing on forming their minds on environmental related issues. This, as mid-level outcome is expected to lead the students into developing independent minded actions as advocates in approaching the issue of continued pollution including those triggered by third party interference in oil theft and pipeline vandalism in the region.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-05-29"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-02"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
