<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-CACITNO57289-Activity 2.3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-57289" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental Centre for Oil Spills and Gas Flaring (NACGOND)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sensitization of communities to stop pipeline vandalism and artisanal refining of crude oil in project communities.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Delta State, two communities were sensitized, Ufuoma Community, Ugheli North LGA and Ukpiovwin Community, Udu LGA of the state. In Rivers State, Kalio-Ama community in Okrika LGA and Ebocha in Okwuzi Community of Ogba/Ndoni/Egbema/ LGA of Rivers State were sensitized. Also, two communities, Otuasega and Gbanrantoru in Bayelsa state were also sensitized on the dangers of pipeline vandalism and artisanal refining of crude oil on the environment and livelihoods of the people. At the end of the exercise, participants made commitments to safeguarding their environment and pledged to form groups and cooperatives to further strengthen the advocacy in the area. They also agreed to make contact with relevant bodies who could help in livelihood trainings so that, the youths in the areas could to be enrolled in skill acquisition programmes as alternative sources to local oil theft and artisanal refining of crude. Secondly, environmental awareness of participants substantially increased based on the information received during the sensitization which inform community members&#x2019; decision to be reporting cases of pipeline vandalism and artisanal refining in the area once they occur to relevant authorities. In Delta State, the activity achieved lower level outcome with the buy-in from the community leadership.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="2.3" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="2.3" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="IG">Bayelsa NGO Forum (BANGOF), Poverty Alleviation for the Poor Initiative (PAFPI) African Center for Leadership, Strategy and Development (Center-LSD). Leadership Initiative for Transformation and Empowerment (Lite-Africa).</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="2.3" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gas Alert for Sustainable Initiative (GASIN)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="2.3" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leadership Initiative for Transformation and Empowerment (LITE-Africa)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="2.3" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Poverty Alleviation for the Poor Initiative (PAFPI)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-06" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity was implemented by five partners at different dates starting from the 5th of June, 2019 in different parts of Delta, Bayelsa and Rivers States.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The National Coordinator of NACGOND is the project director and all inquiries are directed to him.</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coordinator&apos;s Office</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rev. Fr. Edward Obi, MSP</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>08132795461</telephone>
   <email>edyobi@gmail.com</email>
   <website>https://nacgond.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#17 Ndashi Street, D/Line, Port Harcourt.</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity took place in Delta, Bayelsa and Rivers States being the heartland of the Niger Delta area of Nigeria.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15131" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity was aimed at strengthening local institutions to safeguard environment and livelihoods damaged by years of oil spills and gas flaring incidences in the Niger Delta of Nigeria.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-06-06"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-11-20"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2019-12-31">2315940</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Likely evidence of behavioral change taking place in project communities where activity was implemented.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In sensitized communities, the activity achieved lower level outcome with significant buy-in from community groups. Outcome would lead to geometric reduction in cases of oil theft and artisanal refining in project communities as a result of youths taking up alternative sources of livelihoods. Such level of reduction would instigate further reduction in levels of environmental pollution in the communities where this activity was implemented in the long run.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is strong evidence that, in sensitized communities, applied knowledge acquired on the dangers of oil theft and artisanal refining of crude is helping community members better protect their environment and helped to connect them to other sources of livelihood.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-06-06"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-11-20"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
