<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-CACITNO57289-Activity 5.1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-57289" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental Centre for Oil Spills and Gas Flaring (NACGOND)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advocacy visit to heads of targeted schools for their endorsement and support of the project objective.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Seventeen targeted school heads were generally visited across the 6 Niger Delta States where implementing partners are based. These schools include Mkpanak Community Secondary School Ibeno, Akwa Ibom State, Community Secondary Grammer School, Ebughu, Mbo LGA, Akwa Ibom State and Comprehensive High School, Aking, Akamkpa L.G.A, Rivers State. Others include Community Secondary School, Mogho, Gokana LGA Rivers State, Secondary Grammar School, Ibeno L.G.A, Akwa Ibom State, Community Senior Secondary School, Akpajo, Eleme LGA of Rivers State and Ibaka Community Secondary School, Mbo L.G.A, Akwa Ibom State. All the school heads visited endorsed the project objective for the year which led to the ground work for the establishment of school-based Environmental Clubs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="5.1" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment Human Rights and Development (CEHRD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="5.1" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for the Conservation of the Earth FOCONE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="5.1" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GREEN CONCERN FOR DEVLOPMENT (GREENCODE)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="5.1" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peace Point Develpment Fundation- PPDF</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="5.1" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="NACGOND">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NACGOND school club activity was implemented in Cross River, Akwa Ibom, Abia, Rivers, Bayelsa and Delta States.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-28" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity was implemented by various partners on separate dates between May and July, 2019 across states in the Niger Delta.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">All project inquiries goes to the National Coordinator of NACGOND.</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coordinator&apos;s Office</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rev. Fr. Edward Obi, MSP</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>08132795461</telephone>
   <email>edyobi@gmail.com</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">17 Ndashi Street, D/Line, Port Harcourt</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity took place in some states of the Niger Delta, Cross River, Akwa Ibom and Rivers States.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="11120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NACGOND School Clubs have become an instrument for successive transmission of environmental education to youths in a bid to forming the minds towards environmental awareness creation in schools and communities in the Niger Delta.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-05-28"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-07-02"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2019-12-31">343398</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022;Seven heads of targeted schools endorsed the establishment of Environmental Clubs in their schools and pledged to support the sustainability of the club after establishment.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">School principals&apos; consent given for the establishment of environmental clubs.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The approval for the establishment of environmental clubs in targeted schools across the Niger Delta is seen as a process which will lead to lower level outcome being that a students&apos; mind is formed to begin to campaign independently for better management of environmental problems in the Niger Delta including cases of oil theft, pipeline vandalism and artisanal refining. This, on the long run is expected to lead into upper level outcome, being that, the campaign will increase students&apos; awareness creation among their peers, community people and the Niger Delta as a whole with reduction in cases of oil theft, pipeline vandalism and artisanal refining of crude oil.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The heads of targeted schools&#x2019; endorsement for the establishment of Environmental Clubs in their respective schools and pledge to ensure club sustainability which will put the right atmosphere to begin forest conservation, development and natural resource management sensitization among students in these clubs is a positive sign for the future. On the long run, these students shall become environmental vanguards in their schools impacting environmental leadership skills among their peers. At higher level outcome, student environmental leaders shall independently begin to campaign against environmental pollution including those triggered by third party interference.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-05-28"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-02"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
