<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-CACITNO57289-Supplimentary.activity.3.3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-57289" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental Centre for Oil Spills and Gas Flaring (NACGOND)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conduct quarterly visits to the communities/Environmental Monitoring Clubs to assess their performance.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Environmental Clubs were set up to serve as link to penetrate community structures for enlightenment campaigns on peculiar environmental problems in parts of the Niger Delta. So far, club members were visited in all the six states of the Niger Delta where community clubs were established to ascertain their performance. This was to ensure that, the clubs work in line with their objective which was to monitor environmental pollution issues in their communities and report same to appropriate authorities and also to disseminate climate change information to local people. Oil spills, gas flaring and deforestation in parts of Delta, Bayelsa, Rivers and Cross River State necessitated the establishment of these clubs with the objective to assess performance of the communities&#x2019; emerging environmental challenges. After working with opinion leaders, club members were selected, given the training and clubs set up. Already, club members at community level have begun work in various communities where they are operating with some even taking up independent initiatives in reporting oil spills that occurred in their areas to National Oil Spill Detection and Response Agency (NOSDRA), being the Federal Government&#x2019;s environmental regulatory agency for oil and gas activities in the country. Club members were encouraged to carry out campaigns within their communities and to create awareness and also plant trees as a measure to combat climate change effect. They were equally advised to register the clubs with the regulatory authorities so as to gain full status as Community Based Organisations. More so, strategies for engaging with the oil companies, government agents, and other stakeholders to ensure environmental safety in the region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="Supplimentary 3.3" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Environmental Right and Development (FENRAD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="Supplimentary 3.3" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coaition on Gas Flaring and Oil Spills in the Niger Delta- NACGOND</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="supplimentary 3.3" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="Supp. 3.3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity was implemented in all the six states of the Niger Delta with NACGOND presence</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-24" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity took place on separate dates in different states as planned by implementing partners.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">All related project inquiries are directed to the National Coordinator who is the Project Director.</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coordinator&apos;s Office</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rev. Fr. Edward Obi,MSP</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>08132795461</telephone>
   <email>edyobi@gmail.com</email>
   <website>https://nacgond.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#17 Ndashi Street, D/Line, Port Harcourt.</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity took place in parts of the Niger Delta of Nigeria.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relevant environmental education was created in communities using different channels of communication aimed at stimulating collective action from the grassroots towards proper environmental management.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-05-24"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-06-29"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2019-12-31">1903600</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A total of 180 community environmental club members in 6 communities across Cross River, Akwa Ibom, Abia, Rivers, Bayelsa and Delta States were given rel-evant environmental education which will instigate action leading to better envi-ronmental management in their communities.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stimulation of grassroots environmental management action in communities where the project was implemented.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Club members&#x2019; confidence has increased significantly showing in their ability to independently report cases of oil spills and gas leakage in their communities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community members show instant buy-in to project objective.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is increase in the rate of independent action even in monitoring and reporting of environmental issues within project communities.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-05-24"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-01-29"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
