<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-CACITNO57289-Activity 5.4.</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-57289" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental Centre for Oil Spills and Gas Flaring (NACGOND)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organise Essay and Quiz Competition for the Secondary School Clubs at State Levels.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The essay competition was held centrally at the University of Port Harcourt after various schools submitted names of representatives for the competition. The competition took place on the same day with the quiz to avoid suspicion of impersonation or a situation where teachers could write for their students. After entries were collated, a team of examiners who were drawn from among secondary school teachers in the state were given a mandate to examine the students and scores were awarded accordingly. At the end, Tamunobubefebara Gladin of Kings College, Okrika who scored a total of 90% came first; Miibekee Favour with the score of 88% from Bodo City Girls Seconday School, Gokana came second while Adoma B. Mary of Community Secondary School, Mgbede, Gokana LGA with a total score of 85% came third for the essay writing competition. Onyekurundu Wisdom U. of Community Secondary School, Mgbede, Gokana with the score of 75% and Barisere Kpoobari Gbarabe who scored 70% from Ken Saro Wiwa Polytechnic Secondary School, Bori, Khana came fourth and fifth respectively and were given consolation prices as well. In Akwa Ibom State, students of Saint Peter and Paul Comprehensive High School, Ibeno came first with Ibaka Community Secondary Grammar School, Ibaka coming second while Mkpanak Comprehensive School, Ibeno came third respectively. For Abia State, Dean of Wisdom Christian Model Group of Schools, Owaza, Ukwa West came first with National High School, Azumiri, Ukwa East coming second and New Apostolic Model Secondary School, Owaza, Ukwa West finishing third respectively.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity was to orientate and sensitize youths of Secondary School age on Environmental Education for behavioural change and forming their minds for a future in the Niger Delta region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="5.4" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Conflict and Gender Studies (CCGS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="5.4" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Environmental Right and Advocacy (FENRAND)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="5.4" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peace Point Development Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="5.4." type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="Activity 5.4.">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity was implemented in three states of Rivers, Abia and Akwa Ibom. The center in Port Harcourt Rivers State hosted participants from Delta State as well.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-24" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The dates for this activity was 25th of May, 2019 for the event at the University of Port Harcourt, 28th June, 2019 for the event at Abia State and 23rd July, 2019 for the event at Akwa Ibom State respectively.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inquiries are handled by the National Coordinator who is the Project Director.</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coordinator&apos;s Office.</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rev. Fr. Edward Obi, MSP</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>08132795461</telephone>
   <email>edyobi@gmail.com</email>
   <website>https://nacgond.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#17 Ndashi Street, D-Line, Port Harcourt.</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity took place at Mbo Council Hall, Mbo LGA, Akwa Ibom State, East Global Hotel, Obuzor Asa,Ukwa West LGA of Abia State and Auditorium of Centre for Conflict and Gender Studies, University of Port Harcourt.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="41081" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Club members take action in sharing knowledge gained through essay and quiz competitions as upcoming leaders who will resolve environmental problems around them. The quiz competition gave the students opportunity to explore further environmental knowledge especially climate change education.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-05-24"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-07-23"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2019-12-31">3833280</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Essay and quiz competitions enhanced students&apos; mental capability in handling environmental issues confronting them in the Niger Delta with a global picture on how those problems can be jointly addressed through policy and legislation.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is increasing demand that the competitions be extended to other schools within the region.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A total number of 235 club members and 34 teachers who prepared the students and attended the 2019 essay and quiz competitions gained further knowledge on environmental awareness which is helping to expand independent actions in sharing environmental knowledge.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase in the level of competitiveness among students leading to higher consciousness on environmental issues among them.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secondary School Students who participate in the essay and quiz competitions have gained higher consciousness and awareness level on issues of environmental management which will be helpful for them in the future.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-05-24"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-23"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
