<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-CACITNO57289-Activity3.1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-57289" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental Centre for Oil Spills and Gas Flaring (NACGOND)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity 3.1 Create awareness in targeted communities and all stakeholders on the national climate change policy of Nigeria.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Communities where this activity was implemented were first visited to solicit the support of the gate keepers to this project. After reaching agreements, a date was agreed on separate oc-casions in various project locations when the activity was implemented. In various venues across many project locations, sensitization workshops were held with youth groups, women groups and other community groups carefully selected to be in attendance. During the sensiti-zation workshop, general environmental awareness was firstly created to get participants un-derstand the underlying factors to proper environmental management. Climate change issues were discussed further focusing on local peculiarities while mainstreaming local adaptation measures as participants brainstormed on those identified issues. Highlights of the programme in each case was to have participants commit to pursuing climate change course in the various communities with step down sensitization at community levels while focusing on building community resilience to climate change.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To create awareness on the National Climate Change Policy of Nigeria mainstreaming local adaptation measures and mitigation strategies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="3.1" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Leadership Centre for Stratey, Leaderhip nd Development- Centre LSD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="3.1" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Environmental Right and Advocacy (FENRAND)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="3.1" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GREEN CONCERN FOR DEVLOPMENT (GREENCODE)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="3.1" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KEBETKACHE- KEBETKCHE WOMENDEVELOPMENT and RESOURCE CNTRE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="3.1" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Movement for the Survival of the Ogoni People (MOSOP)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Activity 3.1" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="3.1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thus activity was implemented by five implementing partners in different states of the Niger Delta.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-25" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity was held in Buan Community Town Hall, Khana LGA, Rivers State, Ulok Ulok Hall, Ibeno Local Government Secretariat, Akwa Ibom State, Villa Roy Hotel Umuahia Abia State, Nigeria, Old Ekuri Community, Akamkpa, LGA, Cross Rivers State and Chadef Hotel, Inter-bau Roundabout, Government house Road, Asaba, Delta State.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">All inquiries should go to the National Coordinator of NACGOND.</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coordinator&apos;s Offices</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rev. Fr. Edward Obi, MSP</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coordinator OF NACGOND</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>08132795461</telephone>
   <email>edyobi@gmail.com</email>
   <website>https://nacgond.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">17 Ndashi Street, D/Line, Port Harcourt.</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity took place in parts of Rivers, Akwa Ibom, Abia, Cross Rivers and Delta States.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="41081" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022;A significant number of participants who attended the programme in different project locations welcomed the idea of creating awareness on the National Climate Change Policy of Nigeria and their knowledge on local adaptation measures was enhanced. &#x2022;A significant number of pparticipants acknowledged the need for a state level climate change action plans mainstreaming mitigation measures. &#x2022;73 community members from Owaza, Ukwa West and Ukwa East LGAs who partici-pated in the programme in Abia State consented that, there was improved understand-ing of climate change issues especially local adaptation measures and found the need to escalate the sensitization at community level.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-05-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-11-18"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2019-12-30">3659484</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is in existence in project communities that felt need for local adaptation measures such as tree planting exercises in various communities to combat climate change effect and the use of alternative sources of fuel wood for cooking. These two created significantly strong impression on the participants.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increasing signs of local adaptation measures to climate change effect in communities where activity was carried out.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A significant number of participants consented to the need for tree planting as climate change adaptation measure in their respective environs and also expressed their strong desire for relying on alternative sources of fuel wood for cooking. This message was to cascade down to various community levels of participants. Secondly, various participants developed felt need to educate immediate community members on environmental awareness mainstreaming local actions that could exacerbate climate change and how community members could build climate change resilience through measures such as climate smart agriculture, proper refuse management practices such as waste segregation to enable better handling of materials such as plastic waste and reliance on reuse and recycling.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity recorded lower level outcome with buy-in from participants to escalate acquired climate change knowledge at grassroots level to enable local adaptation measures and climate change resilience, much action is required by participants across project communities in the Niger Delta to ensure that, people begin to embrace forestry development and natural resource conservation which is an outcome that will have longer time effect on climate change mitigation and adaptation.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-05-25"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-11-18"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
