<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-CACITNO57289-Activity 2.2 Lobbying and advocacy visits to the Ministry of Environment, NOSDRA and the National Assembly Complex Abuja.</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-57289" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental Centre for Oil Spills and Gas Flaring (NACGOND)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lobbying and advocacy visits to the Ministry of Environment, NOSDRA and the National Assembly Complex Abuja</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Initiate a dialogue &amp; sensitization between oil producing communities, civil society groups, oil majors and the Nigerian government for workable long term sustainable alternatives to oil theft and Artisanal refining.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome Visit to the National Assembly House Committee on Environment afforded the opportunity to re-present the NOSDRA Amendment Bill which, if passed into law will strengthen environmental governance around oil and gas sector in the Niger Delta. Earlier in 2019, Mr. President had refused to consent to the amendment bill sent to him by the National Assembly so a re-engagement of the 9th Assembly will be helpful to put NOSDRA as an oil and gas environmental governance agency in good shape to ensure improvement in the Niger Delta Environment. Most importantly, the issues of human and gender impact which are excluded from the Environmental Impact Assessment Bill were also presented to the National Assembly Committee members. There is generally, an improved relationship between NACGOND and the National Assembly which would enhance the process of environmental governance in the Niger Delta.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity took place on the 25th and 26th of November, 2019 respectively in Abuja and it was targeted at getting the buy-in of the National Assembly Members, Minister of Environment and Director General of National Oil Spill Detection and Response Agency (NOSDRA). The Ministry of Environment, National Oil Spill Detection and Response Agency (NOSDRA) and the National Assembly are state structures that are key in environmental governance in the Niger Delta. Therefore, there is need to have frequent engagements with these agencies and bodies to ensure that, changes in policy and legislation are put in place to salvage the entire Niger Delta from continued environmental decay in the region. The activity was implemented with this at heart targeting the NOSDRA Amendment Bill, Environmental Impact Assessment Act, Petroleum Industry Bill and the Gas Master Plan of Nigeria. Series of policy and legislative sessions were held prior to an official meeting in Abuja targeting key industry stakeholders with the aim of providing technical assistance for the agencies which will enhance the quality of policy and legislation in this line. This visit afforded the opportunity to re-present the NOSDRA Amendment Bill as well as the Environmental Impact Assessment Act to the National Assembly and NOSDRA for re-engagement with the 9th Assembly. At the end of the visit, major achievement was the commitment of stakeholders to re-visit the laws earlier jettisoned by the ruling government of Major General Muhamadu Buhari, Rtd.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="2.2" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment Human Rights and Development (CEHRD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="2.2" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="Lobbying and advocacy visits to the Ministry of Environment, NOSDRA and the National Assembly Complex Abuja.">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NACGOND</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-25" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity took place at the National Assembly Complex and Director General&apos;s Office, NOSDRA Abuja.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NACGOND BOT Chairman</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BOT</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rev. Fr. Edward Obi, MSP</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>2348132795461</telephone>
   <email>edyobi@gmail.com</email>
   <website>https://nacgond.com.</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">17 Ndashi Street, D-Line, Port Harcourt</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity took place in some parts of the Niger Delta region and the Federal Capital Territory, Abuja.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15131" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lobbying and advocacy was aimed at influence policy and legislative change to bring about improvement in environmental governance within the oil and gas sector of Nigeria.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-03-27"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-11-26"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2019-11-26">1134012</value>
  </budget>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advocacy visits took place to the National Assembly Senate Committee on Environment and the Office of the Director General of National Oil Spill Detection and Response Agency (NOSDRA) in Abuja.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Visit opened the door on further engagements with the National Assembly and NOSDRA on key policy and legislative issues needed to improve environmental governance in the Niger Delta of Nigeria.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strong commitment from Nigeria&apos;s Senate Committee Chairman on Environment to re-engage on the NOSDRA Amendment Bill and other related environmental governance bills to improvement environmental conditions in the Niger Delta.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Visit to the National Assembly House Committee on Environment afforded the opportunity to re-present the NOSDRA Amendment Bill which, if passed into law will strengthen environmental governance around oil and gas sector in the Niger Delta. Earlier in 2019, Mr. President had declined assent to the amendment bill sent to him by the National Assembly so a re-engagement of the 9th Assembly will be helpful to put NOSDRA as an oil and gas environmental governance agency in good shape to ensure improvement in the Niger Delta Environment. Most importantly, the issues of human and gender impact which are excluded from the Environmental Impact Assessment Bill were also presented to the National Assembly Committee members. There is generally, an improved relationship between NACGOND and the National Assembly which would enhance the process of environmental governance in the Niger Delta.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-27"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-11-25"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
