<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-IATI-TR-MOI-27-018-163-29440</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="TR-MOI-27-018-163" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local Development and small projects support</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AKED Project/Strengthening Local Governance in Syria/ARC Funding</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity represents the overall project that has been funded by the Dutch MFA. It allows to use the ARC indicators framework as its indicators are the over arching indicators of the whole ARC fund</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="TR-MOI-27-018-163" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LDSPS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="XI-IATI-TR-MOI-27-018-163" type="B1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <transaction ref="DSH0123227-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-01">300000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1st payment recieved</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29440" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dutch MFA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="TR-MOI-27-018-163" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">LDSPS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <sector code="15220" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="DSH0123227">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-01">3600000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Awarded Grant</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29440" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dutch MFA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="TR-MOI-27-018-163" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">LDSPS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <sector code="15220" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Activity-29440-disaggregated-baseline-data-20170731060725.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baseline disaggregation for ARC overall framework indicators (activity 29440)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-07-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">More people don&apos;t have plans to emigrate</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">More people don&apos;t have plans to emigrate</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">OA.6 (disaggregated) Number of programme beneficiaries&#x2019; who report that they have real plans to emigrate within the next year [This indicator is required depending on the programme and its context]</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x2018;Real plans to emigrate&#x2019; refers to concrete measures (i.e.- saving money- selling possessions- chosen destination/route- organized a place to stay- preparing for smuggling/irregular migration- etc.) taken by programme beneficiaries in preparation of moving to another country (including irregular migration)- that provide more insight on the perception of programme beneficiaries towards emigration while indicating the likelihood that such plans will manifest. &#x2018;emigrate&#x2019; refers to the act of moving to another country. Rational: In order to understand and learn more about the impact of the ARC Fund- we must measure the extent to which the ARC programmes have had an influence (positive/negative) on beneficiaries&#x2019; perceptions and hopes regarding their future in the current place of residence. The overarching goal of the ARC Fund is to address root causes of conflict- instability and irregular migration. This means it is also important to measure to what extent beneficiaries are actively considering migration (i.e. have real plans to emigrate) and to be able to track the change in perceptions compared to the start of the programme. Specifically- in order to gain insight in how the intervention has contributed to a situation whereby beneficiaries (increasingly) see a future for themselves in the place where they currently live (i.e.- to test the assumption that the desire and/or necessity to move abroad has decreased/increased). Since this is an impact -indicator (namely overarching indicator) - which attempts to measure at the highest level of long-term change- it is important to recognize that causality may be related to many other factors than the intervention alone. Disaggregation: - Male/ Female - Youth*/Not youth - IDP/Local resident *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who report that they have real plans to emigrate within the next 12 months- at the start of the programme- after two years and at the end of the programme. The number is not cumulative- i.e. you do not add this year&#x2019;s number to last year&#x2019;s number when you report. Data Collection Method: This is an overarching indicator- whereby programme beneficiaries must be asked the question: &#x201C;Do you have real plans to emigrate within the next year?&#x201D; Collecting such data will help gain insight in how the programme has contributed to a change in programme beneficiaries&#x2019;&#x2019; perceptions and hopes regarding their future- compared to the start of the programme &#x2013; i.e. to measure if the desire and/or necessity to move abroad has decreased/increased. This question is difficult to respond when asked directly and may need to be reformulated depending on the local context. several questions will be asked about concrete situations that can be statistically analyzed together. This indicator shall take into consideration the matter of siege (in Ghouta) and borders closing in Syria which might prevent people from preparing concrete plans but yet having the desire to migrate when and if possible in the future. The survey methodology will be using focus group discussions and/or individual questionnaires. The following questions will be asked: - &#x2018;On a scale of 0-3- to what extent do you have real plans to migrate within the next year? Please clarify.&#x2019; 0 &#x2013; none- I have not considered emigration before. 1 &#x2013; I do not have any concrete plans yet- but I have considered the possibility and would like more information. 2 &#x2013; I have made preparations (i.e. saved some money- contacted friends/family abroad)- but am considering delaying my plans (until the siege is over- the borders are open- a possibility for borders&#x2019; smuggling is available the family reunion papers are finished- etc)). 3 &#x2013; I have made concrete arrangements (saved enough money- chosen a destination/route- sold possessions- bought a ticket/organized transportation) and plan to emigrate within the next year. - &#x2018;If you chose answer 2 or 3- where are you planning to emigrate to?&#x2019; - &#x2018;What is the main reason why you are planning to emigrate? (Family reunion- economic reasons- safety reasons- etc.) (for example: Lack of employment opportunities- more money offered for jobs elsewhere- status- threat of violent conflict). The type of surveys will be cross sectional surveys (random sample of programme beneficiaries). The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for local community members. The statistical samples should include various age groups- professional backgrounds and experiences- IDPs- and local residents. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyze the data and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="OA.6" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="20" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="18"></target>
     <actual value="14"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">OA.6 (disaggregated) % of programme beneficiaries&#x2019; who report that they have real plans to emigrate within the next year [This indicator is required depending on the programme and its context]</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x2018;Real plans to emigrate&#x2019; refers to concrete measures (i.e.- saving money- selling possessions- chosen destination/route- organized a place to stay- preparing for smuggling/irregular migration- etc.) taken by programme beneficiaries in preparation of moving to another country (including irregular migration)- that provide more insight on the perception of programme beneficiaries towards emigration while indicating the likelihood that such plans will manifest. &#x2018;emigrate&#x2019; refers to the act of moving to another country. Rational: In order to understand and learn more about the impact of the ARC Fund- we must measure the extent to which the ARC programmes have had an influence (positive/negative) on beneficiaries&#x2019; perceptions and hopes regarding their future in the current place of residence. The overarching goal of the ARC Fund is to address root causes of conflict- instability and irregular migration. This means it is also important to measure to what extent beneficiaries are actively considering migration (i.e. have real plans to emigrate) and to be able to track the change in perceptions compared to the start of the programme. Specifically- in order to gain insight in how the intervention has contributed to a situation whereby beneficiaries (increasingly) see a future for themselves in the place where they currently live (i.e.- to test the assumption that the desire and/or necessity to move abroad has decreased/increased). Since this is an impact -indicator (namely overarching indicator) - which attempts to measure at the highest level of long-term change- it is important to recognize that causality may be related to many other factors than the intervention alone. Disaggregation: - Male/ Female - Youth*/Not youth - IDP/Local resident *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Percentage of programme beneficiaries who report that they have real plans to emigrate within the next 12 months- at the start of the programme- after two years and at the end of the programme. The number is not cumulative- i.e. you do not add this year&#x2019;s number to last year&#x2019;s number when you report. Data Collection Method: This is an overarching indicator- whereby programme beneficiaries must be asked the question: &#x201C;Do you have real plans to emigrate within the next year?&#x201D; Collecting such data will help gain insight in how the programme has contributed to a change in programme beneficiaries&#x2019;&#x2019; perceptions and hopes regarding their future- compared to the start of the programme &#x2013; i.e. to measure if the desire and/or necessity to move abroad has decreased/increased. This question is difficult to respond when asked directly and may need to be reformulated depending on the local context. several questions will be asked about concrete situations that can be statistically analyzed together. This indicator shall take into consideration the matter of siege (in Ghouta) and borders closing in Syria which might prevent people from preparing concrete plans but yet having the desire to migrate when and if possible in the future. The survey methodology will be using focus group discussions and/or individual questionnaires. The following questions will be asked: - &#x2018;On a scale of 0-3- to what extent do you have real plans to migrate within the next year? Please clarify.&#x2019; 0 &#x2013; none- I have not considered emigration before. 1 &#x2013; I do not have any concrete plans yet- but I have considered the possibility and would like more information. 2 &#x2013; I have made preparations (i.e. saved some money- contacted friends/family abroad)- but am considering delaying my plans (until the siege is over- the borders are open- a possibility for borders&#x2019; smuggling is available the family reunion papers are finished- etc)). 3 &#x2013; I have made concrete arrangements (saved enough money- chosen a destination/route- sold possessions- bought a ticket/organized transportation) and plan to emigrate within the next year. - &#x2018;If you chose answer 2 or 3- where are you planning to emigrate to?&#x2019; - &#x2018;What is the main reason why you are planning to emigrate? (Family reunion- economic reasons- safety reasons- etc.) (for example: Lack of employment opportunities- more money offered for jobs elsewhere- status- threat of violent conflict). The type of surveys will be cross sectional surveys (random sample of programme beneficiaries). The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for local community members. The statistical samples should include various age groups- professional backgrounds and experiences- IDPs- and local residents. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyze the data and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashionSource of Data: For this indicator- the source is the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="OA.6" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="4.4" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="4"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People see a safer/more secure future for themselves in the area where they currently live</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People see a safer/more secure future for themselves in the area where they currently live</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">OA.1 (disaggregated) Number of programme beneficiaries who report that they see a safer/more secure future for themselves in the area where they currently live</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x2018;Safer/more secure future&#x2019; refers to the perceptions and hopes of beneficiaries concerning their prospects/opportunities with regard to their safety and security. This includes security in the sense of physical safety or security in socio-political terms (e.g. human rights- freedom of movement and association- participation in civic and political life - including conflict resolution processes) and reflects the extent to which they believe they have a chance to live a life free from fear in the area where they currently live- while also feeling more in control of their lives. As per the Syrian context- and since the physical safety is out of the local authorities control- this definition will be more focusing on security in socio-political terms as defined above. &#x2018;Future&#x2019;: The time-frame for this indicator is at minimum the duration of the programme (3-5 years)- but will most likely be longer considering benefits of certain programme activities might only be reaped after the programme ends. For example- a person who has received skills-training during years 1-3 may have only gotten a job in the last year of the programme. The benefits of this increase in income and improved social status may only become clear in the eyes of the beneficiary during the following years. Thus- grantees must translate the concept of &#x2018;future&#x2019; according to the period which they anticipate is necessary for the long-term impact of the programme to bear visible results. This indicator is used to gain insight into how the ARC programmes have contributed to the &#x2018;stability&#x2019; of the area where beneficiaries live and can be triangulated with data generated through the related life stories indicator (OA.2) which will be collected by the end of the programme. By &#x2018;stability&#x2019; we specifically mean &#x2018;legitimate stability&#x2019;- which indicates that stability is not a goal in itself. Indeed- dictatorships may be stable for long periods. Our aim is the stability that arises from social cohesion between population groups- and from citizens&#x2019; acknowledgement of the legitimacy of existing structures and institutions- both formal and informal and their ability to engage with them. Stability of this nature- giving people a sense of security in both physical and socio-political terms- is a precondition for sustainable development. Rational: In order to understand and learn more about the impact of the ARC Fund- we must measure the extent to which the ARC programmes have had an influence (positive/negative) on beneficiaries&#x2019; perceptions and hopes regarding their future. The ARC Fund aims to have a positive influence on beneficiaries&#x2019; future perspective of the opportunities they have regarding their security- safety- human rights- political influence and other socio-political freedoms. The outcome envisaged at overarching level is therefore to ensure that the root cause underlying trends of conflict- instability and irregular migration have been addressed in such a way that programme beneficiaries- as a result- believe they have a likely chance to build a sustainable life in the place where they currently live and become less vulnerable to forces that threaten their existence (i.e. physical insecurity- political instability etc.). This indicator- specifically- addresses the conflict and (physical and socio-political) stability aspects of related root causes. Disaggregation: Compulsory disaggregation by: - Male/ Female - Youth*/Not youth - IDP/Local resident *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who report that they see a safer/more secure future for themselves in the area where they currently live&#xA0;- at the start of the programme- after two years and at the end of the programme. The number is not cumulative- i.e. you do not add this year&#x2019;s number to last year&#x2019;s number when you report. Data Collection Method: This is an overarching-level indicator- whereby grantees must ask programme beneficiaries the question: &#x201C;Do you see a safer/more secure future for yourself in the area where you currently live?&#x201D;. Collecting such data will help us gain insight in how the programme has contributed to a change in programme beneficiaries&#x2019; perceptions and hopes regarding their future- compared to the start of the programme. This question is difficult to respond when asked directly and may need to be reformulated depending on the local context. The following questions about concrete situations that can be statistically analyzed together will be asked as a proxy indicator: - Do you feel comfortable to express your opinion freely and publicly within your community (regarding political events (local/national) and public life issues such as service provision- elections- local conflicts- etc.) - Are there any public platforms that you can express your opinion through in the area where you live (public meeting- public complaints box/mechanisms- media- etc.)? - Do you feel that you are participating (directly/indirectly) or that your voice is heard when it comes to public decision making (on services and political level) in your area (mainly through the local council and any other key players)? (this question overlaps with indicator OA4) The survey methodology will be using focus group discussions and/or individual questionnaires. The type of surveys will be cross sectional surveys (random sample of programme beneficiaries). The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for local community members. The statistical samples should include various age groups- professional backgrounds and experiences- IDPs- and local residents. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyze the data and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion. Results for this indicator may provide insight into other areas of social change- such as irregular migration. Depending on whether the responses for this indicator are positive/negative (i.e. &#x2018;I do not see a future here&#x2019;) additional questions may be asked in order to get an idea of the how this is linked to the desire and/or necessity to move elsewhere in search of a better socio-economic future has decreased/increased. Where relevant proxy-questions could feed into the overarching indicator (OA.6) that measures the extent to which beneficiaries have &#x2018;real plans to emigrate within the next year&#x2019;. Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="OA.1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="278" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="320"></target>
     <actual value="186"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">OA.1 (disaggregated) % of programme beneficiaries who report that they see a safer/more secure future for themselves in the area where they currently live</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x2018;Safer/more secure future&#x2019; refers to the perceptions and hopes of beneficiaries concerning their prospects/opportunities with regard to their safety and security. This includes security in the sense of physical safety or security in socio-political terms (e.g. human rights- freedom of movement and association- participation in civic and political life - including conflict resolution processes) and reflects the extent to which they believe they have a chance to live a life free from fear in the area where they currently live- while also feeling more in control of their lives. As per the Syrian context- and since the physical safety is out of the local authorities control- this definition will be more focusing on security in socio-political terms as defined above. &#x2018;Future&#x2019;: The time-frame for this indicator is at minimum the duration of the programme (3-5 years)- but will most likely be longer considering benefits of certain programme activities might only be reaped after the programme ends. For example- a person who has received skills-training during years 1-3 may have only gotten a job in the last year of the programme. The benefits of this increase in income and improved social status may only become clear in the eyes of the beneficiary during the following years. Thus- grantees must translate the concept of &#x2018;future&#x2019; according to the period which they anticipate is necessary for the long-term impact of the programme to bear visible results. This indicator is used to gain insight into how the ARC programmes have contributed to the &#x2018;stability&#x2019; of the area where beneficiaries live and can be triangulated with data generated through the related life stories indicator (OA.2) which will be collected by the end of the programme. By &#x2018;stability&#x2019; we specifically mean &#x2018;legitimate stability&#x2019;- which indicates that stability is not a goal in itself. Indeed- dictatorships may be stable for long periods. Our aim is the stability that arises from social cohesion between population groups- and from citizens&#x2019; acknowledgement of the legitimacy of existing structures and institutions- both formal and informal and their ability to engage with them. Stability of this nature- giving people a sense of security in both physical and socio-political terms- is a precondition for sustainable development. Rational: In order to understand and learn more about the impact of the ARC Fund- we must measure the extent to which the ARC programmes have had an influence (positive/negative) on beneficiaries&#x2019; perceptions and hopes regarding their future. The ARC Fund aims to have a positive influence on beneficiaries&#x2019; future perspective of the opportunities they have regarding their security- safety- human rights- political influence and other socio-political freedoms. The outcome envisaged at overarching level is therefore to ensure that the root cause underlying trends of conflict- instability and irregular migration have been addressed in such a way that programme beneficiaries- as a result- believe they have a likely chance to build a sustainable life in the place where they currently live and become less vulnerable to forces that threaten their existence (i.e. physical insecurity- political instability etc.). This indicator- specifically- addresses the conflict and (physical and socio-political) stability aspects of related root causes. Disaggregation: - Male/ Female - Youth*/Not youth - IDP/Local resident *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Percentage of programme beneficiaries who report that they see a safer/more secure future for themselves in the area where they currently live&#xA0;- at the start of the programme- after two years and at the end of the programme. The number is not cumulative- i.e. you do not add this year&#x2019;s number to last year&#x2019;s number when you report. Data Collection Method: This is an overarching-level indicator- whereby grantees must ask programme beneficiaries the question: &#x201C;Do you see a safer/more secure future for yourself in the area where you currently live?&#x201D;. Collecting such data will help us gain insight in how the programme has contributed to a change in programme beneficiaries&#x2019; perceptions and hopes regarding their future- compared to the start of the programme. This question is difficult to respond when asked directly and may need to be reformulated depending on the local context. The following questions about concrete situations that can be statistically analyzed together will be asked as a proxy indicator: - Do you feel comfortable to express your opinion freely and publicly within your community (regarding political events (local/national) and public life issues such as service provision- elections- local conflicts- etc.) - Are there any public platforms that you can express your opinion through in the area where you live (public meeting- public complaints box/mechanisms- media- etc.)? - Do you feel that you are participating (directly/indirectly) or that your voice is heard when it comes to public decision making (on services and political level) in your area (mainly through the local council and any other key players)? (this question overlaps with indicator OA4) The survey methodology will be using focus group discussions and/or individual questionnaires. The type of surveys will be cross sectional surveys (random sample of programme beneficiaries). The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for local community members. The statistical samples should include various age groups- professional backgrounds and experiences- IDPs- and local residents. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyze the data and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion. Results for this indicator may provide insight into other areas of social change- such as irregular migration. Depending on whether the responses for this indicator are positive/negative (i.e. &#x2018;I do not see a future here&#x2019;) additional questions may be asked in order to get an idea of the how this is linked to the desire and/or necessity to move elsewhere in search of a better socio-economic future has decreased/increased. Where relevant proxy-questions could feed into the overarching indicator (OA.6) that measures the extent to which beneficiaries have &#x2018;real plans to emigrate within the next year&#x2019;. Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="OA.1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="61" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="65"></target>
     <actual value="53"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People see a socio-economic future for themselves in the place where they currently live</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People see a socio-economic future for themselves in the place where they currently live</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">OA.4 (disaggregated) Number of programme beneficiaries who report that they see a socio-economic future for themselves in the place where they currently live [This indicator is required for programmes working on result area 4]</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x2018;Socio-economic future&#x2019; refers to the perceptions and hopes of beneficiaries regarding their prospects/opportunities in social and economic terms i.e. the ability to gain enough income and assets for the family- and the social network and resilience of the community to support each other) and the extent to which they believe they have a chance to build a sustainable livelihood/life in the area where they currently live. &#x2018;Future&#x2019;: The time-frame for this indicator is at minimum the duration of the programme (3-5 years)- but will most likely be longer considering benefits of certain programme activities might only be reaped after the programme ends. For example- a person who has received skills-training during years 1-3 may have only gotten a job in the last year of the programme. The benefits of this increase in income and improved social status may only become clear in the eyes of the beneficiary during the following years. Thus- grantees must translate the concept of &#x2018;future&#x2019; according to the period which they anticipate is necessary for the long-term impact of the programme to bear visible results. This indicator is used to gain insight into how the ARC programmes have contributed to the socio-economic &#x2018;stability&#x2019; of the area where beneficiaries live and can be triangulated with data generated through the related life stories indicator (OA.5) which will be collected by the end of the programme. By &#x2018;stability&#x2019; we specifically mean &#x2018;legitimate stability&#x2019;- which indicates that stability is not a goal in itself. Indeed- dictatorships may be stable for long periods. Our aim is the stability that arises from social cohesion between population groups- and from citizens&#x2019; acknowledgement of the legitimacy of existing structures and institutions- both formal and informal. From a socio-economic perspective- &#x2018;stability&#x2019; includes having a secure source of income. Stability of this nature- giving people a sense of security in terms of their ability to maintain a sustainable livelihood in the long run- is a precondition for sustainable development. Rationale: In order to understand and learn more about the impact of the ARC Fund- we must measure the extent to which the ARC programmes have had an influence (positive/negative) on beneficiaries&#x2019; perceptions and hopes regarding their future. The ARC Fund as a whole aims to have a positive influence on beneficiaries&#x2019; future perspective of the opportunities they have (regarding their security- safety- human rights- political influence- economic situation- livelihood- etc.). The outcome envisaged at overarching level is therefore to ensure that the root cause underlying trends of conflict- instability and irregular migration have been addressed in such a way that programme beneficiaries- as a result- believe they have a likely chance to build a sustainable life in the area where they currently live and become less vulnerable to forces that threaten their existence (i.e. livelihood- basic needs- means of support- etc.). This indicator- specifically- addresses the (socio-economic) stability aspect of related root causes. Disaggregation: - Male/ Female - Youth*/Not youth - IDP/Local resident *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who report that they see a socio-economic future for themselves in the area where they currently live- at the start of the programme- after two years and at the end of the programme. The number is not cumulative- i.e. you do not add this year&#x2019;s number to last year&#x2019;s number when you report. Data collection method: This is an overarching-level indicator- whereby programme beneficiaries must be asked the question: &#x201C;Do you see a socio-economic future for yourself in the area where you currently live?&#x201D;. Collecting such data will help gain insight in how the programme has contributed to a change in programme beneficiaries&#x2019; perceptions and hopes regarding their future- compared to the start of the programme. This question is difficult to respond when asked directly and may need to be reformulated depending on the local context. The following questions will be asked about concrete situations that can be statistically analyzed together as a proxy indicator: - Has the economic situation within your community improved within the last year? (examples: job opportunities- access to more services/products- etc.) - Do you feel comfortable and happy living within the community where you are currently based? If not- please explain. - Do you feel that you are participating (directly/indirectly) or that your voice is heard when it comes to public decision making (on services and political level) in your area (mainly through the local council and any other key players)? The survey methodology will be using focus group discussions and/or individual questionnaires. The type of surveys will be cross sectional surveys (random sample of programme beneficiaries). The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for local community members. The statistical samples should include various age groups- professional backgrounds and experiences- IDPs- and local residents. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyze the data and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion. Since this is an overarching-indicator- which attempts to measure long-term change from a broader perspective- it is important to recognize that causality may be related to other factors than the intervention alone. Therefore- grantees are recommended to ask questions that are likely to generate a response from which they can gather information on the local impact of their programme. In order to enrich the analysis- it is desirable to cross-check results for this indicator with data collected through other (overarching) indicators- such as through Life Stories of programme beneficiaries who explain whether/how the program has changed the socio-economic stability of the area where they live (see OA.5). (Only by the end of the program). Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="OA.4" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="211" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="250"></target>
     <actual value="206"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">OA.4 (disaggregated) % of programme beneficiaries who report that they see a socio-economic future for themselves in the place where they currently live [This indicator is required for programmes working on result area 4]</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x2018;Socio-economic future&#x2019; refers to the perceptions and hopes of beneficiaries regarding their prospects/opportunities in social and economic terms i.e. the ability to gain enough income and assets for the family- and the social network and resilience of the community to support each other) and the extent to which they believe they have a chance to build a sustainable livelihood/life in the area where they currently live. &#x2018;Future&#x2019;: The time-frame for this indicator is at minimum the duration of the programme (3-5 years)- but will most likely be longer considering benefits of certain programme activities might only be reaped after the programme ends. For example- a person who has received skills-training during years 1-3 may have only gotten a job in the last year of the programme. The benefits of this increase in income and improved social status may only become clear in the eyes of the beneficiary during the following years. Thus- grantees must translate the concept of &#x2018;future&#x2019; according to the period which they anticipate is necessary for the long-term impact of the programme to bear visible results. This indicator is used to gain insight into how the ARC programmes have contributed to the socio-economic &#x2018;stability&#x2019; of the area where beneficiaries live and can be triangulated with data generated through the related life stories indicator (OA.5) which will be collected by the end of the programme. By &#x2018;stability&#x2019; we specifically mean &#x2018;legitimate stability&#x2019;- which indicates that stability is not a goal in itself. Indeed- dictatorships may be stable for long periods. Our aim is the stability that arises from social cohesion between population groups- and from citizens&#x2019; acknowledgement of the legitimacy of existing structures and institutions- both formal and informal. From a socio-economic perspective- &#x2018;stability&#x2019; includes having a secure source of income. Stability of this nature- giving people a sense of security in terms of their ability to maintain a sustainable livelihood in the long run- is a precondition for sustainable development. Rationale: In order to understand and learn more about the impact of the ARC Fund- we must measure the extent to which the ARC programmes have had an influence (positive/negative) on beneficiaries&#x2019; perceptions and hopes regarding their future. The ARC Fund as a whole aims to have a positive influence on beneficiaries&#x2019; future perspective of the opportunities they have (regarding their security- safety- human rights- political influence- economic situation- livelihood- etc.). The outcome envisaged at overarching level is therefore to ensure that the root cause underlying trends of conflict- instability and irregular migration have been addressed in such a way that programme beneficiaries- as a result- believe they have a likely chance to build a sustainable life in the area where they currently live and become less vulnerable to forces that threaten their existence (i.e. livelihood- basic needs- means of support- etc.). This indicator- specifically- addresses the (socio-economic) stability aspect of related root causes. Disaggregation: - Male/ Female - Youth*/Not youth - IDP/Local resident *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Percentage of programme beneficiaries who report that they see a socio-economic future for themselves in the area where they currently live- at the start of the programme- after two years and at the end of the programme. The number is not cumulative- i.e. you do not add this year&#x2019;s number to last year&#x2019;s number when you report. Data collection method: This is an overarching-level indicator- whereby programme beneficiaries must be asked the question: &#x201C;Do you see a socio-economic future for yourself in the area where you currently live?&#x201D;. Collecting such data will help gain insight in how the programme has contributed to a change in programme beneficiaries&#x2019; perceptions and hopes regarding their future- compared to the start of the programme. This question is difficult to respond when asked directly and may need to be reformulated depending on the local context. The following questions will be asked about concrete situations that can be statistically analyzed together as a proxy indicator: - Has the economic situation within your community improved within the last year? (examples: job opportunities- access to more services/products- etc.) - Do you feel comfortable and happy living within the community where you are currently based? If not- please explain. - Do you feel that you are participating (directly/indirectly) or that your voice is heard when it comes to public decision making (on services and political level) in your area (mainly through the local council and any other key players)? The survey methodology will be using focus group discussions and/or individual questionnaires. The type of surveys will be cross sectional surveys (random sample of programme beneficiaries). The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for local community members. The statistical samples should include various age groups- professional backgrounds and experiences- IDPs- and local residents. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyze the data and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion. Since this is an overarching-indicator- which attempts to measure long-term change from a broader perspective- it is important to recognize that causality may be related to other factors than the intervention alone. Therefore- grantees are recommended to ask questions that are likely to generate a response from which they can gather information on the local impact of their programme. In order to enrich the analysis- it is desirable to cross-check results for this indicator with data collected through other (overarching) indicators- such as through Life Stories of programme beneficiaries who explain whether/how the program has changed the socio-economic stability of the area where they live (see OA.5). (Only by the end of the program). Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="OA.4" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="46" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="55"></target>
     <actual value="59"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People have less personal grievances related to basic services due to an increased ability to meet household needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This long term outcome falls under ARC result area 4.2 Sustainable basic services to prevent the (re)occurrence of conflicts- instability or irregular migration and aims to reduce people&apos;s personal grievances related to basic services due to an increased ability to meet household needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity) in the targeted areas for the local communities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA4.2.1 (disaggregated) Number of programme beneficiaries who report ability to meet current and future (next 12 months) household needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x2018;Household needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity / health services)&#x2019;: the minimum needs of that basic service (e.g. adequate access to water wells- or access to education to secure a basic living) necessary for long-term physical well-being- i.e. excluding psycho-social needs. A &#x2018;household&#x2019; does not equal a family - what it means depends on each beneficiary&#x2019;s personal responsibilities. Thus- a household could be: just one person living alone- a group of people who live together for socioeconomic reasons- a family- or a combination of two families living in different houses for a beneficiary who is (one of) the breadwinner(s) for those two families- etc.. &#x2018;Ability&#x2019;: is for this indicator defined as any of the following 4 levels (of having the minimum of resources necessary for the long-term physical well-being of one&#x2019;s household) on a scale from 0 to 6 [note: one cannot answer by choosing a &#x2018;sublevel&#x2019; in between these 4 distinct levels]: 0: not at all able to meet household needs regarding water /education / electricity / etc, 2: partially able to meet household needs regarding water / education / electricity / etc, 4: almost able to meet household needs regarding water / education / electricity / etc, 6: able to meet household needs regarding water / education / electricity / etc. &#x2018;Future needs&#x2019; refers to the expected needs of a beneficiary in 12 months&#x2019; time (when- possibly- beneficiaries can reap more fruits of the support they have received- because for instance the received education or the seeds or livestock which now benefits from better access to water has now). A beneficiary that is &#x2018;able to meet current and future (in 12 months) household needs regarding the concerned basic service(s)&#x2019; is for this indicator defined as a beneficiary whose average &#x2018;score&#x2019; is either 5 or 6 points- when adding up his/her two scores (i.e. his/her separate answers to the following two questions on the abovementioned scale- for instance (2+4)/2= 3, or (4+6)/2= 5) and dividing them by 2. Said two questions are: 1.&#x201C;Do you feel currently: not at all able (0) / partially able (2) / almost able (4) / able (6) to meet your household&#x2019;s minimum needs for water and/or basic education and/or &#x2026; services (i.e. the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC) necessary for your household&#x2019;s physical well-being?&#x201D; 2.&#x201D; Do you feel that in 12 months&#x2019; time you will be: not at all able (0) / partially &#x2026; etc. &#x201D; Rationale: Result area 4.2 aims to reduce the grievances of people targeted by the intervention regarding water/education- in order to prevent the (re)occurrence of conflicts- instability or irregular migration. This is done by increasing the ability of the target group to meet household needs regarding water/education or other essential basic services. This indicator measures how many programme beneficiaries are able to meet current and future household needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC- such as water and/or education- to any of the 4 degrees/levels described above- as a consequence (long term outcome) of household members benefitting from better access to (better) water/education/etc- directed at the prevention of the (re)occurrence of conflict- instability and/or irregular migration. This can be as a consequence of participation in education programmes (to secure a basic living or be better informed about the risks of migration)- or because their communities have benefitted from the development and implementation of interventions to improve their access to water for human consumption or agriculture- etc. Disaggregation: - Male/Female - Youth*/Not Youth - IDPs/ Local residents - The 7 groups of beneficiaries with an average score of 0- 1- 2- 3- 4- 5- or 6 &#x2018;points&#x2019;. *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). For. Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries which have an average &#x2018;score&#x2019; of 5 or 6 points when measuring the average of their level of ability to meet current and future (next 12 months) household needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC- such as water- education- etc. On the abovementioned scale. Data Collection Method: To enhance uniformity of data (and improve aggregation)- this indicator will measure a beneficiary&#x2019;s ability to meet current and future (next 12 months) household needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC- such as water and/or education- on the following scale from 0 to 6: 0: not at all able to meet household needs regarding water /education / electricity / etc, 2: partially able to meet household needs regarding water /education / electricity / etc, 4: almost able to meet household needs regarding water /education / electricity / etc, 6: able to meet household needs regarding water /education / electricity / etc, [note: one cannot answer by choosing a &#x2018;sublevel&#x2019; in between these 4 distinct levels] The two questions to be asked to respondents is: 1. &#x201C;Do you feel currently: not at all able / partially able / almost able / able meet your household&#x2019;s minimum needs for water and/or basic education and/or etc necessary for your household&#x2019;s physical well-being?&#x201D; 2.&#x201D; Do you feel that in 12 months&#x2019; time you will be: not at all able (0) / partially &#x2026; etc.&#x201D;? The type of surveys will be cross sectional surveys (random sample of programme beneficiaries). The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for local community members. The statistical samples should include various age groups- professional backgrounds and experiences- IDPs- and local residents. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyze the data and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion. As agreed earlier with ARC- and since the suggested measurement method as: &#x201C;A beneficiary that is &#x2018;able to meet current and future (in 12 months) household needs regarding the concerned basic service(s)&#x2019; is for this indicator defined as a beneficiary whose average &#x2018;score&#x2019; is either 5 or 6 points&#x201D; might not be realistic for the situation in Syria- and since the aim of the Syria program is to achieve the scores of 2 and/or 4 (partially and almost meet the household needs). All the results from 0-6 will be reported as per the suggested disaggregation. Additional explanations and data analysis will be added to the narrative section. Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RA 4.2.1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="160" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="200"></target>
     <actual value="197"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA4.2.1 (disaggregated0 % of programme beneficiaries who report ability to meet current and future (next 12 months) household needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x2018;Household needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity / health services)&#x2019;: the minimum needs of that basic service (e.g. adequate access to water wells- or access to education to secure a basic living) necessary for long-term physical well-being- i.e. excluding psycho-social needs. A &#x2018;household&#x2019; does not equal a family - what it means depends on each beneficiary&#x2019;s personal responsibilities. Thus- a household could be: just one person living alone- a group of people who live together for socioeconomic reasons- a family- or a combination of two families living in different houses for a beneficiary who is (one of) the breadwinner(s) for those two families- etc.. &#x2018;Ability&#x2019;: is for this indicator defined as any of the following 4 levels (of having the minimum of resources necessary for the long-term physical well-being of one&#x2019;s household) on a scale from 0 to 6 [note: one cannot answer by choosing a &#x2018;sublevel&#x2019; in between these 4 distinct levels]: 0: not at all able to meet household needs regarding water /education / electricity / etc, 2: partially able to meet household needs regarding water / education / electricity / etc, 4: almost able to meet household needs regarding water / education / electricity / etc, 6: able to meet household needs regarding water / education / electricity / etc. &#x2018;Future needs&#x2019; refers to the expected needs of a beneficiary in 12 months&#x2019; time (when- possibly- beneficiaries can reap more fruits of the support they have received- because for instance the received education or the seeds or livestock which now benefits from better access to water has now). A beneficiary that is &#x2018;able to meet current and future (in 12 months) household needs regarding the concerned basic service(s)&#x2019; is for this indicator defined as a beneficiary whose average &#x2018;score&#x2019; is either 5 or 6 points- when adding up his/her two scores (i.e. his/her separate answers to the following two questions on the abovementioned scale- for instance (2+4)/2= 3, or (4+6)/2= 5) and dividing them by 2. Said two questions are: 1.&#x201C;Do you feel currently: not at all able (0) / partially able (2) / almost able (4) / able (6) to meet your household&#x2019;s minimum needs for water and/or basic education and/or &#x2026; services (i.e. the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC) necessary for your household&#x2019;s physical well-being?&#x201D; 2.&#x201D; Do you feel that in 12 months&#x2019; time you will be: not at all able (0) / partially &#x2026; etc. &#x201D; Rationale: Result area 4.2 aims to reduce the grievances of people targeted by the intervention regarding water/education- in order to prevent the (re)occurrence of conflicts- instability or irregular migration. This is done by increasing the ability of the target group to meet household needs regarding water/education or other essential basic services. This indicator measures how many programme beneficiaries are able to meet current and future household needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC- such as water and/or education- to any of the 4 degrees/levels described above- as a consequence (long term outcome) of household members benefitting from better access to (better) water/education/etc- directed at the prevention of the (re)occurrence of conflict- instability and/or irregular migration. This can be as a consequence of participation in education programmes (to secure a basic living or be better informed about the risks of migration)- or because their communities have benefitted from the development and implementation of interventions to improve their access to water for human consumption or agriculture- etc. Disaggregation: - Male/Female - Youth*/Not Youth - IDPs/ Local residents - The 7 groups of beneficiaries with an average score of 0- 1- 2- 3- 4- 5- or 6 &#x2018;points&#x2019;. *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). For. Unit of Measurement: Percentage of programme beneficiaries which have an average &#x2018;score&#x2019; of 5 or 6 points when measuring the average of their level of ability to meet current and future (next 12 months) household needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC- such as water- education- etc. On the abovementioned scale. Data Collection Method: To enhance uniformity of data (and improve aggregation)- this indicator will measure a beneficiary&#x2019;s ability to meet current and future (next 12 months) household needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC- such as water and/or education- on the following scale from 0 to 6: 0: not at all able to meet household needs regarding water /education / electricity / etc, 2: partially able to meet household needs regarding water /education / electricity / etc, 4: almost able to meet household needs regarding water /education / electricity / etc, 6: able to meet household needs regarding water /education / electricity / etc, [note: one cannot answer by choosing a &#x2018;sublevel&#x2019; in between these 4 distinct levels] The two questions to be asked to respondents is: 1. &#x201C;Do you feel currently: not at all able / partially able / almost able / able meet your household&#x2019;s minimum needs for water and/or basic education and/or etc necessary for your household&#x2019;s physical well-being?&#x201D; 2.&#x201D; Do you feel that in 12 months&#x2019; time you will be: not at all able (0) / partially &#x2026; etc.&#x201D;? The type of surveys will be cross sectional surveys (random sample of programme beneficiaries). The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for local community members. The statistical samples should include various age groups- professional backgrounds and experiences- IDPs- and local residents. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyze the data and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion. As agreed earlier with ARC- and since the suggested measurement method as: &#x201C;A beneficiary that is &#x2018;able to meet current and future (in 12 months) household needs regarding the concerned basic service(s)&#x2019; is for this indicator defined as a beneficiary whose average &#x2018;score&#x2019; is either 5 or 6 points&#x201D; might not be realistic for the situation in Syria- and since the aim of the Syria program is to achieve the scores of 2 and/or 4 (partially and almost meet the household needs). All the results from 0-6 will be reported as per the suggested disaggregation. Additional explanations and data analysis will be added to the narrative section. Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RA 4.2.1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="35" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="40"></target>
     <actual value="60"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People have less personal grievances related to basic services due to an increased ability to meet household needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This long term outcome falls under ARC result area 4.2 Sustainable basic services to prevent the (re)occurrence of conflicts- instability or irregular migration and aims to reduce people&apos;s personal grievances related to basic services due to an increased ability to meet household needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity) in the targeted areas for the local communities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA4.2.3 (disaggregated) Number of programme beneficiaries who have reported a reduction of negative social or economic interaction across intra-societal divides over the last 6 months.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x2018;Negative social or economic interaction across intra-societal divides&#x2019;: A supposed lack of interaction/exchanges of a social (e.g. exchanging views) or economic nature (e.g. an economic transaction)- between a representative from a group or party within a society that does not easily exchange with a representative from another groups or parties- due to a variety of historical reasons- e.g. ethnic rivalry / existence of social or political conflicts / power or gender imbalances / political affiliation- etc. Said interactions or transactions would in itself make social or economic sense- but are lacking because of the described negative socio-economic interaction (rivalry- conflict- social tension- etc.). For the Syria project- and within the current context- the main community sectors targeted for this indicator are the IDPs and women in addition to all community members. Rationale: Result area 4.1 aims to reduce- through (notably) an increase in their ability to meet household needs- the grievances of beneficiaries regarding income or livelihoods (e.g. those related to conflict- instability or irregular migration)- in order to prevent the (re)occurrence of conflicts- instability or irregular migration. This indicator serves as a proxy indicator to assess whether: (a) said grievances (i.e. those related to conflict- instability or irregular migration) are being reduced, and (b) the (re)occurrence of conflicts and instability has become less likely. Disaggregation: - Male/Female - Youth*/Not Youth - IDPS/ Local residents *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries- per calendar year &#x2013; i.e. not cumulative during entire duration of programme - who have reported a reduction of negative social or economic interaction across intra-societal divides over the last 6 months. Data collection method: This is a perception indicator- which means that programme beneficiaries need to be asked the question: &#x201C;Do you experience a reduction of negative social or economic interaction across intra-societal divides over the last 6 months?&#x201D; This question contains obviously complex abstract concepts and is difficult to comprehend and respond when asked as such. To enhance uniformity of data (and improve aggregation)- a set of sample questions will be used as proxy indicator- to assess whether blockages towards intra-societal interaction- trust and cooperation in concrete situations have diminished: - &#x201C;Have you in the last 6 months experienced a general reduction of intra-societal conflict- tension and/or lack of trust /cooperation- which led for instance to more discussions- cooperation to solve a mutual problem or trade with people from groups in society with whom your group experiences conflict- tension and/or lack of trust /cooperation?&#x201D;. - Have you in last 6 months notices a reduction of women exclusion in participating in elections and public meetings in your area? (increase of participation?) - Have you in last 6 months notices a reduction of IDPs exclusion in service provision in your area? (increase of service provision?) The last two questions are to be focusing on IDPs&#x2019; and women&#x2019;s intra-societal interactions. By means: do women/IDPs experience intra-societal conflict with the rest of community members which prevent them from interacting/ participating in decision making/ solving problems- etc. The type of surveys is a cross sectional surveys (random sample of programme beneficiaries). The survey methodology will be using focus group discussions and/or individual questionnaires. The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for beneficiaries. The statistical samples should include representatives of the local CSOs and community groups such as local committees- unions- professional syndicates- etc. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyzing the data- and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion. Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RA4.2.3" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="208" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="250"></target>
     <actual value="141"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA4.2.3 (disaggregated) % of programme beneficiaries who have reported a reduction of negative social or economic interaction across intra-societal divides over the last 6 months.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x2018;Negative social or economic interaction across intra-societal divides&#x2019;: A supposed lack of interaction/exchanges of a social (e.g. exchanging views) or economic nature (e.g. an economic transaction)- between a representative from a group or party within a society that does not easily exchange with a representative from another groups or parties- due to a variety of historical reasons- e.g. ethnic rivalry / existence of social or political conflicts / power or gender imbalances / political affiliation- etc. Said interactions or transactions would in itself make social or economic sense- but are lacking because of the described negative socio-economic interaction (rivalry- conflict- social tension- etc.). For the Syria project- and within the current context- the main community sectors targeted for this indicator are the IDPs and women in addition to all community members. Rationale: Result area 4.1 aims to reduce- through (notably) an increase in their ability to meet household needs- the grievances of beneficiaries regarding income or livelihoods (e.g. those related to conflict- instability or irregular migration)- in order to prevent the (re)occurrence of conflicts- instability or irregular migration. This indicator serves as a proxy indicator to assess whether: (a) said grievances (i.e. those related to conflict- instability or irregular migration) are being reduced, and (b) the (re)occurrence of conflicts and instability has become less likely. Disaggregation: - Male/Female - Youth*/Not Youth - IDPS/ Local residents *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Percentage of programme beneficiaries- per calendar year &#x2013; i.e. not cumulative during entire duration of programme - who have reported a reduction of negative social or economic interaction across intra-societal divides over the last 6 months. Data collection method: This is a perception indicator- which means that programme beneficiaries need to be asked the question: &#x201C;Do you experience a reduction of negative social or economic interaction across intra-societal divides over the last 6 months?&#x201D; This question contains obviously complex abstract concepts and is difficult to comprehend and respond when asked as such. To enhance uniformity of data (and improve aggregation)- a set of sample questions will be used as proxy indicator- to assess whether blockages towards intra-societal interaction- trust and cooperation in concrete situations have diminished: - &#x201C;Have you in the last 6 months experienced a general reduction of intra-societal conflict- tension and/or lack of trust /cooperation- which led for instance to more discussions- cooperation to solve a mutual problem or trade with people from groups in society with whom your group experiences conflict- tension and/or lack of trust /cooperation?&#x201D;. - Have you in last 6 months notices a reduction of women exclusion in participating in elections and public meetings in your area? (increase of participation?) - Have you in last 6 months notices a reduction of IDPs exclusion in service provision in your area? (increase of service provision?) The last two questions are to be focusing on IDPs&#x2019; and women&#x2019;s intra-societal interactions. By means: do women/IDPs experience intra-societal conflict with the rest of community members which prevent them from interacting/ participating in decision making/ solving problems- etc. The type of surveys is a cross sectional surveys (random sample of programme beneficiaries). The survey methodology will be using focus group discussions and/or individual questionnaires. The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for beneficiaries. The statistical samples should include representatives of the local CSOs and community groups such as local committees- unions- professional syndicates- etc. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyzing the data- and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion. Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RA4.2.3" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="46" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="40"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People have less personal grievances related to basic services due to an increased ability to meet household needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This long term outcome falls under ARC result area 4.2 Sustainable basic services to prevent the (re)occurrence of conflicts- instability or irregular migration and aims to reduce people&apos;s personal grievances related to basic services due to an increased ability to meet household needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity) in the targeted areas for the local communities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA4.2.2 (disaggregated) Number of programme beneficiaries who report reduced personal grievances [e.g. those related to conflict- instability or irregular migration] regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x2018;Personal grievances [e.g. those related to conflict- instability or irregular migration] regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity) refer to complaints/criticisms/objections or a strong feeling of an individual programme beneficiary- that he/she has received an unfair (lack of) quantity or quality of that/those service(s). Rationale: Result area 4.2 aims to reduce the personal grievances of persons targeted by the intervention regarding water or education (services)- in order to prevent the (re)occurrence of conflicts- instability or irregular migration. This is done by increasing the ability of the target group to meet needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity). This indicator measures how many individual programme beneficiaries sense that his/her grievances of having received (in the past) an unfair (lack of) quantity or quality of the relevant basic service(s) have recently diminished- as a consequence (long term outcome) of having participated in efforts to improve the delivery of (more and better) of the relevant basic service(s)- directed at the prevention of the (re)occurrence of conflict- instability and/or irregular migration. This can be as a consequence of participation in e.g. education programmes (to secure a basic living or be better informed about the risks of migration)- or because their communities have benefitted from the development and implementation of interventions to improve their access to water for human consumption or agriculture- etc. Disaggregation: - Male/Female - Youth*/Not Youth - IDPs/ Local residents *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who report reduced personal grievances [e.g. those related to conflict- instability- or irregular migration] regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity) at the moment of measurement. Data collection method: This is a perception indicator- which means that programme beneficiaries need to be asked the question: &#x201C;Do you experience a reduction in personal grievances [e.g. those related to conflict- instability or irregular migration] regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity)?&#x201D; This question is difficult to comprehend and respond when asked as such. This question should therefore be reformulated for each context through a series of questions. To enhance uniformity of data (and improve aggregation)- a set of sample questions will be used as a proxy indicator: - &#x201C;Do you currently feel grievances / complaints / strong feelings because you felt you received an unfair amount or quality of water / education / etc. (services)- in such a manner that it created conflict- instability or a desire to emigrate/flee? Explain more (stories will be used to inform the program on qualitative level) - &#x201C;According to you- is the Local Council doing something about the lack of water / education / etc. (services) that the IDPs and all community sectors are in?&#x201D; - &#x201C;Have said grievances / complaints / strong feelings of receiving an unfair amount or quality of water / education / etc. (services)- recently decreased or increased?&#x201D; The type of surveys is a cross sectional surveys (random sample of programme beneficiaries). The survey methodology will be using focus group discussions and/or individual questionnaires. The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for beneficiaries. The statistical samples should include representatives of the local CSOs and community groups such as local committees- unions- professional syndicates- etc. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyzing the data- and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion. Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RA4.2.2" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="210" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="250"></target>
     <actual value="116"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA4.2.2 (disaggregated) % of programme beneficiaries who report reduced personal grievances [e.g. those related to conflict- instability or irregular migration] regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x2018;Personal grievances [e.g. those related to conflict- instability or irregular migration] regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity) refer to complaints/criticisms/objections or a strong feeling of an individual programme beneficiary- that he/she has received an unfair (lack of) quantity or quality of that/those service(s). Rationale: Result area 4.2 aims to reduce the personal grievances of persons targeted by the intervention regarding water or education (services)- in order to prevent the (re)occurrence of conflicts- instability or irregular migration. This is done by increasing the ability of the target group to meet needs regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity). This indicator measures how many individual programme beneficiaries sense that his/her grievances of having received (in the past) an unfair (lack of) quantity or quality of the relevant basic service(s) have recently diminished- as a consequence (long term outcome) of having participated in efforts to improve the delivery of (more and better) of the relevant basic service(s)- directed at the prevention of the (re)occurrence of conflict- instability and/or irregular migration. This can be as a consequence of participation in e.g. education programmes (to secure a basic living or be better informed about the risks of migration)- or because their communities have benefitted from the development and implementation of interventions to improve their access to water for human consumption or agriculture- etc. Disaggregation: - Male/Female - Youth*/Not Youth - IDPs/ Local residents *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Percentage of programme beneficiaries who report reduced personal grievances [e.g. those related to conflict- instability- or irregular migration] regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity) at the moment of measurement. Data collection method: This is a perception indicator- which means that programme beneficiaries need to be asked the question: &#x201C;Do you experience a reduction in personal grievances [e.g. those related to conflict- instability or irregular migration] regarding the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (e.g. water / education / electricity)?&#x201D; This question is difficult to comprehend and respond when asked as such. This question should therefore be reformulated for each context through a series of questions. To enhance uniformity of data (and improve aggregation)- a set of sample questions will be used as a proxy indicator: - &#x201C;Do you currently feel grievances / complaints / strong feelings because you felt you received an unfair amount or quality of water / education / etc. (services)- in such a manner that it created conflict- instability or a desire to emigrate/flee? Explain more (stories will be used to inform the program on qualitative level) - &#x201C;According to you- is the Local Council doing something about the lack of water / education / etc. (services) that the IDPs and all community sectors are in?&#x201D; - &#x201C;Have said grievances / complaints / strong feelings of receiving an unfair amount or quality of water / education / etc. (services)- recently decreased or increased?&#x201D; The type of surveys is a cross sectional surveys (random sample of programme beneficiaries). The survey methodology will be using focus group discussions and/or individual questionnaires. The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for beneficiaries. The statistical samples should include representatives of the local CSOs and community groups such as local committees- unions- professional syndicates- etc. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyzing the data- and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion. Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RA4.2.2" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="46" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="33"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3.c Communities and civil society organisations more effectively influence formal and informal authorities- responsible to maintain security- to perform their task effectively- accountably and in better coordination- responding to citizens needs and rights</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This sub-goal 1.3.b falls under the result area1. Human Security and corresponds to the overarchng sub-goal 1.3: Communities and civil society lead efforts to improved human security independently and in coordination with responsible authorities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1.SG.4 (disaggregated) Number of communities and civil society groups that report they have the capacity to influence formal and/or informal human security authorities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Communities and civil society groups&#x2019; refers to the actors that receive the support of the intervention for capacity development. Within the Syrian context it refers to the local CSOs and local residents/IDPs. &#x2018;the capacity to influence&#x2019; refers to the perception of respondents- i.e. to what extent they feel they are capable and effective in their efforts towards policy influencing- lobbying and advocacy. &#x2018;Formal and informal human security authorities&#x2019; refers to those bodies from the security sector that are targeted through the programme including the local administrative councils Rational: One assumption in the theory of change is that when human security authorities respond to citizens&#x2019; needs and rights- they will contribute to the human security situation in the area. Another assumption is that when pressured- informed and/or persuaded by CSOs and communities- human security authorities become more responsive to citizens&#x2019; rights and needs. The programme supports the capacity development of the community and civil society actors to do so. This indicator measures the number and % of actors who report an increase in their capacity to influence formal and informal human security authorities. The indicator measures the increase compared to the previous year. Disaggregation: - community members/ civil society groups - Local authority (always the local council of the area) - Male/ Female - Youth*/Not youth - IDP/Local resident *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Number of communities and civil society groups which report an increase in their capacity to influence formal and/or informal human security authorities. The number is not cumulative- i.e. you do not add this year&#x2019;s number to last year&#x2019;s number when you report. Data Collection Method: This is a perception indicator- whereby programme beneficiaries must be asked the question: &#x201C;Do you feel you have the ability to influence (in)formal human security authorities?&#x201D; This question is difficult to respond when asked directly and may need to be reformulated depending on the local context. several questions related to trust and cooperation about concrete situations that can be statistically analyzed together will be asked. The survey methodology will be using focus group discussions and/or individual questionnaires. The following questions will be asked: - Do you feel your efforts towards lobby/advocacy on public issues are recognized and action has been taken accordingly by the local authorities? - Would you go to the local authorities to report an incident/ injustice that you experienced? - If yes- how likely do you feel it would be that they follow-up on your report? - Were you/ your organization able to influence the decision making of the local council in the areas that you live/operate in? the questions will be reviewed as part of the overall learning agenda at a later stage. The measurement of this indicator will be compared to that of the year(s) before in order to assess whether and to what extent change (positive/negative) has occurred. The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for beneficiaries. The statistical samples should include representatives of the local CSOs and community groups such as local committees- unions- professional syndicates- etc. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyzing the data- and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion. Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RA1.SG.4" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="179" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="220"></target>
     <actual value="273"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1.SG.4 (disaggregated) % of communities and civil society groups that report they have the capacity to influence formal and/or informal human security authorities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Communities and civil society groups&#x2019; refers to the actors that receive the support of the intervention for capacity development. Within the Syrian context it refers to the local CSOs and local residents/IDPs. &#x2018;the capacity to influence&#x2019; refers to the perception of respondents- i.e. to what extent they feel they are capable and effective in their efforts towards policy influencing- lobbying and advocacy. &#x2018;Formal and informal human security authorities&#x2019; refers to those bodies from the security sector that are targeted through the programme including the local administrative councils Rational: One assumption in the theory of change is that when human security authorities respond to citizens&#x2019; needs and rights- they will contribute to the human security situation in the area. Another assumption is that when pressured- informed and/or persuaded by CSOs and communities- human security authorities become more responsive to citizens&#x2019; rights and needs. The programme supports the capacity development of the community and civil society actors to do so. This indicator measures the number and % of actors who report an increase in their capacity to influence formal and informal human security authorities. The indicator measures the increase compared to the previous year. Disaggregation: - community members/ civil society groups - Local authority (always the local council of the area) - Male/ Female - Youth*/Not youth - IDP/Local resident *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Percentage of communities and civil society groups which report an increase in their capacity to influence formal and/or informal human security authorities. The number is not cumulative- i.e. you do not add this year&#x2019;s number to last year&#x2019;s number when you report. Data Collection Method: This is a perception indicator- whereby programme beneficiaries must be asked the question: &#x201C;Do you feel you have the ability to influence (in)formal human security authorities?&#x201D; This question is difficult to respond when asked directly and may need to be reformulated depending on the local context. several questions related to trust and cooperation about concrete situations that can be statistically analyzed together will be asked. The survey methodology will be using focus group discussions and/or individual questionnaires. The following questions will be asked: - Do you feel your efforts towards lobby/advocacy on public issues are recognized and action has been taken accordingly by the local authorities? - Would you go to the local authorities to report an incident/ injustice that you experienced? - If yes- how likely do you feel it would be that they follow-up on your report? - Were you/ your organization able to influence the decision making of the local council in the areas that you live/operate in? the questions will be reviewed as part of the overall learning agenda at a later stage. The measurement of this indicator will be compared to that of the year(s) before in order to assess whether and to what extent change (positive/negative) has occurred. The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for beneficiaries. The statistical samples should include representatives of the local CSOs and community groups such as local committees- unions- professional syndicates- etc. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyzing the data- and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion. Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RA1.SG.4" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="39" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="45"></target>
     <actual value="87"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3.b Communities and civil society with diverse backgrounds increasingly build social understanding to enhance mutual trust- tolerance and improved human secur</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This sub-goal 1.3.b falls under the result area1. Human Security and corresponds to the overarchng sub-goal 1.3: Communities and civil society lead efforts to improved human security independently and in coordination with responsible authorities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1.SG.3 (disaggregated) Number of programme beneficiaries who report trust and cooperation within the community</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x201C;Trust and cooperation&#x201D; is identified to be the ability to believe- feel confident with- feel the truth and reliability- and the readiness to collaboration among community members and key players from various backgrounds and affiliations Rational: One important step towards improving human security is increasing trust- understanding- tolerance and cooperation between groups with diverse backgrounds within the community and civil society. The assumption is that increased social cohesion as a result of trust-building and cooperation will contribute to improved human security. This indicator measures to what extent beneficiaries experience trust and cooperation within the community. Disaggregation: - Male/ Female - Youth*/Not youth - IDP/Local resident *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who report trust and cooperation [&#x2026;]- in relation to the total number of respondents/beneficiaries. Data Collection Method: This is a perception indicator- whereby programme beneficiaries must be asked the question: &#x201C;Do you experience trust and cooperation within the community?&#x201D; This question is difficult to respond when asked directly and may need to be reformulated depending on the local context. several questions related to trust and cooperation about concrete situations that can be statistically analyzed together will be asked. The survey methodology will be using focus group discussions and/or individual questionnaires. The following questions will be asked: ? &#x2018;Do you attend consultation/ town hall meetings where other groups (IDPS- different ideological and affiliations- etc.) are also invited? ? &#x2018;Do you accept that a person from other groups ((IDPS- different ideological and affiliations- etc.) is being a member of the local council in your area? ? &#x2018;Do you accept to cooperate with individuals from other groups (IDPS- different ideological and affiliations- etc.) in business project or community work project (e.g. service provision- humanitarian aid- etc.)? The measurement of this indicator will be compared to that of the year(s) before in order to assess whether and to what extent change (positive/negative) has occurred. The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for local community members. The statistical samples should include various age groups- professional backgrounds and experiences- IDPs- and local residents. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyze the data and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion. Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RA1.SG.3" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="305" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="350"></target>
     <actual value="205"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1.SG.3 (disaggregated) % of programme beneficiaries who report trust and cooperation within the community</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x201C;Trust and cooperation&#x201D; is identified to be the ability to believe- feel confident with- feel the truth and reliability- and the readiness to collaboration among community members and key players from various backgrounds and affiliations Rational: One important step towards improving human security is increasing trust- understanding- tolerance and cooperation between groups with diverse backgrounds within the community and civil society. The assumption is that increased social cohesion as a result of trust-building and cooperation will contribute to improved human security. This indicator measures to what extent beneficiaries experience trust and cooperation within the community. Disaggregation: - Male/ Female - Youth*/Not youth - IDP/Local resident *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Percentage of programme beneficiaries who report trust and cooperation [&#x2026;]- in relation to the total number of respondents/beneficiaries. Data Collection Method: This is a perception indicator- whereby programme beneficiaries must be asked the question: &#x201C;Do you experience trust and cooperation within the community?&#x201D; This question is difficult to respond when asked directly and may need to be reformulated depending on the local context. several questions related to trust and cooperation about concrete situations that can be statistically analyzed together will be asked. The survey methodology will be using focus group discussions and/or individual questionnaires. The following questions will be asked: ? &#x2018;Do you attend consultation/ town hall meetings where other groups (IDPS- different ideological and affiliations- etc.) are also invited? ? &#x2018;Do you accept that a person from other groups ((IDPS- different ideological and affiliations- etc.) is being a member of the local council in your area? ? &#x2018;Do you accept to cooperate with individuals from other groups (IDPS- different ideological and affiliations- etc.) in business project or community work project (e.g. service provision- humanitarian aid- etc.)? The measurement of this indicator will be compared to that of the year(s) before in order to assess whether and to what extent change (positive/negative) has occurred. The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for local community members. The statistical samples should include various age groups- professional backgrounds and experiences- IDPs- and local residents. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyze the data and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion. Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RA1.SG.3" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="67" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
     <actual value="58"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.2.a Communities- men and women increasingly benefit from access to the specific basic service(s) supported through ARC (excl. education)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This sub-goal 4.2.a falls under the result area 4.2: Sustainable basic services to prevent the (re)occurrence of conflicts- instability or irregular migration and corresponds to the overarching sub-goal 4.2: Sustainable services (incl. for IDPs and refugees) have been provided in a manner that increases legitimacy of institutions and social cohesion</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA4.SG.6 (disaggregated) Number of programme beneficiaries who use the newly established/improved drinking water schemes and water points (objective indicator)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x2018;Drinking water scheme / water points&#x2019;: when we refer to drinking water schemes / water points- reference is made to access to improved water sources that is adequate for human consumption or agricultural use. The qualification of &#x2018;improved drinking water sources&#x2019; includes sources that- by nature of their construction or through active intervention- are protected from outside contamination- particularly fecal matter. It comprises piped water on premises such as piped household water connection located inside the user&#x2019;s dwelling- plot or yard. Other improved drinking water sources include public taps or standpipes- tube wells or boreholes- protected dug wells- protected springs and rainwater collection (UNICEF). In addition- and as per the local Syrian context- protected and clean water tanks provided by the local authorities to the residents are to be considered as an acceptable source for clean water since the high cost of fuel might prevent the intended rehabilitation of water networks and wells. Rationale: The result statement for subgoal 4.2a (i.e. at intermediate level) is that (targeted) communities- men and women increasingly benefit from access to water. The ARC programme aspires (see &#x2013; long term - result statement for RA4.2) that such access will gradually increase people&#x2019;s ability to meet household needs regarding water- which should help reduce the grievances of targeted people regarding water and thus help prevent the (re)occurrence of conflicts- instability or irregular migration. This indicator provides information about whether or not the drinking water schemes/ water points- which ARC grantees have newly established- are actually used by the intended beneficiaries- thereby providing information about the effectiveness of the programme in this regard- within its specific social context. The disaggregation (see below) provides additional information about the practical access by the intended beneficiaries and the inclusiveness of the communities in which the schemes have been developed. The indicator will in that sense also say something about the risk of (re)occurrence of conflicts over access to basic services. Disaggregation: 1) Service Provider: Government/ Local Councils / Private sector / CSOs/ Other 2) Male/ Female 3) Youth*/Not youth 4) IDPs/ Local residents *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who use the newly established water schemes (water sources that have been established during the period of measurement) - per calendar year Data collection method: This indicator will be measured through asking the local councils in each area about the number of beneficiaries that have access to the newly established water points/schemes. The first phase of verification will take place during site visits to the areas where these point/schemes are established to collect documentations. For the second phase of verification- the following question will be asked to the beneficiaries as a household survey- if applicable: - Do you have access to the newly established water schemes/points in your area? Specific attention in collecting information should be given to the use of drinking water by specific intended beneficiary groups (women and IDPs). Measuring access to water in relation to the prevention of the (re)occurrence of conflicts- may require a qualitative assessment of why specific target groups beneficiaries (e.g. women) may be hindered in using the established water sources or lack these sources. This may require an assessment of the effectiveness and quality of the project in terms of involving and reaching specific target group beneficiaries. Access to water does not automatically lead to improved social relations and/or the prevention of (re)occurrence of conflicts. The type of surveys is a cross sectional surveys (random sample of programme beneficiaries). The survey methodology will be using focus group discussions and/or individual questionnaires. The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for beneficiaries. The statistical samples should include representatives of the local CSOs and community groups such as local committees- unions- professional syndicates- etc. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyzing the data- and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion. Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the Local Councils- supporting documentation- and the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RA4.SG.6" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA4.SG.6 (disaggregated) % of programme beneficiaries who use the newly established/improved drinking water schemes and water points (objective indicator)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x2018;Drinking water scheme / water points&#x2019;: when we refer to drinking water schemes / water points- reference is made to access to improved water sources that is adequate for human consumption or agricultural use. The qualification of &#x2018;improved drinking water sources&#x2019; includes sources that- by nature of their construction or through active intervention- are protected from outside contamination- particularly fecal matter. It comprises piped water on premises such as piped household water connection located inside the user&#x2019;s dwelling- plot or yard. Other improved drinking water sources include public taps or standpipes- tube wells or boreholes- protected dug wells- protected springs and rainwater collection (UNICEF). In addition- and as per the local Syrian context- protected and clean water tanks provided by the local authorities to the residents are to be considered as an acceptable source for clean water since the high cost of fuel might prevent the intended rehabilitation of water networks and wells. Rationale: The result statement for subgoal 4.2a (i.e. at intermediate level) is that (targeted) communities- men and women increasingly benefit from access to water. The ARC programme aspires (see &#x2013; long term - result statement for RA4.2) that such access will gradually increase people&#x2019;s ability to meet household needs regarding water- which should help reduce the grievances of targeted people regarding water and thus help prevent the (re)occurrence of conflicts- instability or irregular migration. This indicator provides information about whether or not the drinking water schemes/ water points- which ARC grantees have newly established- are actually used by the intended beneficiaries- thereby providing information about the effectiveness of the programme in this regard- within its specific social context. The disaggregation (see below) provides additional information about the practical access by the intended beneficiaries and the inclusiveness of the communities in which the schemes have been developed. The indicator will in that sense also say something about the risk of (re)occurrence of conflicts over access to basic services. Disaggregation: 1) Service Provider: Government/ Local Councils / Private sector / CSOs/ Other 2) Male/ Female 3) Youth*/Not youth 4) IDPs/ Local residents *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Percentage of programme beneficiaries who use the newly established water schemes (water sources that have been established during the period of measurement) - per calendar year Data collection method: This indicator will be measured through asking the local councils in each area about the number of beneficiaries that have access to the newly established water points/schemes. The first phase of verification will take place during site visits to the areas where these point/schemes are established to collect documentations. For the second phase of verification- the following question will be asked to the beneficiaries as a household survey- if applicable: - Do you have access to the newly established water schemes/points in your area? Specific attention in collecting information should be given to the use of drinking water by specific intended beneficiary groups (women and IDPs). Measuring access to water in relation to the prevention of the (re)occurrence of conflicts- may require a qualitative assessment of why specific target groups beneficiaries (e.g. women) may be hindered in using the established water sources or lack these sources. This may require an assessment of the effectiveness and quality of the project in terms of involving and reaching specific target group beneficiaries. Access to water does not automatically lead to improved social relations and/or the prevention of (re)occurrence of conflicts. The type of surveys is a cross sectional surveys (random sample of programme beneficiaries). The survey methodology will be using focus group discussions and/or individual questionnaires. The tools of data collection will be designed accordingly and include surveys for beneficiaries. The statistical samples should include representatives of the local CSOs and community groups such as local committees- unions- professional syndicates- etc. In addition to keeping an adequate gender balance within the sample. The same tools and collection mechanisms- in addition to similar statistical samples will be maintained during the life of the program to ensure consistency and identicality of the type of the collected data. The M&amp;E team of the Consortium will be responsible of designing the tools- training the field team- designing the beneficiaries sample- collecting the data- analyzing the data- and create the baseline/measurement reports on a timely fashion. Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the Local Councils- supporting documentation- and the programme beneficiaries&#x2019; survey.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RA4.SG.6" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="40"></target>
     <actual value="72"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.2.b Communities- men and women increasingly benefit from access to education</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This sub-goal 4.2.a falls under the result area 4.2: Sustainable basic services to prevent the (re)occurrence of conflicts- instability or irregular migration and corresponds to the overarching sub-goal 4.2: Sustainable services (incl. for IDPs and refugees) have been provided in a manner that increases legitimacy of institutions and social cohesion</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA4.SG.7 (disaggregated) % of programme beneficiaries who have received formal education through the program</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x2018;Formal Education&#x2019;: the hierarchically structured- chronologically graded &#x2018;education system&#x2019;- running from primary school through the university and including- in addition to general academic studies- a variety of specialized programmes and institutions for full-time technical and professional training. Formal education is technical and professional training that is institutionalized- intentional and planned and provided by public organizations and recognized private bodies. It consists primarily of initial education designed for children and young people before their first entry to the labor market. It also includes other types of education such as vocational- special needs and adult education provided they are recognized as part of the formal education system by the relevant national education authorities. (UNESCO) &#x2018;Through the programme&#x2019; means that other than project organizations have provided educational programmes to the programme beneficiaries. Rationale: The result statement for subgoal 4.2a (i.e. at intermediate level) is that (targeted) communities- men and women increasingly benefit from access to education. The ARC programme aspires (see - long term - result statement for RA4.2) that such access will gradually increase people&#x2019;s ability to meet household needs regarding education- which should help reduce the grievances of targeted people regarding education and thus help prevent the (re)occurrence of conflicts- instability or irregular migration. This indicator provides information about whether increased access to (formal) education is actually used by the intended beneficiaries- thereby providing information about the effectiveness of the programme in this regard- within its&#x2019; specific context. The disaggregation (see below) provides additional information about the practical access to education by the intended beneficiaries and the inclusiveness of the formal education/training providers. Disaggregation: 1) Service Provider: Government / Local council/ Private sector / CSOs / Other 2) Male/ Female 3) Children (up to 14 years) / Youth* (15 &#x2013; 24) / Not Youth (25 and beyond) 4) IDPs/ Local residents Desirable disaggregation by (if possible): - Type of education received: ? Technical or Vocational Education ? Primary Education ? Secondary Education ? University Education ? Adult Education *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Percentage of programme beneficiaries who have received formal education- per calendar year Data collection method: The data collection methods will mainly include asking the local councils and the CSOs that works in the field of education about the education programs and the numbers and gender of beneficiaries that are benefiting from these programs. This is an objectively verifiable indicator- which means that documentation is needed to demonstrate how many programme beneficiaries received formal education- e.g. registers of formal training providers (Educational institutes- NGOs- Private sector- other). Specific attention in collecting information should be given to the participation in formal education by the specific targeted beneficiaries (Females and IDPs). Measuring access to education in relation to the prevention of the (re)occurrence of conflicts- may require a qualitative assessment of why specific target groups beneficiaries (e.g. children of a specific ethnic background) may not be taking part in formal education. This may require an assessment of the effectiveness and quality of the project in terms of involving and reaching specific target group beneficiaries. The mere provision of formal education does not automatically lead to improved social relations and/or the prevention of (re)occurrence of conflicts. Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the LCS and CSOs working in the field of education- in addition to form of documentation/register that tracks the number of recipients of formal education.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RA4.SG.7" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="40"></target>
     <actual value="85"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA4.SG.7 (disaggregated) Number of programme beneficiaries who have received formal education through the program</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention of this program is directed including local community members- IDPs- and LCs and CSOs members. &#x2018;Formal Education&#x2019;: the hierarchically structured- chronologically graded &#x2018;education system&#x2019;- running from primary school through the university and including- in addition to general academic studies- a variety of specialized programmes and institutions for full-time technical and professional training. Formal education is technical and professional training that is institutionalized- intentional and planned and provided by public organizations and recognized private bodies. It consists primarily of initial education designed for children and young people before their first entry to the labor market. It also includes other types of education such as vocational- special needs and adult education provided they are recognized as part of the formal education system by the relevant national education authorities. (UNESCO) &#x2018;Through the programme&#x2019; means that other than project organizations have provided educational programmes to the programme beneficiaries. Rationale: The result statement for subgoal 4.2a (i.e. at intermediate level) is that (targeted) communities- men and women increasingly benefit from access to education. The ARC programme aspires (see - long term - result statement for RA4.2) that such access will gradually increase people&#x2019;s ability to meet household needs regarding education- which should help reduce the grievances of targeted people regarding education and thus help prevent the (re)occurrence of conflicts- instability or irregular migration. This indicator provides information about whether increased access to (formal) education is actually used by the intended beneficiaries- thereby providing information about the effectiveness of the programme in this regard- within its&#x2019; specific context. The disaggregation (see below) provides additional information about the practical access to education by the intended beneficiaries and the inclusiveness of the formal education/training providers. Disaggregation: 1) Service Provider: Government / Local council/ Private sector / CSOs / Other 2) Male/ Female 3) Children (up to 14 years) / Youth* (15 &#x2013; 24) / Not Youth (25 and beyond) 4) IDPs/ Local residents Desirable disaggregation by (if possible): - Type of education received: ? Technical or Vocational Education ? Primary Education ? Secondary Education ? University Education ? Adult Education *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Unit of Measurement: Total number of programme beneficiaries who have received formal education- per calendar year Data collection method: The data collection methods will mainly include asking the local councils and the CSOs that works in the field of education about the education programs and the numbers and gender of beneficiaries that are benefiting from these programs. This is an objectively verifiable indicator- which means that documentation is needed to demonstrate how many programme beneficiaries received formal education- e.g. registers of formal training providers (Educational institutes- NGOs- Private sector- other). Specific attention in collecting information should be given to the participation in formal education by the specific targeted beneficiaries (Females and IDPs). Measuring access to education in relation to the prevention of the (re)occurrence of conflicts- may require a qualitative assessment of why specific target groups beneficiaries (e.g. children of a specific ethnic background) may not be taking part in formal education. This may require an assessment of the effectiveness and quality of the project in terms of involving and reaching specific target group beneficiaries. The mere provision of formal education does not automatically lead to improved social relations and/or the prevention of (re)occurrence of conflicts. Source of Data: For this indicator- the source is the LCS and CSOs working in the field of education- in addition to form of documentation/register that tracks the number of recipients of formal education.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="RA4.SG.7" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
