<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-25090</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stomana II Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As part of an overall rationalization of Sidenor, the project will allow increased downstream processing in Bulgaria, thus increasing value generated in Bulgaria and saving the company transport costs from Greece where the bulk of Sidenors long products is currently produced. Stomanas product quality will increase and comply with EU requirements enabling the company to satisfy expected medium-term robust demand growth in the region. The project will benefit from the management expertise of a strong sponsor, who has significant technological know-how.  Also, the sponsor will bring into the project advanced marketing and customer support activities with the aim to providing global solutions to its customers along with established product quality. The project is expected to result in better efficiency due to implementation of new, better technology.       The project is important for strengthening the cross border cooperation and Bulgarian economic growth, especially in light of Bulgarias accession to the EU in 2007. Over the long term, the project is expected to serve as a model for further private-sector development by: providing a clear example of continuity in application of modern management and corporate governance in Bulgaria; attracting a sponsor with first-class expertise; and promoting the development of a key industry for the Bulgarian economy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Steel mini-mill Stomana Industry A.D. (Stomana or the company), an existing IFC client, is the second largest steel producer in Bulgaria.  The company plans to bring into operation a new hot rolling mill, to be located within its existing facilities.  The project, expected to cost about Euro 43 million in capital investment, is going to be implemented over a one and a half to two-year period. It is not going to affect Stomana&apos;&apos;s crude steel capacity as planned investment is in downstream operation.     The installation of a new long products rolling mill in Stomana is an important strategic investment for Sidenor allowing it to:     - rationalize its total production and take a full advantage of Stomanas upstream capacity.     - gradually replace low value added products with the higher added value long products; and    - improve cost competitiveness due to:    - reduction in overall transportation costs;    - more efficient new equipment and processes of the new rolling mill; and    - lower labor cost in Bulgaria than those in Greece.    The project will be sponsored by Sidenor Steel Products Manufacturing S.A. (&quot;Sidenor&quot;) a large Greek manufacturer and marketer of steel products, listed in the Athens Stock Exchange, who acquired Stomana in 2001.  After Sidenors acquisition, Stomana was turned around and transformed into a sound and quite profitable enterprise.  Sidenor is part of Viohalco, Greece, the largest metal processing group in the country, which also sponsored two other IFC projects.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STOMANA-INDUSTRY AD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-25090" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2006-06-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2006-08-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Konstantin Stamenov   Stomana Industry   1, Vladaisko Vastanie St.   2304 Pernik, Bulgaria    The ERS will be disclosed on Stomanas factory gate in Pernik and on Stomanas website.</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bulgaria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="BG-Bulgaria">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will be implemented on Stomanas existing premises, located in the industrial zone of the town of Pernik, Bulgaria.  Pernik is situated about 30 kilometers southwest of Bulgarias capital, Sofia.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>42.6666720000 25.2500000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Iron and Steel</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $21.42 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2006-06-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2006-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2006-06-22">21420000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2006-06-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2006-06-22">21420000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STOMANA-INDUSTRY AD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/25090/stomana-ii-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
