<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-10423</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPIQ/ELEX CEM</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project is to modernize and expand the current electronic components manufacturing, assembly, and testing operations of the production facilities of EPIQ-EA and XPEQT, (together &quot;the company&quot;). The project consists of: (i) significantly increasing the production capacity, and adding new technologies, for printed circuit board (PCB) assembly, complex electronic sub assemblies, and testing; (ii) introducing double color and wider application plastic injection moulding; (iii) enhancing the capacity and technical capability of the tooling sho  p (&quot;the project&quot;).   The existing operations in Bulgaria are only the initial phase of a much larger project, and do not realize the full potential of the facilities in Bulgaria to meet the current market demand growth. The company would benefit significantly from the investment, which would   significantly broaden the technical scope and product range of the facilities   and enable it to further strengthen the Group (includes the ponsors, and their affiliated companies) position in the global contract electronic manufacturing (CEM) market.     EPIQ-EA is limited liability company, founded in 1997, registered in Botevgrad, Bulgaria with a share capital of 1,950,000 BGN, and wholly owned by EPIQ-NV, a public limited company registered in Tessenderlo, Belgium. Its production facility has 3,500 square meters production floor for module assembly and 1000 square meters for assembly, including clean room class 10000, and employs over 500 people. EPIQ EA is QS9000 (1999), VALEO 1000 (1998) and ISO 9002 (1998) certified.      XPEQT (formerly Sigma Delta - Bulgaria) is a limited liability company registered in September 2000 in Sofia, Bulgaria with an authorized share capital of 1,410,500 BGN. It is wholly owned by Sigma Delta Holding N.V. XPEQT specializes in manufacturing of test equipment, and in integrated circuit design and tool making.     IFCs role in the proposed project is three-fold: (i) increase confidence in and support for the Governments privatization efforts; (ii) act as a catalyst for foreign investment and private sector participation in Bulgaria; and (iii) help the Sponsors gain access to long-term financing.   By supporting a well managed Bulgarian production facility such as EPIQ EA, IFC would help encourage and enhance local production of high-tech devices in the electronic/semiconductor appliances manufacturing sector. The project is expected to generate significant number of new jobs along with having a spillover effect. Furthermore, it is envisaged that the appropriate terms and structuring of this investment would help encourage other lenders and investors to consider such other projects in Bulgaria. Another benefit of the proposed project to Bulgaria would be in the form of net foreign exchange earnings as the project is export oriented.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTEGRATED MICRO-ELECTRONICS BULGARIA EOOD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-10423" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2001-05-11" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2001-12-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Nikolay Berov, Managing Director, EPIQ Electronic Assembly, Industrial Zone Microelectronika, 2140 Botevgrad, Bulgaria   phone: +359 48 969 544; fax 359 723 2436; e-mail: nbe@sd-bul.bg</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bulgaria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="BG-Bulgaria">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The manufacturing facilities are located in Sofia and   in Industrialna zona Microelectronica Botevgrad - 2140, Bulgaria  , some 50 km to the north of Sofia. The expansion project foresees construction of two new buildings - one on the existing industrial site in Botevgrad and another one in the city of Sofia.    The locations provides the companies convenient air and land transport connections to Europe.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>42.6666720000 25.2500000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BB - Computer &amp; Electronic Products(Computers &amp; Peripherals, Communications Equip., Elec. Watches &amp; Similar Elec. Products.  Integrated Circuits &amp; the application of Miniturization Technologies characterize this sector.)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $7.98 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2001-05-11"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2001-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2001-05-11">7980000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2001-05-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2001-05-11">7980000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTEGRATED MICRO-ELECTRONICS BULGARIA EOOD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/10423/epiq-elex-cem">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
