<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5209002501-LBR-15111</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public Financial Management (Support) IMF</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d till Offentlig Finansiell Styrning  IMF</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d till reformer och arbete med antikorruption genom st&#xF6;d till teknisk r&#xE5;dgivning till koordineringskontoret f&#xF6;r Public financial    Managment i Liberia genom IMF.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to PFM-reforms and work with anti-corruption through TA support to the Coordination office for PFM in Liberia through IMF.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="43000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IMF/International Monetary Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="43000" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IMF/International Monetary Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15111" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public finance management (PFM)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="1.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1 - By 2030, eradicate extreme poverty for all people everywhere, currently measured as people living on less than $1.25 a day.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">1.1 - Senast 2030 avskaffa den extrema fattigdomen f&#xF6;r alla m&#xE4;nniskor &#xF6;verallt. Med extrem fattigdom avses f&#xF6;r n&#xE4;rvarande m&#xE4;nniskor som lever p&#xE5; mindre &#xE4;n 1,25 US-dollar per dag.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="1.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.4 - By 2030, ensure that all men and women, in particular the poor and the vulnerable, have equal rights to economic resources, as well as access to basic services, ownership and control over land and other forms of property, inheritance, natural resources, appropriate new technology and financial services, including microfinance.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">1.4 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla m&#xE4;n och kvinnor, i synnerhet de fattiga och de utsatta, har lika r&#xE4;tt till ekonomiska resurser, tillg&#xE5;ng till grundl&#xE4;ggande tj&#xE4;nster, m&#xF6;jlighet att &#xE4;ga och kontrollera mark och andra former av egendom samt tillg&#xE5;ng till arv, naturresurser, l&#xE4;mplig ny teknik och finansiella tj&#xE4;nster, inklusive mikrokrediter.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B04" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2010-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">1638125.6549343525</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">975047.6443735318</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2010-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">1638125.6549343523</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">975047.6443735318</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">-251743.3029549848</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-02-01">2655200.178758</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-04-28">1638125.6549343525</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-07-28">975047.6443735318</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-28">-251743.2638313542</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The technical assistance provided through the project has complemented the capacity building and technical assistance being delivered through the multi-donor trust fund, the Integrated Public Financial management Reform Project (IPFMRP), funded by the AfDB, EU, Sida, USAID and the World Bank, signed in 2012. The PFM advisor&#x2019;s presence on the ground (until 2014) helped in coordinating the activities of the two projects to avoid overlaps or duplications.
The project provided a package of continued and strengthened Technical Assistance (TA) in the public financial management. It consisted of a long-term PFM advisor to support PFM reform coordination supported by scoping, briefing and inspection missions, complemented by eight diagnostic and follow-up Fiscal Affairs Department (FAD) missions, 36 Short-Term-Expert (STX) assignments, one training, one study tour, and three capacity-building workshops, to assist the Ministry of Finance (MoF) in designing and implementing the PFM reform program.
During 2011, the project helped in putting in place the framework for PFM reforms for the period 2011-14, around which donors have coordinated their support programs, some of which were channeled through the multi-donor trust fund established in 2012. The advisory support provided by the PFM advisor has helped develop the Reform Coordination Unit (RCU) into taking the lead role in PFM reform matters.
Significant progress has also been made in other areas covered by the project, namely: assisting the Department of the Budget to launch the Medium-Term Expenditure Framework (MTEF) process for the 2012/13 budget; preparation of frameworks and detailed action plans for cash management and county treasuries; and contribution to a government-wide action plan for the management and oversight of state-owned enterprises.
During 2012, funding for PFM reforms was increased by some $28 million through the IPFMRP, for which the project was a major catalyst providing the reform strategy, capacity building and monitoring frameworks, and operational guidelines. The PFM advisor continued to provide close support across the board on all PFM reform components, organizing or contributing to a number of workshops, although his limited access to senior management in 2012 reduced the effectiveness of his advisory role at that level. IMF/FAD led a Public Expenditure and Financial Accountability (PEFA) assessment in 2012 which highlighted progress achieved since 2008.
It also carried out a second fiscal decentralization mission whose report provided detailed guidance on the fiscal aspects of the process and emphasized the urgent need for the MoF to take the lead in these matters. The project also provided a number of STX visits in the areas of monitoring state-owned enterprises, cash management, fiscal reporting, county treasuries, and institutional aspects of project management.
During 2013, the TA provided through the project complemented the capacity building and TA delivered through the IPFMRP. The PFM advisor&#x2019;s presence on the ground, and the information sharing between the two project teams helped coordinate the activities of the two projects to avoid overlaps or duplications. The advisor&#x2019;s on-the-job and formal capacity building efforts have made an effective contribution to staff understanding of the reforms they are engaged in. The resident advisor&#x2019;s coordination effort also ensured timely and appropriate input from the two IMF HQ-led missions in 2013.
In line with the 2013 FAD mission recommendations, the PFM advisor guided the establishment of a Budget Working Group (BWG). The BWG coordinated the preparation of the 2014/15 budget estimates, for approval by Cabinet and submission to the Legislature, prepared the criteria for budget hearings and finalized the budget estimates. A comprehensive MTEF manual was prepared with input from the PFM advisor, which resulted in a more efficient budget preparation process. Efforts to entrench cash management reforms were hampered by changes in the management of the treasury services including the suspension and eventual dismissal of the Controller and Accountant General.
Fiscal reporting improved following the rollout of the Integrated Financial Management System (IFMIS) to major ministries, which contributed to the timely finalization of the annual statements of accounts. Policy changes were made to improve State Owned Enterprises (SOE) reporting mechanisms and inadequate financial management. Some critical progress was made in setting up mechanisms for de-concentrating treasury services including the identification of staff to be deployed, the completion of a county treasury financial manual, and training. A number of workshops funded by the project were held across the country. Fifteen Government representatives attended training at Duke University / USA in January 2014 on the principles and policy options relating to fiscal decentralization.
A short-term expert assisted in training staff to carry out a PEFA self-assessment culminating in the first selfassessment report by Liberia. After July 2014, minimal TA was provided through the project due to Ebola Virus Disease (EVD).
A short-term expert visited Liberia in December 2015 to provide training to county officials on good practice in fiscal decentralization and to assist in implementing the County Financial Management Framework. A local expert participated in the training session with the aim of developing further capacity within MFDP to support counties in implementing Fiscal Decentralization objectives. FAD recommended further assistance in setting up the Local Government Fiscal Board in determining formulas for transferring resources to counties. With respect to the draft Local Government Bill, the expert noted the following issues: 1) the need to clarify responsibilities in the provision of municipal local type services; 2) a lack of pricing mechanisms for the use of services by non-county residents particularly in health; 3) a contradiction between the general hiring power attributed to the Civil Service Agency and the one assigned to counties in the case of teachers; and 4) a lack of clarity as to various tax bases and a gap in establishing the relationship between county tax administrations and the Liberia Revenue Authority.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52090025" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060503" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1320000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Liberia 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Liberia 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
