<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10048A0101-LBR-11330</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Fr&#xE4;mja ungdomsarbete genom st&#xF6;d till TVET</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting Youth Employment Through Support to TVET</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the contribution is to lift beneficiaries from poverty by increasing their chances to gain productive employment. The expected outcome is a robust and inclusive Technical and Vocation Education and Training (TVET) system that is responsive to economic needs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Svenska ambassaden i Monrovia har f&#xE5;tt en f&#xF6;rfr&#xE5;gan fr&#xE5;n UNIDO f&#xF6;r finansiering av USD 6,213,870, uppskattat 55 miljoner kronor f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra Promoting youth employment by supporting technical and vocational education i Liberia f&#xF6;r perioden 2018&#x2013;2023. UNIDO kommer vara huvudansvariga f&#xF6;r att implementera projektet. 

Projektets &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att lyfta unga fr&#xE5;n fattigdom genom att ge dem &#xF6;kade m&#xF6;jligheter till en produktiv anst&#xE4;llning via ett robust och inkluderande TVET-system (Technical Vocational Education and Training), med k&#xE4;nnedom om marknadens ekonomiska behov. Projektet kommer bidra till f&#xF6;ljande resultat: 
- &#xF6;kad kapacitet hos l&#xE4;rare genom formell l&#xE4;rarutbildning som fokuserar p&#xE5; yrkesf&#xF6;rberedande utbildning
- st&#xE4;rkt kompentens bland befolkningensf&#xE4;rdigheter s&#xE5; att det &#xF6;verensst&#xE4;mmer med de ekonomiska behoven (till exempel infrastrukturutveckling och jordbruk)
- &#xF6;ka engagemanget hos privata sektorn f&#xF6;r delaktighet inom TVET-sektorn 

Utveckling av ungdomar kommer vara i fokus, vilket kommer uppn&#xE5;s genom att st&#xE4;rka och bygga p&#xE5; nuvarande institutionell kapaciteterna hos Liberias tekniska och yrkesf&#xF6;rberande utbildnings system f&#xF6;r att leverera relevanta kurser som svarar till behoven hos ekonomin.  

Projektet kommer adressera b&#xE5;de efterfr&#xE5;gan och utbudet p&#xE5; arbetsmarknadens genom att utrusta ungdomar med f&#xE4;rdigheter som &#xF6;kar deras m&#xF6;jlighet till anst&#xE4;llning, och som resultat minskar nuvarande hinder f&#xF6;r f&#xF6;retag att expandera p&#xE5; grund av brist p&#xE5; kompetent arbetskraft.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIDO has applied to Sida for funding of USD 6,213,870, aproximately 55 million SEK, to carry out the promoting youth employment by supporting technical and vocational education in Liberia programme during the period 2018-2023. UNIDO will be the main implementing partner. 

The proposed intervention overall objective is to lift beneficiaries from poverty by increasing their chances to gain productive employment through a robust and inclusive TVET system (Technical Vocational Education and Training) that is responsive to economic needs. The intervention will support the following outputs: 
- improved capacity of teachers through participation in formal teacher training for vocational education; 
- strengthened human capital to correspond to economic needs (e.g. in infrastructure development and agribusiness); 
- and increased participation of the private-sector in stewardship and engagement with TVET sector at the school level.

Emphasis will be placed on youth development. This will be achieved by strengthening and building on the existing institutional capacity of Liberia&apos;s vocational training system to deliver up-to-date training courses relevant to the requirements of the economy. 

The intervention will address both labor demand and supply by equipping young persons with skills that increase their employability and earnings, and by removing bottlenecks to expanding profitable businesses due to skills shortages.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41123" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIDO/United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIDO/United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="113" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secondary Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vocational training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="4.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.3 - By 2030, ensure equal access for all women and men to affordable and quality technical, vocational and tertiary education, including university.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">4.3 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla alla kvinnor och m&#xE4;n lika tillg&#xE5;ng till yrkesutbildning och eftergymnasial utbildning, inklusive h&#xF6;gskoleutbildning, av god kvalitet till en &#xF6;verkomlig kostnad.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.a - Genomf&#xF6;ra reformer f&#xF6;r att ge kvinnor lika r&#xE4;tt till ekonomiska resurser, m&#xF6;jlighet att &#xE4;ga och kontrollera mark och andra former av egendom samt tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster, arv och naturresurser, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.a - Undertake reforms to give women equal rights to economic resources, as well as access to ownership and control over land and other forms of property, financial services, inheritance and natural resources, in accordance with national laws.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.6 - By 2020, substantially reduce the proportion of youth not in employment, education or training.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.6 - Till 2020 v&#xE4;sentligt minska den andel ungdomar som varken arbetar eller studerar.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1726042.5296879315</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1726042.5296879315</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.6985352403</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-12">4027432.569271</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">1726042.5296879315</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-28">1085811.69853524</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/liberia-and-sierra-leone/10048_UNIDOTEVTSupportAgreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement between Sweden and UNIDO</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/liberia-and-sierra-leone/10048_UNIDOTVETSupportDecision.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution (10048)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The period under review covers primarily the inception phase, procurement process for project operations equipment, arrangements for project office set up, conducting key studies and technical assessments in preparation for actual implementation.
The six months inception period (January to June 2019) was successful because it delivered on all the expected deliverables. Project staff and consultants were recruited, and the logical framework was revised to include impact indicators as well as indicators on gender and inclusion. Baselines and targets for some activities were established. Technical needs assessment was done, and it provided insights into the current status of teacher trainings at the Voinjama Multilateral High School (VMHS) and the Booker Washington Institute (BWI) that would guide the intervention. Infrastructure needs assessment was carried out; detailing the current structure of the facility as well as the work that needs to be done. A labor market needs assessment was done, and five vocations were identified as the ones that the current market in Lofa county demands; agriculture, welding/metal goods fabrication, carpentry/woodwork, electricity, automotive repair (light engines), and information and communication technology.
Under Output 1; improved capacity of teachers, administrators and principals through participation in formal TVET teacher training and Vocational Training Center (VTC) administration/management training programmes, the follow results have been attained:
Twenty TVET teachers have been recruited for overseas teachers training. A study tour to expose officials responsible for TVET in Liberia was undertaken to Kenya and Zambia. Relevant staff of the Ministry of Education (MoE) and the Ministry of Youth and Sports (MoYS) participated and documented good practices of properly functioning TVET governance and training delivery systems that could be replicated in Liberia.
8 staff from MOE/MOYS, 17 administrative staff from the TVET institutions (including two from Voinjama Multilateral High School (VMHS)) and four representatives of youth groups were introduced to monitoring and evaluation.
Preliminary work began on a TVET Center for Professional Training, Development, Research, and Innovation (TCPTRI) to be hosted by the BWI, which will act as the interface between TVET institutions and international sources to broker and coordinate TVET capacity development.
Under Output 2; TVET provider infrastructure and delivery system is upgraded to correspond to economic needs, the following have been undertaken: training equipment specification for Liberia and VMHS has been developed, and infrastructure designed work at the VMHS has commenced.
The Liberian TVET system has been benchmarked/compared against the national TVET systems of nine other African countries. This comparison established that Liberia had the lowest level of comparative matching with the international best practice model of TVET system at 36.33%. To make a comparison, the highest comparator score was the one of South Africa at 64.84%.
Under Output 3; increased participation of the private sector in stewardship and engagement with TVET sector at school level including in curriculum development and TVET delivery, the team developed an understanding of the formal and informal private sectors in Voinjama and Lofa County, and generated information required to ensure that TVET programmes are tailored to the needs of the local labour market. Links have been established with over 60 small to medium sized enterprises in 14 sectors.
Regrading Output 4; gender sensitized measures to foster enrolment and retention of female, vulnerable youth and people with disabilities, a gender-specific needs assessment was carried out and established various factors influencing female participation in TVET in Lofa County. These included financing, family influence, pregnancy or forced/early marriage, influence of peers, self-motivation, gender stereotypes and lack of quality TVET courses with the necessary practical components.
In joint effort with the MoE Director for Special and Inclusive Education, an assessment to define education needs and course delivery to persons with disability was carried out. Evidence shows that officials, school administration, teachers and students lack awareness of barriers to access TVET by disabled students but are willing to address this and take action. Most TVET teachers lack skills for inclusive education. Accordingly, VMHS infrastructure upgrade has taken into consideration barrier-free aspects to cater for students with disabilities.
Sweden and the EU Delegation in Liberia agreed that since UNIDO is implementing TVET programs for both donors, a cost-sharing formula of 83% (EU) with 6 schools and 13% (Sweden) with 1 school will be executed to cater to joint project human resources and operational arrangements.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10048" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060503" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1320000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Liberia 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Liberia 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
