<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5209005901-LBR-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Search  for Common Ground Liberia</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Search  for Common Ground Liberia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projektet &quot;st&#xE4;rka kapaciteten hos CSO f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja h&#xE5;llbar          f&#xF6;rvaltning i Liberia&quot; syftar till att bygga den institutionella,     organisation och teknisk kompetens tio liberianska det civila         samh&#xE4;llets organisationer i Liberia. Dessutom kommer programmet att   st&#xF6;dja utvecklingen av regelbundna dialogplattformar genom vilka det  civila samh&#xE4;llets organisationer i Liberia kan ha m&#xF6;jlighet att konst</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project &apos;Strengthening the capacity of CSO to promote sustainable Governance in Liberia&apos; aims to build the institutional,               organizational and technical competency of ten Liberian civil society organizations in Liberia. In addition, the programme will support the development of regular dialogue platforms through which CSOs in       Liberia can be able to constructively engage with the State,private s</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Search for Common Ground</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Search for Common Ground</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">1772813.898860967</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1535343.6098998955</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">583098.8789924051</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">593169.0650469197</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">-988608.1926021153</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">-307425.4124254124</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">1772813.8988609673</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1535343.6098998955</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">583098.878992405</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">593169.0650469197</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">-988608.1926021153</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">-307425.4124254124</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">-25793.8644941545</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-10-01">2941897.354075</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-11-28">1772813.898860967</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">1535343.6098998955</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-11-28">583098.8789924051</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">593169.0650469197</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-28">-494886.3542336235</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-28">-493721.8500555133</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-28">-307425.3714753714</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-28">-25793.8921108349</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Background and overview of the project
The overall goal of the project was to &#x201C;strengthen the capacity of civil society organizations in Liberia to promote a sustained democratic culture, the protection of human rights, and the inclusion of citizens in decision-making&#x201D;. The project sought to achieve the following specific objectives:
1. Increase the programmatic capacity of partner civil society organizations (CSOs) and community-based organizations (CBOs) to engage the state on targeted reform areas;2. Increase the institutional and financial capacity of CSOs and CBOs for sustained engagement with state institutions;3. Strengthen networking and collaboration among CSOs and CBOs at national and county levels;4. Increase information-sharing and dialogue between citizens, state institutions, and CSOs/CBOs at national and county levels.

Examples of results achieved - expected and unexpected
Overall, Search for Common Ground made significant achievement on the objective to&#xA0; strengthen the institutional capacity of civil society organizations to improve their credibility, visibility, effectiveness, and sustainability. The independent external evaluation found evidence that many partner CSOs supported by the project have refined their mission, developed a multi-year strategic plan, communications plan,&#xA0; gender policy and a HR policy. In addition, the supported partner CSOs began to integrate new financial reporting and M&amp;E structures. All of the partner CSOs have improved their sustainability by receiving additional funds to continue their work, and many of them have developed strategies to diversify their revenue generation, such as expanding their offices to rent out board rooms. A number of organizations were eager to pass their new knowledge onto others, with many training peer CSOs on what they learned through the project.&#xA0;
Some of the partners achieved successes in peacebuilding by bringing conflicting groups together to enhance dialogue, in particular Sustainable Development Institute(SDI), Ears for the Masses (EARS), Gender Peace Network (GPN) and Center for Justice and Peace Studies (CJPS). For these four organizations, successful dialogue was corroborated by local government officials and citizens/citizens&#x2019; groups. Bringing groups together to mediate conflicts was particularly important in the target counties, where frequent conflicts over lands between different groups were identified as a potential driver of violence.
Search for Common Ground provided institutional support to seven local organizations at national and county level acting on citizen engagement with decentralization and security sector reforms. The seven organizations supported by Search for Common Ground have documented important results. For example, the Gender Peace Network (GPN) in Grand Gedeh County resolved a longstanding local dispute that existed between residents of Zai and Zleh Towns in Grand Gedeh County where violence between youth from the two towns was common occurrence. The Ears for the Masses (EARS) in Nimba County reported that its work with police and citizen relations has contributed to significant reduction in the occurrence of police violence against citizens.
There was substantial evidence that the majority of CSO partners have improved their institutional capacity, thereby being better positioned to: engage the state around key reforms and monitor progress; engage citizens and raise awareness about issues related to security sector reform and decentralization.
The&#xA0; final evaluation found that the project was highly relevant to the civil society partners who participated in it, as well as to other civil society advocates and leaders in the country. Many of the partners expressed how the project allowed them to focus on what they need to improve institutionally, while giving them the freedom towork on the issues that were of greatest importance to them.
The focus of the project on capacity-building and coalition-building was highly relevant to the civil society space in Liberia. Informants, including project partners, highlighted that there was a lack of cooperation, cohesion and coordination among CSOs, which often limited collective action to effect community change. During the evaluation, all of the project partners indicated that the greatest benefit of the project to their organizations was the collaboration with civil society actors at the national level and across counties. For national partners, the collaboration with county-based CSOs allowed them to extend their presence in the counties where they worked, and to ground their policy-related work in the daily struggles of smaller, local civil society organizations. For county-based partners, the connection with larger and more established national CSOs allowed them to improve their credibility, enhance their knowledge and awareness of sector-specific issues, and gain visibility among national stakeholders and international donors.
In terms of sustainability related indicators, such as receiving additional financial and non-financial resources and developing a sustainability plan, all partners who completed the participatory reflective exercise attributed sustainability-related gains directly to the project. Many of the partners were able to diversify their funding base and to attract additional financial or non-financial resources.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52090059" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060503" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1320000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Liberia 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Liberia 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
