<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5209006401-LBR-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Aid - Sexual &amp; Reproductive Rights</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Action Aid Liberia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall objective
Women, girls and groups exposed to stigma and discrimination across Liberia enjoy fundamental human rights as a result of the claims of a strengthened advocacy oriented civil society and evidence of quality responses from local government and the state.
Specific Objectives:
Objective 1: Women, girls and particularly discriminated groups have improved access to sexual and reproductive health and rights
Objective 2: Women and girls have increased protection from all forms of violence, abuse and exploitation through improved monitoring, risk assessment and prevention efforts.
Objective 3: Capacity of state and non-state actors at sub-national level in 6 counties are strengthened to integrate gender and human rights in the provision of services affecting vulnerable women, youth and girls
Objective 4: An inter-agency development forum developed to act with coordinated and enhanced capacity to influence gender and human rights in targeted policies and development plans at national level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projektet syftar till att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra skyddet och r&#xE4;ttigheterna f&#xF6;r     kvinnor, flickor och andra diskriminerade grupper i sex l&#xE4;n i         Liberia. Det tar upp fr&#xE5;gor som r&#xF6;r sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och r&#xE4;ttigheter, inklusive kvinnlig k&#xF6;nsstympning och diskriminering av   sexuella minoriteter som bland annat HBT personer.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to enhance the protection and rights of women, girls and other groups facing discrimination in 45 communities in four      counties in Liberia. The project will address issues relating to      sexual and reproductive health and rights including female genital    multilation,and discrimination of sexual minorities, including        respect for the human rights of LGBTI.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ActionAid International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ActionAid International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">767671.8049499477</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">583098.8789924051</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">415218.3455328438</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">409045.7546894174</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">912600.9126009126</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">-983.4071849322</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">767671.8049499477</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">583098.8789924053</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">415218.3455328437</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">409045.7546894174</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">912600.9126009126</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">-983.4071849322</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-01">3652690.075538</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">767671.8049499477</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-11-28">583098.8789924051</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-11-28">415218.3455328438</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-28">409045.7546894174</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">912600.9126009125</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-28">-983.4463139416</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and girls have increased access to reproductive health information and services
The established forums for boys and girls in 45 communities in four counties s served as a safe spaces for young people to come together, learn, interact, and discuss issues affecting them and a platformor them&#xA0; to identify collective actions to address problems of concern to them. Young people&#xA0; increased skills and knowledge around HIV/AIDS, SRHR, and human right violations including women&#x2019;s rights, gender analysis, protection laws, and referral systems at the community level. Forums members led community advocacy focusing on engaging community leaders and service providers on the provision of gender responsive services. For examples, girls&#x2019; forums in Medina, Vaye Town, Belleyala, Palala, David Dean Town, Ziah Town, Tianma Town Gbarpolu, Bong and Grand Gedeh led advocacy campaigns demanding improved SRHR and protection services in their communities. Adolescent and young women across the four counties reported easy access to safe and confidential sexual reproductive health services at local health facilities at community and sub-national levels due to increased advocacy and awareness by the forums.&#xA0;
&#xA0;
Support services and networks exist to improve the sexual health and rights for stigmatized and discriminated groups
The Ministry of Justice working with the Liberia National Police establisehd a Diversity Desk with assigned officers to directly support protection cases within the police departmentaffecting members of the LGBTIQ community. The Desk has contributed to significant reduction in discrimination and improvement in the handling of protection cases reported at the Police by members of the LGBTIQ community.&#x201C;I am extremely happy for the project because it has brought out change and increased protection for Community members. Before the police use to arrest us even when we carry our complains. This was so frustrating for the community to the extent that a lot of community members lost their lives because of fear and discrimination. The situation has shifted a lot and we now feel safe in the community&#x201D;. John Weah, member of LGBTI Community in Monrovia. 
Ministry of Justice also provided support with documentation, tracking, and proper follow up of such cases. As part of the process, AAL supported the development of the Universal Period Review (UPR) and Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination against Women (CEDAW) reporting to ensure that cases are properly documented and tracked. People living with HIV/AIDS including women across the four project counties reported improved treatment, care, and support as well.
Improved measures in place to address the special needs of young women and girls engaged in sex work
Increased protection for Sex Workers against SGBV: As the result of the capacity building activities (training, coaching/mentoring), sex workers actively engaged in advocacy for increase in protection against violence, stigma, and discrimination. In 2016 and 2017, sex workers in the Red-Light Community, Montserrado County held several engagement meetings with the National Police on the issue of sexual violence by police officers. Officials of the Police expressed dissatisfaction over the report of their officers not providing the required support to vulnerable groups. Strong warning was given to all officers at Zone 5 and it&#x2019;s depots in the Paynesville belt. Sex workers were encouraged to continue the engagement and report any case of stigma and discrimination. To date, there has not been any report of case against police officer from these stations. Also, four engagement meetings were held with the County Health Team on the issues of access to SRHR service and psychosocial support. As the result of all these engagements, sex workers reported improvement in the handling of their cases.
In 2018, with the project contribution, an Alliance (White Rose Alliance WRA) was established to continue the advocacy for the protection of sex workers specifically addressing issues affecting female sex workers. The presence of WRA has shifted the condition and position of sex workers as they are now leading advocacy at both national and sub-national levels. There are plans to decentralize the Alliance to ensure adequate protection of sex workers across the country. As a way of sustaining the gains, AAL was able to secure funding from the European Union and is currently providing economic empowerment for members of the Alliance. This will further strengthen their capacity to be able to address protection issues. Sex workers from Gbarpolu, Montserrado, and Bong are benefiting from this support. In addition, Gender Based Violence Taskforces in four counties have recognized and incorporated protection mechanisms for sex workers and other vulnerable groups.
Actors in health and education at county and district level increase quality of their response to GBV and harmful traditional practice, working with CSOs and CBOs
As the result of support provided to local authorities (Justice, Internal Affairs, Health, Education, and Gender ministries) there was significant improvement in the provision of services and response to SGBV and harmful traditional practices (HTPs) cases. Culture Department at Ministry of Internal Affairs (MIA) and National Council of Chiefs and Elders (NCCEL) were supported to review and document all traditional sites in the project location. The objective of this was to ensure proper documentation of licensed Zoes and their practices which ensured the regulation of activities. Over the five years, dialogue sessions were held with Ministries of Internal Affairs and Justice, NCCEL, INCHR and other stakeholders to facilitate&#x2019; improved coordination and strengthen reporting and documentation of HTP cases at both national and sub-national level. As a result, INHRC and MOJ have improved their response in handling HTP cases including documentation, referral, and follow up on cases at the court level.
NATPAH in close collaboration with the FGM Working Group and other CSOs have been leading on HTPs engagement at the national and sub-national levels. The project extensively supported the drafting of the FGM Bill where several consultations were done at both national and sub-national levels. This engagement on HTP was not limited to the project locations but also across the 15 counties. In 2017, communities in Nimba reported 4 cases of rape and only 1 reach court level. Financial support was provided to the family for immediate relocation and reintegration into another community. Women in Gbarpolu and Bong championed the end to FGM; successfully leading advocacy initiatives to close 9 bush schools and ensure actions were taken against operations.
Support to County Gender offices has strengthened the response to GBV cases at the community level. At national level, AAL partnered with the Liberian Feminist Forum and other CSOs to advocate for the strengthening of systems and structures to adequately address GBV issues at all levels. Over the five years period, several engagement including dialogues and protests by whom? Were held and demands presented to relevant stakeholders including UN Women and Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Protection. Advocacy campaign is still on-going and AAL will continue to collaborate with other like-minded organizations to ensure demands which were addressed.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52090064" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060503" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1320000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Liberia 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Liberia 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
