<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>IM-CR-024714B-GG14-016</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="IM-CR-024714B" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">openmindedly</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">provide emergency supplies to refugees fleeing from the civil conflict in South Sudan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD requested an exceptional disaster emergency award to support its work responding to the needs of thousands internally displaced persons in South Sudan fleeing a resurgence of rebel hostilities.  The award was used to provide emergency health care and hygiene facilities, non-food item kits and small grants (approximately GBP15.00) to displaced families to purchase basic necessities for shelter, food and clothing. The non-food item kits included a bucket, large plastic sheet, jerry can, two sleeping mats and two blankets.  The project suffered some initial delays caused principally by the very high level of insecurity.  Some logistical aspects of the project proved more complex than originally anticipated, also due to the increasing insecurity of the project area. CAFOD&#x2019;s in-country partner, Caritas Malakal, was particularly affected by the crisis during the critical first weeks of this project. The staff were displaced for a number of weeks and all their assets (including cars, computers, desks and boats) were looted when Malakal town changed hands repeatedly between Government and opposition forces.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GG-OAC" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
   <provider-org ref="GG-OAC">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-CHC-1058226">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
