<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-LEB-21/DDA-3604/SA2/CP/NGO/20814</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Specialized Child Protection Services for 120 Children with Disabilities who are survivors  or at risk of Gender-Based Violence GBV and  provision of children protection services for 120 caregivers of the targeted children with disabilities and 480 children who are survivors of GBV- North Lebanon- Child Protection Sector</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADJI will provide specialized holistic and integrated child protection services for 120 children with disabilities CwDs who are out of education and or survivors of GBV and child protection services for 120 caregivers of the targeted children with disabilities and 480 children who are survivors or at risk of GBV. It will ensure that children (50% girls, 50% boys), despite the challenges faced due to the deteriorating economic situation, are reached and supported to access an integrated package of quality prevention and comprehensive response services including special education, and protection services tailored to their specific needs. The children are from Tripoli (Abi Samra, Mina, Quobbeh, Tabbane, Menieh, Zgharta&#x2026;..). The children with disabilities will be identified by Washington Group Questions WGQs and technical assessments by a specialized team. The disabilities types are moderate or severe intellectual disabilities, sensory disabilities, autism, multiple disabilities, and physical disabilities.

To ensure CwDs protection, ADJI will provide community-based and Focused Psychosocial Support FPSS services for children and caregivers, provide case management for CwDs, and implement social and behavioral change initiatives.

ADJI will provide FPSS sessions for the 120 CwDs to develop their resilience and strengthen peer networks that foster their emotional and mental health wellbeing. In addition, since children with severe and moderate disabilities are in need of tailored rehabilitation services, ADJI will provide the children with disabilities with adopted rehabilitation services as part of case management to improve their wellbeing and integrate them into their community. The program will be delivered remotely and physically, where children will attend the classes remotely 2 days per week and physically for 3 days per week.  

Moreover, ADJI will provide community-based PSS for 480 children identified by the teachers and PSS assistants from 3 different public schools in the North. ADJI will sensitize caregivers and communities on CwDs&apos; rights to strengthen the child protection mechanisms and to decrease attitudes preventing social inclusion. ADJI will cooperate with community leaders/influencers to advocate for children with disabilities&apos; rights, link them with service providers, and ensure PSEA implementation.
Since ADJI is adopting a centered approach, children who need additional services will be referred either internally to a community-based rehabilitation project or externally to a service provider who offers the requested services using RIMS.

Also, ADJI has permanent permission from MEHE (Annex 1) to provide awareness sessions in public schools about CwDs rights and inclusion concept, throughout the project ADJI will sensitize students in 5 public schools in North on child protection, CwDs, and appreciating diversity. CwDs supported by PSS officers/ assistants will conduct some sessions that will help in building themselves esteems. Moreover, various activities will be implemented to advocate for children&apos;s rights, children with disabilities integration, and inclusion in social lives such as sports activities, puppet shows, talent shows..etc. All the activities aim to promote child protection and to demolish the stereotypes about CwDs&apos; capabilities and promote their rights and social inclusion.

At the beginning of the project, all CwDs will receive PSS materials and will be supplied with assistive technologies (including the provision of tablets, accounts in Edmodo, and follow-up on various online platforms..etc). During physical attendance, ADJI will provide specialized transportation for the children to bring them from and to the center in a safe manner. ADJI will support caregivers of CwDs with a monthly data bundle.
The project will start on 1st January 2022 and end on 31st December 2022</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASSOCIATION DES JEUNES ISLAMIQUES</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASSOCIATION DES JEUNES ISLAMIQUES</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samar Mabsout</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+961 3 152 949</telephone>
   <email>accounting@rahmahospital.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ezzat Hussein Agha</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chief Executive Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+961 3 803 383</telephone>
   <email>ezzatagha@rahmahospital.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ihsan Al-Choghari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEO Office Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+961 3 173 432</telephone>
   <email>info@rahmahospital.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LBN5">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">North</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.43330000 35.85000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-18">295502.14</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-18">12700.66</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="LBN71-20814">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-18">308202.8</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASSOCIATION DES JEUNES ISLAMIQUES</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
