<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-LEB-21/DDA-3604/SA2/GBV/NGO/20828</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Empowering 130 Individuals from the LGBTQIA+ Community in Lebanon</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Throughout the 12 months&#x2019; duration of the project Soins Infirmiers et Developpement Communautaire (SIDC) aims to collaboratively work with individuals from the LGBTIQ+ community who are residing in Lebanon. The combined implementation of the project engages individuals from the LGBTQI+ community to reach out to other community members. 

This project consists of: (1) comprehensive case management services to 70 individuals from the LGBTIQ+ community that have experienced gender based violence, (2) 6 group awareness sessions to individuals from the LGBTIQ+ community, (3) 4 awareness sessions to employees from NGOs, (4) 528 one on one online outreach sessions, through online dating apps, reaching 7,920 individuals from the LGBTIQ+ community (5) 96 field outreach visits will be conducted to reach out to 3840 individuals who are at risk, including LGBTIQ+, Drug Users, Sex Workers,...etc

Case Management: 70 individuals from the LGBTIQ+ community will be provided with comprehensive case management services that involve an initial interview with SIDC&#x2019;s social workers to conduct an initial GBV assessment, provide psychosocial support, internally and/or externally refer beneficiaries to needed services, and continuous follow up over the duration of the project. Beneficiaries will benefit from sexual and reproductive health services (HIV, STIs, Hep B amp C testing, counseling, reproductive health consultations, consult with the dermatologist and STI specialist) consult with SIDC&#x2019;s voluntary counseling and testing officer to ensure their safety from any sexually transmitted infections, HIV, Syphillis, Hep B ampC. Moreover, beneficiaries will be internally referred to receive mental health support over the duration of the project. Finally, cash assistance will be provided to the 70 individuals to help reduce their exposure to further GBV, which may include shelter, legal, and medical support, amongst others. 

Awareness Sessions: For the group awareness sessions: 6 will be implemented to 60 individuals from the LGBTIQ+ community to raise their awareness on the topics of GBV, harassment, bullying, substance use, self-care and coping mechanisms, and legal awareness on their rights. 4 sessions will be conducted to 60 employees of NGOs to raise their awareness on sexual orientation, gender identity and expressions, and sexual characteristics (SOGIESC), vulnerability of individuals from the community, their legal rights, and referral pathways. 

For the individual sessions, one on one awareness sessions will be conducted through online dating apps. SIDC will be training 4 individuals from the LGBTIQ+ community on the topics of GBV, HIV, STIs, substance use, harm reduction, their rights, services available to them, and outreach techniques. Through a total of 528 online outreach sessions, the awareness of 7,920 individuals from the LGBTIQ+ will be raised through a peer to peer approach on the topics of GBV, sexual, reproductive, and mental health, harm reduction, services provided at SIDC, and referrals will be conducted when needed. Moreover, for the one on one sessions, SIDC will be training 5 peers to conduct field outreach through SIDC&apos;s mobile unit (on the topics mentioned above). The field outreach team will be present to conduct one on one awareness with 3840 individuals at risk. Team: 5 peers, 1 VCT officer, 1 mobile unit driver.


Finally, dignity kits will be distributed to 130 individuals from the LGBTIQ+ community who have received case management services and attended awareness sessions.

By the end of the project, SIDC will be developing a final project document of best practices which can be used as an advocacy tool to support survivors from the LGBTIQ+ community that have experienced gender based violence. This document will shed light on the needs of the LGBTIQ+ community and it will inspire strategies and recommendations on how to secure service provision for them without stigma and discrimination.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Soins Infirmiers et&#xA0;D&#xE9;veloppement Communautaire</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Soins Infirmiers et&#xA0;D&#xE9;veloppement Communautaire</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-13" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grace Rahhal</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Development Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>70829302</telephone>
   <email>g.rahal@sidc-lebanon.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rana Morcos</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accountant</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>03350234</telephone>
   <email>r.morcos@sidc-lebanon.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LBN1">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beirut</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.88690000 35.51310000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="LBN3">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mount Lebanon</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.83330000 35.53330000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-14"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-18">235100.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-18">8707.41</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="LBN71-20828">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-18">243807.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Soins Infirmiers et&#xA0;D&#xE9;veloppement Communautaire</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305417807">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-09">97523</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Soins Infirmiers et&#xA0;D&#xE9;veloppement Communautaire</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
