<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-LEB-21/DDA-3604/SA2/GBV/INGO/20568</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of GBV prevention and response services to women, girls and individuals at risk in Akkar and Beirut</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To respond to growing needs and risks affecting women, girls and other at risk individuals, IMC proposes GBV response, prevention and risk mitigation activities in three women and girls&#x2019; safe spaces (WGSS) in Akkar (Tekrit and Bebnine) and Beirut (Karm el Zaytoun). All GBV activities consider the intersectional identities of women and girls and individuals at risk including socio-economic vulnerability, nationality, legal status, family status, sexual orientation, age, physical ability, etc. GBV activities aim to reduce and mitigate risks that affect women, girls and other at risk individuals. They also aim to empower women and girls on cognitive, psychosocial, and socio-economic levels. 
IMC&#x2019;s GBV response will consist of case management services using a survivor-centered approach, in line with global interagency guidelines, to help survivors recover from incidents of violence and prevent additional harm. IMC uses innovative and tested women empowerment counseling tools as part of the PSS support offered within case management. When needed and applicable, case management will include the provision of a one-time emergency cash assistance (ECA), where socio-economic vulnerability interacts with and/or exacerbates a protection risk. IMC has previous experience in offering ECA and is familiar with the protection sector guidelines for the provision of emergency cash assistance. Focused PSS activities will be offered to women and girls. Women will benefit from emotional support groups while girls will receive life skills sessions. 
GBV prevention and risk mitigation activities will include awareness raising sessions on a variety of topics including safety in the community and online, GBV services and how to access those including clinical management of rape (CMR), and the dissemination of key messages related to health, legal or other services. IMC will also offer a variety of non-focused PSS activities. Arts expression workshops will also be organized to mark important events in the year, and a variety of recreational activities will also take place in the WGSS to ensure a sense of normalcy and social connectedness.
Dignity kits will be distributed with a focus on menstrual hygiene management items. Prevention activities will also include engaging with men who  to raise their awareness on the cycle of violence, gender justice and their role as allies in ending GBV. 
In order to ensure the protection of women, girls, boys and men by a strong and accountable system against sexual exploitation and abuse, IMC will carry out awareness sessions on PSEA with community members. Sessions will aim at increasing their knowledge on the topic of sexual exploitation and abuse, informing them about their right to safety, and explaining the complaint mechanisms and how to report cases of exploitation and abuse. 
All WGSS are accessible to people with disabilities (PWDs) and IMC&#x2019;s GBV team has undergone training on disability inclusion in GBV case management and focused and non-focused PSS activities. All GBV activities will include an average of 10% PWDs as participants. Additional disability integration training and coaching sessions will be part of this proposed project to continue building staff capacity in disability integration and to provide technical support to the team whenever needed. 
IMC&#x2019;s WGSS exist either in the vicinity of or inside an IMC-supported. Strong collaboration with the health team and the disability inclusion department of IMC ensures safe entry points for GBV survivors through the PHCCs and ensures linkages between programs, offering a holistic intervention and improving safety both at the physical and social/protection levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-13" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anil Kangal</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+96171777493</telephone>
   <email>akangal@internationalmedicalcorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elie Assaf</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Director of Operations</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+96170608816</telephone>
   <email>eassaf@internationalmedicalcorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LBN7">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akkar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.55060000 36.07810000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="LBN1">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beirut</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.88690000 35.51310000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-14"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-01">365819.33</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-01">13548.86</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="LBN71-20568">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-01">379368.19</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305417789">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-09">227620.91</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
