<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://data.mcc.gov/" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:mcc="https://data.mcc.gov/ns#" xmlns:usg="http://foreignassistance.gov/iati#">
  <iati-identifier>US-18-SEN-2750BXCOMD-IRRIGATION</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-18" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRRIGATION</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senegal - IRRIGATION project: This Project aims to enable improved agricultural productivity by extending and improving the quality of the irrigation system in the Delta and the Podor regions of the Senegal River Valley (northern Senegal). Optimal agricultural production could supply Senegal with a significant share of domestic agricultural products, especially rice, its principal staple crop.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-8" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Account - Senegal</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States of America</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-09-23" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-09-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-23" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-23" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senegal</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/evalbrief-092019-senegal-iwrm-int">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving Irrigation Systems and Land Tenure Security in Senegal</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/evalbrief-100121-sen-irr-water-mng">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving Irrigation and Land Rights in Senegal</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://data.mcc.gov/evaluations/index.php/catalog/123">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Irrigation and Water Resource Management</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SEN-2750BXCOMD" type="1"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SEN-2750BXCOMD-IRRIGATION-0311" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SEN-2750BXCOMD-IRRIGATION-0312" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SEN-2750BXCOMD-IRRIGATION-0313" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SEN-2750BXCOMD-IRRIGATION-0314" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SEN-2750BXCOMD-IRRIGATION-0379" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SEN-2750BXCOMD-MON &amp; EVAL" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SEN-2750BXCOMD-NA" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SEN-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SEN-2750BXCOMD-ROADS PJT" type="3"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">10) Prior to each disbursement after the initial disbursement of Program Funding that includes, in whole or in part, funding for construction or physical works relating to the Irrigation and Water Resources Management Project, MCA-Senegal shall have submitted evidence satisfactory to MCC demonstrating the Government&apos;s compliance with the requirements the Irrigation Maintenance Action Plan.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">11) Prior to the initial disbursement of Program Funding that includes, in whole or in part, funding for construction or physical works relating to the Irrigation and Water Resources Management Project (and, with respect to sub-clause (ii) hereof, prior to each such Disbursement thereafter), the Government, through the relevant administrative authority, shall have adopted and published an &quot;arrete&quot; that establishes the Land Allocation Procedures, which shall be consistent with the core principles attached as Schedule 3 to the PIA, and which shall be satisfactory to MCC and (ii) MCA-Senegal shall have submitted evidence satisfactory to MCC demonstrating that the Land Allocation Procedures remains in full forces and effect throughout the Compact Term.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">12) Prior to the initial disbursement of Program Funding that includes, in whole or in part, funding for construction or physical works relating to the Irrigation and Water Resources Management Project (and, with respect to sub-clause (ii) hereof, prior to each such Disbursement thereafter), the Government, through the relevant administrative authority, shall have adopted and published an &quot;arrete&quot; creating the technical land allocation committee(s) that will support the local rural and communal council(s) in applying the Land Allocation Procedures for any given local collective in the Project zone, and (ii) MCA-Senegal shall have submitted evidence satisfactory to MCC demonstrating that such &quot;arrete&quot; remains in full force and effect throughout the Compact Term.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">13) Prior to any disbursement of Program Funding that includes, in whole or in part, funding for the Land Tenure Security Activity, MCC shall be satisfied that the Government has made available to the local rural and communal council(s) in the Project areas the resources and support required to fulfill their land administration duties, including, without limitation, making available to the rural councils (or similar entities) &quot;les secretaires communautaires.&quot;</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">9) Prior to the initial disbursement of Program Funding that includes, in whole or in part, funding for construction or physical works relating to the Irrigation and Water Resources Management Project, the Government, through the Ministry of Agriculture, shall have approved and adopted the Irrigation Maintenance Action Plan, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Further details on conditions precedent affecting this activity can be found in the top-level parent activities.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRRIGATION Results</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">IWRM.09. : Number of hectares formalized (having a land allocation title and registered)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Outcome of Number of hectares of rural land that were officially recognized through the issuance of a land allocation title by the Local Authorities in the project?s intervention areas.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2011">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of hectares of rural land that were officially recognized through the issuance of a land allocation title by the Local Authorities in the project?s intervention areas.  Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2010-09-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-09-23"></period-end>
     <target value="3440">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of hectares of rural land that were officially recognized through the issuance of a land allocation title by the Local Authorities in the project?s intervention areas.  Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of hectares of rural land that were officially recognized through the issuance of a land allocation title by the Local Authorities in the project?s intervention areas.  Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">IWRM.29. : Number of participants in the training modules on land tenure security tools</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Process of Number of participants in the training modules on land tenure security tools</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants in the training modules on land tenure security tools  Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2010-09-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-09-23"></period-end>
     <target value="1600">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants in the training modules on land tenure security tools  Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="144">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants in the training modules on land tenure security tools  Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">IWRM.29.2.1 : Number of participants in the training modules on land tenure security tools (Ngallenka - Female)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Process of Number of participants in the training modules on land tenure security tools</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="NULL" year="2010">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants in the training modules on land tenure security tools  Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2010-09-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-09-23"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants in the training modules on land tenure security tools  Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants in the training modules on land tenure security tools  Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">IWRM.29.1.1 : Number of participants in the training modules on land tenure security tools (Delta - Female)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Process of Number of participants in the training modules on land tenure security tools</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="NULL" year="2010">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants in the training modules on land tenure security tools  Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2010-09-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-09-23"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants in the training modules on land tenure security tools  Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants in the training modules on land tenure security tools  Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">IWRM.05.??: Cropping intensity (Ngallenka)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Outcome of The cropping intensity in the Ngallenka irrigated areas is calculated according to the following formula: Total number of hectares cultivated per year / Total number of cultivable hectares. The cultivable land represents the all the land that can be culti</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0.2" year="2011">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The cropping intensity in the Ngallenka irrigated areas is calculated according to the following formula: Total number of hectares cultivated per year / Total number of cultivable hectares. The cultivable land represents the all the land that can be culti Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2010-09-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-09-23"></period-end>
     <target value="1.2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The cropping intensity in the Ngallenka irrigated areas is calculated according to the following formula: Total number of hectares cultivated per year / Total number of cultivable hectares. The cultivable land represents the all the land that can be culti Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The cropping intensity in the Ngallenka irrigated areas is calculated according to the following formula: Total number of hectares cultivated per year / Total number of cultivable hectares. The cultivable land represents the all the land that can be culti Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflicts successfully mediated</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of The number of disputed land and property rights cases that have been resolved by local authorities, contractors, mediators or courts with compact support</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of disputed land and property rights cases that have been resolved by local authorities, contractors, mediators or courts with compact support Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2010-09-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-09-23"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of disputed land and property rights cases that have been resolved by local authorities, contractors, mediators or courts with compact support Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="32">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of disputed land and property rights cases that have been resolved by local authorities, contractors, mediators or courts with compact support Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">IWRM.30. : Temporary employment generated in irrigation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Process of The number of people temporarily employed or contracted by MCA-contracted construction companies to work on construction of irrigation systems</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2012">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people temporarily employed or contracted by MCA-contracted construction companies to work on construction of irrigation systems Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2010-09-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-09-23"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people temporarily employed or contracted by MCA-contracted construction companies to work on construction of irrigation systems Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="444">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people temporarily employed or contracted by MCA-contracted construction companies to work on construction of irrigation systems Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percent disbursed of irrigation construction contracts</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Process of The total amount of all signed construction contracts for agricultural irrigation investments disbursed divided by the total value of all signed contracts.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2011">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total amount of all signed construction contracts for agricultural irrigation investments disbursed divided by the total value of all signed contracts. Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2010-09-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-09-23"></period-end>
     <target value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total amount of all signed construction contracts for agricultural irrigation investments disbursed divided by the total value of all signed contracts. Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="16.77">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total amount of all signed construction contracts for agricultural irrigation investments disbursed divided by the total value of all signed contracts. Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">IWRM.25. : Value of construction contracts signed for irrigation infrastructure in the Delta</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Process of The value of all signed construction contracts for agricultural irrigation investments using compact funds.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2010">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The value of all signed construction contracts for agricultural irrigation investments using compact funds.  Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2010-09-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-09-23"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The value of all signed construction contracts for agricultural irrigation investments using compact funds.  Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="147664251.2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The value of all signed construction contracts for agricultural irrigation investments using compact funds.  Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">IWRM.25. : Value of construction contracts signed for irrigation infrastructure in the Ngallenka</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Process of The value of all signed construction contracts for agricultural irrigation investments using compact funds.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2010">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The value of all signed construction contracts for agricultural irrigation investments using compact funds.  Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2010-09-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-09-23"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The value of all signed construction contracts for agricultural irrigation investments using compact funds.  Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="9643722.46">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The value of all signed construction contracts for agricultural irrigation investments using compact funds.  Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">IWRM.04.?:: Cropping intensity (Delta)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Outcome of The value of all signed construction contracts for agricultural irrigation investments using compact funds.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0.6" year="2011">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The value of all signed construction contracts for agricultural irrigation investments using compact funds.  Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2010-09-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-09-23"></period-end>
     <target value="0.7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The value of all signed construction contracts for agricultural irrigation investments using compact funds.  Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.56">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The value of all signed construction contracts for agricultural irrigation investments using compact funds.  Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">IWRM.07.?: Hectares under production across cropping seasons</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Outcome of Total number of hectares devoted to agricultural production with the irrigation and drainage systems supported by the MCC in the Delta and Ngallenka. Each hectare will be counted once for each cropping season in which it is under production (thus, the sam</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="21400" year="2011">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of hectares devoted to agricultural production with the irrigation and drainage systems supported by the MCC in the Delta and Ngallenka. Each hectare will be counted once for each cropping season in which it is under production (thus, the sam Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2010-09-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-09-23"></period-end>
     <target value="23600">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of hectares devoted to agricultural production with the irrigation and drainage systems supported by the MCC in the Delta and Ngallenka. Each hectare will be counted once for each cropping season in which it is under production (thus, the sam Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="20008">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of hectares devoted to agricultural production with the irrigation and drainage systems supported by the MCC in the Delta and Ngallenka. Each hectare will be counted once for each cropping season in which it is under production (thus, the sam Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">IWRM.06. : Total area with improved irrigation infrastructure (Delta and Ngallenka)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Outcome of Total number of hectares that are supplied with complete systems for improved irrigation (land that has access to irrigation water flows, has been properly leveled)  The improved irrigation areas include those that were already improved prior to the MCC p</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="34848" year="2011">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of hectares that are supplied with complete systems for improved irrigation (land that has access to irrigation water flows, has been properly leveled)  The improved irrigation areas include those that were already improved prior to the MCC p Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2010-09-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-09-23"></period-end>
     <target value="38381">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of hectares that are supplied with complete systems for improved irrigation (land that has access to irrigation water flows, has been properly leveled)  The improved irrigation areas include those that were already improved prior to the MCC p Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="37502">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of hectares that are supplied with complete systems for improved irrigation (land that has access to irrigation water flows, has been properly leveled)  The improved irrigation areas include those that were already improved prior to the MCC p Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">IWRM.01.?: Rice paddy production</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Outcome of Total quantity of paddy rice produced per annum in the project?s intervention areas.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="102000" year="2011">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total quantity of paddy rice produced per annum in the project?s intervention areas. Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2010-09-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-09-23"></period-end>
     <target value="111000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total quantity of paddy rice produced per annum in the project?s intervention areas. Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="110737">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total quantity of paddy rice produced per annum in the project?s intervention areas. Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
