<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://data.mcc.gov/" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:mcc="https://data.mcc.gov/ns#" xmlns:usg="http://foreignassistance.gov/iati#">
  <iati-identifier>US-18-SE2-2750BXCOMD</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-18" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senegal II-Compact</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In December 2018, MCC signed a compact to partner with the Government of Senegal to strengthen the power sector to meet the growing demand for reliable electricity for citizens and businesses. The Senegal Power Compact will support three projects focused on improving the transmission network in and around the capital of Dakar, increasing electricity access in agricultural areas of the south and central regions, and improving the overall governance of the sector. The compact also aims to increase private sector participation and help ensure that Senegal maximizes benefits from existing and future private investment. The Government of Senegal will contribute an additional $50 million to the compact to drive economic growth and progress.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-8" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Account - Senegal</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States of America</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-10" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administration &amp; Finance</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Open Data Team</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>202-521-3618</telephone>
   <email>opendata@mcc.gov</email>
   <website>data.mcc.gov</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1099 14th Street NW, Suite 700, Washington, DC 20005-3550</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senegal</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-30">2278326</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-30">3943006</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-30">3389112</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-30">2198773</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-30">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-30">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/compact-senegal-power">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senegal Power Compact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <category code="A09"></category>
   <category code="A11"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SE2-2750BX69GD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SE2-2750BXCOMD-ACCESSELEC" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SE2-2750BXCOMD-MON &amp; EVAL" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SE2-2750BXCOMD-NA" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SE2-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SE2-2750BXCOMD-RS CAP BLD" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SE2-2750BXCOMD-TRANS NTWK" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SE2-2750BXDILD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SEN-2750BX69GD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SEN-2750BXCOMD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SEN-2750BXDILD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SN" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Appointment of an entity or individual to provide fiscal agent services, as approved by MCC, until such time as the Government provides to MCC a true and complete copy of a Fiscal Agent Agreement, duly executed and in full force and effect, and the fiscal agent engaged thereby is mobilized.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Appointment of an entity or individual to provide procurement agent services, as approved by MCC, until such time as the Government provides to MCC a true and complete copy of a Procurement Agent Agreement, duly executed and in full force and effect, and the procurement agent engaged thereby is mobilized.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For any Compact CDF Disbursement occurring after this Compact has entered into force in accordance with Article 7: MCC is satisfied, in its sole discretion, that(i) MCC has received copies of any reports due from any technical consultants (including environmental auditors engaged by MCA-Senegal II) for any Activity since the previous Disbursement Request, and all such reports are in form and substance satisfactory to MCC; (ii) the Implementation Plan Documents and Fiscal Accountability Plan are current and updated and are in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, and there has been progress satisfactory to MCC on the components of the Implementation Plan for any relevant Projects or Activities related to such Compact CDF Disbursement; (iii) there has been progress satisfactory to MCC on the M&amp;E Plan and Social and Gender Integration Plan for any relevant Projects or Activities and substantial compliance with the requirements of the M&amp;E Plan and Social and Gender Integration Plan (including the targets set forth therein and any applicable reporting requirements set forth therein for the relevant Disbursement Period); (iv) there has been no material negative finding in any financial audit report delivered in accordance with this Compact and the Audit Plan for the prior two quarters (or such other period as the Audit Plan may require); (v) MCC does not have grounds for concluding that any matter certified to it in the related MCA Disbursement Certificate, the Fiscal Agent Disbursement Certificate, or the Procurement Agent Disbursement Certificate is not ascertified; and (vi) if any of the officers or key staff of MCA-Senegal II have been removed or resigned and the position remains vacant, MCA-Senegal II is actively engaged in recruiting a replacement.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">If any proceeds of the Compact CDF Disbursement are to be deposited in one or more bank accounts, MCC has received satisfactory evidence that (i) the Bank Agreement has been executed and (ii) the Permitted Accounts have been established.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCC has not determined, in its sole discretion, that an act, omission, condition, or event has occurred that would be the basis for MCC to suspend or terminate, in whole or in part, this Compact or MCC Funding in accordance with Section 5.1 of this Compact.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCC is satisfied, in its sole discretion, that (i) the activities being funded with such Compact CDF Disbursement are necessary, advisable or otherwise consistent with the goal of facilitating the implementation of this Compact and are not expected to violate any applicable law or regulation; (ii) no material default or breach of any covenant, obligation, or responsibility by the Government, MCA-Senegal II, or any Government entity has occurred and is continuing under this Compact or any Supplemental Agreement; (iii) there has been no violation of, and the use of requested funds for the purposes requested are not expected to violate, the limitations on use or treatment of MCC Funding set forth in Section 2.7 of this Compact or in any applicable law or regulation; (iv) any Taxes paid with MCC Funding through the date 90 days prior to the start of the applicable Disbursement Period have been reimbursed by the Government in full in accordance with Section 2.8(c) of this Compact; and (v) the Government has satisfied all of its payment obligations, including any insurance, indemnification, tax payments, or other obligations, and contributed all resources required from it, under this Compact and any Supplemental Agreement.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to the third Compact CDF Disbursement, the Government (or MCA-Senegal II)  shall have signed a contract for a management oversight and social environmental support consultant.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government (or MCA-Senegal II) has delivered to MCC the following documents, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC:(i) a completed Disbursement Request, together with the applicable Periodic Reports, for the applicable Disbursement Period, all in accordance with the Reporting Guidelines; (ii) a certificate of the Government (or MCA-Senegal II), dated as of the date of the Compact CDF Disbursement Request, in such form as provided by MCC; (iii) if a Fiscal Agent has been engaged, a Fiscal Agent Disbursement Certificate; and (iv) if a Procurement Agent has been engaged, a Procurement Agent Disbursement Certificate.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government (or UFC or MCA-Senegal II) has delivered to MCC a Compact CDF procurement plan acceptable to MCC</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government (or UFC or MCA-Senegal II) has delivered to MCC an interim fiscal accountability plan acceptable to MCC</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government (or UFC or MCA-Senegal II) has delivered to MCC an updated spinning reserves strategy and action plan adopted by Senelec, including a timeline for implementation, sufficient to ensure the spinning reserves level required for the stability of the network.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
