<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05256-12:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHESHIRE SERVICES UGANDA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cheshire Services Uganda (CSU) is a local organization established in 1997, working to improve the quality of life of Persons with Disabilities through influencing policy change by providing models of inclusive development as well as advocacy and lobbying for improvements in policy practice to include persons with disability through the Programme areas of Inclusive Education, Livelihoods, Human Rights promotion, Health and rehabilitation and support for Daily Living.

Our mission is to rehabilitate andempower Persons withdisabilities to lead a dignified and productive life. CSU supports promotion of rights of PWD while aiming at influencing inclusivelegislations, policies and programmes. We provide models for inclusive development as well as direct lobbying and advocacy for improvement in policy and practice to increase participation of PWD in development.

Action for youth with disabilities Uganda (AYDU) was founded by and for youth with disabilities. AYDU advocates for the rights of youth with disabilities in Uganda in the areas of higher education, reproductive health and employment. This project is in line with AYDU#s strategic objective number 3; To enhance access to employment for youth with disabilities which is in line with the project thematic area.

AYDU co-ordinates the policy advocacynetwork and which brings together DPOs and government institutions to advocate for the rights of persons with disabilities and influence policy implementation and amendments.  AYDU has conducted a studyon employment patterns of youth with disabilities in both public and private sectors in Uganda and as a result, a disability enhancement strategy for the organisation was developed and these activities have guided the development of this project.

The 1995 constitution of Uganda (as amended), Article 40 guarantees that every person in Uganda has the right to practice his or her profession and carry out any lawful occupation, trade or business. Article 35: #(1) states that persons with disabilities havearight to respect and human dignity and the State and society shall take appropriate measures to ensure that they realise their full mental and physical potential. Section 6 (1) of the Employment Act (2006) provides that it shall be the duty of all parties including the Minister, labour officers and the industrial court to seek to promote equality of opportunity with a view to eliminating any discrimination in employment. The Uganda National Employment Policy 2011, in its guiding principle No. 6.7, recognises affirmative action in favour of the vulnerable groups. Section 12, of the PWD Act 2006, prohibits discrimination against a qualified person in employment on grounds of disability and elaborates on acts that constitute discrimination. The Equal Opportunities Commission Act 2007 section 3(a, b and c) provides for a penalty for any offence committed by a person who refuses to employ another person.

The project aims to increase access to gainful employment among young People with disabilities in Tororo District by advocating for the implementation of provisions in the above policies and Legislations. The project will be anchored on the Employment Act (2006); Section 6 (1) states that it shall be the duty of all parties including the Minister, labour officers and the industrial court to seek to promote equality of opportunity with a view to eliminating any discrimination in employment; Section 6(3) declares discrimination in employment unlawful.

Goal of project is to contribute to increased access to gainful employment among Persons with disabilities in Uganda.

The specific objectives ;

1. To create awareness among employers on disability inclusive employment policies and legislation as a way of promoting employment of youth with disabilities.
2. To empower youth with disabilities on their rights to employment.
3. To support employers to develop and implement institutional disability inclusivepolicies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHESHIRE SERVICES  TORORO PROJECT CSU</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cheshire Services Uganda (CSU) is a locally registered Non-Governmental Organization working for and with Persons with Disabilities(PWDs), Orphans and other vulnerable Children. CSU was established in 1994 and legally registered in 1997. CSU was established witha goal to coordinate provision of services by the Cheshire homes, now referred to as Cheshire Services in Uganda.
The mandate of CSU is;
1. To plan, mobilize resources and coordinate activities of the constituent services;
2. To reduce illiteracy among Persons with Disabilities through promotion of education, training and life-long learning;
3. To improve livelihoods of PWDs and their families through skills training, grants and other interventions;
4. To provide quality and comprehensive rehabilitation services to Children with Disabilities (CWDs);
5. To advocate for the inclusion of Persons with Disabilities and;
6. To contribute to disability related policy change at both macro and micro levels.

ACHIEVEMENTS
What have been the principal results in the past three years that contribute to significant, structural, sustained and positive improvement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?

CSU has implemented programmes to improve the quality of life of PWDs in five thematic programme areas; education, economic empowerment, advocacy and rehabilitation.
Under Education, with funding from the UK government, Cheshire Services Uganda has been working to promote inclusive education in Uganda through the Girls# Education Challenge project for girls with disabilities in Uganda targeting over 2089 girls with disabilities in low income communities of Kampala since 2008. Theproject focuses on retention and transition of GWDs in school. As a result a total of 2024 girls have been able to keep in school thus a retention rate of 96.9% for GWDs in school and out of the 557 project supported girls who sat for primary leaving examinationsin the past 3 years, 504 were able to join secondary education, 49 joined post primary skills training and only 4 failed to join any post primary education and training for various reasons thus a transition rate of 99%.
The organisation has worked in over 13 districts.  Our most recent advocacy projects include; the EU funded Bukwo and Sironko district human rights project for PWDs implemented between 2012 and 2014.  Through this project, we influenced the Bukwo district local government to put in place the district disability council and increased budget support to PWDs such as NAADs at that time.  In Sironko district, the project lobbied for provision of tenders to PWDs.  In Kaliro district between 2011and 2013, we supported 60 young PWDs to receive livelihoods support from the district.   Between2009 and 2013, the organisation implemented a project to popularise the UNCRPD in Budaka, Buikwe and Wakiso districts.  The local governments of Buikwe and Wakiso increased allocations of CDD grants to groups of PWDs.  In Buikwe and Budaka, there was improved accessibility to the office building.
Under economic empowerment, the organisation through various projects has supported vocational skills training for over 1500 PWDs in the project districts and provided start up kits and capital to each one of them thus improving on their livelihoods and household income. As a result PWDs are no longer looked at as a burden but rather as individuals who can contribute to the sustainable development of a community.

2. INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE
The Vision: An inclusive societywhere Persons with disabilities are respected and enjoy better quality life

Mission Statement: To rehabilitate and empower Personswith disabilities to lead a dignified and productive life.

Mission: What is the current purpose of the organisation?
Institutionalobjectives: What are the principal changes the organisation seeks to achieve over the long term?
SO1: To empower CSU member services to develop towards sustenance;
SO2: To holistically empower PWDs through education and life-long learning;
SO3: To improve the PWDs# incomes through, placements, skills training, and advisory support and market linkages;
SO4: To raise disability rights awarenessthrough advocacy and;
SO5: To build the institutional capacity of CSU to deliver on her mandate

Field(s) of activity: What are theprincipal thematic and geographic areas in which the organisation works?  Who are the social actors that benefit from the work?
NO.THEMATIC AREA GEOGRAPHICAL AREA BENEFICIAIRIES
1 Education Greater Kampala and Amolatar district Children with Disabilities of school going age
2 Livelihoods Adjumani and Moyo districts Men and Women living with Disabilities
3 Human Rights promotion Cross cuttingin all projects Persons with Disabilities
4 Health and Rehabilitation Cross cutting in all projects persons with Disabilities

4. STRATEGIC POSITIONING
Analyse the environment in which the organisation works? Who are the other relevant social actors, including government and business, and what roles do theyplay? #In this context, what is unique about the position of the organisation?

No. Actor Roles
1 Ministry of Education and Sports policy guidance on SNE/IE, curriculum adaptation, assessment, teacher education
development of relevant tools includingPIN for supported girls,
2 Ministry of Gender, Labour and Social Development (MoGLSD): policy guidance on disability, children and gender affairs,    Coordination of technical child protection working group, referral for cases of violence against children through the national help line; monitoring of project implementation activities such as economic empowerment activities.
3 Kampala Capital City Authority: Support monitoring and strengthening of community support groups through registration as Community Based Organisations (CBOs) and also enable them benefit from government support schemes such as CDD grants.
4 CSOs andDPOs support advocacy activities, joint monitoring, referral network, leverage and sustainability of project outcomes
5 District local government  Joint monitoring and evaluation of projects
6 Health service providers Conduct assessment, review, assistive devices, therapy, corrective surgeries,
7 Media Community Sensitization and awareness</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.34730 32.63088</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-19">164994</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-01">68163</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHESHIRE SERVICES  TORORO PROJECT CSU</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-01">42839</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHESHIRE SERVICES  TORORO PROJECT CSU</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-01">45287</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHESHIRE SERVICES  TORORO PROJECT CSU</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-10-01">8705</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHESHIRE SERVICES  TORORO PROJECT CSU</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-01">68163</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-01">42839</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-01">45287</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-10-01">8705</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05256-12:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000141" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000923"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007881"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05256"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Voice Influencing grants Uganda"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(Informal) groups and organisations as well as their alliances, coalitions and networks have capacity to use a diverse set of tools to influence decision makers.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3.1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># (informal) groups, organisations and networks reporting benefits on using a diverse set of tools and instruments to influence other social actors</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.3.1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-12-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="3"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(Informal) groups and organisations as well as their alliances, coalitions and networks have capacity to use a diverse set of tools to influence decision makers.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3.b</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Influencing grants and Sudden Opportunity grants allocated by Voice</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.3.b" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-12-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3.c.ii</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># expert support on influencing decision makers provided by grantees to rightsholder groups</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.3.c.ii" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-12-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3.c.i</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># peer-to-peer platforms on influencing decision makers set up among grantee projects</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.3.c.i" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-12-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3.a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># plans to strengthen their capacity on influencing decision makers defined by (informal) groups, organisations and networks</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.3.a" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-12-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-12-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-12-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
