<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05223-18:ID</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SAPDA - SRHR for Youth PWD - ID</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Currently the youth and the youth with disabilities have similar problems related to services on Hak Kesehatan Seksual dan Reproduksi (HKSR/Sexual and Reproductive Health and Right). Many programs related to HKSR are implemented, yet they have not fulfilled optimally the needs of youth and touth with disabilities. It is due to the fact that there is no open space for active participation for the youth with disabilities in formulating and programs planning. Therefore, it#s a normal when the existing programs are synergizedand have not reached youth with disabilities. The condition will be solved by implementing at least two approaches. The first is tobuild the movement of youth and youth with disabilities to voice rights on body autonomy in HKSR and thesecond to strengthen advocacy networking on inclusive services of HKSR.

This project, youth and youth with disabilities will organize movement on fulfilling HKSR collectively. In parallel, youth and youth with disabilities will organize collective agenda with SAPDA to establish networking and cooperation with related parties. These networking and cooperation will improve quality of sexual health and reproductive healthservices for youth and youth with disabilities.

This project will be initiated byconducting study on road map of health services for persons with disabilities, and other programs (PIK-R, PKPR, PIKM). These study is important to organized in order to see what extent the existing programs can full fill of needs of youth and youth withdisabilities.

Other activity in this project is organize baseline survey in intervention area (Jember, East Java Province). This survey is aimed to map out the current condition on health services, gender and social life of the society related to HKSR. This activity is followed with capacity building activity for youth and youth with disabilities. Capacity building activity will be organized related to advocacy, creating campaign media, utilizing electronic and non-electronic media, and social media as campaign tools, writing story of change and monitoring and evaluation.
The following activity is to hold thematic discussion regularly by involving related parties, such as SKPD (local agency apparatus), health and educational service providers, disabledpeople organizations, community leaders, parents of youth and youth with disabilities, and academes. This discussion is to map out the existing problems, either from service providers, policy makers and service recipients, as well to provide space for collective agreement in improving and enhancing the existing services.

Media campaign will be organized simultaneously, utilizing media advocacy. Youth and youth with disabilities will organize this activity along with related parties; therefore role distribution on who is doing what is taken place.
National youth conference and festival is a meeting amongst youth and youth with disabilities from all over areas and various backgrounds to share and enrich stories/experiences/lessons learns/ informationtoimprove capacities in conducting changes. National Youth conference will generate creative ideas and strategies on advocacy of HKSR services though various media. All activities within this project will present roles of each party in conducting changesto improve inclusive HKSR services.

Main target of this project are youth, deaft youth, and blind youth as agent of change. For physical disabilities and mental intelectual disabilities as an indirect beneficiaries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sentra Advokasi Perempuan Difabel dan Anak (SAPDA) is a Non Governmental Organization (NGO) with vision #struggle to realize changes, just, freedom, welfare and  equality for the fulfilment and protection on the rights of women, persons with disabilitiesand children in the inclusive society based on the human rights equality#.
In order to realize its goal, SAPDA Foundation develops strategic programs:
1. organize study on knowledge and scientific research
2. struggle in realizing the public policy guaranteeing the fulfilment on rights of women, persons with disabilities and children on education, health and employment.
3. organize empowerment, education and advocacy on issues related to women, persons with disabilities and children for public.
4. establish collaboration with related stakeholders on handling problems involving persons with disabilities and children.
5. establish SAPDA as crisis centre for women, persons with disabilities and children.
6. develop Resource Centre as centre of information and knowledge on disabilities, women and children
At operational level, these strategy programs are generated into several activities on Main streaming Disability within society and government agencies, supervising on violent against women with disabilities, supervising for communities of persons withdisabilities, teenagers with disabilities and parents of children with disabilities, especially on education of reproductive health.
In organizing campaign and public education, SAPDA applies severalstrategies. Develop accessibility through SAPDA goes to School activity and to raise awareness on acceptance towards disability through a series of capacity building, seminar, discussions, workshops, FGDs, and mainstreaming disability activities.
SAPDA also produces various media channels. Productions on audio-visual media: documentary films, educational films on reproductive health for deaf people, films on inclusive emergency response, film on audit of accessibility towards public facilities in Yogyakarta City, film #Difabel bergerak dari bawah# that can accelerate in creating socialinclusion within society. Productions on printed media are: a pocket book on reproductive health for parents, a pocket book on violence, module on reproductive health forparents and supervisors, module on handling violence against women with disabilities, comic on lessons learnt of program on strengthening public services, and bulletin disseminated in several communities, and convergence media.

SAPDA coverage area in Indonesia. Currently, SAPDA works with DRF related to SRHR advocacy for teenagers with disabilities in DIY, Kupang City -Nusa Tenggara Timur Province-, and Malang City -Jawa Timur Province-. In addition to that, SAPDA also works at Program Peduli Pilar Disabilitas as a program from Coordinating Ministry of Human Development and Culture at Banjarmasin City, South Kalimantan Province together with PPDI of Banjarmasin City, Jember, and Perpenca Jember. SAPDA organizes supervison towards communities in Turi Sub-district and Tempel Sub-district, Sleman, DIY. In domain of cases on violence against persons with disabilities, Division of Women With Disability Crisis Centre (WDCC) organizes supervision towards cases in DIY, LPA Nusa Tenggara Barat Province, Persani Kupang, HWDI Yogyakarta City to formulate referral mechanism on handling cases of violence against women with disabilities. WDCC also works with Banjarmasin Municipality and Yogyakarta Municipality to formulate indicators on inclusive city of legal protection.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yayasan SentraAdvokasi Perempuan Di</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-8.1844 113.6680</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-10">24970</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-10-01">12485</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yayasan SentraAdvokasi Perempuan Di</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-01">12485</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yayasan SentraAdvokasi Perempuan Di</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-10-01">12485</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-01">12485</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05223-18:ID">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000141" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000923"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007881"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05223"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Voice Empowerment Grants Indonesia"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rightsholders (individuals and groups) are willing and able to work on their own empowerment.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># change agendas developed by rightsholder groups based on the facilitation of programme staff and partner organisations</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.a" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-09-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="5"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.b</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># change agendas implemented by rightsholder groups based on the support of programme staff and partner organisations</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.b" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-09-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.c</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># grantees incorporating new approaches in realising their change agendas</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.c" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-09-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rightsholders (individuals and groups) are willing and able to work on their own empowerment.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># rightsholder groups indicating to have safe spaces to convene and work</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-09-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># rightsholder groups presenting their collective demands to external stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-09-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.3</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% rightsholder groups indicating increased confidence to raise their voice</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.3" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-09-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-09-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-09-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
