<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-04857-12:VN</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving access to health care services</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Healthcare system in Vietnam is organized by 4 levels, central, provincial, district and commune levels. Among which, commune healthcare stations play an important role in implementing most of activities on preventive healthcare, prevention of and response to diseases, health checkup and primary healthcare services for people, as well as implementing commune level population and family planning program; providing monitoring and oversight of healthcare activities in communes, towns and villages; facilitating participation of communities in healthcare activities.

Commune healthcare stations are of importance for the people, especially in remote areas with difficult economic circumstances and transportation infrastructure. According to an assessment, ethnic minority communities and poor people have limited access to higher level healthcare services given their habits and challenging economic and transportation conditions. Surveys carried out by CDI in 2014 in #akrong district, Quang Tri province and in 2012 in Da Bac district, Hoa Binh province, with samples of almost 400 households/ each district, among people who had accessed commune or district based healthcare services within 12 months prior to the surveys found that in Quang Tri province, 88,65% of surveyed people used commune healthcare services, 11,4% used district level services. While in Hoa Binh, numbers of people accessing commune and district level healthcare servicesfor treatment purposes accounted for only 40% and 60% respectively within previous 12 months.

However, services provided at commune healthcare stations are of low quality, inadequately responsive to the people#s needs for health check and treatment. In remoted areas, the percentage of health stations having doctors is quite low. In Quang Tri, currently, only 60% of commune level healthcare stations having doctors as required. On the other hand, findings from surveys in Quang Tri and Hoa Binh provinces with regards to quality of commune healthcare stations included insufficient facilities; unfriendly attitude of healthcare officials; high costs charged to patients even though they were covered by healthcare insurance, which was assessed to be unaffordable for the people; unsupportive attitude and behavior of commune healthcareofficials against patients applying for upstream transfer and the people#s inconfidence in quality of commune level services. As result, people prefers to either go up to higher level or pay for private services usingtheir pocket money.

Low quality healthcare services at grass-root level increases inequality in access to healthcare. Commune healthcare stations are far from being able to meet the local needs for health checkup and treatment which results in people having to access higher level servicesat provincial or central level hospital for instance. However, this is not commonly the case for poor people and ethnic minority people given their habits and economic/ transportation difficulties. It means currently the health insurancefund is basicallyused to cover the healthcare payments of mid-income populations. Healthcare insurance policies are inadequately benefiting the poor.

Ministry of Health is planning for the improvement of system of commune healhcare stations and development of #household doctors# model. However, this plan so far has not been successfully implemented in reality due to the lack of concrete measures. Additionally, provincial authorities have their ownership in allocating public budget for local healthcare. Normally, threshold of budget allocated for commune healthcare is approximately 20-30 million/ station/ year. With this limited funding level, it is challenging for commune healthcare stations to function properly. Not to mention that they are operated in an inflexiblemanner, not responsive to actual needs of local people.

After a field trip to a commune healthcare station in August of 2016, Deputy Prime Minister, Vu Duc Dam, requested Ministry of Health and Vietnam Social Security to push up their cooperation to elaborate specific and practical solutions to enhance the role of local healthcare system, which might include: Regulations on establishment of health tracking book for each individual citizen in localities; list of drugs, list of services provided at local healthcare stations;  up to 20% of the fund for medical services for outpatients calculated on the number of individuals registering with primary healthcare providers at commune level. This is seen as an opportunity for local communities to make the actualsituations as well as urgent needs for healthcare and treatment recognized by policy makers at central and local levels.

Pursuant to the Decision No. 2151/Q#- BYT dated onJune 4th, 2015 of MOH on #Innovation of serving manner and attitude of health officials toward the satisfaction of patients#, assessment of patients# level of satisfaction has been implemented in some localities through public opinions polls, hotlines, etc.,. This is actually a welcomed policy though its implementation remains limited at the level of some big hospitals and so far, it has beenacknowledged as a mean of encouraging, motivating and rewarding only.

This proposed project is based on MOH#s decision on #Innovation of serving manner and attitude of health officials towardthe satisfaction of patients# at local level, which is most accessible level for the local people, especially for those living in remote areas and ethnic minority communities. Findings of the assessment will not only be used as an evidence to requestforhigher quality services delivered by service providers, but also help to inform advocacy efforts since they are considered as criteria used to formulate budget allocation with the principle that #higher quality of healthcare services provided by health stations increases demand, higher demand requires higher funding#.

On the other hand, by further enabling dialogue with local people, understanding their needs, the project aims to influence policies which allow commune healthcare stations to develop demand based plans, which is appropriate to the local characterized contexts instead of the current imposed planning approach. This project is designed with expected results as below:

Result 1: Contribute to the improved awareness and accountabilityon the critical role of local healthcare system for the local community.
Result 2: Contribute to the improved capacity of local healthcare system in delivering service (including management capacity, quantity and quality of services) through interventionson budget allocation process to make sure it is implemented in a more transparent and targeted manner</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Development and Integration (CDI) is Vietnamese non #governmental, non- profit organization working for the rights of the disadvantaged groups to build a society of equity, solidarity and sustainable development.
Vision
The Center for Development and Integration aims at socio-economic development and good governance to build a society where the poor, women, men and children are respected and treated fairly in the context  of rapid economic integration in Vietnam and Asia.
Mission
To make acontribution to narrowing the social gaps and finding solutions to the emerging issues of the society through supporting activities, advocacy and capacitybuilding.
Goal (2015-2020)
To be a capable and prestigious civil society organizaton that aims towards equitable and sustainable development and shared prosperity through activities to promote and ensure the rights of disadvantaged groups.
Priorities themes
Good Governance
Labor rights
Inclusive Growth
Regarding Good Governance theme, CDI bringsmore than 8 years of experience working in participatory planning and budget transparency, accountability and people#s participation (BTAP) in Vietnam.
CDI is responsible for carrying out the Open Budget Survey in Vietnam every two years and working on monthly online budget tracker for Vietnam. Joining the international network on budget transparency given CDI the many chances to exchange, shared learning and capacity building on budget transparency and accountability, especially citizen budget tool.
CDIis a member of Budget Transparency Coalition of Vietnam CSOs advocating for State budget law amendment towards Transparency, Accountability and People Participation; an active member of CSO#s workinggroup advocating Vietnam Government joining Open Government Partnership.
CDI also has significant local experiences across provinces in Vietnam, having carried out social audits, budget monitoring, participatory budget and planning, promoting people participationin development process, capacity building forlocal partners and developed working relationships with local institutions and actors.
CDI has been collaborating with Irish Aid, EC, Oxfam, AFAP, CBPP (Center on Budget and Policy Priorities), etc for the work on BTAPin Vietnam.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trung tam Phat trien va hoi nhap</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="10" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-27">79008</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-07-01">19752</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D Lobby&amp;Advocacy</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trung tam Phat trien va hoi nhap</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-11-01">39504</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D Lobby&amp;Advocacy</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trung tam Phat trien va hoi nhap</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-05-01">19752</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D Lobby&amp;Advocacy</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trung tam Phat trien va hoi nhap</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-07-01">19752</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-1-PPR-27538" ref="NL-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-11-01">39504</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-1-PPR-27538" ref="NL-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-05-01">19752</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-1-PPR-27538" ref="NL-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-04857-12:VN">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000142" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000988"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007256"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Vietnam (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-04857"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="SPD&amp;D L&amp;A CO VIE Support Finance 4 Devel"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2400</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved policies Governments and global actors: # cases (sub)national governments or global actors adopting and/or implementing improved gender sensitive policies on promotion of a transparent, accountable and inclusive financial sector.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases (sub)national governments or global actors adopting and/or implementing improved gender sensitive policies on promotion of a transparent, accountable and inclusive financial sector -DD2</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-04-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2400</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved policies Governments and global actors: # cases (sub)national governments or global actors adopting and/or implementing improved gender sensitive policies on promotion of a transparent, accountable and inclusive financial sector.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2400-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">pieces of evidence (documents, studies, videos, testimonies etc.) produced by Oxfam Novib and partners in support of development/adoption of alternative policies/approaches</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2400-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-04-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2400-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">pieces of evidence (documents, studies, videos, testimonies etc.) produced by Oxfam Novib and partners to support monitoring of practices and implementation of policies by governments and global actors</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2400-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-04-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2440</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased citizens voice: # of women and men taking action campaigning, demanding and/or engaging for a  transparent, accountable and inclusive financial sector that integrates ESG &amp; Humand Rights criteria and/or towards financial inclusion</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2440-D</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">media citations of Oxfam and partners research or products</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2440-D" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-04-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="10"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2440-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men participating in public events / spaces organized by Oxfam Novib and partners</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2440-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-04-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="150"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2440-C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">public events/spaces organised by Oxfam Novib and partners in which citizens express their needs and aspirations to policy makers.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2440-C" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-04-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="5"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2440-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women participating in public events / spaces organized by Oxfam Novib and partners</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2440-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-04-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="150"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2440</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased citizens voice: # of women and men taking action campaigning, demanding and/or engaging for a  transparent, accountable and inclusive financial sector that integrates ESG &amp; Humand Rights criteria and/or towards financial inclusion</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2440-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men taking action campaigning, demanding and/or engaging for a  transparent, accountable and inclusive financial sector that integrates ESG &amp; Humand Rights criteria and/or towards financial inclusion</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2440-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-04-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="20"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2440-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women taking action campaigning, demanding and/or engaging for a  transparent, accountable and inclusive financial sector that integrates ESG &amp; Humand Rights criteria and/or towards financial inclusion</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2440-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-04-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="20"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
