<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05257-03:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">URAA- Challenging Ageism in Uganda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda Reach the Aged Association (URAA) was formed in 1993 and is a registered non-governmental organisation (NGO) #To champion the realization and preservation of a dignified quality of life for older persons in Uganda&quot; given that Older persons (OPs) in Uganda face significant issues ranging from poverty, lack of access to adequate health and financial services, income insecurity, exclusionfrom health insurance schemes (as they are considered a high risk group).

The Understand and Challenge Ageism Campaign project to promote a campaign on understanding and challenging ageism to older persons in Uganda, to transform humanitarian and development public and private sector policies and improve access to social services such as health, empowring the older persons to lobby for timely and adequate service delivery by  engaging in planning and budgeting processes, policies and programmes.

The URA inends to ultimately challenge the understanding, perceptions and attitudes at individual, family and community level towards older persons, roll out an Ageism campaign strategy at national level (starting with 6 pilot districts) in Uganda, generate evidence to strengthen national, district and community structures and share best practice documents for meangingful engagement with the respective stakeholders, government, departments private sector and shared at locally, nationally and international fora to be tested and scaled up</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Uganda Reach the Aged Association (URAA) was founded in 1991 but registered in 1993 as an NGO by a group of committed Ugandans who included Cardinal Emmanuel Wamala, Mrs Erina Baingana, Mr John Baptist Walusimbi among others. It is a national, not for profit,non government, membership organization with offices in Kampala but operating countrywide.
Why: The URAA thrust can be summarized as:
# The weakening traditional extended family care mechanisms. These in the past were responsible for providingcare and social security for older persons. Their weakening and erosion is leaving many older persons with inadequate care and often resulting in loneliness and isolation.
# The increasing social and economic burden associated with care for older personsand the orphans is another factor that motivated the founding of the URAA.
# The extreme poverty levels that most old person#s experience. This poverty is caused by loss of productivity due to old age and the mistaken perception that older persons are nolonger useful to society.
# Ageing is increasingly being recognized

URAA increasingly seeks to promote family/community care as opposed to institutional care which in manyways tends to alienate older persons. URAA works in partnership with others tosupport older persons and age care organizations nationally. It later moved to URAA mains target is to see older persons and children under their care in Uganda living a dignified self-fulfilled poverty free life.

URAA has grown rapidly to a nationalassociation with over 80 member organizations in all the regions. URAA is mandated to promote quality wellbeing of OPs through its member organizations. The aim of URAA is to provide a platform for fellowship, mutual support, hope and a voice to Ops. Specifically the organization focuses on advocacy to raise awareness on Op#s issues and fight stigma to Ops through the rights-based approach aimed at promoting dignified living by advocating and promoting equitable access economic empowerment, social welfare,treatment, care and support, and wellbeing of OPs.

Our Projects put a high consideration on gender aspect and women and girls are a priority on out Projects. Following the principles of leave no one behind (LNOB), URAA uses intergenerational approaches in its work. Creating solidarity across generations or sustainable developments it believes in wisdom, experiences, energy and ideals of older person#s women and men, youth including OVCs under the care of older persons. It supports intergenerationaldialogues on Human right issues and gender equality and ensures that all people young and old recognize themselves as the owners, drivers and beneficiaries. This is done in community dialogues between rights holders and duty bearers. This approach buildsbridgesfor different gender and generations to work together in mutually empowering relationships thus has enabled URAA to produce intergenerational relations and partnerships which have produced a well-integrated society to protect human rights improveon access to justice and fight against gender inequality.

URAA is a network member of Help Age International, a worldwide Network that helps older persons claim their rights, challenge discrimination and overcome poverty so that they can lead dignified, secure, active and healthy lives.

2. ACHIEVEMENTS
What have been the principal results in the past three years that contribute to significant, structural, sustained and positive improvement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?
URAA#s work purely is towards alleviating the plight of older persons and their adjacent families (since 70% of OVCS actually reside with older persons) in view of these the achievements to-date are as follows;
Economic Empowerment for Older Persons:
# Supported Older persons and thus increased the number of older persons accessing secure incomes, through engagement in varied economic activities as groups and as individuals. We boast of farmers engaged in sustainable post-harvest handling practices that have led to improved prices of their rice and maize produce.
# URAA member organizations (OPAs) have establish micro projectsfor household income.
# URAA member Organizations are engaged in group based savings andcredit schemes, (e.g. VSLAs) that offer soft loans to members for investment and thus improvement in their household incomes.
# Influence to financial and insurance institutions to incorporate Ops Associations; URAA has over the years supportedit memberOPAs to partner with banks like Barclays, Finance Trust where its members have savings accounts.

Addressing the Social Welfare of Older Persons:

# URAA is still at the forefront of advocacy for the inclusion of Non Communicable Disease onthe essential drugs lists of Health facilities equipped in Uganda, while this is work in progress considerations are being made to do so.
# URAA through consulted efforts of it Thematic Working group for HIV &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; AIDS has had tremendous contributions to the reductionin the prevalence and impact of HIV and AIDS on older persons.
# Some members of URAA example in Mukono have successfully managed to have ordinances passed in their district in the affirmative for older persons not to line up in Banks or whenaccessing medical services.
# URAA with partners have contributed to the reduction in the incidences of abuse and violation of the rights of older persons but also improved access to legal, financial, social and medical services and agricultural inputs for olderperson, with its trained team of older person leaders, associations, paralegals and Older Citizen monitoring group members in Mukono, Hoima, Kasese, Iganga and Bundibudyo Districts amongst others in Uganda .

Networking, information and communication:
# URAA is active in at least 2 relevant national, regional and international networks; namely Uganda Social Protection Platform (as Chair), Africa Social Protection Platform (as Uganda Convener), these platforms are at the forefront of advocacy for better services for older persons in Uganda and within the Region.
# The two networks are also vibrant national and regional older persons# network that are functional.
# URAA is in partnership with age care organizations to promote rights of OPs, namely Reach one Torch One (ROTOM) in Mukono, Health Nest Uganda (HENU) in Entebbe, Grandmother Consortium in Canada, HelpAge InternationalUganda and Africa Regional Office.
# URAA is a member of the Uganda National NGO Forum (UNNGOF), Uganda Network of AIDS Service Organizations (UNASO) and National Union of Researchers and Research Users (NURRU).  It also has District level partner NGOs and CBO in63 districts in Uganda, for purposes of effective identification of community needs, programme implementation andcapacity building.

Policy influence and Research:
# Over the years URAA has established itself as a source of data on issues concerning older personsthat can inform policy formulation and advocacy in Uganda.
# URAA has over the years contributed tothemainstreaming and integrationof OPs issues in at least 10 national based policies example; the National Policy for Older Persons 2009, National Council for older person Act 2013, National Council for Older person Regulations 2015, The National Social Protection Policy for Uganda 2015.
# Overthe years URAA has built capacity of varied Older Person thus now boasts of an organized stakeholder movement in place to lobby andadvocate for OPs.

Strengthen URAA institutional capacity and effectiveness.
# Over the years URAA BoD and staff have worked tirelyto have diversified financial resource base including donor and own generated resources to support running it activities and projects in Uganda.
# URAA has established program and financial structures,systems and policies that enable URAA to achieve its Mission in place, these are enshrined in its drafted policies but are mainstreamed in its daily implantation of interventions/projects.
# URAA ensures to strengthen the capacity its membersand staff to leadcommunity action for Older Person rights.
# URAA#s member organizations are vibrant and sustainable and their work is visible amongst their constituents.
In terms of impact the following can be also enumerated under just one example of a Project on Access to Justice and Rights Awareness Project in Hoima;
# Field visits and follow-ups with paralegals showed that; 90% of the paralegals are adequately supporting rights protection of older persons, 382 land issues were reported to paralegals, 133 land cases resolved at community level and 30 cases referred, 145 property rights issues and 842 persons received legal advice, 18 cases concluded by court and 41 cases being followed up.
# Documentation of success stories: 8 success stories have been documentedand shared and older persons were happy with the work done by URAA as one had this to say:  #without them could not repose my land and live peacefully#. Also lessons learnt such as project inception meetings provided stakeholder#s information on the project objectives and activities, working through paralegals increased appreciation and use of ADR. The coordination committee linked up older persons issues in sub county development plan and shared on media and project reports.
# Sub county leaders are realising the need to support and protect the rights of older Persons and integrate them in existing government programs.The older persons have been integrated and benefited from Operation Wealth Creation and Community Driven Development.
# Increased utilization of the services of paralegals by older persons and communities in resolving land conflicts. Its indicator; is that the project has made impact on the lives of older persons in accessing justice and awareness raised.
3. INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE
The Vision: A dignified, self-fulfilled poverty free ageing Uganda.

Mission Statement: To champion the realisation and preservation of a dignified quality of life for Older Persons in Uganda.

Mission: What is the current purpose of theorganisation?
URAA seeks to be the leadnational level advocacy and service agency that represents the needs and interests of older persons. All these are pursued through its five strategic objetives namely;
1. To economically empower older persons.
2. To address the social welfare of elderly people.
3. To strengthen networking, communication and integration between URAA, OPs and other stakeholders.
4. To carry out research, policylobby and advocacy for older persons.
5. To strengthen URAA institutional capacity andeffectiveness.
6. To address the needs of older persons in emergency and disaster situations.
Institutional objectives: What are the principal changes the organisation seeks to achieve over the long term?
# That Older persons# are economically empowered to meet own and their beneficiaries# needs.
# That the social welfare of elderly people addressed.
# That networking, communication and integration between URAA, OPs and other stakeholders is strengthened.
# Research, policy lobbyand advocacy for older persons is carried out to inform policy formulation.
# URAA institutional capacity and effectiveness is strengthen to serve the older persons better.
# Older persons in emergency and disaster situations need addressed and situation alleviated.

Field(s) of activity: What are the principal thematic and geographic areas in which the organisation works?  Who are the social actors that benefit from the work?
URAA has a permit to work in any part of the country but at the moment has presencein at least 63 Districts of Uganda scattered in all regions of Uganda, where we work with Older Person Association (OPAs), these are community based organisations registered with the relevant community development offices in their respective districts. In addition to the Head office in Kampala, currently URAA also has a field office in Adjumani where it is working with older South Sudanese refugees resident in ten (10) of the Settlements in Adjumani.
The principal thematic areas include;
Policyadvocacy, Resourcemobilization, Member capacity building, Research and Documentation, institutional development, Networking and Older persons development interventions.
In terms of social actors benefiting from the work of URAA;
URAA Primarily worksfor and with older persons as individuals but best in their organised groups to advance their rights and therefore reduce their socio-economic plight while indirectly contributes to ensuring their adjacent beneficiaries are also safe and their plight lessened.
Others include;
#Older person leaders from the National to the community levels namely;
# National Council for Older Person Regional representatives, District Councilors for Older Persons, Older Person Association leaders and members, Older Citizen or Person (for the case of Refugees) Monitoring Group Members in Uganda and the District older person executive members (a 12 member committee in each district)
# Relevant District committee#s in-charge of older person affairs like the Gender and Social Services inevery district.
These benefit from URAA capacity Building as well as coaching, mentoring and joint lobby and advocacy interventions in their areas of jurisdiction, so far in at least 30 Districts in Uganda.
To do this work, URAA has partnered withlocaland international age care agencies including ministries especially the mother Ministry of Gender, Labour and Social Development but also with the Ministry of Health. URAA implements some of it projects in collaboration with these ministries which contributed tosustainability of its interventions.

4. STRATEGIC POSITIONING
Analyse the environment in which the organisation works? Who are the other relevant social actors, including government and business, and what roles do they play? #In this context,what is unique about the position of the organisation?

Over 90% of older Ugandans live in rural areas and are primarily engaged in the informal agricultural sector with many suffering from age discrimination, income insecurity. Current estimatesindicate that 72% of older people are the heads of household  and many have the added burden of caring for orphaned children (63% of orphans and vulnerable children live alone or are cared for by older people). While they carry the responsibilities of supporting families, older people also face both increasing health challenges and discrimination as they age.

They are generally excluded from development programs and often discriminated against when attempting to access social services. An additional challenge for theolder population in Uganda is the lack of education and high illiteracy rates: more thanhalf of older Ugandans have never been to school and close to 80% of older women are illiterate.

Other social actors include Age care organizations like Helpage International, ROTOM, HENU and other CSOs. These support URAA#s advocacy agenda.

URAA has for long built partnership and relationship with the Ministry of Gender and Social Development (MGLSD) and other development partners atnational and sub national level which provide entry point for using sub national initiatives to influence national agenda.  Given the factthat URAA is leading network of older in Uganda presents advantage of influencing issues at high levels.

URAA isalso a member of the United Nations Open Ended Working Group (OEWG) and a Network member of Help Age International. These affiliations offers opportunities for it to share results through reports and exerts on issues of human rights promotion and protection, access to justice and gender equality for older  and other marginalized groups.  In this way URAA contributes to humanitarian actions that are Human rightsprotection and gender equality for the marginalized groups. URAA carries out regular information sharing with MGLSD and Ministry ofForeign Affairs which carry out coordination and linkages with the permanent mission to the UN to ensure Uganda#s effective participation at OEWG subsequent sessions. Thus URAA reports to the OEWG on measures to strengthen the promotion and protection of human rights of vulnerable populations, thus contributes to Human rights and care of vulnerable populations, with a special focus on violence and abuse against older and especially older women.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UGANDA REACH THE AGED ASSOCIATION URAA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.36516 32.63731</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-21">156762</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-01">45866</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UGANDA REACH THE AGED ASSOCIATION URAA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-01">35726</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UGANDA REACH THE AGED ASSOCIATION URAA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-01">39929</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UGANDA REACH THE AGED ASSOCIATION URAA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-01">19565</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UGANDA REACH THE AGED ASSOCIATION URAA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-01">15676</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UGANDA REACH THE AGED ASSOCIATION URAA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-01">45866</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-01">35726</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-01">39929</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-01">19565</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-01">15676</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05257-03:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000141" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000923"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007881"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05257"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Voice Innovate Learn grants Uganda"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grantees, rightsholder groups and other key stakeholders develop and implement innovative strategies to reach, empower and strengthen the capacities of rightsholders.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Communities of Practice supported by programme staff and Linking and Learning facilitating organisations to define a set of learning questions</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.1.a" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-08-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.b</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Communities of Practice with active participation of grantees emerging through Linking and Learning processes</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.1.b" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-08-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="5"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.c.i</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># and type (article, training material, blog, podcast, video) of publications produced by Communities of Practice to develop, share and document knowledge</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.1.c.i" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-08-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.c.ii</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># learning meetings held by Communities of Practice to develop, share and document knowledge</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.1.c.ii" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-08-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grantees, rightsholder groups and other key stakeholders develop and implement innovative strategies to reach, empower and strengthen the capacities of rightsholders.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># grantees, rightsholder groups and other key stakeholders reporting use of new insights and innovative approaches that they have acquired through Linking and Learning</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.1.1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-08-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-08-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-08-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
