<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05760-11:KH</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening capacity of coalitions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fisheries Action Coalition Team (FACT) is a coalition of NGOs established in 2000 by a group of NGO members working on fisheries and environmental issues around the Tonle Sap Lake. It was established as part of the environment project of the NGO Forum onCambodia.At that time, a group of NGOs interested in fisheries issues formed a sub-working group which then was supported by different international NGOs such as Oxfam, NGO Forum on Cambodia, and Environment Justice-Foundation. The group of eight NGOs later decided to form the Fisheries Action Coalition Team. In January 2004, FACT separated from the NGO Forum on Cambodia following the reform in fisheries sector of Cambodia, in which the government declared to release up to 56% of the commercial fishing lots to community management. FACT#s active members are all Cambodian NGO staff members who are committed to conducting advocacy in fisheries issues and monitoring policy reforms. FACT#s program mobilizes provincial NGOs and Community Based Organizations (CBOs) to more effective conduct advocacy programs that respond to development policies and development programs. FACT focuses its work around the Tonle Sap, Coastal andMekong provinces, on issues that affect Cambodian communities# livelihoods. FACT collaborates with NGOs concerned with fisheries involved with local fishing communities. FACT works towards building a strong coalition of NGOs and local grassroots# organizations toprotect fisheries, water resources and other natural resources in Tonle Sap Lake, Mekong River, and Cambodian marine regions along the coastal provinces.

Under this requested project FACT aim contribute to the improvement of policies and law enforcement, better access to and control of fishery resources, and improved livelihoods.

To achieve about aim, the followings are the project outcomesand project activities which FACT proposed to work within the 12 months period, Jan - Dec 2020.

Outcome 1: CCF and NGO-CF are strengthened to become better organized and more professional

Output 1: Providing capacity to CCBO and NGO partners on natural/fisheries resources management, and other legal frameworks such as Environment Law, Fisheries Law, Sub-Decrees related to fisheries resources management

Activity 1.2.1 (budget code2.1) Training courses on relevant subjects to NGO-CF: FACT will conduct one training to NGOCoalition on Fisheries (NGO-CF) members with expectation of 30 participants, of whom at least 10 is women. Topic of training is related to one or more of these subjects: Advocacy skill, communication skills, leadership and related fisheries legal framework,#etc. The specific subjects will be identified during the first meeting of NGO-CF.

Activity 1.2.2 (budget code 2.2) Training courses on relevant subjects toCCF: FACT will conduct one training to Coalition of Cambodia Fishers (CCF) members with expectation of 55 participants, of whom at least 20 is women. Topic of training is related to one or more of these subjects: Advocacy skill, communication skills, leadership and related fisheries legal framework,#etc. The specific subjects will be identified during the first meeting of CCF.


Activity 1.2.3 (budget code 2.3) Conduct study tour/annual reflection for NGO-CF members: FACT will conduct a study tour/reflection by inviting around 30 NGO-CF members, of whom at least 10 is women. The purpose of this study tour is to reflect the annual achievements of NGO-CF#s work and plan for next year and exchange more experiences, lesson learnt and challenges in networkingand advocacy on fisheries resources management among the partners and other outside partners.

Activity 1.2..4 (budget code 2.4) Conduct study tour/annual reflection for CCF members: FACT will conduct a study tour/annual reflection by inviting around 30NGO-CF members, of whom at least 10 is women. The purpose of this study tour is to reflect the annual achievements of NGO-CF#s work and plan for next year and exchange more experiences, lesson learnt and challenges in networking and advocacy on fisheriesresources management among thepartners and other outside partners.


Outcome 2:  NGOs partners and fishers representatives are empowered and partner with Fisheries Administration to advocate for better fisheries resources management via policy dialogues and advocacy campaigns

Output 2.1 Policy dialogues on and advocacy activities at sub-national and national levels, for better fisheries resources management have been conducted.

Activity 2.1.1 (budget code 2.5). Conduct NGO-CF meeting (3 times/year): FACT will keep strengthening the existing nationalNGO network NGO Coalition on Fisheries (NGO-CF) with 46 NGO partners. The purpose of the meeting is to discuss internally among theNGO partners of the network on internal issue # including workingstrategy to partner with FiA and other government officials # monitor the progresses of the results of the both previous internal NGO partners and main Cambodia Fisheries Network (CFN) meeting whereFiA also joined and prepare for the coming main CFN meeting.

Activity 2.1.2 (budget code 2.6). Conduct CCF meeting (3times/year): FACT will keep supporting CCF to host its CCF meetings (3times/year) in which around 55 CBO/CFi members are invited to join. The purpose of the meeting is to discuss internallyamongthe 55 CFi-members of the CCF on internal issue # including working strategy to work with NGO partners and partner with FiA and other government officials # monitor the progresses of the results of the previous internal CCF and main CFN meeting wherebothNGO partners and FiA also joined and prepare for the coming main CFN meeting.

Activity 2.1.3(budget code 2.7). Conduct main CFN meeting (2times/year): FACT will keep organizing meeting of Cambodia Fisheries Network (CFN) where representatives ofNGO-CF members, CCF members , and around 17 national FiA and FiA cantonment officials are members and invited to join. It#s expected that around 60participants,  of whom at least 25 is women, will be invited to join each of the meeting The purpose ofthe meeting is to review the progresses of the relevant issues/challenges raised in previous meeting(s) and discuss on new fisheries related issues, including illegal fishing activities, policies,#etc.

Activity 2.1.4 (budget code 2.8) Conduct sub-nationalCFN meeting: FACT will coordinate to organize sub-  sub-national CFN meeting among NGO partners, CCF, and/or competent authorities (provincial FiA, authorities, policy, courts,#) to address the fisheries related issues at regional levels (Mekong, Tonle Sap, andcoastal). At least two meetings and 40 participants, of whom at least 10 is women, at each of the region will be organized. The main purpose of the meeting is address any fisheries related issues in which can be addressed at sub-national levelwithout bringing the issues to national level. There be at least 150 participants will be invited to join each forum.

Activity 2.1.4 Conduct national round table/forum discussion: FACT will conduct one national public forum. The purpose of the forum is toshare fisheries related issues and together address the identified issues, in which can#t by addressed by and selected by CFN or NGO partners, among other multi-stakeholders such as FiA, MoE, MAFF, MoI, and court. The forum also aims at discussing onother legalframeworks such as amendment of Fisheries Law, Sub-degree on CFi management. There will be at least 60 participants will be invited to join this forum, of whom at least 25 is women.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fisheries Action Coalition Team (FACT) is a coalition of NGOs established in 2000 by a group of NGO members working on fisheries and environmental issues around the Tonle Sap Lake. It was established as part of the environment project of the NGO Forum onCambodia.At that time, a group of NGOs interested in fisheries issues formed a sub-working group which then was supported by different international NGOs such as Oxfam, NGO Forum on Cambodia, and Environment Justice-Foundation. The group of eight NGOs later decided to form the Fisheries Action Coalition Team. In January 2004, FACT separated forum the NGO Forum on Cambodia following the reform in fisheries sector of Cambodia, in which the government declared to release up to 56% of the commercial fishinglots to community management. FACT#s active members are all Cambodian NGO staff members who are committed to conducting advocacy in fisheries issues and monitoring policy reforms. FACT#s program mobilizes provincial NGOs and Community Based Organizations(CBOs) to more effective conduct advocacy programs that respond to development policies and development programs. FACT focuses its work around the Tonle Sap, Coastal and Mekong provinces, on issues that affect Cambodian communities# livelihoods. FACT collaborates with NGOs concerned with fisheries involved with local fishing communities. FACT works towards building a strong coalition of NGOs and local grassroots# organizations to protect fisheries, water resources and other natural resources in Tonle SapLake, Mekong River, and Cambodian marine regions along the coastal provinces.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fisheries Action Coalition Team</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to a sustainable livelihood</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31310" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-15">33537</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-15">-13713</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-01">33537</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fisheries Action Coalition Team</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-01">-13713</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fisheries Action Coalition Team</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-01">33537</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-01">-13713</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05760-11:KH">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000122" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007251"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Cambodia (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05760"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="ONL-UR New and Strategic Initiatives"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing towards small scale producers land rights and access to water and/or more inclusive land and/or water governance processes (following Oxfam Novib/partners actions)</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing promoting small scale producers land rights and access to water and/or to participate in more inclusive land and/or water governance processes (following Oxfam Novib/partners actions) -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-01-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="20"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="20"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-05-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing towards small scale producers land rights and access to water and/or more inclusive land and/or water governance processes (following Oxfam Novib/partners actions)</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-01-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="5"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="5"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-05-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
