<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-04725-29:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MADA Humanitarian Response</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Manna Development Agency (MADA) was established in 2016 by a five member group referred to as the organization#s board of directorsand became operational in the same year on food security, cross boarder peace building and community development platform.In mid-2017 MADA started as a community based organization registered with Kaabong District Local Government and Karenga Lower Local Government., MADA kick started the process of registration with the National NGO Bureau after a resolution from the BoDs meeting held on the1st July, 2017 and now MADA is registered with National NGO Bureau as a local NGO.  MADA head Quarters is in Karenga Centre, Sub-county, Dodoth West County, Karamoja Uganda. MADA Operates in Lobalangit, Karenga and Lokori sub-counties at the moment with hope of expanding to other 16 sub-counties of Kaabong District. MADA also has presence in Lamwo as it registered with Lamwo District Local Government
MADA has got a Board of Directors comprising of 5 members 2 females and 3 males, its also guided with documents such as constitution, human Resource Policy, Financial Policy, Procurement and Disposal of Assets guidelines and other Policies and principles guiding her operation. MADA has a broad spectrum of interventions in the areas affecting the most vulnerable in society. These include; communities, women, persons affected and infected by HIV/AIDS, the youths and the elderly. MADA was thus formed to respond to the challenges facing the community, youth, women, communities and the elderlyby improving food security, addressing issues related togender inequality as they constitute a greater percentage of the most vulnerable and the most excluded groups in the Community.
MADA considers community participation and inclusiveness as an approach which needs the local community to come together to realize that for development to succeed, the population should be kept in all processes related to development design, formulation and implementation. MADA works within this strategy which will simultaneously generate information
ACHIEVEMENT
What have been the principal results in the past three years that contribute to significant, structural, sustained and positive improvement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?
The last project implemented has seen some drastic change that there are improved livelihoods for the people who the response targeted.
MADA has been able to expand in operations, having started from South Sudan now operating in both Uganda and South Sudan. MADA implemented a project called skilling the youth for sustainable development in South Sudan and it was successful through hands on training for school drop outs for late primary and earlysecondary. Most of thosewho participated in the training initiative are currently engaged in income generating activities for instance operating small restaurants, others employed to the government and others taken by contractors as their workers. For the 100 youth trained in the last assessment conducted by the organization 60 boys, girls and women are activity making use of their skills andknowledge gained from the intervention
The community of Opotipot parish who benefited from the chilli seeds are now working towardsplanting more chilli not only for deterring animals from their gardens but also for commercial use.
3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE
Mission: What is the current purpose of the organisation?
Working towards the attainment of human development and helping to educate its beneficiaries to fulfill their moral obligation in alleviating suffering, respect human rights and removal of all social injustices
What are the principal changes the organisation seeks to achieve over the long term?

The organizations seeks to invest more on the communities we work with through constant engagement on how to remain food secure even in times of food stress by ensuring that, the communities we work with are organized into farmer groups who produce food not only  for consumption some should be commercialized to meet other basic requirements. MADA feels that the empowered community will remain vibrant in meeting their daily needs and save for the future
Field(s) of activity: What are the principal thematic and geographic areas inwhich the organisation works?
To promote grassroots peace amongst the communities of Karenga and Bira along the Uganda and South Sudan boarder &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Kaabong as a whole
To enhance social services such as education, food security &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Livelihoods and water &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; sanitation
To promote good governance, democracy and human rights including Women Rights &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; civic education
Sensitize the community on the scourge of HIV/AIDS and other STDs.
To promote environment and wildlife conservation
To provide humanitarian emergency response on food security vulnerable livelihoods
 Who are the social actors that benefit from the work?
People we work with who include: women, girls, boys, elderly, men, PWDs and PSNs, government authorities at the lower level and Civil Society Organizations.
4. STRATEGIC POSITIONING
Analyse the environment in which the organisation works?
Increasing pressures on organizations to be more competitive is taking centre stage to be seen to deliver services to the community. MADA is currently focusing interest on the emergency response, though it has been implementing most of the projects which are related to development. The management of the organization decided that it was necessary to refocus the organization to be also ready when issues to related acrisis occurs the organization should have the minimum standards torespond to the an emergency in a most appropriate and timely manner.
Who are the other relevant social actors, including governmentand business, and what roles do they play? &apos;
Local communities in the operation area being part of the project planning design, implementation and monitoring.
Local authorities at the sub county level, they are involved in the assessment, identification of the affected communities and also give guidance onthe working protocols of the government

Civil society organization for coordination andtimely response, to avoid work duplication and use of resources in the most effective and efficient way

District local government for an enabling environment tooperate and guiding principles which are all captured in the MoUs.

The organizations also works closely with the relevant private sector (suppliers and vendors)  for goods and services which aid the successful intervention
In this context, what is unique about the position of the organisation?

The community accepted and recognizing that, MADA can deliver the humanitarian assistance to the intended community. The organization is the only active local organization based in the whole of Dodoth West of Kaabong district, justify her proximity to the vulnerable community from the crop raiding and also to the border with South Sudan
5. FUNCTIONAL ORGANISATIONAL CHART include below your organisational chart)- document provided already
How are authorityandresponsibilities structured? For each operational unit, indicate the job titles, number of people in each position, and if they are menor women.
See annex for the organization chart
Note that, the highlighted areas are the ones which currentlyactivedue to limited funding source
6. CURRENT BALANCE SHEET/FINANCIAL POSITION (document provided already)
Oxfam Novib requires information about what theorganisation owns, debts that you must pay and your net financial worth. Therefore, we ask for a balance sheet (available in Microsoft Excel) for your entire organisation as it stands at the end of your two most recent fiscal years.

As stated in the RAMON, MADA conducts an audit every two years where the last one was conducted in 2016 for south Sudanprogramme as for the case of the Uganda programme the organization through the humanitarian capacity building fund has planned to the audit be conducted between May and July 2018.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MANNA DEVELOPMENT AGENCY MADA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-12">41000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-01">24600</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MANNA DEVELOPMENT AGENCY MADA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-01">12300</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MANNA DEVELOPMENT AGENCY MADA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">4100</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MANNA DEVELOPMENT AGENCY MADA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-01">24600</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-01">12300</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">4100</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-04725-29:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000916"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-04725"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="IKEA Foundation ELNHA"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-05-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="18"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="200"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="42"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="46"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="62"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="500"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-05-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="18"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="200"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="21"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="36"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="62"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="700"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-05-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="121"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="121"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="30"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="340"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="367"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="87"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="400"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-05-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="121"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="121"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="23"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="340"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="367"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="60"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="500"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
