<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05255-12:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Inclusive Comm. Help</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Inclusive Community Help (FICH) previously called Fight to Improve Community Health (FICH) an indigenous National Non-Governmental organization registered with NGO Board Kampala, no. S.5914/12762. FICH has been in operation with it former name (Fight to Improve Community Health) since 2010 as a Community Based Organization in Oyam district before re-branding to current #Foundation for Inclusive Community Help#.

Supporting the formation of women#s VSLA groups for improved livelihood willbe implemented by Foundation for Inclusive Community Help (FICH). The project will strengthen the capacity and economic development of women at risk of HIV/AIDS and with low household incomes in the communities of Loro and Iceme sub-counties. The eighteenmonths# program aims to make a difference in the lives of 240 group members directly by organizing them into VSLA groups and increasing their capacity to access services and resources through government economic programs such as youth and women livelihoodprograms and linkages to financial andBusiness Development Services by the end of project period in 2020 within Oyam district.
To achieve successful outcomes, the project responds to the women at risk of HIV/AIDS with low income challenges and will involve multiple stakeholders and players including government departments, civil society organizations (CSOs); faith#based organizations (FBOs); Community Based Organisations (CBOs), the private sector such as financial institutions and Business DevelopmentService Providers. FICH will focus in four major objectiveareas: VSLA group formation and organising capacity, life skills and entrepreneurship training, economic strengthening, and linkages to opportunities.

The project will focus on vulnerable rural women aged 15 to 30 including women who are expose and at risk of HIV/AIDS with low household income. This target group is an often#neglected subpopulation and many are heads of households and caregivers in their communities and they are able to influencepolicies and practices for inclusive development of women.

Goal: To support formation of and build capacity of VSLA#s for improved livelihood and access to resources among low income, rural women in Oyam district aged 15 to 30 who are at risk of HIV/AIDS

Specific Objectives;
# To establish and strengthen participation of 240 group members in livelihoods development through the operation of sustainable enterprises in order to increase household incomes and job creations.
# To increase the participation of 240 beneficiaries in local governance through village savings and loan associations.
# To provide support and linkages to VSLA groups for members to access other opportunities such as government livelihood programs, financialand business development services
# To provide women with opportunities for life skills development in order to develop a collective voice demanding quality services, advocating for women rights, and promoting gender equality.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FICH was founded by and first registered in 2010 with its former definition #Fight to Improve Community Health# before its re-branding to its current definition #Foundation for Inclusive Community Help#. Its establishment is focused to influence the fullparticipation of youth and community in the fight against economic, educational, environmental and health related threats and challenges. This, anticipation is being achieved by carrying out mobilization, sensitization, conducting research, providing support to quality education and initiating livelihood projects, providing disability prevention services, provision of technical skills and trainings, providing business mentorship &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; counselling, and promoting job creation among young people in the community.
FICH has reached this level today because of great dedication of time, resources, expertise and network of greatest contacts around the globe and that is the secret of FICH development to greatness every single day. Our strategic partnerships have contributed and provided FICH with vast experience in working with post conflict communities in Northern Uganda. We are able to understand in details who they are, which partner and stakeholders to bring on board to support our initiatives.
Furthermore, FICHis strengthening its functions and management system through knowledge sharing and professionals. In organizational development process, we are able to understand organization focus, image, identity and culture. From this learning, FICH rebranded itselffrom Fight to Improve Community Health to Foundationfor Inclusive Community Help to give it a competitive edge to develop and serve the target program participants. With the same organizational development process board structure, function and effectiveness is more professional to attract partners, grants and donations as governance is one of the key areas that shows transparency and capacity of handling organizational resources among many areas targeted by organizational Development. On the other side,Monitoring, Learning and Evaluation is greatly capacitated and has helped FICH establish ML&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;E department that has eased tracking organizational activities &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; outcomes easier.
The organization is founded by the current team leader (Executive Director), Emmy Zoomlamai Okello and he is mentoring other staff to take the lead before joining advisory board of the organization.

2. ACHIEVEMENTS
What have been the principal results in the past three years thatcontribute to significant, structural, sustained andpositive improvement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?

Through implementation of different programs in the past three years, FICH has developed more cost-effective programs and scaledup many initiatives which is improving gender equality and reducing poverty in the community. For example, through second chance education for girls affected by conflict program, FICH is able to unleash low-self- esteem among beneficiaries, there isevidence of retention in school, provision of technical skills development, empowered communities and young people, exposure to human rights best practices and economic development among all program participants and key stakeholders in Oyam district and other areas within Northern Uganda.

3. INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE
The Vision: A generation of healthy, innovative, productive and self-reliant youth and women

Mission Statement: FICH exists to transform youth and women through sustainable opportunities and descent work in a thriving community

Mission: What is the current purpose of the organisation?
Institutional objectives: What are the principal changes the organisation seeks to achieve over the long term?
1) To promote quality education and lifelonglearning for children and youth in formal and non-formal education cycle.
2) To promote sustainable economic growth that provide decent employment for vulnerable people.
3) To promote healthy lives for good well-being of vulnerable people in the community.
4) Conduct action oriented research and surveys to establish appropriate positive response programs.
5) To strengthen organizational means of implementation and partnership for sustainable growth and programs management.

Field(s) of activity: What are the principal thematic and geographic areas in which the organisation works?  Who are the social actors that benefit from the work?
Currently our work targets communities within the Northern Uganda with office based in Oyam and below are principlethematic areas.
Livelihood: FICH#s livelihoods programs tackle the root causes of poverty by addressing problems of Access and unitization of land especially for women, production, access, and income. The activities are tailored to meet community orindividual specific needs and are designed to boost agricultural production, value addition, start-up equipment, support micro-enterprise initiatives, and enhance a vulnerable community#saccess to sustainable sources of income.
Education: The fundamental base for FICH Education program combines concept, research, andpractice. The essential knowledge is derived from the usual environment that can best be understood within the context of #Experimentation#. It is from this background that FICH promotes learning outcomes in literacy and numeracy among children age 6-16 years in order to focus public attention and stimulate action towards leaning of children through research. FICH education program also responds to the needs of marginalized children and youth through opportunities to obtain second-chance education and job skills training to comprehend the understanding of future generation.
Entrepreneurship: FICH chose critical areas of intervention on broader traditional context which include attitudes, mind-set and behaviours toward entrepreneurship, influencing policies and the business environment, and enabling interaction for exchange of goods and services for money among young people and other markets. FICH entrepreneurship program differs from convectional business training but it highlights essential entrepreneurial skills from gender perspective, whether applying to starting or improving individual, family or group business it addresses the practical and strategic needs of low-income women in enterprise bystrengthening their basic business and people management skills. It shows women how to develop #their personal entrepreneurial traits and obtain support through groups, networks and institutions dealing with enterprise development.

Health: FICH focuses on delivering effective health services to its beneficiaries specifically in the areas of Sexual and Reproductive Health information and services for depressed population especially youth and socially excluded groups. Other services include HIV/AIDS andHygiene and Sanitation awareness creation. Impressively, FICH always partner with health department at District and National levels including development partners to deliver information and services to the target groups that FICH serves in the community.

4. STRATEGIC POSITIONING
Analyse the environment in which the organisation works? Who are the other relevant social actors, including government and business, and what roles do they play? #In this context, what is unique about the position of the organisation?

In addition to Government and businesses within the FICH catchment areas, there are other development partners like Communities basedorganizations, faith-based organization, local/national and international organizations supporting social development. The unique positioning of FICH is that, it is a grassroots initiative with focus on sharpening advocacy skills and continuing with strategic thinking and networking. The organization is learning and using social media in its work andto amplifythe voices of vulnerable people.A major area for FICH is the continuous improvement in its rights protection strategies by using rights based-approach in more effective way to benefit women and children at a grassroot level as we link to national and international framework.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Inclusive Community FICH</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.6548 -84.2621</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-19">25000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-01">11291</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Inclusive Community FICH</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-01">7613</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Inclusive Community FICH</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-01">4845</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Inclusive Community FICH</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-10-01">1250</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Inclusive Community FICH</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-01">11291</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-01">7613</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-01">4845</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-10-01">1250</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05255-12:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000141" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000923"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007881"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05255"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Voice Empowerment grants Uganda"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rightsholders (individuals and groups) are willing and able to work on their own empowerment.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># change agendas developed by rightsholder groups based on the facilitation of programme staff and partner organisations</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.a" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.b</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># change agendas implemented by rightsholder groups based on the support of programme staff and partner organisations</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.b" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.c</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># grantees incorporating new approaches in realising their change agendas</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.c" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rightsholders (individuals and groups) are willing and able to work on their own empowerment.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># rightsholder groups indicating to have safe spaces to convene and work</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># rightsholder groups presenting their collective demands to external stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.3</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% rightsholder groups indicating increased confidence to raise their voice</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.3" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="3"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
