<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06490-04:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save Humanity Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; SAVE HUMANITY AFRICA (SHA) is a Non-profit making and non-discriminative Refugee youth led Community Based organization (CBO) striving to alleviate poverty, diseases and conflicts through innovative approaches by involving the community. We are partners workingwith the youth and the local communities, and other NGO&#x2019;S.
&#x2022; It was founded on the 26th/05/2019 and later registered as a CBO with Local Government.

Strength of the organization
&#x2022; SHA is legally registered and recognized by the office the Prime Minister (OPM) refugee department and UNHCR as a Community based organization operating in the Rhino Camp refugee Settlement.
&#x2022; The advisory council is comprised of all competent persons working with various NGO&#x2019;S and aged between 35 years and above.
&#x2022;  Competent staff sourced from the open market i.e. An Executive director with strong background in Diplomacy and a Finance officer with strong Financial Background, Field Officers with dynamic and vast experience in community mobilization and engagement.
&#x2022; SHA will leave its door open to volunteers and other NGO&#x2019;S to add strength to the team.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HISTORY:
Save Humanity Africa (SHA) was formed to respond to peace building, health education and livelihood gaps existing in the refugees and host communities through innovative approaches by involving the communities themselves.
It was founded on the26/05/2019 by a group of determined, dynamic and like minded youths of refugee and host communities working in the humanitarian sector. However, the organization commenced officially in February 2020 being registered at sub-county and district local government, as well as Office of the prime minister and UNHCR CBO data log.
Save Humanity Africa (SHA) has also developed organization policies including theHuman Resource Policy, Finance Policy and Procedures Manual, anti-fraud policy, code of conduct, Operations and Procurement Policy,gender and Prevention of sexual exploitation and Abuse (PSEA), all integrated under the Age, Gender and Diversity Mainstreaming (AGDM) principle.
2. ACHIEVEMENTS
Men and women, girls and boys have positive mind change in response to Covid-19 prevention and management which has led to installation of hand washing facilities at homes and other public units as result of the Covid-19 community awareness we have conducted in Ocea zone.

People in the operational areas have massively engaged in farming which has reduced starvation and over dependence on food ratio distributed by WFP and other relief agencies.

Our advocacy for community peace has reduced the prevalence of SGBV, child abuse and other social misfits in Ocea &apos;C&apos; village restoring peace and harmony to the larger extent.

People in Ocea C village have taken positive initiatives in planting trees as a result of SHA staff and volunteers advocating for treeplanting through practice demonstration by having plantedsome in the area.

The rate of pregnancy among adolescent girls have been reduced in Ocea zone from the month of June compared to when learners were sent home due to the lockdown aimed at curbing the spreadof corona virus in March. This was evident asSHA has been conducting sessions with adolescent girls and boys under the theme &quot;Adolescent for Future&quot;.

3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE
Vision: To be the leading and vibrant innovative grassroots organization which enhances communities with strategic methods of fighting diseases, poverty and conflict through community involvement.

Mission: To awaken, prepare and empower a self-reliant community(s) of disadvantaged people through innovative intervention solution to overcome theircommon flight of diseases, poverty and conflict through innovative education campaigns.

Core values
&#x2022; Love and care through charitable works,
&#x2022; Respect for diversity,
&#x2022; Integrity,
&#x2022;  Commitment to innovation and creativity.
&#x2022; Involvement and participation.

Principle objectives
&#x2022; Strengthening community awareness on health education.
&#x2022; Engaging in livelihood activities I.e. agriculture and environment to scale sustainable food security, and restore green spaces and ecosystem.
&#x2022; Promote and responding to Peace building initiatives in the communities for sustainable coexistence amongst refugees and with the host Communities.

Field(s) of activity:
SHA&apos;s principal thematic programs are; Peace building, health education, and livelihood (agriculture and environment) targeting three zones (Ocea, Eden and Tika) in Rhino Camp Refugee Settlement.
Our social actors include Church leaders, youth and other relevant stakeholders, partner Community Based Organizations (CBOs), health personnel including the village health teams for health education and Core Beneficiary Communities. Agriculture and environment practitioners among others being social actors for livelihood.
Thematic areas of our work: Describe what you do in each (as relevant)
&#x2022; Water Sanitation and Hygiene
&#x2022;Livelihood
&#x2022; Distribute seeds for nutritious foods.
&#x2022; Provision of fresh-up trainings for local farmers through seminars.
&#x2022; Advocate and support livestock rearing
&#x2022; Supportuse of agricultural modern tools.
&#x2022; Health
&#x2022; Preventive diseases awarenessand education.
&#x2022; Promotion of sports and gymnastics and exercise activities for fitness and health wellness.
&#x2022; Supporting adolescent girls with hygiene management skills including menstrualhealth.
&#x2022; Promoting home health science campaigns.
&#x2022; Promotingpositive family planning.
&#x2022; Support school and village health clubs.
&#x2022; Protection, Peace building, Social Cohesion
&#x2022; Build and support youth business groups.
&#x2022; Establishment of recreational centers.
&#x2022; Promoting games and sports.
&#x2022; Conducting peace building capacity trainings.
&#x2022; Formation and support to community peace forums and committees.
&#x2022; Conduct community dialogues and peace building sensitization.
&#x2022; Environment and Energy
&#x2022; Carrying out community awareness on environmental protectionandconservation.
&#x2022; Promotion, advocacy and campaigns for ecosystem and green space.
&#x2022; Distribution of tree seedlings
&#x2022; Promote and support use of modern energy saving stoves.
&#x2022; Identification and mark painting of natural trees for protection.
&#x2022; Education.
&#x2022; Others - specify
Areas of operation:
Our activities are carried out in Ocea, Eden and Tika zones of Rhino Camp Refugee Settlement.

4. STRATEGIC POSITIONING
We are aware of the difference in environment in the geographical setting of our operation due to the facts that the people we serve are from diverse historical backgrounds and heritage. we therefore work in both risky and safe environments in executing the organization&apos;s mission. But with affirmative risk mitigation measures put in place.

RhinoCamp has brought in Refugees from Majorly South Sudan and a few others from the Democratic Republic of Congo, Burundi, Sudan and Rwanda. Notably, these groups have diverse cultural and Geographical (regional) settings endowed with the possibility of different behaviours and attitudes. Some of these communities have conflicting differences from their Countries of Origin possibly bringing with them anger and the feeling of revenge. Yet the Refugees are now living with the Host Communities containing in their differences andsimilarities. It has been noted that such difference created a few recorded misunderstandings and conflicts in the settlement. Attempts to genuinely create harmonies living and peaceful coexistence never fall in vain as such diversity could be transformed into strength of the entire Settlement.

There are also other relevant social actors; local government agencies, private companies, NGOs and other local agencies providing both relief and development programs and services atvarious capacities. In Rhino Camp, we work withCommunity structures, Health institutions, local Non-Governmental Organizations, International Organizations and Donor Agencies supporting our mission as well as Beneficiary community that form the basis ofour Principle objectives.

We are so unique in our work in the sense that we are based within the community with our members being members from the communities having the same historical background. Our staff and Volunteers understand the real problemsof their people and are understood better by their people. Besides, they understand and speak the local languages making us an immediate response agency in times of needs.
Finally, the formation of theorganization was supported by the local people itserves. It is endorsed by Board of Directors comprised of persons from the RefugeeCommunity and Ugandan Nationals.

S/NO OPERATIONAL UNIT TITLE # OF POSITIONS SEX  REPORTS TO
01 Senior management Executive Director 01 m Board of Directors
02 Programmes- Programme Officer 01 m Executive Director
03 Finance Finance Officer 01 f Executive Director
04 HR/Admin  HR/Admin Officer &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Assit. 02 1m;1f Executive Director
05 Programmes  Communication officer 03 (1f:2 m) Executive Director
06 Programmes Project coordinators 01 m Programme Officer
07 Programmes Membership Coordinator 01 m Project Coordinators
08 Programmes Volunteers. 12 -  7f &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; 5m Project Coordinators
09 Administration Support staffs NON (f: m) HR/Admin Officer
  22 (f: m)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save Humanity Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-02">17500</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-01">17500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save Humanity Africa</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-01">17500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06490-04:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000101" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002179"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06490"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Pilot Grant Facility for refugee-led Org"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-08-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="21208"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="327"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10804"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-08-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="27952"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="555"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12003"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-08-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="21208"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="327"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10804"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-08-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="27952"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="555"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12003"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
