<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05982-12:IN</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India - Health &amp; Education</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regulation of private sector regulatory frameworks in health-

1) Documenting and highlighting issues of patients# exploitation through offline campaigns in collaboration with Offline campaign through CSOs, patients# rights group collaboration in majorcities to build the narrative of overcharging and loot by private hospitals, and of the need for regulation by adoption and implementation of patients# rights.

2) Creation of an online portal to collect grievances of patients regarding their exploitation particularly in private hospitals, along with demands on need for regulation and implementation of patients# rights charter.

3) Building public opinion on the issues through online and offline mobilization including organizing public hearings, run for rights of patients #Walkathons/marathons at the national and state level to highlight the issues around patients# exploitation in private healthcare and need to ensure implementation of improved regulation of private healthcare sector.

4) Lobbying and advocacy with MPs/MLAs, Niti Aayog, PMO, Health Minister, Standing Committee, Opposition party on need for the implementation of patients# rights through individual meetingsand roundtables.

5) Raising issues of violation of patients# rights to Human Rights Commissions and advocate to push to enforce notification of Patient Rights.

6) Public hearing and interface with government at National and state level on cases of denial under national health protection scheme/ PMJAY

Strengthening public systems

1) Consolidation, validation and advocacy on social accountability experience in health and education. This would result in the creation of a set of tools and materials for mobilization on health and education to be taken up in advocacy on issues of citizen participation in health and education in the years to come.

2) Fiscal Justice. Budget advocacy skills would strengthened of health and education activists to integrate a robust fiscal justice narrative in the campaign.
a. Workshops at National level to enhance budget analysis and advocacy skills of civil society organizations to further strengthen the capacities of CSOs to analyze and advocate for enhanced budgetary provisions at the national and state level
b. State level health and education budget advocacy workshops (in 5 states) would be undertaken to support advocacy plans at the state level.

3) Evidence generation and policy analysis on school closure. A recent trend has been the closure of government schoolsby the state underthe pretext of rationalization. The evidence of impact on girls and students from marginalized communities would collected to support advocacy. Instances identified would be used for advocacy with the mainstream media and outreach to elected peoples# representatives (particularly the legislators  who earlier took part  in the Yes Democracy campaign) and judicial spaces.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2008, various Oxfams in India joined forces to form Oxfam India. Registered as an independent organisation, Oxfam India has indigenous staff and board members. We are a member of the global confederation of 20 Oxfams.

We focus on four poverty eliminating goals

1: Livelihood: More women and men will realise their right to secure and sustainable livelihoods.
2: Fight for women: More women will lead a violence-free life. This can be achieved through changes in attitudes and beliefs about gender relations and through encouraging women&apos;s engagement and assuming leadership in institutions and decision-making roles.
3: Education and Health: People living in poverty, especially women and, girls will realise their right to accessible and affordable healthcare, education, clean water and sanitation.
4: Human Rights: Those facing a humanitarian crisis will be assured the protection and the assistance they need, regardless of who they are, where they live or how they are affected.

We see poverty as a problem of power, the lack of power.&#x92; We workwith 60 NGOs at the grassroots&#x92; level to tackle poverty and inequality where it germinates. Our programmes are currently active in the critical states of Bihar, Chhattisgarh, Jharkhand, Odisha and Uttar Pradesh. We work with the most marginalised segments &#x96; Dalits, Tribals, Muslims, and Women. For them, poverty is more than lack of income, healthcare and education. It is a crippling state where these groups do not have any control in deciding the course of their own lives. They are excluded from basic decision-making rights.

Oxfam works primarily through grassroots organisations to bring deep-rooted sustainable changes in people&#x92;s lives. We do this through long-term development programming and link it to positive policy changes at various levels. We work for the socially excludedand most marginalised communities by mobilising them to campaign for greater economic and social reforms. We use our learnings about what works and what doesn&#x92;t at the grassroots level, through research and advocacy, to bring about pro-poor changes in policies and institutions.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam India</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="10" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-21">69821</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-01">69821</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Discretionary Funds Southern Affiliates</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam India</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-01">69821</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05982-12:IN">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007558"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05982"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Discretionary Fund 2019 -2020"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2310</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved policies Private Sector:  # cases where Oxfam Novib&#x2019;s/partners influencing has contributed to adopting and/or implementing improved gender sensitive policies holding private sector to account for extreme inequality and poverty.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where Oxfam Novib&#x2019;s/partners influencing has contributed to adopting and/or implementing improved gender sensitive policies holding private sector to account for extreme inequality and poverty -DD2</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-04-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clinical Establishment Act, states capping medical prices acts, advisory of the Human Right  Commission</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2310</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved policies Private Sector:  # cases where Oxfam Novib&#x2019;s/partners influencing has contributed to adopting and/or implementing improved gender sensitive policies holding private sector to account for extreme inequality and poverty.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2310-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">pieces of evidence (documents, studies, videos, testimonies etc.) produced by Oxfam Novib and partners in support of development/adoption of alternative policies/approaches</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2310-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-04-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clinical Establishment Act, states capping medical prices acts, advisory of the Human Right  Commission</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2310-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">pieces of evidence (documents, studies, videos, testimonies etc.) produced by Oxfam Novib and partners to support monitoring of practices and implementation of policies by the private sector</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2310-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-04-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clinical Establishment Act, states capping medical prices acts, advisory of the Human Right  Commission</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
