<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05255-14:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">JONAM YOUTH DEVELOPMENT Initiative</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonam Youth Development Initiative (JOYODI) is a legally registered not-for-profit Non-Governmental Organization incorporated as Company with Limited Liability on the 4th February, 2008. JOYODI is based at Kapita, along Wadelai road in Pakwach Town Council, JonamCounty - Pakwach district. The organization has 8 years of experience in identifying and tackling community health needs.

Equal Voices, Equal Rights (EVER) is a project idea which seeks to challenge discrimination, exploitation, abuse and violence that rural women and girls are subjected to in Pakwach Town Council. Gender Based Violence (GBV) is a serious issue in Uganda as a whole but more pronounced in rural areas. According to the Ministry of Gender, labour and social development, more women (39%) have suffered effects of GBV compared to men (11%). This is even more prevalent in marriage (62%). The common forms of GBV in Pakwach district include defilement, assault, rape, threats of violence, child neglect, deprivation of property, widow inheritance, forced marital sex and forced early marriage. These are primary fuelled by the patriarchal mind-set of our society which has led to power imbalance between males and females.

Goal: To reduce violence against married women and create an enabling environment for their socio-economic wellbeing. Equal Voices, Equal Rights (EVER) has three specific objectives as below;

# Increase individual awareness on GBV and challenge attitudes and harmful traditional practices that promote GBV. Married men and women (18-35 years) increased their knowledge on causes and effects of GBV and the possible consequences of GBV. Improved respect and attitude of men towards their wives, reduced harmfultraditional practices that promote GBV. Survivors of GBV more informed about the available avenues for seeking redress.
# Increasedaccess of women and girls to socio-economic opportunities. This objective will specifically empower women and girls to demand for social and economic opportunities that they are lawfully entitled to; including education and land ownership among others. It seeks to achieve equal property distribution between male and females, increased linkage and involvement of women and girls in government aided community economic projects such as NUSAF III, Community Driven Development (CDD) and Youth Livelihood Programme (YLP).
# Improved coordination and partnership for effective GBV response. Under this objective, JOYODI envisions increased partnership and collaboration with all key stakeholders to address GBV, community leaders trained and supporting advocacy against GBV, a platform created to enable quarterly or bi-annual dialogue on GBV with all stakeholders, improved referral and support for survivors and collective action planning for betterGBV prevention.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">JONAM YOUTH DEVELOPMENT INITIATIVE JOYODI</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonam Youth Development Initiative (JOYODI) is a legally registered not-for-profit Non-Governmental Organization incorporated as Company with Limited Liability on the 4th February, 2008. JOYODI is based at Kapita, along Wadelai road in Pakwach Town Council, JonamCounty - Pakwach district. The organization has 10 years of experience in identifying and tackling community social and economic needs.

JOYODI was founded by local elites of Pakwach district with a purpose of contributing to the development of Pakwach district. A 9-member Board of Trustees (BoT) comprising of individuals with high integrity, qualification and experience in development issuesprovides oversight and guidance to management staff, while daily activities of the Organization are managed by the Programme Officer and other departmental. Human resource and Accounting policy tools are also in place and strictly enforced to guide operations.

Over the years, JOYODI has worked with many partners in pursuit of its vision and mission. Between 2008 and 2012, our major focus wason HIV prevention and economic empowerment. However, with more experience and lessons learnt, Sexual and reproductive health and Gender equality key components of our prorammes. The inclusion of Gender programming has helped us implement projects in a more responsive manner, taking into consideration the unique needs and challenges facing men and women. This proved successful in our SRHR projects supported by AMPLIFYCHANGE.
JOYODI has also increased scale of operation since its inception. 2 Sub Counties are now covered out of 6 in Pakwach district. We hope with more partners we can cover the entire district eventually.

ACHIEVEMENTS
What have been theprincipal results in the past three years that contribute tosignificant, structural, sustained and positive improvement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?

- Through our community sensitization events, JOYODI has increased individual awarenessabout GBV and the available avenues for seeking support. Although there is still high need to scale-up awareness creation on GBV, JOYODI has already contributed significantly to this.
- Our partnership with AFARD and Gorta, has enabled us to contribute tolivelihood improvement through goat rearing, poultry and sim-sim farming.
- We have increased awareness on SRH among young men and women in Panyango and Pakwach Town Council.
- Increased accessed to Family planning services for rural women through our partnership with UHMG and Marie Stopes.
- With over 30 Village Volunteers, JOYODI has created a referralsystem that tracks and reports GBV and other health cases from the rural communities of Panyango Sub County.
- Our work in combating GBV has securedfor us partnership with organizations such as MEMPROW (Mentoring and Empowerment Program for Young Women) and TASO (the Program Officer is a GBV Champion for Pakwach district).
2. INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE
The Vision: Informed, healthy and economically sustainable people in Jonam County.

Mission Statement: Is to empower the people of Jonam County to productively and sustainably engage in improving their own welfare.

Mission: What is the current purpose of the organisation?
To increase operational scale and deliver socio-economic services all over Pakwach district.
Institutional objectives: What are the principal changes the organisation seeks to achieve over the long term?
# Expand JOYODI#s coverage and improve access and utilization of reproductivehealth, HIV/AIDS, and Sanitation and Hygiene services and products.
# Improve the ability of youths and other vulnerable populations to engage in income generating activities.
# Reduce gender and other forms of inequality and injustices that hinderrealization of full potential of men and women.
# Contribute to the improvement of education quality and skills development among young men and women.
# Improve JOYODI#s management and administrative capacity to sustain service delivery in Jonam County.
Field(s) of activity: What are the principalthematic and geographic areas in which the organisation works?  Who are the social actors that benefit from the work?
Our major thematic areas include;
Health security
- Sexual Reproductive health
-  HIV/AIDS
-  Water, Sanitation and Hygiene
Socio-Economic development and livelihood
- Agri-business
- Entrepreneurship training and IGAs.
- Gender Equality &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Human Rights
JOYODI is mandatedto operate in the entire district of Pakwach, but currently worksin2 sub counties of Pakwach Town Council and Panyango Sub County in. We hope with more partnerships and projects we will cover the entire district eventually.

4. STRATEGIC POSITIONING
Analyse the environment in which the organisation works? Who are theother relevant social actors, including government and business, and what roles do they play? #In this context, what is unique about the position of the organisation?

# Local Governments, Religious and cultural leaders, education institutions, media and civil society organizations are our most important stakeholders. JOYODI is well known and familiar with the best approaches for enlisting the support and participation of these stakeholders in our interventions.
# As alocally based Organizationwith direct contact with community, JOYODI has a better understanding of relevant interventions that can improve people#s welfare.
# With 10 years of experience in tackling community challenges related to health and social matters, JOYODI is strategically equipped to deliver for communities of Pakwach district.
# JOYODI has clear implementation strategy which includes working with its trained Village Health Volunteers. This helps to create a community response structure and sustain interventions undertaken. This tested approach has delivered success in all our previous projects.
# JOYODI owns a modern office block, with office equipment and a conference hall. This is lacking in most rural NGOs.
# Experienced and well qualified staff run JOYODI#s programmes.Our success over the years has been partly attributed to good quality manpower and their commitment to work, learn and innovate.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>30.1861 31.47092</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-05">25000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-01">8142</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">JONAM YOUTH DEVELOPMENT INITIATIVE JOYODI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-01">8630</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">JONAM YOUTH DEVELOPMENT INITIATIVE JOYODI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-01">6978</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">JONAM YOUTH DEVELOPMENT INITIATIVE JOYODI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-01">1250</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">JONAM YOUTH DEVELOPMENT INITIATIVE JOYODI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-01">8142</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-01">8630</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-01">6978</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-01">1250</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05255-14:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000141" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000923"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007881"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05255"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Voice Empowerment grants Uganda"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rightsholders (individuals and groups) are willing and able to work on their own empowerment.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># change agendas developed by rightsholder groups based on the facilitation of programme staff and partner organisations</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.a" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.b</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># change agendas implemented by rightsholder groups based on the support of programme staff and partner organisations</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.b" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.c</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># grantees incorporating new approaches in realising their change agendas</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.c" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rightsholders (individuals and groups) are willing and able to work on their own empowerment.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># rightsholder groups indicating to have safe spaces to convene and work</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># rightsholder groups presenting their collective demands to external stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.3</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% rightsholder groups indicating increased confidence to raise their voice</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.3" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
