<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06455-02:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FURA:Flood disaster response in Kasese</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will reach out to a total 15,000 individuals in Kasese district, the worst affected area with the current floods.,  Focus will be on provision of life saving essential WASH interventions including construction of emergency latrines and bathing shelters, distribution of essential WASH NFIs (containers for water collection and distribution, household water treatment chemicals, soap etc), Rehabilitation of damaged water systems (handpumps springs etc) Hygiene Promotion using both contact and non-contact based approaches. Oxfam will implement the response in partnership with FURA, a local Oxfam partner within the region with operations and establishments in Kasese. FURA has good knowledge of the geography, social and cultural set up of the area and previously worked with Oxfam on the Ebola Preparedness and response interventions in Kasese. FURA will implement software activities such as distribution ofWASH NFIs, community engagement and risk communication community sensitization through all available mechanisms. Oxfam will provideoverall technical back stopping and implementation of major technical infrastructural activities in collaboration with district line departments and FURA

Rehabilitation of broken-down bore holes, damaged pipe lines and protected springs within the affected areas. At least 7 bore holes, and 2 protected springs will be rehabilitated in the Kasese district to restore back safe water supply to these affected villages. The rehabilitation will include well redevelopment, replacement of worn out parts, reconstruction of embankment walls for the protected springs and disinfection for rehabilitated systems

Distribution of Household Water treatment tablets: At least 15 boxes of water treatment tablets will be distributed to the affected population in Kasese districts. This will support water quality improvement in areas relying on contaminated water sources thus avoid possible outbreak of water borne diseases including cholera. Oxfam and partner will work with Village Health Teams (VHTs) to facilitate demonstrations on appropriate use and water quality monitoring. This will be a short-term measure and will be stopped immediately rehabilitation of damaged water sources is complete.

Procurement and distribution of household hygiene kits such as water collection and storage containers as well as soap will bedistributed to affected households targeting at least 750 households. The WASH NFIs will include 750 Jerry cans of 20 litres, 750 drinking water buckets, and 100 cartoons of soap. This will support strengthening safe water chain management at household level as well as well us practice of handwashing with soap particularly in this period of COVID 19.

Water quality monitoring for both bacteriological and FRC will be undertaken at all water sources with the affected areas. The project will support the district water departments to strengthen water quality monitoring to ensure that affected communities are accessing safe water.

Construction of communallatrines and bath shelters at evacuation centres, 20 gender segregated communal latrines and bathe shelters will be constructed at evacuation centres and hand washing facilities installed in areas where they do not exist, this will be accompanied by hygiene promotion activities. This will enhance good hygiene and sanitation practices to avoid disease outbreak at evacuation centres. Latrine cleaning tools and detergents will be procured and distributed to all evacuation centres where communal latrines have been set up, communities will be mobilized to ensure continued cleaning of latrines and refilling of hand washing facilities on rotation basis for easy operation and maintenance of the facilities.

Procurement and distribution of waste mobile bins at evacuation centres. At least 10 waste mobile bins for solid waste collection and transportation to rubbish pits will be procured and distributed to evacuation centres. This will help address the challenges of vermin as well as enhance vector control and avoid diseases at the centres.

Community dialogues with the affected people will be conducted, this will enhance community participation and ensure two-way communication between the partners and affected communities across the 3 affected districts. At least 2 meetings will be conducted amongst the affected communities in Kasese District.

Reproduction and dissemination of IEC materials on hygiene and sanitation promotion, as well COVID 19 prevention measures. Billboards, PVC burners and flyers depicting key messages will be produced, installed and distributed in strategic locations at community level.

Post distribution monitoring, the project will also conduct post distribution monitoringexercises for WASH NFIs distributed. Joint monitoring exercise will be done to enhance quality implementation of the project</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FOUNDATION FOR URBAN RURAL ADVANCEM</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for urban and rural advancement is a registered, indigenous non-profit humanitarian service and development organizationfounded in 1993 to provide service to the urban and rural poor communities of Kasese and beyond. In pursuit of her vision-a #community of health, informed and harmonious persons meeting their basic needs with ease,# FURA Uganda has over the last 19years become one of the most leading organizations in livelihoods in rwenzori region. to date, in bid to address the problem of urban and rural poverty, food security, poor service delivery by government and ensure improved livelihoods food security, citizen engagement and social accountability and building communities resilience to disasters, FURA operates at community, regional and national levels.   FURA IS registered as an NGO number 1233 and as accompany limited by guarantee without share capital in the ministry of justice and constitutional affairs registration number 69927. The primary constituency of FURA#S work is the rural and urban poor, especially the most disadvantaged communities affected by conflicts and other humanitarian crisis.FURA intervenes in awide range of disaster Prepared and management, livelihoods, governance,  advocacy and community empowerment issues such as savings and loans associations, citizen engagement and social accountability, school gardening and parent led gardens, NAADS monitoring, disaster risk reduction and advocacy for the elderly.
FURA#S activities and programmatic competencies are organized around four thematic areas of
# Sustainable livelihoods
# Disaster preparedness and management
# Advocacy and human rights
# Research, consultancy and information management.
FURA Over the years has undertaken and delivered capacity building, advocacy and alliance building, direct action on poverty, research, learning and publications in response to the extreme poverty and suffering among communities. The vast experience generated through these interventions accounts for FURA#S competences in livelihoods work which include  Improving access to reliable savings and credit management system, equip clients with business skills, adopting a user friendly M&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;E system for SPM and VA model, Enhancing resilience of poor women and men agricultural producersin vulnerable communities  to disaster risks and climate variations, improving access of producer groups to NAADS services  in Kasese district, enabling increase in food security through increased productivity andincomes at household level,  improving the quality of education at primary school level through effective participation of parents in school activities, acting as learning centre for good agronomic practices that  increases adoption of good agricultural practicesand innovations in communities and Process documentation, Contributing to an enabling environment for government accountability in Kasese district that fosters active participation of citizens and enhances access of poor communities to government services.
FURA Uganda has its headquarters located in Kilembe quarters, Kasese municipal council, through which sub county and district level activities are conducted. FURA works in all the 28 sub counties of Kasese district, 4town councils and in the municipality. In addition tothis, FURA also extends services to the districts of Bundibugyo and Ntoroko. Also in emergencies, FURA goes beyond Rwenzori region and covers all parts of the country in response to emergencies.  Currently FURA responds to EBOLA outbreak.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.17249 30.08587</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-24">25774</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-01">25774</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib CAT fund</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FOUNDATION FOR URBAN RURAL ADVANCEM</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-07-01">25774</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FOUNDATION FOR URBAN RURAL ADVANCEM</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-01">-25774</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FOUNDATION FOR URBAN RURAL ADVANCEM</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-07-01">25774</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-01">-25774</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-01">25774</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06455-02:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000101" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06455"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Flood disaster response in Kasese"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-06-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1286"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1590"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="7200"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-06-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="2065"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2384"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="7800"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-06-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1590"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="7600"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="7200"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-06-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2384"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="8400"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="7800"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
