<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05823-09:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEEU Livelihoods project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Economic Empowerment Uganda in a consortium with Initiative for Rural Empowerment and TRINOL  Seminars International Limited will be implementing the project: The Refugee and host community integrated Emergency food security and vulnerability livelihoods project in Yumbe district.  The consortium will be engaged in the following activities:

1.1 Activities
- Project launch (Community awareness and mobilization of stakeholders)
- Beneficiary selection and verification
- sensitization of beneficiaries on unconditional cash transfers
1.2. Activities
- Formation and strengthening of Self-Help groups for Savings (VSLA) (10 groups of 250 beneficiaries).
- Training ToTs in financial literacy and entrepreneurship to be extended to 5 people in a group of 10 members
- Cash for Work initiatives (cash given to those who are active and evaluated groups or individuals).
2.1.  Activities
- Organize farmer groups (10 groups of 25 members each) composed of household representatives who will be
   given relevant inputs jointly to participate in agricultural production.
- Agriculture input support - seeds &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; tools
- Provision of high nutritive and yielding fruit seedlings(10 groups of 25 members each)
- Agriculture extension service support for kitchen gardens (16 days / 6 months)
- Training on raising and planting fruit seedlings.

2.2. Activities
- Conduct host and refugee exchange learning visits
- Conduct host and refugee community dialogue meetings

3.1.Activities
- ToT Training in financial literacy and entrepreneurship (to be extended to 5 people in a group of 10)
- Conduct quarterly stakeholders review meetings.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CENTRE 4 ECONOMIC EMPOWERMENT UGAND CEEU</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Economic Empowerment # Uganda (CEEU) is a NNGO founded in 2003 by three volunteers based in North Western Region of Uganda (West Nile) with its headquarters in Yumbe District. The organizations membership consists of twenty (20) members of whom eight (12) are female and twelve (08) males. It is a Local Non-Government Organisation (NGO) working in partnership with all grass root communities, Local Governments, National and International NGOs. CEEU works with disadvantaged communities to pursue her goals and objectives of improving capacities for improved household food security, women rights, clean water and Sanitation, education, healthy lifestyle and promoting good governance for increased access to socio-economic services for effective and sustainable poverty eradication. Centre for Economic Empowerment - Uganda was formerly called Needy kids # Uganda, a Civil Society Organization Registered with Yumbe District Local Government department of Community Services. It was formed in 2003 after 17years from when the Ugandans returned from exile (from Sudan and Democratic Republic of Congo) with the overall goal of socio-economic development amongst the disadvantaged communities of West Nile Region who returned back from exile.

1. RESOLUTION AND JUSTIFICATION FOR THE CHANGE OF NAME
In view to expand on her thematic areas, the board of Needy Kids # Uganda resolved to change its name to Centre for Economic Empowerment # Uganda (CEEU) to cover environmental conservation, gender and economic empowerment, health, education, and governance and human rightsissues. The new name has given the organization a better positioning in delivering her services to achieve an empowered community for sustainable household development through strengthening the capacity of women, children and youth to demand and access improved socio-economic services in the country. The new name took effect in the year 2017 since it was already reserved with the registrar ofCompanies and subsequently registered as an NGO with the Ministry of Internal Affairs under S5914/12676 on 16th Aug, 2016.
ACHIEVEMENTS
What have been the principal results in the past three years that contribute to significant, structural, sustained and positiveimprovement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?
Centre for Economic Empowerment Uganda has been implementing interventions in West Nile region under the emergency response for South Sudanese refugees since 2007. CEEU has registered big achievements through its interventions with funding from reputable organisations in the West Nile region of Uganda.
As an achievement CEEU implemented the Integrated Environmental Conservation (IEC) with funding from Oxfam GB Yumbe District Environment Department. Through this project we sensitized Communities on Environmental conservation, trained Environmental protection volunteers, established woodlots and tree planting in communities and refugee settlement areas in Yumbe district.
With fundingfrom Aga Khan Foundation, CEEU has Supported 50 District Primary Schools, Strengthened the capacity of School Management Committees, mentored School Management Committee on Gender and documentation of best practices for replication of similar interventions to other Primary Schools in the region. The initiative has kept the girl child in school thus preventing them from abuse.
Weimplemented the HIV/AIDS Prevention (HAP) project for OVCs with technical support from Aids Integrated Model (AIM) with funding from USAID. Through this intervention CEEU Supported 160 orphans, trained 42 counsellors, formed 4 women groups and provided PMTCT services to 120 households in Yumbe District.
Under the Uganda Malaria Consortium funded by Minnesota International, CEEUdistributed 342long lasting insecticide treated nets in Health facilities to pregnant mothers and sensitized communities in 6 selected market places on HIV/AIDS in Yumbe District, and Trained 132 Community Medical Distributors/ VHTS.
SNV supported CEEUin 2015 and as an achievement we carried out building capacity of School Management Committees, Community Empowerment Project, Sustainable sanitation and Hygiene for all (SSH4A), Built capacity of School management committees in 50 schools, Promoted safewater and sanitation in 3 Sub Counties and 12 Schools in Arua District, trained community leader and women groups on legal issues on sanitation and constructed latrinesto community member without latrines.
CEEU#s efforts were recognized by major donorsand stakeholders thus opening doors for the organization to join major forums such as the national NGO forum, Yumbe District NGO forum, National NGO Bureau ministry of internal affairs through renew of our operating permit, certified by QUAM, recognized by DENIVA and registered by URSB as a company limited by guarantee.
CEEU has managed to consolidate its existence in the district through creating good relations with district  leadership and other humanitarian actors.

INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE
Mission:
Strengthen the capacity of women, children and youth to demand and access improved socio-economic services
Institutional objectives:
1. To advocate and promote rights and responsibilities of children, women and youth in Uganda.
2. To promote effectiveparticipation of women, children and youth in government programmes such as health,education, agriculture, water and sanitation, and environment.
3. To enhance income levels of women, children and youth by providing effective services for improved livelihood.
4. To promote openness, transparency and accountability in all spheres of life.
5. purposes of undertaking the implementation, supervision, monitoring and evaluation of projects/programs that have a bearing on people#shuman rights, good governance and democracy.
What are the principal thematic Field(s) of activity:
Health
1. Mainstreaming the project into organizations programme this will scale up the HIV/AIDS/TB awareness impact in the community for sustainability process.
2.Networking with government and other partners in order to enhance the capacity of communities to demand for more services to reducethe prevalence of HIV/AID/TB among the youth, women and ex-combatants and Business community.
3. To work in partnership with HIV/AIDS clinics, post-test clubs, health facilities, HIV/AIDS networks, women groups, youth groups, cultural groups, religious institutions and privates sector.
4. Working with other donors, Agencies, capacity building organizations and communities.
5. Develop highly illustrated and translated to materials to schools and communities about ABC and IEC
6. Establishment of anti-AIDS peer support clubs
7. Organize training for anti-AIDS peer groups for capacity building
8. Training of councillor Aids at Zonal level
9. Identify teachers both ECD and train them at school level to provide guidance and counselling.
10. Organize training for prevention of HIV/AIDS/TB for Youths out of schools and hard reach areas.
11. Support school based sexual transmitted illnessprevention initiatives
12. Organize couple to couple counselling
13. Organize dialogue for Husband and wives# groups on HIV/AIDS/TB
14. Organize drama shows for highly risked groups on dangers of HIV/AIDS/TB in 4 Zones in Bidibidi camps
15. Orientation workshop for stakeholders on HIV/AIDSTB
16. Disseminate key message on HIV/AIDS counselling and testing through masses, media charts and strips
17. Training communities of owned resource as counsellor Aides
18. Support to home-based HIV/AIDS counselling and testing
19. Organize youths# friends# services on HCT for adolescents both in schools and out of school
20. Mobilize pregnant women to test for HIV/AIDS/TB
21. Community Education program to promote individual on PMTCT /Condom at family level
22. Training of traditional health practitioners on PMTCT
23. Community mobilization/sensitization to address GBV on PMTCT
24. Support to innovative dialogue aimed at increasing male involvement in PMTCT
25. Organize home visits, home and community counselling
26. Train and support community counsellors to offer psychosocial support
27. Community campaign to improve knowledge, attitude related to care and support and reduce stigma against people living positively with HIV/AIDS
Education
1. CEEU tocontinue support the Lead Civil Society Organisations (LCSOs) to help all the 50 AKF supported primary school in Yumbe District to develop the authentic SDPs subject for fundraising for primary schools.
2. Involvement of lower local Governments, District, LCSOs, SMCs/PTAs, FBO, Elders to continue to oversee the 50 AKF supported schools in Yumbe District
3. Lead CSOs will work closely with stakeholders of all the 50 primary schools in Yumbe District to organize fundraising for primary schools at all levels e.g. MPs, Local leaders, civil servants, CBOs, FBOs, private sector, and existing opportunities# such Mentors and mentees working in the project schools
    Environment
1. Advocate for agroforestry
2. Climate change mitigation and awareness creation
3. Promotion of energy efficient technologies
4. Promotion of afforestation and reforestation
5. Educate communities on the use of lorena stoves
Governance
1. Community monitoring: This is carried out by the community monitors in two thematic areasof health and Education. They will monitor using pre designed tools which has specific areas to monitor at a facility level. The monitoring tools will then be collected at CEEU office on monthly basis in order to compile the issues for engaging with the leaders starting at the facility level to the district level. Specific attention will be paid to recruit women and youth monitors.
2. Radio drama: This will be acted and recorded and played on local FM stations in order to sensitize the citizens on service delivery issues.
3. Forum theatre performances: Youth groups will be contracted to perform music, dance and drama on selected thematic areas and topics in order to sensitize and educate the population on their rights and roles in service delivery and governance as a whole. Forum theatre will also be used to provoke the citizens on their right to health and education and the role and duties they play in realizing these rights.
4. Radio talk shows: This will be implemented quarterly for health and education. The radio talk show topics will be derived from the issues arising from the communities through the monitoring process and also dialogues from the community to the district. In these talk shows, there will be space for the citizens to call in and discuss with their leaders.
5. Neighbourhood assemblies: These are sub county level dialogues which will be conducted at the local levels to provide a plat form for the citizens to interface with the local government leaders at the sub county level. Here,the sub county will also disseminate their development plans to the citizens. This will make the citizens active in planning their development within the sub county.
6. Districts face the citizens: This will be a dialogue platform at the district level where the citizens will have a chance to make their input into the district development plans and also be able to discuss various other service delivery related issues with the district leaders both elected and technical
7. Organize media public debates through local radio stations. The public will be made to report issues affecting them in service delivery in pre-planned radio programs to report what is happening in health, education and service delivery in general.
8. Embracing sector working groups in district and lower local councils. Needy Kids # Uganda intends to work through youth, women, people with disabilities and other vulnerable groups and councils for sustainability.
9. Local revenue enhancement committees will be created comprising civil servants, CSOs, religious leaders, business communities, market venders, taxi operators and politicians both at Sub-counties and district levels
# Geographic areas in which the organisation works?
The organization works in west Nile region and particularly in Yumbe district in 14 sub counties 5 zones of bidibidi refugee settlement, and Arua District in 17 sub counties including Omugo imvepi and Rhino camp refugee settlement areas.
Who are the social actors that benefit from the work?
The social actorswho benefit from our work are Local Governments department of community services, Community based organizations, women advocate and lobbying associations, HIV/AIDS support networks, south Sudanese and Dr Congo women refugee activists, refugee disability youth and network, women groups, Farmers associations, Youth Groups, Village savings and loans associations/groups
STRATEGIC POSITIONING
a) Analyse the environment in which the organisation works
Centre for Economic Empowerment # Uganda (CEEU) has its operational mandate towork in Yumbe district West Nile Region of Uganda. Yumbe district is situated in the extreme West Nile region of Uganda bordering the Republic of South Sudan in the North. The district is now the new gateway for refugees and asylum seekers from South Sudan who are running way for renewed fighting in their country. CEEU Works amidst international NGOs, inter regional actors, regional actors, sub conentental region NGOs, National NGOs, district forums, network/community Based organizations and private sector and Farmer associations. The target project area is situated in remote location of Bidibidi Zones 3, 4 and 5. The road network to those locations are impassable during rainy seasons. Host communities are hospitable and accommodative.
Who are the other relevant social actors, including government and business?
The other relevant social actors in the region are civil society organizations, private sector foundations, international NGOs, local Governments, Faith based organisations, national and international Bodies.
 What roles do they play?
These actors play varied roles in our area of operation. The local governments regulate operationalization of other actors in thedistrict and in the region at large. The roles played by other humanitarian actors is to mobilise resources so as to support the affected communities so as to achieve their aims, goals and objectives. They participate in advisory &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; decision-making processesand ensure quality programme implementation in the region.
 #In this context, what is unique about the position of the organisation?
The very unique aspect of the organization is being a local organization and it#s at the grass root, sub counties, zones and Districts these gives us a very unique advantage to respond to emergencies fast. Centre for Economic Empowerment Uganda implemented interventions in West Nile under the emergency response for South Sudanese refugees since 2016 which gives us a unique positioning in thedistrict. CEEU#s expertise is in Agriculture, WASH, Education, Livelihoods, business development and mentorship, life skills training, environmental protection and management in the region is an added advantage. The organization actively collaborates with the District local government and NGOs. CEEU is a member of the Yumbe NGO Forum and a number of NGO working groups in the district.
The local experiences, language, culture, social aspects, environmental issues these than position her in to understanding Ngo operational environment, community, operational aspects, refugee culture and working with local governments, sub counties and zones at the campshost community
The other unique aspect of the organization is to integrate working with private sector, farmers associations, NGO forums NGOnetworks, political environment, social aspect like women groups, youth groups, PSN groups, children people with disability, blind, and refugees.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>3.45655 31.24931</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-06">24889</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-01">1392</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CRA Programme Expenditures Country Offic</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CENTRE 4 ECONOMIC EMPOWERMENT UGAND CEEU</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-01">24889</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CENTRE 4 ECONOMIC EMPOWERMENT UGAND CEEU</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-01">-1392</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CENTRE 4 ECONOMIC EMPOWERMENT UGAND CEEU</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-01">24889</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-01">-1392</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-01">1392</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05823-09:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001704"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05823"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="ELNHA Phase II"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-10-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="114"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="114"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="500"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-10-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="174"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="288"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="500"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-10-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="220"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="274"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="500"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-10-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="280"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="359"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="500"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
