<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05410-02:IN</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CP - OIN Promoting Civil Society  India</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through this project, Oxfam Novib supports Oxfam India to contribute to an enabling environment for and participation of civil society and other stakeholders in the implementation of the 2030 agenda for social development in India. Civil society organizations have a crucial role to play in advancing a people driven and owned sustainable development agenda and to represent the poor and most marginalized members of society.

To allow civil society to play this pivotal role, Oxfam India identified the need to promote and widen the legal and social spaces for civil society participation. This entails developing and amplifying positive narratives on the contributions of civil society as well as creating local spaces for citizen participation and encouragingyouth participation and leadership within these spaces. To do this, the project follows a four-pronged strategy:

1. The project aims to promote a positive public discourse on the integral role of civil society in the relationship between citizens and effective states. Oxfam India works together with the National Foundation for India (NFI), a non-profit charitable trust that mobilizes public opinion and generates resources for supporting development action. The project entails capacity building of mediaprofessionals to effectively document issues around social inclusion and the role of civil society in addressing these issues. Furthermore, Oxfam India will highlight the positive contributions of civil society to India#s social and economic developmentthrough multiple media channels, including photo and video documentations, articles in newspapers and online blogs, and a book.
2. Recognizing the vital importance of youth participation and active citizenship to maintain civic space now and in the future, Oxfam India aims to support informal youth groups that are organic,relevant to the ground and committed to social change. On this objective Oxfam India works together with the Society for Rural Urban and Tribal Initiative (SRUTI), a not-for-profit organization that works towards social change at the grass roots across rural and urban India. The project will offer perspective building trainings for youth to practice active citizenship and leadership within their community and facilitate community participation in local governance.
3. Oxfam India will sensitize businesses on their role within rights-based development and encourage the private sector to move beyond their narrow corporate social responsibility engagementtowards using its leverage to maintain and widen civic space.
4. Oxfam India will actively engage with other civil society actors to ensure continuous building of a positive narrative on civic space and civil society and future programming to ensure engagement ofcivil society in India#ssocial development agenda.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2008, various Oxfams in India joined forces to form Oxfam India. Registered as an independent organisation, Oxfam India has indigenous staff and board members. We are a member of the global confederation of 20 Oxfams.

We focus on four poverty eliminating goals

1: Livelihood: More women and men will realise their right to secure and sustainable livelihoods.
2: Fight for women: More women will lead a violence-free life. This can be achieved through changes in attitudes and beliefs about gender relations and through encouraging women&apos;s engagement and assuming leadership in institutions and decision-making roles.
3: Education and Health: People living in poverty, especially women and, girls will realise their right to accessible and affordable healthcare, education, clean water and sanitation.
4: Human Rights: Those facing a humanitarian crisis will be assured the protection and the assistance they need, regardless of who they are, where they live or how they are affected.

We see poverty as a problem of power, the lack of power.&#x92; We workwith 60 NGOs at the grassroots&#x92; level to tackle poverty and inequality where it germinates. Our programmes are currently active in the critical states of Bihar, Chhattisgarh, Jharkhand, Odisha and Uttar Pradesh. We work with the most marginalised segments &#x96; Dalits, Tribals, Muslims, and Women. For them, poverty is more than lack of income, healthcare and education. It is a crippling state where these groups do not have any control in deciding the course of their own lives. They are excluded from basic decision-making rights.

Oxfam works primarily through grassroots organisations to bring deep-rooted sustainable changes in people&#x92;s lives. We do this through long-term development programming and link it to positive policy changes at various levels. We work for the socially excludedand most marginalised communities by mobilising them to campaign for greater economic and social reforms. We use our learnings about what works and what doesn&#x92;t at the grassroots level, through research and advocacy, to bring about pro-poor changes in policies and institutions.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam India</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-06">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-06">-1086</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-08-01">80000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Discretionary Funds Southern Affiliates</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam India</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-01">18914</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Discretionary Funds Southern Affiliates</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam India</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-08-01">80000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-01">18914</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05410-02:IN">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007863"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05410"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Promoting Civil Society in India"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-07-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="3"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-07-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="3"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
