<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05739-02:KH</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Srer Khmer-Rice Seed Enterprise Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rice is the principal crop of farmers in Cambodia. Rice production accounts for 15 percent of agricultural value added and paddy occupies 75 percent of the cultivated land. Rice production, processing, and marketing are estimated to employ about 3 million people,or more than 20 percent of the country#s working-age population. Rice production as the main crop to sustain the livelihood of mostCambodian in rural area. This production output is dependent upon many inputs, of which rice seed is one of the most critical. Without available or accessible quality seed, many small-scale farmers are exposed to the potential of food insecurity and they depend on previous year successive rice seed saving for their future rice cultivation. Ministry of Agriculture Forestry and Fishery (MAFF) set-off its direction for 2018 to increase the total rice production to at least 9.44 million tons per year through boosting the purerice seed production and providing the extension work to farmer to produce this type of rice for better market. This project is created aiming to contribute this direction. It will work with 15 farmer seed producer groups (RSPG), at least 300 small-scale farmers,including 50% of women, to produce and market high-quality seeds, adapted to the needsof farmers.

The overall objective of the project is to enhance the livelihoods, income and rice seed security of small-scale farmers by improving their rice seed production andaccess to high-quality seeds adapted to farmers# needs and preferences. Specific project objectives include:
- Strengthen the capacity of seed producer groups targeted to improve affordability and access of appropriate rice seeds for small-scale farmers in their local communities
- Foster enabling conditions and partnerships with private sector for diffusion of rice seeds through farmer seed enterprises development

Oxfam in partnership with a local partner organization namely Srer Khmer (SK), have been working with a fewgroups of smallholder farmers, mostly women, that were trained on SRI and rice seed production. These groups called RSPG  produce the fragrant rice seed for selling in their community. The groups have the potential to become rice seed production enterprises. Therefore, the fund under this project will enable SK to enlarge its work with existing RSPGs and establish more new RSPGs in Pursat province to produce rice seed for their communities.

The direct beneficiaries of this project are 300 small-scale farmers, including 55% women, involved in RSPGs in thetargeted area as well as the partner staff from NGOs, Provincial Department of Agriculture Forestry and Fishery (PDAFF), Cambodia Agriculture Research and Development Institute (CARDI) of MAFF and the agri-business companies/entrepreneurs (seed buyers).

The indirect beneficiaries are the 1,200 household members of the groups and other small-scale farmers in the communities who will have access to good quality rice seed and increase their rice crop productivity. The project targeted 2 rural districts inPursat province: Kandieng and Krakor district. These districts have the highest poverty rate in the country (over 28%)and most of smallholder#s household livelihoods highly depend on rice production. Other actors in agricultural sector may also benefitfrom this project include local traders, rice millers, exporters in Pursat province and relevant policy makers. Local traders, rice millers and exporters will be connected in the form of contract farming with RSPGs for supplying rice seed. In addition, theproject works in close collaboration with General Directorate of Agriculture (GDA) of MAFF for rice seed productions by linking and encouraging small-scale farmers to seek support from public and private sector to enhance their capacity in soil fertility, water, pest, and disease management, minimize risk and increase market opportunities.

The project#s results also contribute strongly to the outcomes of the Resilience Program in Oxfam Country Strategy (OCS) 2015 # 2020 in Cambodia. The project willalsocreate synergies with and add value to Oxfam#s on-going project investments, namely the Women#s Economic Empowerment in Agriculture (WEEA) project, which isbeing implemented by SK in Pursat province. The project will select the potential farmers from WEEin Agriculture project to supportgood quality of rice seed and establish as rice seed producer groups. The existing rice seed producer group of WEE in Ag project can exchange their learning and sharing good experiences in both technical and groupmanagement from successful RSPG of this project. The project staff will work together as team to regularly attend in the monthly/quarterly meeting with WEE in Agriculture project staff meeting for updating, partnering, sharing and cooperating. Furthermore,WEEinAgriculture project will continue to support RSPGs after the SEED project finished.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-23-7069110" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Background and Capability of Srer Khmer
Srer Khmer means Field of Cambodia, a local NGO dedicated to the support of sustainable socio-economic development through research, training, education and community development by promoting participatory learning, farmer-led activities, farmers networking, sustainable agriculture, and natural resources management.
VISION
Farming communities and community development workers must have the capacity, rights and ownership in making decision on any issues that are relevant to sustain their living.

MISSION
Srer Khmer, in recognition of farmers&apos; rights and community development workers to learn, use and manage theirown community resources and participate in any decision related to their livelihood, is committed to providing farmers opportunities to gain knowledge and strengthen their capacity to lead and manage their lives through participatory learning approaches which build on understanding the fundamental relationship between agriculture, environment and rural societies.

GOAL
Farmers and community development workers having increased control of their lives based on a mastery of ecological and social knowledge and skill.
To achieve this mission and goal, Srer Khmer works in close cooperation with relevantfarmers groups, government institutions and other NGOs based on the values of honesty, equity, positive encouragement, gender equity and responsibility. Specially, Srer Khmer works with Farmer Trainers as main partners in developing broad farmer-to-farmertraining activities in the areas of ecological agriculture and livelihood related issues. Farmer Trainers have played an important role in organizing farmer meetings and follow-up training activities. Key government district IPM trainers have been contacted to support these activities as a technical advisor to Farmer Trainers.

Establishment, Legal Status and Award
Srer Khmer was established and registered with the Ministry of Interior of the Royal Government of Cambodia and the local authorities on January 9, 2002 by a group of former staff of FAO Community IPM Program. The FAO project started in Cambodia in 1996 and ended in late 2001, therefore, to continue the activity of community based integrated pest management (IPM) Farmer Field Schools, a proven approach to successful ecological learning and farmer networking, Srer Khmer was the response to the need to further build on the work of FAO and facilitate the work of farmers-led activities.

Srer Khmer is certified by NGO Code Compliance Committeeof NGO Good Practice Project (NGO GPP) to award the NGO good practices project certificate. This award meant that NGO GPP recognizes and appreciates Srer Khmer&apos;s efforts in complying with all standards and being role model NGO in Cambodia. To learn moregoto www.ccc-cambodia.org.

Organizational Structure and Management
The basic elements of Srer Khmer&apos;s organizational structure and the management are as follows:
- A Board of Directors which oversees and sets policy including Srer Khmer Statutes, Personnel Policy, Financial Policy for the organization, meets every four months to monitor Srer Khmer#s activities and give feedback to the Executive Director who is responsible to the Board. The current Board has seven members and have 3 times meeting per year. However, the extraordinary meetings can call from any members if necessary take action on urgent matters should the need arise.

- The Executive Director is responsibility for all day-to-day activities, programs, projects and staff.

- The Management Committee consists of the Executive Director, Programme Manager and the Admin/Finance Manager has the role of coordinating and assisting the Executive Director with day-to-day activities.

- The Technical Coordination Committee (TCC) consisted of Executive Director, Programme Manager, Programme Officers, Project Managers and Admin/Finance Unit. TCC has the role of providing inputs on technical issues. TCC has at least 2 times meeting per year to set technical guideline for Srer Khmer.

Staffing
At the moment, Srer Khmer has more than 50 full time staff members including technical staff, support staff and graduate (intern) trainees. Most of them were based in the project based in the provinces. Fifteen (15) of them are women. Srer Khmer also has1Volunteer from Australia Volunteers to assist withprogram/organization development. Srer Khmer used to have more than 10 Australian Volunteers from AVI, VIDA and AYAD to work with us from the past.

Apart from staff, we also have a network of well-trained farmer trainers at the provincial, district, commune, andvillage levels where we can call upon for providing training at their respective communities.

Program Thematic Areas (2011 # 2015):
1. Sustainable Agriculture and Land Resources Rights
2.Natural Resources Management and Livelihoods
3. Climate Changes Adaptation and DRR
4. Agri-Business and Value Chains
5. Training, Research and Consultancy to support small provincial NGOs.

Srer Khmer plays a role as Service Provider. Training on topics related to FFS/post-FFS, FLS, Socio-economic analysis, living soil, integrated homestead production, insect ecology, farmer association management, business planning, participatory marketing study, project management,participatory monitoring andevaluation, knowledge management, Training of Trainers, and other topics related ecological agricultureand community/rural development, etc., Participatory research and analysis and Project review and evaluation.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Srer Khmer</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.0661 103.5224</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to a sustainable livelihood</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="15" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-08">35402</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-01">35402</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Srer Khmer</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-01">-542</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Srer Khmer</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-01">35402</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="US-EIN-23-7069110" ref="US-EIN-23-7069110">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-01">-542</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="US-EIN-23-7069110" ref="US-EIN-23-7069110">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05739-02:KH">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000123" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001682"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007251"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Cambodia (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05739"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Rice Seed Enterprise Project"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1560</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to: # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to increase their seed, nutrition or food security.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1560-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1560-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="142"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="86"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="135"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1560-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1560-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="103"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="173"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="165"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1560</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to: # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to increase their seed, nutrition or food security.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1560-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to increase their seed, nutrition or food security.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1560-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="210"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="551"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="540"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1560-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to increase their seed, nutrition or food security.security.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1560-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-11-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="315"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="678"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="660"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
