<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-000143</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grow Campaign</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our Vision
GROW is a campaign for the billions of us who eat food and over a billion men and women who grow it, to ensure a future in which no one goes to bed hungry. We are changing the food system by campaigning with people around the world on 3 crucial battle grounds in the fight against hunger: unsustainable food production and consumption; climate change; and the threat to peoples# access to natural resources such as land rights violations.

Our approach
Our campaign is all about people claimingpower in the fight against hunger, whether that#s poor communities fighting for enough nutritious food to feed their families, or middle class consumers fighting for quality, choice and cost. Addressing inequality is key to claiming power # we will challenge elites and powerful vested interests that stand to gain by excluding small scale producers, by failing to act on climate change and by violating peoples# land rights. And we will put women#s rights front and center of all our campaigning.

We will do this by helping to build worldwide public movements (working with networks, allies, social movements, partners, progressive organizations and influential individuals) which promote sustainable consumption and enforce the role of consumers north and south as active agents of change.  We will also hold governments and private sector actors to account to ensure their actions respect the rights of women, food producers and vulnerable communities.

Our aims
Our overall aim is that people living in povertyclaim power in the way the world manages land, water and climate change, so that they can grow or buy enough food to eat # now and in the future. We campaign so that more governments, multilateral institutions and companies are implementing policies thatpromote sustainable food production and consumption, and are supporting those most vulnerable to climate change.

We are working towards 3 key objectives:
# We want to increase government funding for small scale food production and a greater proportion of private investment in agriculture focused on helping, not harming, small scale food producers.
# We want communities that are vulnerable to climate change to have greater access to adaption finance and other forms of support, and we want to furthercut carbon emissions.
# And finally, we want women and communities to protect and realize their rights to land.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl/Mission-and-vision">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-01-12"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
