<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05823-22:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARITAS Karamoja Alliance Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Just like in the previous year, CARITAS Kotido in this ELNHA  PHASE II  year two will act as the support partner in Karamoja coordinating the implementation of the joint action plans in Karamoja (for Kotido and Kaabong districts); on behalf of the Karamoja Humanitarian Alliance.  The Alliance has 24 member organisations with a steering committee comprising of 09 members who hold the responsibilities of making decisions on how the Humanitarian Action Fund (HAF) will be implemented together with the host support partner.

The following will be the activities the Alliance agreed upon to implement in the second year of the project in the second phase:
Result #1: Improved coordination and collaboration among LHA
# Mutual understanding and appreciation of the scope and benefits of each other#s work
# Ensure having information flows between actors;
# Strengthen partnerships we have amongst ourselves and with INGOs
# Collaborative ways of working.
# Encourage consortium in humanitarian preparedness and response
# Humanitarian actors should be working interdependently.(working together)
# Build collaborative behavior whether with or without funds.
# Complaints and Feedback handling mechanisms
Strategies.
1. Quarterly regional coordination meetings byalliance members.
2. Information sharing, Joint assessments and Early warning among actors.
3. Encourage consortium in humanitarian preparedness and response
4. Conduct joint Assessments, early warning.
Activities.
1. Conduct quarterly  Coordinationand Review meetings with the Alliance members
2. Conduct quarterly Coordination meetings with the HAF Committee and the sector Heads
3. Support the website updating and information uploading to the website
4. Support members to attend Cash working Groupmeetings, WASH and EFSL working group meetings within the region and at national level.
5. Formation of Consortia amongst the Local actors
6. Conduct Joint Assessments and support the process of early warning.

Result #2: Updated, resourced and activated District Contingency Plans in Karamoja
# Annually  updating and activation of contingency plans through active DDMCs
# Integration of contingency plans in District Planning process and budgets (incl. relevant departments)
# Policy influence at thedistrict and sub county level
# Establish pool of emergency preparedness funds through lobby and advocacy including the 5% commitment.
# Having a humanitarian preparedness and response strategic plan/ document.
# Strengthen the capacities of the lowerlocal governments on contingency planning and on response
Strategies
# Meetings
# Dialogues
# Peer to peer
# Support members attend Cash working group meetings.

Activities.
1. Organize Practical hands-on simulation exercise for the DDMCs (Kotido, Kaabongand Karenga) on data collection and reporting tools on disaster.
2. Follow-up meetings for district from the district budgets with the Councilors with reviews of the budgets submitted by the districts to ensure the implementation of the 5% commitment.
3. Support the mentorship and of the DEC and District Councillors on Disaster and gender responsive budgeting at district and Subcouty levels.
4. Dissemination of early warning information to inform community preparedness. (Radio programmes) in allthe districts Kotido, Kaabong and Karenga.
5. Support the process of hazard mapping and vulnerability risk assessment to inform updating of contingency plans for the districts of Kaabong, Kotido and Karenga and updating of the contingency plans.
6. Mentorship of the Karenga and sub county/division DDMCs on Contingency planning, roles and responsibilities and disaster inclusive planning.
7. Support quarterly Coordinationmeetings of the DDMC in the districts of Kotido, Kaabong and Karenga.
8. Support Quarterly Advocacy and influencing meetings in thedistricts of Kotido, Kaabong and Karenga
Result #3: LNHA mobilize resources # internal and external # to lead and deliver humanitarian preparedness and response.
# Local actors have resident capacityin each organization (staff) for resource mobilization
# Partnerships/ consortia are developed which complement their strengths, resources and capacities and reach scale.
# Local actors advocate for a Pooled fund for locally led humanitarian action (building on HRGF experience) which can be resourced by donors, and which complements available government funding.
# The EDs of the local and national humanitarian actors should commit some % of their administrative funds to alliance to run the secretariat.
#Having a pool of local experts in humanitarian response and preparedness.
Strategies.
# Trainings
# Meetings
# Peer to peer
# Joint proposals
# CTP modalities Designed
Activities
1. Strengthening the QUAM process through linking actors to theQUAMsecretariat.
2. Support the development of the fundraising/resource Mobilization strategy for the alliance for sustainability.
3. Refresher mentorship LNHA BODs on Financial management and good governance.
4. Support the process of mapping out the donorsof the different interventions.
5. Support development of proposals Using CTP modalities.
6. Training of LNHAs on Resource mobilization and practical proposal writing
7. Support the data collection of on the different humanitarian Issues in the region.


Result #4: Increased visibility and recognition of local humanitarian actors in Karamoja to donors, communities and government.
# Strengthen the process of documentation among the actors.
# Increasing publicity of LNHA in humanitarian work throughlead and funding organization.
# The alliance should be open to different categories of actors like private sector, politicians.
# Encourage local actors to conduct self-assessments and thereafter conduct an external organizational capacity assessment.
# Reach out for internal capacity learning within the local actors.
Strategies
# Sharing information through visibility materials, website, social media etc.
# Document shared achievements and successes stories
# Show casing the work of local actors
# Newsletters, website.

Activities.
1. Support information sharing through IEC materials for purposes of the Localization agenda, through newsletters, documentaries, brochures, booklets supplements on the works done by the local actors.
2.Documentation of the success stories and innovative approaches to be shared on the website for visibility and recognition of the work of actors.

Result #5: Local national humanitarian actors are trusted and accountable to communities and stakeholders.
# Efficient and effective utilization of available resources by LNHA for humanitarian action and response
# Delivery of timely responses to humanitarian disasters in accordance with humanitarian standards and principles
# Using community feed-back, (Peer) reviews and learning for continuous improving effectiveness of humanitarian interventions.
Strategies
# Meetings,
# Trainings, Assessments,
# Dialogues
# Consortium building
Activities.
1. Documentation ofthe innovation approaches on CTP implemented bythe LNHAs
2. Support the strengthening of the local structures (PDCs and the LCs) inthe planning process.
3. Support SDMCs to actively engage in the planning process and ensure their  participation in the DDMC coordination meetings in Karenga
4. Conduct feedback meetings to the community.
5. Document partnerships between LNHAs and INGOs
Result #6: Local humanitarian actors promote resilience of communities through all their intervention in vulnerable communities (humanitarian and development) andinfluencing.
# Potential Risk and Conflicts are monitored, analyzed and inform both humanitarian as well as development programs and interventions of local actors.
# Support communities in developing resilience assets, actions  and plans
# Local actors advocate both humanitarian and development actors engaged in Karamoja to support and fund programs promoting community resilience.
# Local actors able to use the CTP modalities in their response.
Strategies
# Resilience building initiatives in thecommunity.
# Integrate resilience, humanitarian and development interventions.
# Consortia building.
# Contingency plan development and updating.
Activities
1. Documentation of the innovation approaches on CTP implemented by the LNHAs
2. Support the strengthening of the local structures (PDCs and the LCs) in the planning process.
3. Support SDMCs to actively engage in the planning process and ensure their participation in the DDMC coordination meetings in Karenga
4.
7. Sustainability of the platformbeyond the project.
# The EDsof the local and national humanitarian actors should commit some % of their administrative funds to alliance to run the secretariat.
# Annual subscription for all members should be something which is a must together with membership fee which is paid once.
# The alliance should be open to different categories of actors like private sector, politicians#
# Encourage consortium in humanitarian preparedness and response.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARITAS</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Kotido is mandated with the task of assessing the needs of the people, designing and implementing developmental interventions with the aim of changing the lives in Kotido Catholic Diocese.  In the last two decades, Caritas Kotido has worked mainly in the areas of social economic development, particularly targeting poor farmers and pastoralists, women, and people living with HIV/AIDS, as well as orphans and vulnerable children.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>3.00713 34.11330</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-08">55015</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-08">-1384</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-07-01">41261</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARITAS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-01">13754</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARITAS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-01">-1384</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARITAS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-07-01">41261</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-01">13754</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-01">-1384</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05823-22:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001704"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05823"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="ELNHA Phase II"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5220</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs is increased that initiate, deliver and lead quality humanitarian response, and influence and advocate to hold governments and privated sector accountable.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5220-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs is increased that initiate, deliver and lead quality humanitarian response, and influence and advocate to hold governments and privated sector accountable.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5220-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-05-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="15"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="25"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="17"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5220</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs is increased that initiate, deliver and lead quality humanitarian response, and influence and advocate to hold governments and privated sector accountable.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5220-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5220-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-05-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="30"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="17"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
