<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05576-03:KH</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rachana-WEE in Agriculture</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RACHANA, are proposing the new project proposal on Women Economic Empowerment in Agriculture (WEE), this project contributes to address the key problems that have affected to the women who are living at rural areas; especially the women are in the targetareas. They are playing the important roles in family in the social agricultural and health sectors. As we knew that the poverty, especially the economic conditions in Takoe province continue to force many men to seek work overseas; then left behind the women engage more with the agricultural sectors. It curbs the need for migration in order to reduce household debt and increases productivity. The knowledge and skills of women required to do responses such roles from producing and processing produce, especially agriculture produce,to selling it at markets.

The aim of this project is to improve women#s economic position in agriculture value chains so that women enjoy a bigger share of the value they produce. In phase I (July 2018 # Jun 2019), by targeting the 45 villages of ten communes intwo rural districts of Takeo province, Treang and Koah Andet district, the project will work directly with 1,750 farmers (75% women) and benefit 7,000 people indirectly, including 4,200 women and 2,800 men.

The project#s overall objectives are: i). Participants of the project organized in formal and informal groups to develop business and leadership skills; ii). men and women farmers enhancethe quantity and quality of their products, obtain better prices, and reduce their exposure to risk; and iii). participant women#s collective better representation and voice influence positively private sector and government policies to create a more equitable economic environment. The 3 main expected result of the project forthree year implementation are: women smallholder farmers will have increased the quantity and quality of their products, obtained better prices, and reduced their exposure to risk; women participating in collective groups (formal or informal) will have increased their power and opportunities to compete and engage successfully in their local markets; and more women farmers are recognized and self- recognized as primary agents in family economic development.
The project will seek men#s participation and involvement to challenge gender imbalances. By the women will be involved to improve their capabilities applying roles in the social and agricultural economics, empower for the decision-making, control of asserts and participate in the social and politicalevents. The women and their families are living to adapting the climate change resilience and disaster risk reduction, increasing the agriculture production, promoting to access the Micro-finance institutes for capital investment; they are also encouraged to work in the collective approach for the value chain and to influence the market prices. It will support women collectives# access to key inputs, information and skills, and their capacity to influence positively private sector and government policiesand practices.

This project is expected to improve women#s economic position in agriculture value chains, during the project implementation, the 1750 small households farmers (80% are women) receive the long seasonal training on climate resilience agriculture technique based on identified potential commodities to be improved; GAP/SRP, post-harvest and soil fertility management, mulching, crop diversity, climate change; sustainable women-friendly homestead models sustainable women-friendly homestead models; women entrepreneurship; ability to develop and conduct business plan and smart agriculture plan. Moreover, they will receive the start-up inputs from the project and support in linking to the micro-finance institutes for access loan for their business investment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-23-7069110" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">#Rachana#, in Khmer means to be creative and artistic.  Rachana is a locally staffed and managed Cambodian NGO based in Koh Andeth District of Takeo Province.  Rachana was established and officially recognized as a Cambodian NGO on September 13, 1994.  It was formed in order to continue and expand the work of the US based Cambodian Humanitarian Foundation (CHF).

When Rachana took over the work of CHF on September 13, 1994, it formulated a two-year transitional plan to train local people to assume responsibilities for themanagement of the project. In July 1995, it set a child spacing community-based distribution (CBD) Component and Maternal and ChildHealth (MCH) program in October 1996.
Funding from PACT/JSI/USAID was ceased in April 1, 1997. However, the Maternal and Child Health program was able to continue through the support from Terre des Hommes, Netherlands. In 1998, the HIV/AIDS prevention project wasalso supported by the Khmer HIV/AIDS NGO Alliance (KHANA).
At the request of the Daunkeo Operational District Health Department, Rachana replicated its community based model and its experience in Sre Ronong, Prey Sloek, Khvao, Roneam, Thlork and Leay Bo Health Centers, Daunkeo Operational District, Takeo Province. The program had achieved significant results from its operations, meeting and exceeding project goals, objectives and targets.
Through the technical support from Canadian Center for International Studies and Cooperation (CECI) in Cambodia, In 2003, Rachana established two more programs on: Firstly- HIV/AIDS Prevention and Livelihoods for Women and Vulnerable Communities in rural area of Cambodia with the donation of L#oeuvre L&#xE9;ger in 5 communes of Treang district, Takeo provice, and Secondly- Community Participation in the Development of Health Center and Health and Nutrition Promotion with the donation of Canadian Cooperation Office (CCO) in Health and Nutrition Initiatives Fund to the three health cent# Rachana provided the facilitation to the communities through the participatory approaches that made the communities creating their own fundraising activities for supports the running health centers; HCMC, VHSGs and local authorities. Communities have understanding about the causes and effects of Diarrhea, worms, Typhoid fever, dengue Hemorrhagic fever diseases and accessed the health center services.
# Rachana promoted the eco-agricultural farming system SRI Model and Income generation activities by using different innovation techniques. These approaches helped poor farmers shiftedfrom the tradition cultivation to the SRI model. They have shared the lesson learned and experiences about the farming system and vegetable production to the neighbored families in the communities.
# The Community based organizations (CBOs) gained the empowerment, competencies and ownership. The approaches were applied to farmer-based association, social equity fund, rice bank, credit and saving groups. Those CBOs were functioning, clear structures, rules and policies and specified roles/responsibilities.  Community leaders were able to lead and managed the social and economic activities include; saving and credit loans, and animal banks, rice banks and health social funds.
Rachana is provincially located and has strong connection to local communities in Takeo, understanding the key needs, livelihood, environment, and development issues. Rachana team are dedicated professional technicians and project managers, skilled in natural resource and environment management, disaster management planning, and livelihood development. The team works closely with local authorities and forms strong relationships in the delivery of the projects, understanding the importance of seeking collaborative and sustainable solutions. The team is focused on inclusive participation, including poor women, men and youth in the four project areas of works as stated above.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RACHANA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-09" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-09" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to a sustainable livelihood</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="8" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-07-09"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-06">51341</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-01">25670</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">RACHANA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-01">25670</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">RACHANA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">-1721</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">RACHANA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-01">25670</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="US-EIN-23-7069110" ref="US-EIN-23-7069110">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-01">25670</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="US-EIN-23-7069110" ref="US-EIN-23-7069110">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">-1721</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="US-EIN-23-7069110" ref="US-EIN-23-7069110">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05576-03:KH">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000123" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001566"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007251"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Cambodia (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05576"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Women Economic Empowerment in Agricultur"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to  increase their productivity and/or income, or to strengthen their bargaining position, ensuring equal benefit to men and women.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-09" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="610"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="613"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-09"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="613"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-09" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1130"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1137"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-09"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1137"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to  increase their productivity and/or income, or to strengthen their bargaining position, ensuring equal benefit to men and women.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to  increase their productivity and/or income, or to strengthen their bargaining position, ensuring equal benefit to men and women.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-09" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="600"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="613"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-09"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="613"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to  increase their productivity and/or income, or to strengthen their bargaining position, ensuring equal benefit to men and women.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-09" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1100"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1120"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-09"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1137"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
