<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05328-08:VN</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IWTU living wage research</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Institute for Workers and Trade Union (IWTU) will conduct a research in 5 provinces including Hai Duong, Hai Phong, Thanh Hoa, Tien Giang, Dong Nai, aiming at providing evidence to Oxfam campaign for iconic brands to commit to paying living wages in the global garment supply chains and public awareness in Viet Nam and Australia to promote a living wage for garment workers.

the project time frame: Jan-Sep 2018

Objectives of the research
1. Examine status of wage determination in Australia sourced garment companies inVietnam (policies and practices) and obstacles to paying a living wage;
2. Examine status of wage related working conditions of workers working in Australia sourced garment companies in Vietnam.
3. Implication of actual wage to workers and their family (income vsliving expenses: food, medical care, WASH, electricity, child education etc. )
4. Provide recommendations based on research findings
Outcome
- A full and a summary report in English and Vietnamese sent to OXFAM with data collected. The report will be prepared in EEnglish (max 50 pages including annex, with executive summary) then translated into Vietnamese.
- A national seminar to disclose the report

Methodology:
The research should provide a clear picture of wage determination status (policy and practices) and wages related working conditions in the garment sector and its implication  of actual wage on workers#life, specifically:
- Comparison between actual wages workers received and various benchmarks
- Analysis of root causes of low wage from the below perspectives:
o Businessand supply chain practices.
o Dialogue, communication, and negotiation deficits
o Workers# rights deficits
o Obstacles to paying a living wage
- Identifying problems workers face due to low wage, especially the female workers in their life concerning health, work-life balance, housing, access to health care and education services, water and electricity, social life, so on.
- Recommendations based on the findings of the research

Literature review:
- a review of the wage system in Vietnam including the legislative framework, the MW system and the difference in wage fixing in different economic sectors
- a review of the wage fixing systems in the garment sector
- a review of the trends of wages paid to rank-and-file workers in the garment industry with special focus on the female workers# wages.
- A review of other working conditions in the garment sector including working hours, OSH, labour relations etc that influence wages.

Action research using quantitative and qualitative methods to achieve the objectives of the research. The IWTU willuse questionnaires to collect information for quantitative research and conduct individual interviews and group discussions for qualitative research. Observations methods will be applied.

Selection of sample:
6 factories can be chosen among the list to cover 4 wage regions and both North and South: 1 factory in Dong Nai (South) and and 1 factory in Hai Phong North for region 1, 1 factory in Tien Giang (South) for region 2, 2 factories in Hai Duong (for region 3) and 1 factory in Thanh Hoa for region 4. This could be revised later considering ratio of factories in the wage regions or brand sources.
Total of interviewees:
- 150 workers in quantitative survey (off-site)
- 60 workers in FGD (on-site)
- 12-18 worker in-depth interviews for case studies
- 24 enterprise union officials interviewed (on-site)
- 18 managers interviewed (on-site)
- 15 provincial union officials and 10 provincial labour administrators
- 02 officials from MOLISA: one from wage and industrial relations bureau and the other from the legal department
- 02 members of the National Wage Council: one from VCCI and the other from the VGCL
- 02 scholars researching wages and labour standards in the garmentsector</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Porticus Global Porticus Asia Limited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IWTU works as a think-tank of the VGCL. The IWTU was established in 1995 by the VGCL. At present, the IWTU has 15 permanent researchers and a contingent of about 70 regular research collaborators who are from other research institutes, research agencies and universities and cooperate with the IWTU to do the research on different topics. The IWTU has three departments: Scientific Research Department, Scientific Information &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Management Department and Personelle &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Administration Department.

The mainfunctionof the IWTU is to do research on workers and trade unionism and conduct capacity-building activities for enhancement and promotion of workers#rights and trade union rights through mass media, public campaign on law and policy-making, law enforcement and in order to advise the VGCL to claim workers# rights to the level of international labour standards. As a research institute, the IWTU also does research on all areas related to human rights for awareness campaigns so as to protect, promote and enforce human rights in the country.

Research areas of strength:
- The working class and workers# life in Vietnam and in the world
- The trade unions movement in Vietnam and in the world
- Economic, political, social and cultural rights of the workingpopulation
- Workers# rights at the workplace; trade union rights; social dialogue and collective bargaining.
- Employment and industrial relations, particularly the industrial relations problems at work, including grievances, complaints, collective work stoppages or strikes.
- International, regional and national tools for improving workers# life
- Other areas related to the socio-economic policies and other policies for the population in the country.

The IWTU does research on its own for the VGCL. The IWTU also does research through its cooperation with its informal network and the system of VGCL, 63 provincial federations of labour and 20 national industrial unions. The IWTU can reach workplaces through this network and system.

The IWTU alsodoes research and organize campaign to raise awareness to the public in general.

At present, the IWTU is focused on doing research and campaign on the following topics:
- International labour standards and its application in Vietnam
- Urgent and pressing issues of the working population
- Minimum wage, living wage and workers#s life
- Vietnam labour movement in the process of international integration
- Promoting social dialogue, collective bargaining and industrial relations
- Fighting the law-making of downward labour protection
- Free trade agreements and their impacts on Vietnamese workers
- Care for physical and metal life of the working population
- Labour rights and social rights of the people.
- Prediction of the future plight of theworking people of Vietnam in 10 or 20 years#time.
- Industry 4.0 and possible impacts on workers.

International andnational donors for the IWTU

At the moment:
- Rosa Luxembourg Stiftung assists the IWTU to promote social rights in Vietnam.
- Arepresentative from the IWTU has just participated in the Speaker Tour in Germany this year 2017 at the invitation of Rosa Luxemburg Stiftung to speak on the sitation of workers in Vietnam and possible impacts of Industry 4.0.

In the past:
- ILO usedtoassist the IWTU to conduct a seminar on mimum wage and experiences of Norway
- FES used to assist the IWTU on conduct a research on sub-contacted/sub-leased workers, working conditions in textile and garment sector and  situation of unemployed workers
- ILO is assisting the IWTU to do a research on unfair labour practices against trade union members and representatives and a leaflet on unfair labour practices are being produced for public awareness.
- Norwegean Trade Union Confederation (LO Norway)assists the IWTU to conduct a survey on minimum wage.


Plan for the coming time:

- Labour rights constitute human rights. The IWTU wishes to have a consultative status in ASEAN Intergovernmental Commission on Human Rights (AICHR) so as to have more opportunities to promote labour standards for the improvement of the working people#s life.
- The IWTU plans and hope to cooperate with national and international organizations and NGO to do research and organize campaign on living wage and enhancementof national labour standards to the level of international labour standards in the fields of freedom of association, collective bargaining, elimination of child labour, forced labour and gender-based discrimation at the workplace and in society at large and other topics to ensure a fair share for the workers in the economic development aimed at an inclusive and sustainable development.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam General Confederation of La</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-23">25475</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-03-01">15788</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Australia own funds OAU</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam General Confederation of La</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">3947</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Australia own funds OAU</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam General Confederation of La</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-04-01">5740</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Porticus Asia Limited</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam General Confederation of La</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-01">548</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Porticus Asia Limited</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam General Confederation of La</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-03-01">15788</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM Australia</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">3947</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM Australia</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-04-01">5740</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Porticus Global Porticus Asia Limited</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-01">548</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Porticus Global Porticus Asia Limited</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05328-08:VN">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001440;1001470"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007256"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Vietnam (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05328"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Social Protection for Migrant Workers"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2180</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects and programmes more effective: # cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories on civil society space and strengthening</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2180-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories on civil society space and strenghtening</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2180-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-01-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2180</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects and programmes more effective: # cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories on civil society space and strengthening</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2180-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">evidence products (track records, cases, evaluations etc.) produced that assess Oxfam Novib&#x2019;s programmes and projects effectiveness and quality</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2180-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-01-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
