<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05255-05:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARTNERS FOR COMMUNITY HEALTH-PACHEDO</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PACHEDO#s #Empowering  disadvantaged women to protect  their  rights  against exploitation  and sexual  violence and abuse  in Bungatira sub-county, Gulu district# project focuses at addressing the women rights abuses, violence and exploitation arising from the imbalance of power due to accessing productive resources such as land, water, finance and inequalities in the employment, these particularly include; single mothers who produced children outside marriage either in the camps or during abduction, widows, the elderly women, women with chronic illnesses like mental illness, HIV &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; AIDS, women with disabilities and  rural married women fully accustomed to cultural norms and practices.

The project intends to address such imbalance by empowering women and their protection structures with information about women rights (according to CEDAW), equip them with skills relevant for women to voice out and respond to various forms of abuses, exploitation and violence. The specific objectives will include:

1.To increase knowledge of 400 disadvantaged women and other community members about women rights to productive resources (land, finances and employment), available legal instruments and the role of the state and various stake holders in defending women against all forms of exploitation, abuse and violence   in Bungatira Sub-county .
2. To build the capacity of 16 Women Rights Advocacy Groups (WRAG) on life skills and trans-formative leadership to be able to provide peer to peer rights and policy awarenessand community engagements.
3. To empower 400 women with employable business and apprenticeship skills to engage in productive livelihood activities and fight against stigma and discrimination.
4. Facilitate the disadvantaged women with information, skills tailored to advocate and promote Behavioural Change and Communication and  support  for social economic empowerment for all rural women</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARTNERS 4 COMMUNITY HEALTH &amp; DEVEL PACHEDO</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partners for Community Health and Development Organisation(PACHEDO) is a Not for profit community Based Organization(CBO) that was started in 2007 by a team of volunteer community development workers that included social workers, agriculturalists, healthworkers, teachers, lawyers and Academicians. The organisation was established with aim of supporting communities live a dignified, healthy, and productive life, socio-economically empowered to innovatively meet and demand for their basic needs and rights, which served as the ultimate goal of the organization. Especially targeting  the vulnerable population of Gulu  comprised of: children, women and Youth exposed to violence and exclusion; Persons living with HIV &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; AIDS, Adolescents with reproductive health challenges, the mentally ill, youth, the older persons and persons with disability in conflict, post conflict and natural disaster affected communities.
Since then PACHEDO has been committed in providing services in areas of protection particularly covering transitional justice, GBVprevention and response, child protection, education. Community health targeting  Reproductive health and HIV &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; AIDS care andsupport, mental health and PSS, WASH and waste management and Nutrition and in Agriculture and sustainable livelihoods of Gulu.

Over time, PACHEDO has greatly made greater strides in areas of programme development, areas of coverage/operation, human resource development and expansion, finance and systems strengthening.  In programmes, there has been enormous improvement in the quality of generated projects and interventions modes and approaches of delivery such as the community support systems model in promoting all protection activities, other community participatory approaches such CMDRR (Community Managed Disaster Risk Reduction), SMART Agriculture etc. PACHEDO has also managed to recruit qualified personnel in all its programme areas with the lowest staff holding a diploma. In the areas of systems, PACHEDO has also put in place the HR Policy,Financial Policy, child protection, Gender policy among others. PACHEDO has got a qualified Board with a clear and standardised policy manual guideline and Directors signed contracts and playing their roles expected of them. Gender mainstreaming has taken centre stage in the organisation through 50, 50% policy in the recruitment. Women have taken leadership positions and given special considerations at the workplace. PACHEDO is also shifting from spread sheets to QuickBooks before the end of March and bylegality of registration shifting from CBO to NGO by the end of April.
2. ACHIEVEMENTS
What have been the principal results in the past three years that contribute to significant, structural, sustained and positive improvement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?

In the past three years(2015-2017) PACHEDO was able to build up partnerships with donor and technical partners that provided PACHEDO with financialand technical support to appropriately respond to the recovery challenges and human rights issues faced by the vulnerable people during and after the LRA conflict particularly the women, youth, children of all genders (Male and Female) in Gulu especially those women and girls  subjected to various forms of violence and abuse relating to access to their fundamental rights and entitlements suchas land, basic services etc and associated vulnerabilities.
For instance
# 2014-2016 PACHEDO entered into a partnership with VSO (Voluntary Services Overseas) with support from UKAID to provide life skills and psychosocial support to the vulnerable youth-informalstudents under Youth Development Programme. In this project PACHEDO was able to empower a total of 3,655 LRA conflict affected youth enrolled at all VSO Supported Vocational Institutions with basic conflict mediation and problem solving knowledge and skills including peace education and civic values. This enabled the Young People to peacefully adjust and adopt peaceful means of conflict management and promote peaceful co-existence within them, their families, and the entire communities.
# 2015-2016, PACHEDO entered in a partnership with Save the Children with support from USAID to scale up GREAT (Gender Roles, Equality and Transformation) innovations.A technical approach and tools that focused at building the capacity adolescent youth-girls and boys, women and community support structures such as the cultural institutions to be able to prevent issues of violence towards women and abuse of their rights. In this case the approach aimed at improving  Sexual and reproductive health reducing  gender based violence and promoting gender equality in Northern Uganda and strategically focused  at working with and ensuring that Boys and Girls aged 10-19 form equitable gender norms and adopt attitudes and behaviours which positively influence healthy  outcomes and reduced  gender-based violence. Save the Children/Straight talk foundation based in Gulu provided technical support to PACHEDO and a full package of training on CAC, toolkit, inward looking before outward the knowledge and skills that enabled PACHEDO to equip over 12,000 vulnerable children and women and other community members to defend the Sexual Reproductive Rights of such vulnerable persons in Gulu schools, Households and communities.
# 2015-2018, PACHEDO signed a contract with Private Sector Foundation with the funding from EU and later World Bank under ALREP and Skills Development Facility 2 was able to empower over 2300 war affected women and youth-small holder farmers (Male and Female) with livelihood skills particularly crop production, agro processing in different areas, entrepreneurial skills for self reliance, poverty reduction and employment creation.
# 2016-2018, PACHEDO joined NGO forum policy advocacy platform in Gulu where 8 PACHEDO staff were trained policy dialogue processes by National NGO forum. The partnership that has build PACHEDO#s capacity of programming, community engagements and right based work and advocacy with the vulnerable people like women and their related protection structures.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.77240 32.28807</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-04">24001</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-01">9080</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARTNERS 4 COMMUNITY HEALTH &amp; DEVEL PACHEDO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-10-01">7295</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARTNERS 4 COMMUNITY HEALTH &amp; DEVEL PACHEDO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-01">5225</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARTNERS 4 COMMUNITY HEALTH &amp; DEVEL PACHEDO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-01">2400</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARTNERS 4 COMMUNITY HEALTH &amp; DEVEL PACHEDO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-01">9080</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-10-01">7295</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-01">5225</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-01">2400</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05255-05:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000141" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000923"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007881"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05255"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Voice Empowerment grants Uganda"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rightsholders (individuals and groups) are willing and able to work on their own empowerment.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># change agendas developed by rightsholder groups based on the facilitation of programme staff and partner organisations</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.a" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-03-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.b</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># change agendas implemented by rightsholder groups based on the support of programme staff and partner organisations</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.b" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-03-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.c</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># grantees incorporating new approaches in realising their change agendas</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.c" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-03-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rightsholders (individuals and groups) are willing and able to work on their own empowerment.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># rightsholder groups indicating to have safe spaces to convene and work</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-03-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="15"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="5"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># rightsholder groups presenting their collective demands to external stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-03-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="15"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="5"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.3</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% rightsholder groups indicating increased confidence to raise their voice</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.1.3" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-03-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="10"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="5"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-03-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-03-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
