<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-04256-02:LA</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender-sensitive Environment Protection</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Lao People#s Democratic Republic (Lao PDR) has made impressive economic growth and poverty reduction over the last decade. However, the country still faces some exceptional challenges in reducing poverty and providing equitable development for its approximately 6.77 million citizens.  The challenges include: transforming the impressive economic growth into sustainable development; turningnatural capital into capital and market liberation for equitable growth and the development that is inclusive andequitable.
Lao PDRis building its development progress on the opportunities provided by its rich natural resources i.e. forests, fisheries, biodiversity, minerals and energy (in the form of coal, petroleum, gas and hydropower). However, it is also recognised that there are different development pathways as there is a view that the current resource-extractive model of economic development is unsustainable, and that risk-bearing and benefit-sharing is inequitable.
In term of Foreign Direct Investment, the energy sector in Laos, which dominated largely by hydropower, has received most of the investment amounting to US$5.082 billion from 2006 to 2011, followed by mining sector (US$2.598 billion), agriculture (US$ 1.847 billion), service industry (US$ 1.526 billion) and manufacturing (US$ 1.071 billion).
Mining  deals  represent  21%  of  all investment  projects  but an astonishing 50% of the total area  under  investment,  making it the largest subsector. Mining exploration projects cover vast expanses of land (1,026,873ha), almost equal to all other areas under concession or lease combined. Mining  is  the  largest  subsector  in  terms  of  both  area  and  number of projects (21% of allprojects, 50% of total area). It is estimated that the sector could give direct employment at about 20000 with indirect employment estimated as being between 30000 and 40000. So far, the sector has provided employment of 8000 workers, representing 0.28% of total work force in the economy. Women account for about 10% of the workforce due to limited knowledge and training in mining.
More local people especially women and children have been employed in artisanal mining. It is estimated that artisanal mining employs between 15,000 and 50,000 people with women making up approximately 75 percent of those involved. But it poses serious threats to the health of women and children who work in the artisanal mining.
Lao PDR has massive exploitable hydropower potential that can be sold to theregion that is looking to imported energy to power their economies. Currently there are 66 hydropower projects (of which nine are on the Mekong mainstream) under further study or construction and the Government of Laos expects three to four hydropower projects tobe developed each year until 2020.  However, the #use# of water through hydropower does unavoidably modify the nature of water resources and there are trade-offs. By changing natural flow regimes food security is affected and fisheries can be wiped out, the resultant loss of nutrients and changed sedimentation has a negative impact on the livelihoods of river dependent communities.
There are gendered impacts of water resources policies and decisions. Too often women are not actively consulted on the impacts of a proposed hydropower project and their views are not incorporated into the design and implementation by the developers. The hydropower privatesector developers need encouragement and guidance to incorporate meaningful gender impact assessments into projects in order to ensure that women and girls do not suffer disproportionate negative impacts and derive optimal benefits.
Despite the fact that women aswell as men consume, produce and use natural resources for their livelihoods, women have limited control and ownership over resources. Because men and women are likely to have different roles in the family, community, and work force, they are likely to have different personal priorities when it comes to environmental protection at the local and community level. Men and women are also likely to have different interactions with the environment, which present each gender with different opportunities to protect it. It is likely that men and women adopt different approaches and are the source of different types of knowledge regarding environmental protection. The roles and needs/interests of both men and women must be taken into account for effective programme design in initiatives forenvironmental sustainability
It is concluded that hearing women#s voice-practical and strategic interests is central to gender mainstreaming. Risk assessment needs to identify gender costs and potential benefits in order to be comprehensive. Better project planning, with design and economic and social management plans, is more likely to include men/women interests to reap tangible benefits and have a better chance of positive communication relation. The core finding of the project which was discussed across all the consultations and workshops in the country is to use existing processes for Economic and Social impact assessment and management to improve gender outcomes
The aim of this project is to empower women, create an enabling environment for them to access opportunity for better livelihood and contributing to gender equality for poverty reduction. The target groups are women leaders potential candidates, village, district and provincial authorities; villagers; Lao Women#s Union; Departments of Public Administration, Mass Media, Ministry of Energy and Mining, and Ministry of Natural Resource and Environment.
Overall objective is to empower women by creating an enabling environment for them to access local politics and decision-making power thereby contributing to gender equality and poverty reduction. The specific objectives are:
(1) To create awareness of gender issues and women in order to sensitise the targeted groups onthe need for women to participate in mining and hydropower planning process in communities for the better livelihood.
(2) Support women led livelihood microfinance for the poorest of the poor women at mining sites for them to access to productive microfinance products
(3) To learn to use and adapt the existing tools for community mobilisation in gender impact assessment in mining and hydropower and to facilitate networking and information sharing among stakeholders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lao Women&apos;s Union</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The LWU is an organization to present and protect the fair benefits of the Lao women and children of all ethnic groups in the country. Its status is equivalent to a ministry and has an organizational network from the central to the grass root level with the rolesto mobilize sodality among women of all ethic groups, and to educate all women about their rights and obligations. Therefore, they actively contribute to national socio-economic development as well as to urge for the implementation of gender equality and promotion of the advancement of women. The LWU was founded in 1945.

The country has revised a number laws to guaranty the women rights suchas of the enactment of the Law on Development and Protection of Women in 2004, the 2005 amendment of the Penal Law criminalizing discrimination against women in article 177, and the existence of the Counselling and Protection Centre for Women and Children, and revisions of the Family Law in 2009.

The Lao Women&#x92;s Union (LWU) is implementing the 5 programme which consisted of 16 projects in the country. The main activities include vocational training, extension of micro credit, handicraft development and income generation activities for women. The LWU set up a  large number of saving groups in 6 provinces of 16 , in 20 districts  with 134.132 members  and established saving groups in 47 poorest districts.

Between 1997 and 2004, : Gender Resource Information and Development Centre GRID was established as a key department of LWU, gender resource centresand libraries in five strategic locations in five provinces in the country. It also has radio outreach programmes, which reach out to the villagers in rural remote districts and villages. It has established gender shelves at the Central National Library and at the Library of the National University of Laos. In 2000, the work and activities of GRID were effectively evaluated and it was recommended to extend it to Phase II for 4 years i.e. 2001-2004.

The GRID centre is a capacity building Project of theLao Women&apos;s Union supported by the Norwegian Aid Agency (NORAD) and United Nations Development Programme (UNDP). NORAD will stop funding GRID in October 2004. GRID is the only national focal point for the collection, storage and dissemination of information on women and gender issues in the Lao PDR. GRID focuses its work and activities at the provincial, district and grassroots village levels, in all sectors.
The objectives of GRID are:
(a) To promote, increase and disseminate information on gender anddevelopment in the Lao PDR;
(b) To incorporate gender issues into the planning process at all levels;
(c) To strengthen and promote women&#x92;s participation in the development process and decision making; and
(d) To upgrade gender knowledge and ability of government officials in different levels.

The main activities of GRID are to:
(a) Set up Gender Resource Information and Development centres and libraries ;
(b) Organise training of trainers (ToTs) and gender training for the target groups ;
(c) Conduct research on important issues related to the situation of women and gender in the social economic development and politics in the Lao PDR ;
(d) Develop and disseminate communication tools related to gender and development ; and
(e) Cooperate and collaborate with other agencies in order to mainstream gender into development planning, programmes and projects.


GRID has, during the pastsix years, done a lot  of gender sensitisation and awareness raising of the Government officials from the nationalto the village grassroots levels. It has has also imparted gender analysis and planning skills to policy makers and planners, and mainstreamed genderconcerns into the National Poverty Eradication Programme (NPEP) and Training Handbook of the Committee for Planning and Cooperation(CPC). GRID is working closely with the CPC, which is the main planning body in the country. It also works with the Department of  Statistics (DOS), Ministry of Planning and Investment (MPI) in the collection and dissemination of sex-disaggregated statistics to facilitate the Government&#x92;s gender mainstreaming strategy. It works with the Ministry of Information and Culture and trained some journalists/reporters to mainstream gender issues in their work. Currently GRID is buildingthe gender mainstreaming capacities of both the Governance and Public Administration Reform (GPAR) Programme, and the Women&#x92;s Caucus of the National Assembly.
While LWU will bethe formal project holder, GRID will be the project implementor, drawingfromthe expertise of other groups.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-23-7069110" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laos</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="80" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to a sustainable livelihood</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="5" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to an identity</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-25">62021</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-03-01">10705</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Government Co-funding Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lao Women&apos;s Union</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-03-01">38487</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lao Women&apos;s Union</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-09-01">12829</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lao Women&apos;s Union</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-03-01">38487</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="US-EIN-23-7069110" ref="US-EIN-23-7069110">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-09-01">12829</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="US-EIN-23-7069110" ref="US-EIN-23-7069110">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-03-01">10705</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-04256-02:LA">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000791"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007254"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Laos (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-04256"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Gender-sensitive Environment Protection"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">10</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no of policy changes regarding legislation, regulation and/or practices on access to property or inheritance rights and/or compensation mechanisms for loss, in the fields of land and water and preservation of biodiversity in particular to the benefit of w</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">010-C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Lobby trajectories (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="010-C" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">010-E</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Organisations trained SRE (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="010-E" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">010-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="010-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">010-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Studies (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="010-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">010-D</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Training seminars (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="010-D" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">10</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no of policy changes regarding legislation, regulation and/or practices on access to property or inheritance rights and/or compensation mechanisms for loss, in the fields of land and water and preservation of biodiversity in particular to the benefit of w</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">010-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Policy changes AIM1 BB 010</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="010-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of partner organisations better able to communicate at the national and international levels the voice of people in rural areas living in poverty</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">004-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partnerorg AIM1 MO 004</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="004-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of partner organisations better able to communicate at the national and international levels the voice of people in rural areas living in poverty</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">004-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Local organisations of produc (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="004-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">004-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="004-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men (small-scale crop farmers, cattle farmers, fisher folk) able to use sustainable production methods enabling them to better protect and use sustainably their livelihood resources</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">001-02</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Female AIM1 DAB 001</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="001-02" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">001-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Male AIM1 DAB 001</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="001-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men (small-scale crop farmers, cattle farmers, fisher folk) able to use sustainable production methods enabling them to better protect and use sustainably their livelihood resources</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">001-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="001-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men in rural areas using financial services such as credit, savings and micro-insurance and productinnovation services and marketing training</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">002-02</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Female AIM1 DAB 002</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="002-02" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">002-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Male AIM1 DAB 002</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="002-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. of women and men in rural areas using financial services such as credit, savings and micro-insurance and productinnovation services and marketing training</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">002-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Microfinancing organisations (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="002-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">002-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Social brands (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="002-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">50</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. policy changes of government showing the adoption and enforcing of regulations or legislation regarding human rights of women, especially their right to integrity of the body and their right to social and political participation</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">050-E</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Networks female leadership (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="050-E" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">050-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners international womensrights (o</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="050-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">050-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners national womensrights (output</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="050-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">050-D</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Partners participation of women (outpu</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="050-D" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">050-C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Regional networks (output)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="050-C" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">50</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">no. policy changes of government showing the adoption and enforcing of regulations or legislation regarding human rights of women, especially their right to integrity of the body and their right to social and political participation</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">050-01</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Policy changes AIM5 BB 050</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="050-01" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-03-01" value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
