<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-04725-28:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FORUM 4 KALONGO PARIS Humanitarian Respo</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization Background
Forum for Kalongo Parish Women Associations (FOKAPAWA) is a Local Non-Governmental Organization founded in 1998 with a purpose of contributing to elevating the conditions of women and youths who suffered from the effects of the war in Acholi sub-region with particular focus on Agago District. FOKAPAWA operates in 13 sub-counties and 3 Town Councils of Agago district. Since inception FOKAPAWA has worked with more than 250 groups with at least 60% women. The groups/associations areour entry points inmost interventions. FOKAPAWA is registered by the national NGO Board with registration number S 5914/3325. FOKAPAWA#s interventionstargets women and youth as their first beneficiaries in its programming and implementation.
Vision
Aneconomically empowered community of women and youths who can demand for their rights at community and household levels
Mission
To support women and youths to knowtheir rights and be able to work towards a better livelihood by getting involved in IGAsand peace building activities in Agago  Districts.
Values
# Equality
# Self Reliance
# Integrity
# Team spirit
# Accountability and Transparency
Specific objectives are;
1. Topromote equal justice and rights for all.
2. To promote better Agricultural practices and the culture of saving among the women andyouth for self sustainability.
3. To provide psychosocial support to post war survivors.
4. To mobilize the community to change their attitude and behaviors that perpetuates Gender Based Violence/Domestic violence.
5. To facilitate women and youth to be actively involved in Peace building activities.
6. To promote quality education
Thematic Areas
1) Education with focus on Girl child
To mobilize the community towards their rights to education especially the excluded persons, notably women and girl children, FOKAPAWA# focus is on addressing the immediate needs of girl children and women; and strengthening the capacity of the surrounding circles of influence across Agago district.
To achieve this we commit ourselves to;
# Increasing enrollment and retention rate in Primary schools with keen focus on girl child,
# Improving parents# participation in planning, implementation and monitoring of school programs,
# Improving quality of education services,
# And increasing adult knowledge especially women in reading and writing.
To strengthen our economic empowerment component, our education program focuses on; 1)Functioning Adult Literacy (FAL) so as to build the capacity of women/women group in record keeping and numeracy, 2) girl children for gender equity.

2) Peace building
To create a peaceful society, FOKAPAWA commits to;
# Strengthening the capacity of formal and informal structures to mitigate and resolve conflict so as to createa peaceful community,
# Inspiring community to crate and own peaceful initiatives of resolving conflicts in community,
# Reducing land conflict and,
# Reintegrating and rehabilitating Formerly Abducted Persons

3) Justice and Equality
Aware thatsustainable transformation can only take place when the poor and the excluded knows their rights and the process of attaining them, FOKAPAWA#s  focusis  on raising  awareness on rights, mitigation of land conflict, employing participatory approaches to mobilizing and building right consciousness among the excluded/ vulnerable in communities and groups we work with alongside duty bearers.
To achieve this we commit ourselves to;
# Deepening the level of mainstreaming response to women# rights in all ourwork,and championing the fore-frontingwomen issues/concerns within development context,
# Strengthening the capacity of duty bearers to account to right holders and for the right holders to demand from duty bearers so as to create socially accountablegovernance,
# And reduction of Gender Based Violence.
# Enhancing capacity of social structures (traditional and religious leaders) to perform to their mandates in mitigating land conflict in community.

4) Economic Empowerment Addressing       on needs ofthe poor and the vulnerable as a way To address the commonneeds of the poor and the excluded we focus on; 1)livelihood and food security and, 2)development of micro finance and micro enterprises. The two components are broken at intervention levels into; Production and marketing, Micro finance and micro enterprises, andinstitutionalization of community groups.
Here we are driven by desire to
# Increase household income,
# And promote sustainable agriculture.

a) Promotion of Production and marketing
To Promotion Production and marketing, or focus is on distribution of farm inputs, encouraging animal traction and best agronomic practices, agro forestry, establishment of demonstration and multiplication schemes as well as exchange learning visit bywomen groups/farmers alongside providing market information.

b) Promotion of Micro finance and micro enterprises
The focus is on Village Saving and Loan Association (VSLA) and Income Generating Activities (IGAs). The targetis women groups and or anygroup of the same interest that can voluntary form themselves into groups (VSLA groups), the groups are trained on starting and maintaining micro enterprises with loan capital coming from their VSLA savings.
c) Community institutionalization through group developments
We strive to transform the VSLA groups into self managing groups with governing principles of operation. We connect the transformed formal groups to financial institutions and related government departments to increase their capitalbase and promote sustainability.

5) Psychosocial support
To reduce trauma and help built a society of peaceful mind, FOKAPAWA commits to;
1. Building a strong voluntary Community Based/owned counseling bases in community,
2. Building a powerful network ofbothformal and informal structures capable of addressing trauma and conflict related issues,
3. And offering at convenience of survivors, counseling services.

6) Health
Here the focus is;
1. Reproductive health care,
2. And HIV prevention.

Mainstreaming/ Cross Cutting Issues
At all levels of implementation we take into consideration the following;
1. Gender,
2. Child protection,
3. Environment,
4. And HIV/AIDS
5. Disaster and emergency occurrence</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FOKAPAWA head Quarter Offices is in Kalongo Town Council, Agago District, Acholi Sub Region Uganda. FOKAPAWA has a Board of Directors comprising of 9 members 7 females and 2males, its also guided with documents such as constitution, human Resource Policy, Financial Policy, Procurement and Disposal of Assets guidelines and other Policies and principles guiding her operation. FOKAPAWA has a broad spectrum of interventions in the areas affecting the most vulnerable in society, Governances and Human rights, Livelihood, socialaccountability, Women empowerment, with a target beneficiaries both direct and indirect. These include; communities, women, personsaffected and infected by HIV/AIDS, the youths and the elderly. FOKAPAWA considers community participation and inclusiveness as an approach which needs the local community to come together to realize that for development to succeed, the population should be kept in all processes related to development design, formulation and implementation.
ACHIEVEMENT
What have been the principal results in the past three years that contribute to significant, structural, sustained and positive improvement in the lives of men, women, girlsand boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?
The last project implemented has seen some drastic change that there are improved livelihoods, women empowerment, good Governances and social accountability, women rights for both direct and indirect beneficiaries, key among other project include; .
1-Project Name called Transforming life (ROCOKWO in Luo) a project that wasmeant to support the vulnerable women and girls who are chronically faced by poverty in the locations where we work with a focus ofcreating an environment when men and women can actively participate in economic activities for sustainable livelihood, combating violence against women and men while addressing psychosocial needs as an effect of long lasted war, the project implemented was guidedunder objective, To  ensure that the most vulnerable women and girls have their increased economic power and secured access and control to productive resources. Obj2. To support communities to be able to foresee and manage crisis related to conflict and disaster and maintain social cohesion through protectionof the most vulnerable group.
2- Be in stay school in project which it result to better equipped education activities but focus more on girl education in primary schools mainly. The planned conducted or implemented, Trained teachers on their roles and responsibilities, establishment of PTA/SMC members in 13 primary schools, Formed clubs in all theschools, trained club members on life skills

3- Citizen Participation for quality services delivery project , it#s a project beingimplemented in the six sub counties in Agago District, the  project aim towards in seeing that services delivery is improved under sectors of health, education and Water, the project was guided by two main objectives Objective1. To strengthen the capacity of Organization and oversight committees in lower LG for improve accountability in the sectors of water, health and education in Agago district. Objective2:To empower citizens to engage their Local Government leaders in service delivery in the sectors of health, education and water.

4- The project aim at strengthening for improved HIV/AIDS and OVC services delivery which was implemented in the four sub counties in Agago District, FOKAPAWA took a lead on HIV prevention by creating demand and uptake of HIV services and product,theproject targeted  existing VHT, PHLAS,Bodaboda, people in long term retationship,Commersercial sex worker ,OVC, youth in and out ofschool, the project was implemented due to the guide of the following objectives, To increases access and utilizationof HIV/AIDS care treatment and support services to adult adolescent and children living with HIV/AIDS in targeted communities.Obj2. To establishedeffectives referrals linkages and partnerships for comprehensives HIV services.
3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE
Mission: What is the current purpose of the organisation?
FOKAPAWA Mission;  To support women and youths to know their rights and be able to work towards abetter livelihood by getting involved in IGAs and peace building activities in Agago District.

What are the principal changes the organisation seeks to achieve over the long term?

The organizations seeks to invest more on the communities we work with through constant engagement on how to remain food secure even in times of food stress by ensuring that, the communities we work with are organized into farmer groups who produce food not only  for consumption some should be commercialized to meet other basic requirements. MADA feels that the empowered community will remain vibrant in meeting their daily needs and save for the future
Field(s) of activity: What are the principal thematic and geographic areas in which the organisation works?
Thematic Areas
1) Education with focus on Girl child
To mobilize the community towards their rights to education especially the excluded persons, notably women and girl children, FOKAPAWA# focus is on addressing the immediate needs of girl children and women; and strengthening the capacity of the surrounding circles of influence across Agago district.
To achieve this we commit ourselves to;
# Increasing enrollment and retention rate in Primary schools with keen focus on girl child,
# Improving parents# participation in planning, implementation and monitoring of school programs,
# Improving quality of education services,
# And increasing adult knowledge especially women in reading and writing.
Tostrengthen our economic empowerment component, our education program focuses on; 1)Functioning Adult Literacy (FAL) so as to build the capacity of women/women group in record keeping and numeracy, 2) girl children for gender equity.

2) Peace building
To create apeaceful society, FOKAPAWA commits to;
# Strengthening the capacity of formal and informal structures to mitigate and resolve conflict so as to create a peaceful community,
# Inspiring community to crate and own peaceful initiatives of resolving conflicts in community,
# Reducing land conflict and,
# Reintegrating and rehabilitating Formerly Abducted Persons

3) Justice and Equality
Aware that sustainable transformation can only take place when the poor and the excluded knows their rights and the process of attaining them, FOKAPAWA#s  focus is  on raising  awareness on rights, mitigation of land conflict, employing participatory approaches tomobilizing and building right consciousness among the excluded/ vulnerable in communities and groups we work with alongside duty bearers.
To achieve this we commit ourselves to;
# Deepening the level of mainstreaming response to women# rights in all our work, and championing the fore-fronting women issues/concerns within development context,
# Strengthening the capacity of duty bearers to account to right holders and for the right holders to demand from duty bearers so as to create socially accountable governance,
# And reduction of Gender Based Violence.
# Enhancing capacity of social structures (traditional and religious leaders) to perform to their mandates in mitigating land conflict in community.

4) Economic Empowerment Addressing on needs of the poor and the vulnerable as a way To address the common needs of the poor and the excluded we focus on; 1)livelihood and food security and, 2)development of micro finance and micro enterprises. The two components are broken at intervention levels into; Production and marketing, Micro finance and micro enterprises, and institutionalization of community groups.
Here we are driven by desire to
# Increase household income,
# And promote sustainable agriculture.

a) Promotion of Production and marketing
To Promotion Production and marketing, or focus is on distribution of farm inputs, encouraging animal traction and best agronomic practices, agro forestry, establishment of demonstration and multiplication schemes as well as exchange learning visit by women groups/farmers alongside providing market information.

b) Promotion of Micro finance and micro enterprises
The focus is on Village Saving and Loan Association (VSLA) and Income Generating Activities (IGAs). The target is women groups and or any group of the same interest that can voluntary form themselves into groups (VSLA groups), the groups are trained on starting and maintaining micro enterprises with loan capital coming from their VSLA savings.
c) Community institutionalization through groupdevelopments
We strive to transform the VSLA groups into self-managing groups with governing principles of operation. We connect the transformed formal groups to financial institutions and related government departments to increase their capital baseandpromote sustainability.

5) Good Governance and Leadership-social accountability
To reduce trauma and help built a society of peaceful mind, FOKAPAWA commits to;
1. Building a strong voluntary Community Based/owned counselling bases in community,
2.Building a powerful network of both formal and informal structures capable of addressing trauma and conflict related issues,
3. And offering at convenience of survivors, counselling services.

6) Health
Here the focus is;
1. Reproductive health care,
2. And HIV prevention.

Mainstreaming/ Cross Cutting Issues
At all levels of implementation we take into consideration the following;
1. Gender,
2. Child protection,
3. Environment,
4. And HIV/AIDS
5. Disaster and emergency occurrence
 Whoare the social actors that benefit from the work?
People we work with who include: women, girls, boys, elderly, men, PWDs and PSNs, government authorities at the lower level and Civil Society Organizations.
4. STRATEGIC POSITIONING
Analyse the environment in which the organisation works?
Increasing pressures on organizations to be more competitive is taking centre stage to be seen to deliver services to the community. FOKAPAWA currently focuses keen interest on the emergency response, though it has been implementing most of the projects which are related to development. The management of the organization decided that it was necessary to refocus the organization to be also ready when issues to related a crisis occurs the organization should have the minimum standards to respond to the an emergency in a most appropriate and timely manner.
Who are the other relevant social actors, including government and business, and what roles do they play? &apos;
Local communities in the operation area being part of the project planning design, implementation and monitoring.
Local authorities at the sub county level, they are involved in the assessment, identification of the affected communities and also give guidanceon the working protocols of the government

Civil society organization for coordination and timely response, to avoid work duplication and use of resources in the most effective and efficient way

District local government for an enabling environment to operate and guiding principles which are all captured in the MoUs.

The organizations also works closely with the relevant private sector (suppliers and vendors)  for goods and services which aid the successful intervention.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FORUM 4 KALONGO PARISH WOMEN ASSOCI FOCAPAWA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>3.04724 33.36544</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-13">63584</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-01">20700</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FORUM 4 KALONGO PARISH WOMEN ASSOCI FOCAPAWA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-01">10350</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FORUM 4 KALONGO PARISH WOMEN ASSOCI FOCAPAWA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-01">29084</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FORUM 4 KALONGO PARISH WOMEN ASSOCI FOCAPAWA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">3450</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FORUM 4 KALONGO PARISH WOMEN ASSOCI FOCAPAWA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-01">20700</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-01">10350</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-01">29084</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">3450</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-04725-28:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000916"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-04725"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="IKEA Foundation ELNHA"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5320</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasing that participate or initiate influencing for space in humanitarian work and that are capable of effective humanitarian response according to humanitarian standards.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5320-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasing that participate or initiate influencing for space in humanitarian work and that are capable of effective humanitarian response according to humanitarian standards.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5320-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-05-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="16"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="4"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="5"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="8"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5320</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasing that participate or initiate influencing for space in humanitarian work and that are capable of effective humanitarian response according to humanitarian standards.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5320-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5320-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-05-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-05-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="12"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="14"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="4"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="5"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="8"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
