<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05121-05:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">504435 SEATINI UGANDA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The private sector remains a key engine of economic growth  and can play an important role in promoting sustainable economic development in Uganda through enhancing agriculture, industrial and services development, contributing to domestic resource mobilization and generating employment opportunities, among others. In Uganda, the private sector comprises both foreign and domestic enterprises and firms engaged within key sectors of agriculture, services, industry and infrastructure. Majority of the domestic private sector lies within the informal sector i.e. the Micro Small and Medium Enterprises (MSMEs). This sector is an important source of employment # creating 19 out of 20 non-agriculture jobs with young people occupying 94.7%  of these jobs. The sector also contributes to up to 43%  of GDP at market prices majority of which have not been in existence for more than 5 years, and with 90% of them operating for less than 20 years.
Despite this potential, this sector unlike their foreign counterparts (foreign direct investors), face peculiar challenges including limited access to investment capital given the high interest rate of up to 24% per annum which increases the cost of credit, low level of skills and technology, competition from foreign firms which crowd out domestic enterprises and limited government support. Consequently, only a handful of the domestic enterprises have survived to celebrate their first birthday. This is despite the fact that the sector can play an important role in acceleratinggrowth, alleviating poverty and improving the quality of life of the people of Uganda.
This has further been aggravated by the existing trade and investment policy frameworks which do notadequately support strengthening the competitiveness of the domestic private sector. They place more emphasis on attracting ForeignDirector Investment (FDI) rather than strengthening and improving domestic investors&apos; capacity and participation in various sectorsfor the overall improvement of the economy. These policies and laws majorly aim to protect the interests and rights of foreign investments at the cost of the community rights. The Investment Code, 2000 and the Uganda Free Zones Act, 2014 for example provide investment incentives such as tax holidays and land concessions for foreign investors seeking to establish in Uganda.
In addition, the existing investment related policy frameworks assume that the challenges faced by these firms are the same. They thus provide general strategies for the private sector development and remain silent on efforts to address some of the underlying challenges that limit their capacity to be competitive. The policies for example are not explicit on sourcing locally and forming joint ventures which are both critical for promoting local content, creating employment, facilitating backward and forward linkages, boosting production and productivity enhancing the domestic industrial sector development. The existing policies are also silent on foreign investors&apos; engagement in petty trade,of which majority of them import the merchandise and consequently crowd out domestic enterprises engaged in these sectors.
Domestic private sector is imperative as it can contribute to increased production and productivity, employment creationfor thegreater majority of the local population and contribute to increase domestic resource mobilization through taxation. Domestic investments are more likely to benefit the local community and contribute to greater economic development if compared to FDIs whichrepatriate profits and often operate outside the host country&apos;s policies and laws on environment protection and human rights among others.
It should be noted that despite the efforts by government to attract greater FDI flows and the subsequent increaseof this flow into the country, this rise has not resulted into rises in employment creation, meaningful technology and skills transfer, value addition and private sector development including growth of the service, industry and agriculture sector production and productivity. This state of play has made it more and more apparent to enhance local private sector capacity to increase domestic investment into the economy and foster structural transformation for economic growth and development.
Currently, there are a number of ongoing policy processes which require civil society and private sector engagement to influence a policy environment to strengthen domestic private sector competitiveness for sustainable development and improved livelihoods. These processes include the development of the Private Sector Development Strategy, the development of the strategy for the Free Zones Authority and the amendment of the Investment Code Act 2000. The project will also advocate for the review of the Public Procurement and Disposal of Assets (PPDA) Act to be reflective and coherent with the Buy Uganda Build Uganda (BUBU) policy which promotes local content. Engaging in these processes is imperative and thus necessitates raising stakeholders&apos; awareness to effectively participate in and influence these processes.
It is therefore imperative to advocate for and influence the review of private sector related policy frameworks to enhance local content and joint venture formation. Adopting such legal frameworks can go a long way in facilitating forward and backward linkages which are critical for employment creation, increased production and productivity as well as increase tax revenue generation.
SEATINI wishes therefore to propose a project on Promoting investment policies that support domestic private sector competitiveness for sustainable development in Uganda.
Overall objective
To strengthen domestic private sector competitiveness through a conducive trade and investment policy framework for sustainable development in Uganda</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SEATINI UGANDA</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Southern and Eastern African Trade, Information and Negotiations Institute (SEATINI) Uganda is a regional non-governmental organisation founded in 1996 soon after the WTO Singapore Ministerial Conference. It happened when people realised that Africa in particular and Third World countries in general were marginalised in the World Trade Organisation&apos;s negotiations.
SEATINI was formed to enhance the capacity in these negotiations of African trade officials and negotiators through technical assistance,and also through extending the trade debate to other stakeholders, especially civil society organisations, the media and parliaments. SEATINI also brings together African trade officials and negotiators, with a purpose of consolidating Africa&apos;s negotiating positions.

SEATINI was born when it was observed that:
- African public policy in international forums is often determined ad hoc, and African governments are mostly takers, not makers, of international decisions that affect people&apos;s lives. Governments often sign international trade agreements without adequate information or analysis. Alternatively, the lack of a clear perception of their interests, they often resort to a simple negative posture rather than make commitments to agreements that mightbe of value to them;
- the private sector is equally badly informed about the challenges of globalisation and the effect of the multilateral trading regime;
- civil society understands the complexities of the international regime but it is often excludedfrom decision-making, both at home and in international forums.

Presently, the organisation has offices in Harare, Johannesburg, Kampala, Nairobi and Geneva.  The Uganda office was established in 2001 and is fully registered with the Ministry of Internal Affairs. The country chapters are semi-autonomous with the country director responsible for reporting to the regional director in Zimbabwe. SEATINI has one board for the whole organisation.

ON THE FINANCE FOR DEVELOPMENT PROJECT: SEATINI Uganda is leading the implementation of Tax Justice interventions in Uganda at national level. This is aimed at influencing fair tax policy reform in Uganda at national level and closely works with other national and subnational level F4D partners.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="33110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="10" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-26">9465</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-26">10000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-11-01">10000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Innovation Fund</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SEATINI UGANDA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-11-01">9465</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SEATINI UGANDA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-06-01">10000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SEATINI UGANDA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-11-01">-10000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SEATINI UGANDA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-11-01">9465</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-06-01">10000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-11-01">-10000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-11-01">10000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05121-05:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05121"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Enterprising for Development"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2480</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects and programmes more effective: # cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories on transparent and accountable finance</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2480-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories on transparent and accountable finance</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2480-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2016-04-01" value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2480</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects and programmes more effective: # cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories on transparent and accountable finance</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2480-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">evidence products (track records, cases, evaluations etc.) produced that assess Oxfam Novib&#x2019;s programmes and projects effectiveness and quality</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2480-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2016-04-01" value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
