<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06301-06:17</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Full Circle Tax Watch in West Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is empowering young people (but with a specific focus on LGBTIQ+ communities and persons living with disabilities) across Ghana, Nigeria and Mali with the skills to improve (social) accountability around fiscal issues, most especially taxation and public budgeting as a means to improve their access to comprehensive (particularly healthcare and education).

Long term, the project partners aim to promote the greater inclusion of marginalized communities in fiscal policy-making and practices monitoring dialogues. The idea is to both: (i) expand the institutional support for inclusion of marginalised people to proactively engage with tax policy reforms and budget monitoring; and (ii) improve the understanding of budget and fiscal monitoring, pro-poor tax policy, efficienttax collection and public budget allocations by organisations addressing the health and education needs of marginalised populationsin project countries. To accomplish this, the project is:

1. Conducting research (participatory action research) on two areas: (a)current fiscal (both taxation and budget) policy and practice monitoring initiatives in Ghana, Nigeria and Mali through the lens ofthe marginalized groups to highlight inclusive and exclusive policies and practices, and (b) to research the current budget expenditure on marginalized communities (particularly by the Global Fund#s Country Coordinating Mechanisms).
2. Developing advocacy briefs based on research findings and recommendations and then pre-test these materials.
3. Conducting face to face advocacy meetings, using briefs, with in-country stakeholders and national authorities on tax and budgeting.
4. Creating knowledge-sharing workshops to improve knowledge of stakeholders working in existing budget monitoring initiatives, to improve their inclusion of youth, LGBTIQ+, and people with disabilities in their projects. And for marginalized people to learn about tax and budget policy and practices at national, provincial and municipal levels.
5. Runing a seven-month advocacy campaign in each country, built on the knowledge gained through the research, advocacy briefs, knowledge sharing, and link and learn events.

The project is implemented by a consortium is composed of five distinct organisaitons led by the Kids &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Teens Resource Centre:
# KIDS &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; TEENS RESOURCE CENTRE (K&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;TRC) is a registered non-governmental organization established in December 2002 to advance, promote and support efforts of government andall other stakeholders involved in children and young people developmental activities. K&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;TRC has been working among children and young people for the past 14 years and have made remarkable impacts in the lives of young people in communities we work through service provision, information sharing, capacity development, mentoring and participatory community development.
# ARCAD SANTE PLUS:Formerly known as ARCAD-SIDA Mali, the Association for Community Resilience towards Access to Development and Health PLUS (ARCAD Sant&#xE9; PLUS) is a Malian community-based organization created in 1994. ARCAD Sant&#xE9; PLUS is a recognized public-interest organization since 2016 and has been a key partner of the State of Mali since 2000 in the implementation of the malian initiative for access to antiretroviral treatments (ARV) and in the decentralization of HIV services accross the country. Founding member of Coalition PLUS in 2008, ARCAD Sant&#xE9; PLUS coordinate Coalition PLUS West Africa Platform since 2014. Involving 23 associations in 8 countries, the platform is a network for South-South capacity building.
# ACCOUNTABILITY INTERNATIONAL: Accountability International has a 12 year long history working in partnerships and collaborating with dozens if not hundreds of partners. As an organisation we have worked to popularise accountability, been a leader in participatory action research for human rights in Africa and as a think tank are steeped in learning and experimenting. AI brings expertise in Participatory Action Research, a broad spectrum of human rights knowledge and experience and a strong network of marginalised people.
# SOCIETY FOR AIDS IN AFRICA: Founded in 1989, the Society for AIDS in Africa (SAA) is a non-government, non-profit making, civic and community oriented organisation with the overall goal of mitigating the impact of HIV and AIDS, TB as well as Malaria in the African continent, through various activities. SAA envisions an African continent free of AIDS, TB, Malaria and emerging infections, where the communities are empowered, with no stigma and discrimination against PLHIV, key populations and their families and where there is social justice, and equity to accessing treatment, care and support.
# PEERREVIEW FORUM: The Peer Review Forum is an organization working towards ensuring accountability of allstakeholders responding to theHIV epidemic in Nigeria towards the goal of elimination of AIDS in Nigeria by 2030. It was inaugurated in 2016 with the institutionof a platform to bring together all stakeholders to discuss the status of the HIV response annually. As a watchdog for the Nigeria HIV response, its mission is to amplify the diverse voices of communities, by ensuring that the voices inform and drive the HIV programs in Nigeria.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KIDS &amp; TEENS RESOURCE CENTRE</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kids &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Teens Resource Centre (K&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;TRC) is a registered non-governmental organisation established in 2002 to advance, promote and support efforts of government and all other stakeholders involved in children and young people developmental activities. K&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;TRC has been working with children and young people for the past 14 years and has made remarkable impacts in the lives of youngpeople in communities through continuous service provision, information sharing, capacity development, mentoring, and participatorycommunity development.

K&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;TRC envisions a #secured future# where young people are empowered to actively participate and contribute to the sustainable development of their own communities. The mission is to create an enabling environment that equips young people with the knowledge and skills required for their self-actualization and development.

K&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;TRC has her head office in Akure, with physical offices in 4 states across 3 of the 6 geo-political zones of Nigeria namely Ondo, Ekiti, Kwara and Plateau States. K&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;TRC is also a member of many national civil society networks in Nigeria. In the African Region, K&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;TRC coordinates young people on HIV &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; AIDS in West Africa. K&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;TRC led many advocacy to First Ladies of West African Countries for more responsive participation of the First Ladies on Adolescent Girls and Young Women interventions across Republic of Benin, Ghana, Togo, Nigeriaand Cote D#Ivorie.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Africa Reg</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-23">46000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-10-01">43700</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KIDS &amp; TEENS RESOURCE CENTRE</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">2300</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KIDS &amp; TEENS RESOURCE CENTRE</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-10-01">43700</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">2300</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06301-06:17">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000141" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001989"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007881"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06301"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="From Open to Inclusive Governance"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grantees, rightsholder groups and other key stakeholders develop and implement innovative strategies to reach, empower and strengthen the capacities of rightsholders.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Communities of Practice supported by programme staff and Linking and Learning facilitating organisations to define a set of learning questions</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.1.a" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.b</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Communities of Practice with active participation of grantees emerging through Linking and Learning processes</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.1.b" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.c.i</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># and type (article, training material, blog, podcast, video) of publications produced by Communities of Practice to develop, share and document knowledge</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.1.c.i" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.c.ii</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># learning meetings held by Communities of Practice to develop, share and document knowledge</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.1.c.ii" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grantees, rightsholder groups and other key stakeholders develop and implement innovative strategies to reach, empower and strengthen the capacities of rightsholders.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># grantees, rightsholder groups and other key stakeholders reporting use of new insights and innovative approaches that they have acquired through Linking and Learning</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.1.1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
