<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05720-09:NL</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IUCN IMVO award 2019 Metal Negot.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2457/5000
IUCN NL is currently working with around 200 local partner organizations in more than 30 countries to strengthen biodiversity and ecosystem protection and to &quot;mainstream&quot; ecosystem thinking within development scenarios. In recent years, however, we are increasingly confronted with the overlap of mining concessions (industrial or small-scale or artisanal) with the national protected area system or. with the corridors that connect protected areas. This overlap coincides with a clear increase in (regularly fatal) violence against conservationists and local leaders who interfere with these developments. With regard to the extractive sector, IUCNand its partners are emphatically committed to reducing the long-term risks to biodiversity and ecosystems (and the services arising from those systems) to socially acceptable levels.

* As part of the global union, IUCN NL has a large field of experience and knowledge at the intersection of biodiversity and business that can be relied upon to promote legal and best practice practical mining and derived value chains. IUCN and IUCN NL are also highly experienced in multi-stakeholder dialogue and negotiation processes. Thisin general, but certainly also where it concerns specifically reducing the ecological footprint or the Dutch economy or the ecological footprint or Dutch as a transit country.

* During the negotiations for the covenant for the gold sector, we were the only partythat explicitly focused on ecological sustainability and the protection of biological diversity / natural capital. The expectation regarding the covenant for the metallurgical sector is that here too there is an explicit need for a party that looks beyond sec human rights and social justice. Due to limited capacity, IUCN NL initially decided not to participate in this sector covenant, partly in view of the amount or (uncovered) time spent in the gold covenant. However, at MinBuZa - DG International Economic Relations &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; DG Inclusive Green Growth, there was such a strong need for input from IUCN NL that we decided in April 2017 to invest in the covenant for the metallurgical sector. We signed the declaration of intent for this covenant on 24-04-2017.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IUCN National Committe of Netherlands is the Dutch branch of TheInternational Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) , a membership Union uniquely composed of both government and civil society organisations. It provides public, private and non-governmental organisations with the knowledge and tools that enable human progress, economic development and nature conservation to take place together.

Created in 1948, IUCN has evolved into the world&#x92;s largest and most diverse environmental network. It harnesses the experience, resources and reach of its 1,300 Member organisations and the input of some 10,000 experts. IUCN is the global authority on the status of the natural world and the measures needed to safeguard it. Our experts are organised into six commissions dedicated to speciessurvival, environmental law, protected areas, social and economic policy, ecosystem management, and education and communication.

The ability to convene diverse stakeholders and provide the latest science, objective recommendations and on-the-ground expertise drives IUCN&#x92;s mission of informing and empowering conservation efforts worldwide. We provide a neutral forum in which governments, NGOs, scientists, businesses, local communities, indigenous peoples groups, faith-based organisations and others can work together to forge and implement solutions to environmental challenges.

By facilitating these solutions, IUCN provides governments and institutions at all levels with the impetus to achieve universal goals, including on biodiversity, climate change and sustainable development, which IUCN was instrumental in defining.

Combined, our knowledge base and diverse membership make IUCN an incubator and trusted repository of best practices, conservation tools, and international guidelines and standards. As the only environmental organisation with official United Nations Observer Status, IUCN ensures that nature conservation has a voice at the highest level of international governance.

IUCN&#x92;s expertise and extensive network provide a solid foundation for a large and diverse portfolio of conservation projects around the world. Combining the latest science with the traditional knowledge of local communities, these projects work to reverse habitat loss, restore ecosystems and improve people&#x92;s well-being. They also produce a wealth of data and information which feeds into IUCN&#x92;s analytical capacity.

Through their affiliation with IUCN, Member organisations are part of a democratic process, voting Resolutions which drive the global conservation agenda. They meet every four years at the IUCN World Conservation Congress to setpriorities and agree on the Union&#x92;s work programme. IUCN congresses have produced several key international environmental agreements including the Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD), the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species (CITES), the World Heritage Convention, and the Ramsar Convention on wetlands. We continue to help these conventions strengthen and evolve so thatthey can respond to emerging challenges.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IUCN</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="32110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="10" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-06">27040</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-01">27040</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Min. Foreign Affairs general</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IUCN</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-01">27040</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29298" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05720-09:NL">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001618"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007865"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05720"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="IMVO Negotiations Facility 2019-2021"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2410</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved policies: # cases private sector adopting/implementing improved policies on increasing transparency &amp; accountability, on integration of ESG &amp; Human Rights criteria in policy and practice and/or on promotion of financial inclusion of poor people</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases private sector adopting/implementing improved policies on increasing transparency &amp; accountability, on integration of ESG &amp; Human Rights criteria in policy and practice and/or on promotion of financial inclusion of poor people -DD2</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-02-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2410</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved policies: # cases private sector adopting/implementing improved policies on increasing transparency &amp; accountability, on integration of ESG &amp; Human Rights criteria in policy and practice and/or on promotion of financial inclusion of poor people</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2410-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">pieces of evidence (documents, studies, videos, testimonies etc.) produced by Oxfam Novib and partners in support of development/adoption of alternative policies/approaches</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2410-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-02-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2410-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">pieces of evidence (documents, studies, videos, testimonies etc.) produced by Oxfam Novib and partners to support monitoring of practices and implementation of policies by the private sector</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2410-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-02-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
