<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-000005</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting and protecting human rights of sexual minorities in Pakistan, Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This cross-sectoral Oxfam programme seeks to contribute to the equal rights and sexual autonomy for lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender people (LGBT).

The programme proposes activities that will strengthen the capacity of civil society organisations, groups and networks of LGBT persons so that they can individually and/or collectively speak out on, and challenge infringements of their human rights on the basis of sexual orientation. This includes intolerance, discriminatory practices and laws that prevent them from realizing all of their rights. Such a distinction is important in building awareness, planning and implementing networking efforts, solidarity building, and the advocacy and lobbying promoting the freedom of expression, movement, thought, opinion, and non-discrimination, as well as their right to equality before the law or access to justice. The programme will also work with human rights defenders, women#s rights and LGBT activists, lawyers and youth organizations toward an enabling environment to promote and support the rights of these sexual minorities. Lessons learned in the three countries of implementation will be collected to improve approaches to LGBT rights programming in Muslim and African context.

Project activities will be implemented through three Oxfam Affiliates in three countries: Oxfam Novib in Pakistan, Oxfam Australia in South Africa, and Oxfam Canada in Zimbabwe. Local partners are Naz Male Health Alliance, Sexual Rights Centre, Vovo, The Inner Circle and the Triangle Project.

In all three countries sexual minorities are subjected to discrimination and rights violations whereas for South Africa the sexual rights of women are more limited than those of men.

Main current donor agency is the Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs. Oxfam Novib has provided matching funds.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl/Mission-and-vision">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-01-12"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
