<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05576-04:KH</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Srer Khmer-WEE in Agriculture</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Srer Khmer will be implementing of the Women Economic Empowerment in Agriculture (WEEA) project in Pursat province, the project will be delivered over 12 months from July 2018 through June 2019. The aim of this project is to improve women#s economic position in agriculture value chains so that women enjoy a bigger share of the value they produce. The project will seek men#s participation and involvement to challenge gender imbalances. It will support women#s collectives# access to key inputs, informationand skills and their capacity to influence positively Private Sector and Government policies and practices. It will seek to support women to use a variety of tools to document project successes and to bring this evidence to key spaces (e.g. village, commune, provincial, national).The specific objectives are (i) To strengthen the capacity of women collective groups so that they can access information, financial services, and training to develop business and leadership skills. (ii) To sustainably improvethe production process so that men and women farmers enhance the quantity and quality of their products, obtain better prices, and reduce their exposure to risk and (iii) To foster women#s collective representation and voice to influence positively privatesector and government policies and practices in agricultural value chains to create a more equitable economic environment.

The proposed project was directly benefit 1,750 farmers (80% are women) from 30 villages (and an estimated over 8,750 family member beneficiaries) of the poorest and most vulnerable households in target villages members in a positive manner and agricultural production and productivity are increased and diversified, both for food security and income and farmers learn to better manage natural resources more effectively in a way that contributes tosustainable livelihoods. The criterion of target beneficiaries includes (i) ID-Poor households, small-holder HHs (land less than 1ha), landless HHs, women-headed HHs, PWD households, households affected by GBV, HIV/AIDS and natural disasters from members and non-members of SHGs groups in the target communities will acquiring the resilient techniques of vegetable, rice and livestock production, farm chemical safety, and post-harvest management.

The Integrated Farmer Field School (IFFS) on integrated agriculture and marketing (IAM) using the Farmer Field School approach of discovery and learning over 12 weeks. The farmer groups will also be encouraged to develop Individual Action Plans totackle environmental problems such as pesticide use, health and safety. Regarding group action,farmer participants will be encouraged to form and register Saving for change/Farmer Associations/ Agriculture Cooperative (ACs) toaddress larger matters andtomaintain farmer interest in the farm ecosystems and farm development on a sustainable basis. The FarmerGroups will be given additional training to support these endeavours and to increase and diversify their production and improve thequality of their market-oriented agricultural products. In addition, the project will be mobilized in the future to increase awareness on hygiene and sanitation and resilience to climate change and disaster through promote biogas, solar installation, using toilet, pond rehabilitated and improved cooking stove.

1,750 farmers directly benefit and approximately 8,750 of their family members through improved food security, increased income, access to low interest loans, and membership and engagement in Farmer Associations where members can share information about agricultural techniques and discuss and act on shared concerns. However, farmers will have abetter understanding of the opportunities offered by improved access to markets and different marketing mechanisms. Furthermore, farmers will be able to experiment with different marketing opportunities by understanding markets better and by marketing different crops through improved crops calendar.

In addition, small holders will learn how to keep records and compilelessons learned from experiences, successes/failures, and new initiatives relating to the new business model for smallholder farmers. All lesson learned, experiences, successes/failures, and new initiatives relating to this new business model will be recorded, compiled, and published in Khmer language and shared with other famers within the target areas and the wider community.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-23-7069110" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Background and Capability of Srer Khmer
Srer Khmer means Field of Cambodia, a local NGO dedicated to the support of sustainable socio-economic development through research, training, education and community development by promoting participatory learning, farmer-led activities, farmers networking, sustainable agriculture, and natural resources management.
VISION
Farming communities and community development workers must have the capacity, rights and ownership in making decision on any issues that are relevant to sustain their living.

MISSION
Srer Khmer, in recognition of farmers&apos; rights and community development workers to learn, use and manage theirown community resources and participate in any decision related to their livelihood, is committed to providing farmers opportunities to gain knowledge and strengthen their capacity to lead and manage their lives through participatory learning approaches which build on understanding the fundamental relationship between agriculture, environment and rural societies.

GOAL
Farmers and community development workers having increased control of their lives based on a mastery of ecological and social knowledge and skill.
To achieve this mission and goal, Srer Khmer works in close cooperation with relevantfarmers groups, government institutions and other NGOs based on the values of honesty, equity, positive encouragement, gender equity and responsibility. Specially, Srer Khmer works with Farmer Trainers as main partners in developing broad farmer-to-farmertraining activities in the areas of ecological agriculture and livelihood related issues. Farmer Trainers have played an important role in organizing farmer meetings and follow-up training activities. Key government district IPM trainers have been contacted to support these activities as a technical advisor to Farmer Trainers.

Establishment, Legal Status and Award
Srer Khmer was established and registered with the Ministry of Interior of the Royal Government of Cambodia and the local authorities on January 9, 2002 by a group of former staff of FAO Community IPM Program. The FAO project started in Cambodia in 1996 and ended in late 2001, therefore, to continue the activity of community based integrated pest management (IPM) Farmer Field Schools, a proven approach to successful ecological learning and farmer networking, Srer Khmer was the response to the need to further build on the work of FAO and facilitate the work of farmers-led activities.

Srer Khmer is certified by NGO Code Compliance Committeeof NGO Good Practice Project (NGO GPP) to award the NGO good practices project certificate. This award meant that NGO GPP recognizes and appreciates Srer Khmer&apos;s efforts in complying with all standards and being role model NGO in Cambodia. To learn moregoto www.ccc-cambodia.org.

Organizational Structure and Management
The basic elements of Srer Khmer&apos;s organizational structure and the management are as follows:
- A Board of Directors which oversees and sets policy including Srer Khmer Statutes, Personnel Policy, Financial Policy for the organization, meets every four months to monitor Srer Khmer#s activities and give feedback to the Executive Director who is responsible to the Board. The current Board has seven members and have 3 times meeting per year. However, the extraordinary meetings can call from any members if necessary take action on urgent matters should the need arise.

- The Executive Director is responsibility for all day-to-day activities, programs, projects and staff.

- The Management Committee consists of the Executive Director, Programme Manager and the Admin/Finance Manager has the role of coordinating and assisting the Executive Director with day-to-day activities.

- The Technical Coordination Committee (TCC) consisted of Executive Director, Programme Manager, Programme Officers, Project Managers and Admin/Finance Unit. TCC has the role of providing inputs on technical issues. TCC has at least 2 times meeting per year to set technical guideline for Srer Khmer.

Staffing
At the moment, Srer Khmer has more than 50 full time staff members including technical staff, support staff and graduate (intern) trainees. Most of them were based in the project based in the provinces. Fifteen (15) of them are women. Srer Khmer also has1Volunteer from Australia Volunteers to assist withprogram/organization development. Srer Khmer used to have more than 10 Australian Volunteers from AVI, VIDA and AYAD to work with us from the past.

Apart from staff, we also have a network of well-trained farmer trainers at the provincial, district, commune, andvillage levels where we can call upon for providing training at their respective communities.

Program Thematic Areas (2011 # 2015):
1. Sustainable Agriculture and Land Resources Rights
2.Natural Resources Management and Livelihoods
3. Climate Changes Adaptation and DRR
4. Agri-Business and Value Chains
5. Training, Research and Consultancy to support small provincial NGOs.

Srer Khmer plays a role as Service Provider. Training on topics related to FFS/post-FFS, FLS, Socio-economic analysis, living soil, integrated homestead production, insect ecology, farmer association management, business planning, participatory marketing study, project management,participatory monitoring andevaluation, knowledge management, Training of Trainers, and other topics related ecological agricultureand community/rural development, etc., Participatory research and analysis and Project review and evaluation.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Srer Khmer</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-09" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-09" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to a sustainable livelihood</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="8" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-07-09"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-13">51341</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-01">34196</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Srer Khmer</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-01">17144</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Srer Khmer</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-01">-2232</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Srer Khmer</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-01">34196</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="US-EIN-23-7069110" ref="US-EIN-23-7069110">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-01">17144</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-01">-2232</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05576-04:KH">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000123" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001566"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007251"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Cambodia (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05576"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Women Economic Empowerment in Agricultur"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to  increase their productivity and/or income, or to strengthen their bargaining position, ensuring equal benefit to men and women.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-09" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="650"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="650"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-09"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="613"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-09" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1137"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1150"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-09"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1137"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to  increase their productivity and/or income, or to strengthen their bargaining position, ensuring equal benefit to men and women.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to  increase their productivity and/or income, or to strengthen their bargaining position, ensuring equal benefit to men and women.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-09" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="650"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="700"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-09"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="613"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to  increase their productivity and/or income, or to strengthen their bargaining position, ensuring equal benefit to men and women.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-09" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1137"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1137"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-09"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1137"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
