<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-209131-GB-CHC-209131-NF-EGY</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-209131" secondary-reporter="0" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BRITISH COUNCIL</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton fund, Egypt</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Governmental and non governmental Research institutes in Egypt and young career researchers working at Egyptian governmental Universities, institutes and research centres.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Initiate new research and innovation collaborations between institutions in Egypt and the UK - Build capacity of young career researchers and create a cohort of global research network - translation of research knowledge into tangible benefits - focus on topics or themes which have relevance to the economic development and welfare of Egypt - facilitate collaboration between universities and industry to ensure that new research can benefit all in society.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Higher Education and Scientific Research, Science, Technology &amp; Innovation Funding Authority is the main Local partner for Research grants. Central Department of Mission Sector is the main partner for PhD scholarships.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Newton-Mosharafa Fund is &#xA3;50 million, a science and innovation partnership between the UK and Egypt that has run since 2014.  It aims to advance the capacity of the Egyptian science sector; increase the amount of quality scientific research and innovation and helps mitigate social and economic challenges in Egypt through the development of new research and innovation; and to establish and maintain sustainable, long term and mutual beneficial partnerships between the British and Egyptian science and innovation sectors. The Newton Mosharafa Fund in Egypt consists of the Institutional Links programme which is small scale seed funding on institutional level to build collaborations between institutions in UK and Egypt and the Newton Fund Impact Scheme which is a programme designed to provide previous and current Newton award holders with the opportunity to further impact from their work in a way that strengthens the profile of the Fund and to add tangible value to the investment already made by partner funders and the UK.  The Newton Mosharafa PhD programme is designed to support Egyptian researchers to do their PhD at UK Higher Education institutions. The programme supports both general missions (full degree scholarships of three years), as well as joint supervisions (for students to do research for a year at a UK university as part of their Egyptian PhD).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-209131" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-209131" role="2" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-209131" role="4" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Department of Mission Sector</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy (BEIS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <telephone>00441619577755</telephone>
   <email>IATI@britishcouncil.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-id code="360630" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cairo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>30.0345  31.1459</pos>
   </point>
   <location-class code="2"></location-class>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton Egypt is a national project and is delivered in Cairo, covering the entire country.</narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="11420" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-04-01">550067</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
