<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41198677-AFGO_FUND-XM-DAC-7-PPR-29646</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41198677" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hivos</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syrian Women&apos;s Participation in Peace and Security: The way forward</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Full and equal participation of women in peace, security and democracy in Syria is key to ensure the rights, protection and equality of women and girls both during and after the conflict. Without women&#x2019;s full participation, the issues faced by women will continue to be ignored and opposed by all major parties to the conflict, as it is a structural problem.                                                                                            
Historic opportunities are now available to effect this participation. One of them is the appointment of the Women&#x2019;s Advisory Board by the UN to advise the UN Special Envoy for Syria. There is momentum, and this programme is designed to capitalise on this momentum to create more space for women&#x2019;s participation in key arenas, as well as institutionalise their participation so that it can weather all potential scenarios, while building a force from bottom up.

The overall objective for this work is to strengthen prospects for sustainable peace and security in Syria through the creation of an enabling environment to increase the full and meaningful participation of women in the peace process and in decision-making at the local level, and to contribute to gender-sensitive structural changes of norms, laws and institutions, also in relation to key protection issues faced by women and girls,

This project will work on three short-term objectives:                                                

1. More Syrian women will have become influential leaders in the peace process, in key sectors, and in decision-making at the local level (with increasing support from male leaders) 
2. First steps in structural and sustainable changes of harmful gender norms, laws and institutions 
3. Increased awareness amongst targeted female and male leaders on key protection issues faced by Syrian women and girls 

To realise these outcomes, the consortium will implement three intervention strategies, each of which is aligned with the three approaches of the National Action Plan (NAP) for UNSCR 1325, namely empowerment, knowledge sharing, and advocacy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCSD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41198677" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hivos</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41198677" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hivos</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs The Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rabitat Al Mouwatana</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SWFP</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hivos</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@hivos.org</email>
   <website>https://www.hivos.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">741511</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">656516</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">601973</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">499998</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-20">521849</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29646" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTRYOFFOREIG</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-17">320000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29646" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTRYOFFOREIG</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-24">300155</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29646" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTRYOFFOREIG</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-10-18">37183</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29646" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTRYOFFOREIG</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-10-18">620155</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29646" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTRYOFFOREIG</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">175660</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29646" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTRYOFFOREIG</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-07-03">475000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29646" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTRYOFFOREIG</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">24998</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29646" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTRYOFFOREIG</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-11-25">2000000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29646" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-25">499998</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29646" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-04">216629</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-18">325147</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">278177</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">173469</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://iati.hivos.org/docs/EXTA_1339623.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">190513 Annex A - Hivos Annual narrative report SWPPS 2018, activity no. 29646</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-05-13"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C. More Syrian men and women have a greater understanding of - protection issues and - interventions for women and girls</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">C1 Number of interventions by beneficiaries to promote awareness of protection issues for Syrian women and girls at all levels (at Track I, II, and III)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the purpose of this programme, Track I, II and III are defined as follows: 
1. Track &quot;Track I stakeholders are defined as decision-making representatives of a state&apos;s government (this can include political, military and judicial representatives), representatives of international governing bodies such as the UN, the EU, and the World Bank, and international coalitions of high level decision-makers such as the Geneva process.&quot;
2. Track II stakeholders are defined as any actors who seek to influence Track I processes and decisions, but who do not have direct decision-making authority. This can include national parliaments or governing bodies, as well non-governmental bodies such as NGOs and educational institutions that work in multiple locations within Syria.&quot;
3. Track III stakeholders are defined as any non-state person or organization working at the local level who is influenced by the decisions of the Track I and II stakeholders, but does not have direct decision-making authority related to those decisions.&quot;</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activities associated with interventions by beneficiaries to promote awareness of protection issues for Syrian women and girls at all levels (at Track I, II, and III) were not activated in 2017. Progress was made towards preparing for these activities, which will be implemented from 2018 onwards.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="65">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2019, 19 local initiatives were implemented in coordination with women beneficiaries, focusing on promoting awareness of protection issues for Syrian women and girls at all levels (at Track I, II, and III). The initiatives focused on prevention and protection issues such as child marriage, physical abuse, domestic abuse, harassment (including verbal as well as public pressure on women&#x2019;s dress), and female detainees, among others.

The awareness campaigns took place across Hama, Hassakeh, Aleppo, Idlib, Suwayda in Syria; and in Turkey. The initiatives were held to correspond to the 16 days of activism as part of the International Day for the Elimination of Violence Against Women on November 25, 2019. Under a campaign named, Say It Out Loud, the initiatives were implemented in collaboration with the Peace Circles partner network, I Am She. The main objective of the initiatives was to combat
violence against women by raising awareness of the types of violence practiced as well as its impact.

The three workshop curricula were important in raising awareness of protection issues and interventions for women and men.  
- In 2019, 16 workshops were implemented, targeting more than 202 unduplicated women in 2019 across the Legal Rights Academy, Political Academy, and Gender Academy. These workshops helped to increase the knowledge of protection and prevention mechanisms of Syrian women in terms of their rights, laws, community attitudes, political systems and the peace process, while also encouraging a network of support and solidarity among participants. This is essential to build up the skills and resilience of Syrian women and men to cultural and conflict dynamics that threaten the safety of Syrians. 
- The protection needs of Syrian women were highlighted and actions to increase their protection were launched through the 19 community initiatives implemented in 2019. In particular, participating women were able to rapidly respond to the protection needs of women displaced in the northeast due to Turkish intervention, and in the northwest by GoS, to try to ensure that humanitarian aid was more sensitive to the specific concerns and needs these people.
- Through advocacy initiatives that compliment this programme objectives, the consortium was able to bring together nearly 100 representatives of 63 Syrian Track III and II CSOs together with INGOs and nearly 20 Track I representatives, sharing gender sensitive recommendations on civil society and women engagement in the peace process and NGO sector in Syria.

Consortium partners also participated in two program advocacy missions, which highlighted protection issues facing Syrian women and men, as well as recommendations to improve the gender inclusion and effectiveness of the political negotiations in Geneva. 

In 2020: 1- &#x201C;Speak it out Loud&quot; campaign, from April to july2020 aimed to combat violence against women especially during the pandemic of COVID -19 and to identify its impact on Syrian women and girls. During the campaign, I am She Network has advocated for protecting women from domestic, economic, and social violence.

2- Two initiatives Psychosocial support initiative for women of Urfa and Gaziantep peace circles to lead psychosocial support for women affected by COVID-19 pandemic from Sep to Oct2020.

43 reported by CL</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B First steps in structural and sustainable changes of -harmful gender norms, -laws and -institutions.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B3 Number of CSOs from different sectors of society at track I, II, and III, that collaborate and/or participated in multi-stakeholder initiatives</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the purpose of this programme, Track I, II and III are defined as follows: 
1. Track &quot;Track I stakeholders are defined as decision-making representatives of a state&apos;s government (this can include political, military and judicial representatives), representatives of international governing bodies such as the UN, the EU, and the World Bank, and international coalitions of high level decision-makers such as the Geneva process.&quot;
2. Track II stakeholders are defined as any actors who seek to influence Track I processes and decisions, but who do not have direct decision-making authority. This can include national parliaments or governing bodies, as well non-governmental bodies such as NGOs and educational institutions that work in multiple locations within Syria.&quot;
3. Track III stakeholders are defined as any non-state person or organization working at the local level who is influenced by the decisions of the Track I and II stakeholders, but does not have direct decision-making authority related to those decisions.&quot;</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="77">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">63 CSOs from different sectors of society at Track I, II, and III, collaborated and/or participated in multi-stakeholder initiatives. Through advocacy initiatives that compliment this programme objectives, CCSD was able to bring together nearly 100 representatives of 43 Syrian Track III and II CSOs together with INGOs and nearly 20 Track I representatives, sharing gender sensitive recommendations on civil society and women engagement in the peace process and NGO sector in Syria. In 2020: At least 5 women have participated in consultation meetings before official meeting of the Constitutional Committee in August 2020. 

At least 5 women have been consulted with the principles that could be discussed within the constitutional process. 

3 reported by CL: #1: 3 videos on the 1325 law with IFE-EFI&amp;BC &amp; Heinrich-B&#xF6;ll-Stiftung &amp; Amica; #2: Awareness and dialogue session with Mobaderoon on the impact of Covid-19 on Syrian</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eight Syrian-led CSOs took part in one multi-stakeholder activity conducted in 2017. Twelve participants, represented these 8 CSOs with 4 from Track I and 6 from Track II and 1 from Track III.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B1 Number of interventions by male and female beneficiaries  to address and &#x2013;promote awareness on -gender biases and address and &#x2013;promote awareness on -gender biases and- gender inequality at all levels (Track I, II and III)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the purpose of this programme, Track I, II and III are defined as follows: 
1. Track &quot;Track I stakeholders are defined as decision-making representatives of a state&apos;s government (this can include political, military and judicial representatives), representatives of international governing bodies such as the UN, the EU, and the World Bank, and international coalitions of high level decision-makers such as the Geneva process.&quot;
2. Track II stakeholders are defined as any actors who seek to influence Track I processes and decisions, but who do not have direct decision-making authority. This can include national parliaments or governing bodies, as well non-governmental bodies such as NGOs and educational institutions that work in multiple locations within Syria.&quot;
3. Track III stakeholders are defined as any non-state person or organization working at the local level who is influenced by the decisions of the Track I and II stakeholders, but does not have direct decision-making authority related to those decisions.&quot;</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activities associated with interventions  by male and female beneficiaries  to address and &#x2013;promote awareness on -gender biases and address and &#x2013;promote awareness on -gender biases and- gender inequality at all levels (Track I, II and III), were not activated in 2017. Preparations to support these interventions are underway to launch them from 2018 onwards.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="35">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2019, 9 of the 19 local initiatives implemented by male and female beneficiaries, with the support of consortium partners CCSD and SWFP, to address gender biases and gender inequality at all levels. These activities that targeted parents and teachers to prevent early marriage in Idlib; 2 GBV training for civilian leaders, and 12 meetings with local women leaders in the I Am She network to improve their consideration of the protection issues in their work. In 2020: &quot;1- Consultation process: 500 questionnaires were worked on with Syrian women about the needs of women and the obstacles facing women in political participation and the impact of COVID19, and the most important recommendations were drawn up and submitted directly to OSE

2- Meetings within a group Space for Collaboration  that includes Syrian women from tracks I, II, III to prepare for the consultations of CSSR meeting before Brussel Conference. 

3- A training course for the Developmental Academy was carried out for 2 days, from 26-27 September 2020with the total participation of 18  people, by 1 man and 17 women, from the Peace Circles of Urfa and Gaziantep. The training course aimed to increase women&apos;s awareness of the developments on gender norms and laws.


4-CCSD  support the launch of a campaign to fill the gender technology gap from September  2020, titled &#x201C;Technology for All (#technologyforall)&#x201D;, by publishing awareness posters with expressions supporting the importance of providing support and encouragement for women with technology.&quot;

7 reportted by CL: In active interventions during the work of the constitutional committee, in the constitutional law and its monitoring practices/mechanisms&apos; discussions, in the Charter for a New Syria, in the Paper on &apos;Coexistence&quot;, in the Gender Lens Approach of all CL projects, Research Paper on the Impact of Covid-19 on increasing violence against women, awareness session on Covid-19 

1 reported by SWFP: In coordiantion with 2 partner organizations, which are Josour for building the Syrian Civic Organizations, and Peace forum of Syrian women a companies agaist harmful Gender Norms was organized. Each orgnaization conducted different activiteis such as training, brouchure, and dialogue sessions</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B2 Number of instances of collaboration between individuals from different sectors of society at track I, II, and III</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the purpose of this programme, Track I, II and III are defined as follows: 
1. Track &quot;Track I stakeholders are defined as decision-making representatives of a state&apos;s government (this can include political, military and judicial representatives), representatives of international governing bodies such as the UN, the EU, and the World Bank, and international coalitions of high level decision-makers such as the Geneva process.&quot;
2. Track II stakeholders are defined as any actors who seek to influence Track I processes and decisions, but who do not have direct decision-making authority. This can include national parliaments or governing bodies, as well non-governmental bodies such as NGOs and educational institutions that work in multiple locations within Syria.&quot;
3. Track III stakeholders are defined as any non-state person or organization working at the local level who is influenced by the decisions of the Track I and II stakeholders, but does not have direct decision-making authority related to those decisions.&quot;</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="83">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There were 49 instances of collaboration between individuals from different sectors of society at Track I, II, and III, in 2019. This includes:
- 42 events under the 19 local initiatives in 2019, which were launched by beneficiaries in collaboration with implementing parties to improve coordination and communications among beneficiaries at all levels (Track I, II and III);
- 1 Annual Coordination and Networking Conference in July 2019; 
- 6 advocacy events, that brought together Syrian CSOs (including consortium partners) with individuals at Track I and II. In 2020: 1- Three women from I am She Network participated in the consultations of CSSR in Turkey. 

2- Three women from I am She Network were part of the meeting with SE Geir Pederson and they brought to the discussion the voices and recommendations of civil society from the local level.


3- Two women that we worked with participated in Brussels Conference and side events and consultation.  

 
4- One woman participated in the UNDP invitatives &quot; Progress prgram&quot; 

5- Two woman participated in the Euro-Mediterranean Initiative to map the work of the GBV in Syria. 

6- CCSD organized at least three meetings to support women who will be involved in Brussel conference in June and also between women leaders to cope with COVID-19

7- One woman participated in in the fifth conference to Empower Arab Women to Work With International Organizations and the Role of Women in Sustainable Development in 11Oct2020

8- The participation of 4 women from the Urfa circle in a session with Hadi Al-Bahra, the co-chair of the Constitutional Committee, in27Sep2020 and they discussed with him the most important issues of concern to the Syrians, and they must be included in the constitution

9- Three members of the I Am She Network (the coordinator of the network and two members from the Urfa Circle) participated in the two-day regional consultations of the Civil Society Support Chamber in Turkey and in the preparatory meetings with the Syrians.

26 reported by CL</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="62">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There were three instances of collaboration between individuals from different sectors of society at track I, II, and III, as part of this programme&#x2019;s activities in 2017.
The first instance of collaboration was through 8 consultations with 8 different people (7 women and 1 man) representing 5 CSOs. Of these CSOs 4 were Syrian representing different political affiliations; 4 of the participants were from Track I and 4 from Track II. The consultations sought diverse input and feedback for planned multi-stakeholder events in 2017 and 2018.
The second instance of collaboration was through a two day multi-stakeholder meeting in 2017. Two one-day dialogue meetings were combined, which brought together 12 participants (11 women and 1 man) of whom 5 were from Track I and 6 from Track II of whom 1 was a man, and 1 woman from Track III. There was 1 representative of the education sector.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA More women working within sectors and across divides actively engaged in efforts to change -structures, - norms and -policies to increase gender equality</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA2A Number of changes in regulations, policies or political statements at track I, II, and III, that try to further women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mid-term outcomes are measured annually to track medium to long-term change as a result of the programme. Mid-term outcome 2A is an indicator for the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and relates to Enabling Environment indicator EE1, Changes in Control. 

Regulations, policies or political statements by key personnel involved in the Geneva peace process at Track I and II are measured. Any regulations, policies or political statements at Track III focus on areas and beneficiaries targeted by the programme. 
For the purpose of this programme, Track I, II and III</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The monthly humanitarian and political updates ( 5 in total) from the SE to the security council included talking about the WAB and also there is some improvemnets on the impact of women in Mr. Pederson briefings. 

The Syrian National Coalition for Opposition Forces directed towards greater inclusion of women by forming committees inside Syria, the so-called Women&apos;s Office, and Turkey, forming committees to involve the eastern regions, mainly women.

The National Coalition invited women to contribute to the formation of the Syrian- Turkish committee

Poltical process-Consiutional Committee-UN: 1) Holding of the third session of the constitutional committee in August 2020. 2) The third block of the constitutional committee including members demanding a gender sensitive consituiton.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There were no changes in laws, regulations, statements and policies to further women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality that could be attributed to this programme&#x2019;s activities in 2017. This is due to the fact that the activities which target this change have been implemented from 2018 onwards.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Within Syria,  1) Removing the reservation on article no. 02 of CEDAW in 2017, 2) Repeal Article 548 of the Penal Code of 1949, known as the &quot;mitigating excuse&quot; for &quot;honor crimes.&quot;, 3) Drafting the UNSCR 1325 Action Plan. However, partners observed that this took place without any participantion from the civic organization, and with a complete neglect of the reality of the conflict in Syria. A notable shift was observed in furthering women&apos;s rights and gender equality through the discourse around the Syrian Constitutional Committee. This was difficult to quantify, however the Consortium observed that the Office of the Special Envoy was seen as instrumental in supporting demands for further women&apos;s rights and gender equality</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA3A Number of local communities that show an increase in positive attitudes relating to women&#x2019;s leadership and political participation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mid-term outcomes are measured annually to track medium to long-term change as a result of the programme. Mid-term outcome 3A is an indicator for the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and relates to Enabling Environment indicator EE2, Changes in values and norms</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">12 communities show an increase in positive attitudes relating to women&#x2019;s leadership and political participation in 2019.
In 2017, communities in 12 locations in Syria and in neighbouring locations were targeted.
In 2018, communities in 11 of the original 12 locations in Syria and in neighbouring locations were targeted.
In 2019, communities in 12 of the original 22 locations in Syria and in neighbouring locations were targeted.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In previous years, the Consortium was able to survey attitudes in local communities on women&#x2019;s leadership and political participation. Because of COVID-19 and resource constraints, a survey within local communities was not possible in 2020. However there were some indicators through local initiatives including advocacy campaigns against article nr. 03 in the Syrian constitution that states &quot;Islam is the primary source of legislation&quot; and an increase in the the number of the women that stand for people assemble election.

In previous years, 12 communities show an increase in positive attitudes relating to women&#x2019;s leadership and political participation in 2019.
In 2017, communities in 12 locations in Syria and in neighbouring locations were targeted.
In 2018, communities in 11 of the original 12 locations in Syria and in neighbouring locations were targeted.
In 2019, communities in 12 of the original 22 locations in Syria and in neighbouring locations were targeted.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The data on the number of local communities that show an increase in positive attitudes relating to women&#x2019;s leadership and political participation are not available as yet for 2017. Data collection showing annual changes in local communities&#x2019; attitudes to women&#x2019;s leadership will be conducted from 2018 onwards as the first phase of the all programme&#x2019;s interventions are initiated.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA4 Increase in protection of women and girls facing gender based violence</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is a percentage value!</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A needs assessment of over 648 participants of whom 93.5% were women revealed that 62% of all respondents reported feeling unsafe in their communities in 2019 while 38% felt safe on some level in 2019. In 2018, 58% of targeted respondents reported feeling unsafe. The majority of Syrian women do not feel protected from GBV.

This is a 4% decrease in women&#x2019;s self-reported protection, reflecting the long-term support needed to change GSBV and the continuing insecurity throughout Syria. The respondents may also be reporting lower levels of protection if they have increased their awareness of their rights and issues affecting them.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Data collection showing changes in the protection of women and girls in targeted locations will be conducted from 2018 onwards after the first phase of all the programme&#x2019;s interventions targeting this outcome are initiated.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In previous years, the Consortium was able to survey attitudes in local communities on women&#x2019;s leadership and political participation. Because of COVID-19 and resource constraints, a survey within local communities was not possible in 2020. 

In 2019, a needs assessment of over 648 participants of whom 93.5% were women revealed that 62% of all respondents reported feeling unsafe in their communities in 2019 while 38% felt safe on some level in 2019. In 2018, 58% of targeted respondents reported feeling unsafe. The majority of Syrian women do not feel protected from GBV.

This is a 4% decrease in women&#x2019;s self-reported protection, reflecting the long-term support needed to change GSBV and the continuing insecurity throughout Syria. The respondents may also be reporting lower levels of protection if they have increased their awareness of their rights and issues affecting them.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA3B Increase in local communities relating to women&#x2019;s leadership and political participation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is a percentage value!</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In previous years, the Consortium was able to survey attitudes in local communities on women&#x2019;s leadership and political participation. Because of COVID-19 and resource constraints, a survey within local communities was not possible in 2020. 

There was a 4% increase in 2019 in targeted respondents&#x2019; support for women&#x2019;s leadership.

In 2018, 84% of the 486 respondents reported support for women&apos;s leadership. This is determined based on answers to the statements; Yes, women can be leaders and Yes, I would vote for a woman candidate. In 2019, of the 648 respondents, 88% on average across the four regions supported Syrian women&#x2019;s leadership in answer to these two statements.

A caveat in the data should be highlighted: 93.5% of community representatives targeted were women and included those who had participated in this programme&#x2019;s training. As such, this data positively reflects the impact of this programme on women in the targeted community but the position of men is still ambiguous.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="24">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The data on the local communities&#x2019; relating to women&#x2019;s leadership and political participation, are unavailable as yet for 2017. Data collection showing annual changes in local communities&#x2019; attitudes to women&#x2019;s leadership will be conducted from 2018 onwards after the first phase of the all programme&#x2019;s interventions targeting this outcome are initiated.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA2B Inclusion of gender-sensitive language in statements, laws, policies, agreements, etc.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">this is a percentage value!
In order to measure the gender-sensitivity in key laws, policies, and agreements at the Track I, II and III levels, the following checklist of questions and scores were designed and applied: 
1.	Are masculine and feminine forms used?
2.	Are gender stereotypes avoided? For example, connecting weakness to women or suggesting that women are only housewives or victims.
3.	Are women and girls mentioned in the content of the law, policy, statement or document?
4.	Are the particular needs, experiences and perspectives of women and girls included in the document? (For example, a policy about education may highlight that women face more barriers to access education because of cultural practices that promote men or early marriage etc.).  
5.	Are women and girls given equal rights to men in the document (for example a law stating that women have the same rights to divorce as men)
6.	Is the difference between the impact of a policy, procedure, or event on women versus men acknowledged? 

The gender sensitivity of statements, laws, policies, agreements, are scored in the following manner:
&#x2022;	If 2 out of the 6 criteria are met then the document/statement/policy is considered to be slightly gender sensitive / inclusive of women and girls.
&#x2022;	If 3 out of 6 of these criteria are met then the document/statement/policy is considered to be basically gender sensitive / inclusive of women and girls.
&#x2022;	If 5 or more of these criteria are met then the document/statement/policy is considered to be highly gender sensitive / inclusive of women and girls. 
Regulations, policies or political statements by key personnel involved in the Geneva peace process at Track I and II are measured. Any regulations, policies or political statements at Track III focus on areas and beneficiaries targeted by the programme.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">See above &amp; 1) Removing the reservation on article no. 02 of CEDAW in 2017, 2) Repeal Article 548 of the Penal Code of 1949, known as the &quot;mitigating excuse&quot; for &quot;honor crimes.&quot;, 3) Drafting the UNSCR 1325 Action Plan. However, without any participantion from civil organizations.

The feminist and Civil organizations: 1) Advocacy campaigns against article nr. 03 in the Syrian constitution that state &quot;Islam is the primary source of legislation&quot; 2) Compaigns, studies, and manuals on the &quot;Gender sensitive consiutions&quot; and &quot;Gender senstiive legilsations&quot;: 3) consucting a number of national consultation for developing guidlines for implementation of women, peace and Security Agenda in Syria.4) Incrasing the number of the women that stand for people assemble election. Noticeable increase in the number of CSOs using gender sensitive language in their informative materials, bylaws and code of conducts, to showcase a higher participation of women in decision-making positions, as well as Empowerment Team Leads. However, unlike previous years, because of resource and capacity constraints, as well as the impact of COVID-19, the Consortium could not survey a representative sample of CSOs as in previous years.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="27">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The data on the Inclusion of gender-sensitive language in statements, laws, policies, agreements is related to medium-to long-term outcomes and are measured annually at the end of all completed programme activities. The data for 2018 is as yet unavailable. Data collection showing annual changes in gender-sensitive language will be available from 2018 onwards after the first phase of all the programme&#x2019;s activities targeting this outcome are initiated.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA1 Increase the number of capable women in decision making bodies at all tracks including positions in the peace process and other key sectors</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">this is a percentage value!
&#x201C;Decision-making&#x201D; position is defined as an independent worker, department head, manager or organizational director. 
The key sectors being measured are: health, education, media, business and local government. 
For the purpose of this programme, Track I, II and III are defined as follows: 
1. Track &quot;Track I stakeholders are defined as decision-making representatives of a state&apos;s government (this can include political, military and judicial representatives), representatives of international governing bodies such as the UN, the EU, and the World Bank, and international coalitions of high level decision-makers such as the Geneva process.&quot;
2. Track II stakeholders are defined as any actors who seek to influence Track I processes and decisions, but who do not have direct decision-making authority. This can include national parliaments or governing bodies, as well non-governmental bodies such as NGOs and educational institutions that work in multiple locations within Syria.&quot;
3. Track III stakeholders are defined as any non-state person or organization working at the local level who is influenced by the decisions of the Track I and II stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The data on the number of capable women in decision making bodies at all tracks including positions in the peace process and other key sectors, is related to medium-to long-term outcomes and are measured annually at the end of all completed programme activities. The data for 2018 is as yet unavailable. Data collection showing annual changes will be available from 2018 onwards after the first phase of all the programme&#x2019;s activities targeting this outcome are initiated.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There has been a 3.5 percent decrease in the number of women leaders in the target institutions (please see baseline Annex table 1 for more details). In 2019, there were 930 women (representing 46.5%) out of total membership of 2001 across 46 institutions at Track I, II, and III. In 2018, there were 920 (representing 50%) out of total membership of 1,838 across 46 institutions at Track I, II, and III. While there was a decrease in the overall number in 2018, women&#x2019;s membership in these decision-making bodies seems to have increased overall.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This data is not yet available for 2020. 106 people have had their capacity built in order to be involved in decision-making.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A. More Syrian women will have become influential leaders -in the peace process, -in key sectors, and -in decision-making at the local level (with increasing support from male leaders)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A2 Number of events launched by beneficiaries in collaboration with implementing parties CCSD, SL4C, SWFP to improve coordination and communications among beneficiaries at all levels (Track I, II and III)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the purpose of this programme, Track I, II and III are defined as follows: 
1. Track &quot;Track I stakeholders are defined as decision-making representatives of a state&apos;s government (this can include political, military and judicial representatives), representatives of international governing bodies such as the UN, the EU, and the World Bank, and international coalitions of high level decision-makers such as the Geneva process.&quot;
2. Track II stakeholders are defined as any actors who seek to influence Track I processes and decisions, but who do not have direct decision-making authority. This can include national parliaments or governing bodies, as well non-governmental bodies such as NGOs and educational institutions that work in multiple locations within Syria.&quot;
3. Track III stakeholders are defined as any non-state person or organization working at the local level who is influenced by the decisions of the Track I and II stakeholders, but does not have direct decision-making authority related to those decisions.&quot;</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="46">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Events launched by beneficiaries in collaboration with implementing programme partners to improve coordination and communications among beneficiaries at all levels (Track I, II and III), were not initiated in 2017. These interventions will begin from 2018 onwards.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="101">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There were 101 events under the local initiatives, which were launched by beneficiaries in collaboration with implementing parties to improve coordination and communications among beneficiaries at all levels (Track I, II and III). Which included all aspects of coordination, through which the network worked to implement the initiatives with the highest efficiency and quality. The sub-activities included  (preparation meetings, coordinate and evaluate activities, discussion forums, awareness seminars, follow-up visits, focus group discussions,  training workshops, orientation sessions,  campaigns, an awareness film presentation, and a needs assessment questionnaire.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A3 Number of CSOs that engage in local initiatives</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Short-term outcome A3 is an indicator for the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and relates to component 1, Capacity to commit and act.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="157">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">157 entities (organizations, association, task force and media institutions), were targeted across the education, business, health, media, and civil society organizations sectors.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="39">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interventions associated with local initiatives initiated and led by CSOs were not activated in 2017.  Program partners are implementing local initiatives in 2018.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1 Number of local &#x130;nitiatives initiated and led by women beneficiaries</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interventions associated with local initiatives initiated and led by women beneficiaries were not activated in 2017.  Program partners are implementing local initiatives in 2018.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Up to 2020, there were 30 initiatives designed, initiated, and led by women beneficiaries with the coordination and support of consortium partner, 10 had implemented CCSD by collaboration with I am she Network, as well as 9had implemented SWFP by collaboration with the local implementing partners. Under these 19 initiatives, 117 different activities were implemented to promote or address GBV and gender inequality.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
