<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://data.mcc.gov/" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:mcc="https://data.mcc.gov/ns#" xmlns:usg="http://foreignassistance.gov/iati#">
  <iati-identifier>US-18-MWI-2750BXCOMD</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-18" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malawi-Compact</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malawi&apos;s $350.7 million Millennium Challenge Corporation compact is a single-sector program designed to increase incomes and reduce poverty by revitalizing Malawi&apos;s power sector and improving the availability, reliability and quality of the power supply.  The compact&apos;s Power Sector Revitalization Project seeks to increase the capacity and stability of the national electricity grid and bolster the efficiency and sustainability of hydropower generation.  Project activities will support an enabling environment for future expansion by strengthening sector institutions and enhancing sector regulation and governance. As a result of these activities, the compact intends to reduce energy costs to enterprises and households and improve productivity in the agriculture, manufacturing and service sectors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-8" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Account - Malawi</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States of America</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administration &amp; Finance</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Open Data Team</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>202-521-3618</telephone>
   <email>opendata@mcc.gov</email>
   <website>data.mcc.gov</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1099 14th Street NW, Suite 700, Washington, DC 20005-3550</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malawi</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/star-report-malawi">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malawi STAR Report: Full Program Lifecycle Report</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A06"></category>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/where-we-work/err/malawi-compact">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Rate of Return</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A03"></category>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/malawi-compact-me-plan">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malawi Compact Monitoring and Evaluation Plan</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A03"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/evalbrief-042019-malawi-power">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fostering sustainability in Malawi?s electricity sector</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/evalbrief-032521-malawi-idp">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving Power Quality and Reliability in Malawi</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/evalbrief-041620-mwi-enrm">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving land management for hydropower generation in Malawi</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/news-and-events/feature/malawi-compact-closeout">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malawi Compact Closeout</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/evalbrief-041620-mwi-enrm-cs">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting sustainable land management in Malawi</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.mcc.gov/content/uploads/2017/05/Malawi_CA_withCover.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malawi Constraints Analysis</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/compact-malawi">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Compact between MCC and Malawi</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <category code="A11"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/star-report-malawi">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malawi Compact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A06"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/malawi-compact-kpi">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malawi Compact Key Performance Indicators</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MW" type="1"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MW2-2750BX69GD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MW2-2750BXDILD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MWI-2750BX69GD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MWI-2750BXCOMD-GENDER" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MWI-2750BXCOMD-MON &amp; EVAL" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MWI-2750BXCOMD-NA" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MWI-2750BXCOMD-NRM" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MWI-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MWI-2750BXCOMD-PWR REFORM" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MWI-2750BXCOMD-PWR" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MWI-2750BXDILD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) MCA-Malawi has delivered in form and substance satisfactory to MCC a completed Disbursement Request, together with the Periodic Reports covering the related Disbursement Period.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">10) MCC has determined in its sole discretion that there has been no material negative finding in any financial audit report delivered in accordance with the Compact and Audit Plan, for the prior two quarters (or such other period as the Audit Plan may require).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">11) MCC has determined in its sole discretion that any Taxes paid with MCC Funding through the date ninety (90) days prior to the start of the applicable Disbursement Period have been reimbursed by the Government in full in accordance with Section 2.8(c) of the Compact.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">12) MCC has determined in its sole discretion that the Government has satisfied all of its payment obligations, including any insurance, indemnification, tax payments or other obligations, and contributed all resources required from it, under the Compact, this Agreement and any Supplemental Agreement.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">13) MCC has determined in its sole discretion that MCC does not have grounds for concluding that any matter certified to it in the related MCA Disbursement Certificate, Procurement Agent Disbursement Certificate or Fiscal Agent Disbursement Certificate is not as certified.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">14) MCC has determined in its sole discretion that no act, omission, condition, or event has occurred that would be the basis for MCC to suspend or terminate, in whole or in part, the Compact or MCC Funding in accordance with Section 5.1 of the Compact.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">15) MCC has determined in its sole discretion that each of the Officers remains engaged, or if a position is vacant, MCA-Malawi is actively engaged, to MCC&apos;s satisfaction, in recruiting a replacement.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">16) MCC has determined in its sole discretion that MCA-Malawi has complied in all material respects with its obligations set forth in Section 2.1(d) with respect to the establishment of a BCS and its obligations set forth in Section 2.3 with respect to the establishment of an M&amp;E Plan.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">17) Prior to the second Disbursement of Program Funding, MCA-Malawi will have developed a comprehensive Social and Gender Integration Plan, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2) MCA-Malawi has delivered  in form and substance satisfactory to MCC copies of any reports from any technical (including environmental) auditors engaged by MCA-Malawi for any Activity delivered since the previous Disbursement Request.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3) MCA-Malawi has delivered in form and substance satisfactory to MCCa certificate of MCA-Malawi, dated as of the date of such Disbursement Request, substantially in the form provided by MCC (the &quot;MCA Disbursement Certificate&quot;).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4) MCA-Malawi has delivered in form and substance satisfactory to MCC a certificate of the Procurement Agent, substantially in the form provided by MCC (the &quot;Procurement Agent Disbursement Certificate&quot;).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5) MCA-Malawi has delivered in form and substance satisfactory to MCC a certificate of the Fiscal Agent, substantially in the form provided by MCC (the &quot;Fiscal Agent Disbursement Certificate&quot;).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">6) MCC has determined in its sole discretion that no material default or breach of any covenant, obligation or responsibility by the Government, MCA-Malawi or any Government entity has occurred and is continuing under this Agreement, the Compact or any Supplemental Agreement.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">7) MCC has determined in its sole discretion that the activities to be funded with such Disbursement will not violate any applicable law or regulation.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">8) MCC has determined in its sole discretion that the Implementation Plan Documents and Fiscal Accountability Plan are current and updated and are in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, and there has been progress satisfactory to MCC on the components of the Implementation Plan for any relevant Project or Activities related to such Disbursement.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">9) MCC has determined in its sole discretion that there has been progress satisfactory to MCC on the M&amp;E Plan and Social and Gender Integration Plan for the Program, the Project or relevant Activity and substantial compliance with the requirements of the M&amp;E Plan and Social and Gender Integration Plan (including the targets set forth therein and any applicable reporting requirements set forth therein for the relevant Disbursement Period).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EIF 1) MCA-M has established a Permitted Account, if such has not already occurred, if funding is to be disbursed to a bank account.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EIF 2) Each of the officers has been selected and engaged by MCA-Malawi and approved by MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EIF 3) Government has formed MCA-Malawi and the Board has adopted the Trust Deed and such Trust deed has been approved by MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EIF 4) MCA-M has developed the Fiscal Accountability Plan.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EIF 5) Compact has entered into force as provided in Art. 7 of the Compact.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EIF 6) MCA-Malawi has developed a complete Implementation Plan.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EIF 7) MCA-Malawi has developed the M&amp;E Plan, and the plan has been approved by the Board and MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EIF 8) MCA-Malawi has delivered to MCC the following documents, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC:  (i) a completed Disbursement Request, together with any relevant Periodic Reports;  (ii) copies of any relevant reports from any technical auditors;  (iii) a certificate of MCA-Malawi, in the form requested by MCC;  (iv)  a certificate of the Procurement Agent, in the form requested by MCC;  (v) a certificate of the Fiscal Agent, in the form provided by MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EIF 9) MCC has determined in its sole discretion that  (i) no material default or breach of any covenant, obligation or responsibility by the Government, MCA-Malawi or any Government entity has occurred and is continuing;  (ii) the activities to be funded with such Disbursement will not violate any applicable law or regulation;  (iii) the Implementation Plan Documents and Fiscal Accountability Plan are current and updated, and there has been progress satisfactory to MCC on the components of the Implementation Plan;  (iv) there has been progress satisfactory to MCC on the M&amp;E Plan and Social and Gender Integration Plan for the Program, the Project or relevant Activity  (v)  there has been no material negative finding in any financial audit report delivered in accordance with the Compact and Audit Plan;  (vi)  any Taxes paid with MCC Funding through the date ninety (90) days prior to the start of the applicable Disbursement Period have been reimbursed by the Government;  (vii)  the Government has satisfied all of its payment obligations, including any insurance, indemnification, tax payments or other obligations;  (viii) MCC does not have grounds for concluding that any matter certified to it in the related MCA Disbursement Certificate, Procurement Agent Disbursement Certificate or Fiscal Agent Disbursement Certificate is not as certified;  (ix) no act, omission, condition, or event has occurred that would be the basis for MCC to suspend or terminate, in whole or in part, the Compact or MCC Funding; (x) each of the Officers remains engaged, or if a position is vacant, MCA-Malawi is actively engaged in recruiting a replacement (xi) MCA-Malawi has complied in all material respects with its obligations set forth in Section 2.1(d) with respect to the establishment of a Bid Challenge System and its obligations set forth in Section 2.3 with respect to the establishment of an M&amp;E Plan</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For any CIF Disbursement occurring after this Compact has entered into force in accordance with Article 7, (a) MCC has received copies of any reports due from any technical consultants (including environmental auditors engaged by MCA-Malawi) for any Activity since the previous Disbursement Request, and all such reports are in form and substance satisfactory to MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For any CIF Disbursement occurring after this Compact has entered into force in accordance with Article 7, (b) the Implementation Plan Documents and Fiscal Accountability Plan are current and updated and are in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, and there has been progress satisfactory to MCC on the components of the Implementation Plan for the Projects or any relevant Activities related to such CIF Disbursement.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For any CIF Disbursement occurring after this Compact has entered into force in accordance with Article 7, (c) there has been progress satisfactory to MCC on the M&amp;E Plan and Social and Gender Integration Plan for the Program or Project or relevant Activity and substantial compliance with the requirements of the M&amp;E Plan and Social and Gender Integration Plan (including the targets set forth therein and any applicable reporting requirements set forth therein for the relevant Disbursement Period).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For any CIF Disbursement occurring after this Compact has entered into force in accordance with Article 7, (d) there has been no material negative finding in any financial audit report delivered in accordance with this Compact and the Audit Plan, for the prior two quarters (or such other period as the Audit Plan may require).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For any CIF Disbursement occurring after this Compact has entered into force in accordance with Article 7, (e) MCC does not have grounds for concluding that any matter certified to it in the related MCA Disbursement Certificate, the Fiscal Agent Disbursement Certificate or the Procurement Agent Disbursement Certificate is not as certified.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For any CIF Disbursement occurring after this Compact has entered into force in accordance with Article 7, (f) if any of the officers or key staff of MCA-Malawi have been removed or resigned and the position remains vacant, MCA-Malawi is actively engaged in recruiting a replacement.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to Initial CIF Disbursement:  1.(a)(i) The Government (or MCA-Malawi) has delivered to MCC an interim fiscal accountability plan acceptable to MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to Initial CIF Disbursement:  1.(a)(ii) The Government (or MCA-Malawi) has delivered to MCC a CIF procurement plan acceptable to MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to each CIF Disbursement:  (b) If any proceeds of the CIF Disbursement are to be deposited in a bank account, MCC has received satisfactory evidence that (i) the Bank Agreement has been executed and (ii) the Permitted Accounts have been established</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to each CIF Disbursement:  (c) Appointment of an entity or individual to provide fiscal agent services, as approved by MCC, until such time as the Government provides to MCC a true and complete copy of a Fiscal Agent Agreement, duly executed and in full force and effect, and the fiscal agent engaged thereby is mobilized</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to each CIF Disbursement:  (d) Appointment of an entity or individual to provide procurement agent services, as approved by MCC, until such time as the Government provides to MCC a true and complete copy of the Procurement Agent Agreement, duly executed and in full force and effect, and the procurement agent engaged thereby is mobilized</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to each CIF Disbursement:  2.(a)(i) The Government (or MCA-Malawi) has delivered, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC: (i) A completed Disbursement Request, together with the applicable Periodic Reports, for the applicable Disbursement Period, all in accordance with the Reporting Guidelines</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to each CIF Disbursement:  2.(a)(ii) The Government (or MCA-Malawi) has delivered, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC:  (ii) a certificate of the Government (or MCA-Malawi), dated as of the date of the CIF Disbursement Request, in such form as provided by MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to each CIF Disbursement:  2.(a)(iii) The Government (or MCA-Malawi) has delivered, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC:  (iii) If this Compact has entered into force in accordance with Article 7,  (1) a Fiscal Agent Disbursement Certificate and (2) a Procurement Agent Disbursement Certificate.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malawi-2750BXCOMD Results</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of households connected to the national grid (Female)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Outcome of Number of households that have access to a legal connection to electricity service from an electrical utility or service provider / Total number of households in the country.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="5" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of households that have access to a legal connection to electricity service from an electrical utility or service provider / Total number of households in the country. Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of households that have access to a legal connection to electricity service from an electrical utility or service provider / Total number of households in the country. Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7.6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of households that have access to a legal connection to electricity service from an electrical utility or service provider / Total number of households in the country. Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of households connected to the national grid</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Outcome of Number of households that have access to a legal connection to electricity service from an electrical utility or service provider / Total number of households in the country.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="7.1" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of households that have access to a legal connection to electricity service from an electrical utility or service provider / Total number of households in the country. Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of households that have access to a legal connection to electricity service from an electrical utility or service provider / Total number of households in the country. Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="10.7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of households that have access to a legal connection to electricity service from an electrical utility or service provider / Total number of households in the country. Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of households connected to the national grid (Male)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Outcome of Number of households that have access to a legal connection to electricity service from an electrical utility or service provider / Total number of households in the country.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="7.8" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of households that have access to a legal connection to electricity service from an electrical utility or service provider / Total number of households in the country. Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of households that have access to a legal connection to electricity service from an electrical utility or service provider / Total number of households in the country. Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="11.9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of households that have access to a legal connection to electricity service from an electrical utility or service provider / Total number of households in the country. Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Poverty rate or poverty gap (Male-headed households)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Goal of Number of people living below the poverty line based on PPP international dollars at National Level</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="36" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people living below the poverty line based on PPP international dollars at National Level Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people living below the poverty line based on PPP international dollars at National Level Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people living below the poverty line based on PPP international dollars at National Level Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Poverty rate or poverty gap (Female-headed households)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Goal of Number of people living below the poverty line based on PPP international dollars at National Level</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="47.2" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people living below the poverty line based on PPP international dollars at National Level Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people living below the poverty line based on PPP international dollars at National Level Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people living below the poverty line based on PPP international dollars at National Level Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Poverty rate or poverty gap</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Goal of Number of people living below the poverty line based on PPP international dollars at National Level</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="54" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people living below the poverty line based on PPP international dollars at National Level Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people living below the poverty line based on PPP international dollars at National Level Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="51.5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people living below the poverty line based on PPP international dollars at National Level Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Investment in power sub-sector - total USD million committed by financial close</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Outcome of Total USD$ million committed by outside parties by financial close</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="434.7" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total USD$ million committed by outside parties by financial close Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total USD$ million committed by outside parties by financial close Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total USD$ million committed by outside parties by financial close Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
