<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="ENG" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-30214009-SCC-LB</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-30214009" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="ENG">PAX</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Strengthening Civil Courage &#x2013; Lebanon</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Lebanon is facing multiple crises: an economic crisis, refugee crisis, political crisis and a health crisis. On top of that, young Lebanese citizens have been demonstrating for change against state corruption and the lack of accountability of the political elite. At the same time, the rights to freedom of speech and assembly is under pressure due to increasing measures by the government. In addition, the deteriorating context has contributed to an increase in Gender_x0002_based Violence (GBV) throughout the country. Therefore, the projection and expansion of civic space is a necessity to push for reforms, hold accountable the political elite and to combat the challenges Lebanon is facing.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="ENG">The activity is part of a larger programme implemented by the Strengthening Civil Courage Alliance, consisting of ABAAD &#x2013; Resource Center for Gender Equality, Amnesty International The Netherlands, DefendDefenders, PAX and their partner networks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="ENG">The overall objective is that Lebanon&#x2019;s civic change movement defends its civic space and acts as an inclusive collective to foster gender equality, address community tensions and hold local and national actors accountable for human rights violations. Specifically, the program seeks for activists and civil society to protect their civic space to freely express their concerns; for civil society and the international community to pressure Lebanese and international actors for greater protection of Syrian refugees, and for girls and women to have better protection and expand their influence on their economic, social and political rights.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="ENG">The target groups are (young) Lebanese activists and activist groups that can mobilise other people into a movement of social change; Lebanese partner CSOs who can create and protect fee and open cultural spaces; Lebanese local and national authorities; international actors; women and girl; men and boys; and, religious leaders that can be of significant importance in increasing the tolerance and acceptance of others in a divided society such as Lebanon&#x2019;s.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="LB-MOI-497" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="ENG">ABAAD &#x2013; Resource Center for Gender Equality</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-30214009-C380" ref="NL-KVK-30214009" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="ENG">PAX</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-30214009-SCC-LB" ref="NL-KVK-30214009" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="ENG">PAX</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-30214009-SCC-LB" ref="NL-KVK-30214009" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="ENG">PAX</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Various programme partners</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="ENG">PAX</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>iati-pax@paxforpeace.nl</email>
   <website>www.paxforpeace.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="ENG">P.O. Box 19318
  3501 DH Utrecht
  The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Lebanon</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="40" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Ending violence against women and girls</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movement, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">321065</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">350066</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">354565</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">353935</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">341315</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">322429</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="ENG">2021 SCC financing</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-30214009-C380" ref="NL-KVK-30214009" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="ENG">PAX</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-30214009-SCC-LB" ref="NL-KVK-30214009" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="ENG">PAX</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">238246</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="ENG">2021 Total Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">84183</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="ENG">2021 Total disbursements</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-30214009-SCC-LB" ref="NL-KVK-30214009" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="ENG">PAX</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Various programme partners</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">1725464</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="ENG">SCC budget 2021-2025 for PAX projects</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-30214009-C380" ref="NL-KVK-30214009" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="ENG">PAX</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-30214009-SCC-LB" ref="NL-KVK-30214009" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="ENG">PAX</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-30214009-C380" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Capacity Development Programme Partners</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="ENG"># of CSOs with increased L&amp;A capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="SCS051" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2022">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="ENG">1 partner (women-led) analysed  their L &amp; A capacities in one or more of 8 areas (A. Produce evidence, B. Inspiring trust among power holders, C. Represent constituency interests, D. Analyse the political arena, E. Produce tailored messages, F.Work collectively, G. Build rapport with power holders, H. Adapt to ongoing environmental changes), determining the need to prioritize strengthening capacity area A.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ENG">By the end of 2022, 1 partner (women-led) will have strengthened L &amp; A capacities in A. Produce evidence, specifically A1. research skills and A2. links with knowledge institutions/think tanks</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Output 3.4.3 National and regional campaigns launched on advocating women&#x2019;s economic, social, and political rights.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="ENG"># and description of advocacy initiatives carried out by partner CSOs for, by or with their membership/ constituency. (SCS4)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="SCS041" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="ENG">ABAAD will be identifying keyt messages that are aligning with GBV sector  to be used in the campaign aiming at ending violence agaisnt women and advocating for their rights and allowing them to voice outtheir concerns. the campaign will be launched in the 16 days of activism in november each year from now until 2025 (throughout the program). the campaign will also focus on the women status during  economic, financial and security crises taking place in lebanon. it will focus on the  unfair laws against women regarding sexual violence laws in lebanon</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ENG">5 campaigns will be launched; 1 every year throughout the program. this is in line with the GBV sector and the 16 days of activism that takes place november each year from 2021 until 2025.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Outcome 1.3 Lebanese partner CSOs have developed capacities to create and expand (online) gender-sensitive and inclusive civic spaces (including cultural and art spaces)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="ENG"># and description of CSOs using a Gender and Social Inclusion lens during all phases of the programming cycle with specific attention to youth (SCS8)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="SCS081" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Lebanese partners CSOs have no policies or approaches yet that promote inclusivity.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ENG">As part of the gender capacity self-assessments, 3 CSOs have all requested support to create gender and inclusivity policies for their organisations. There have been delays in the implementation of the gender capacity development from ABAAD due to contextual challenges</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ENG">CSOs will design and begin to implement gender and inclusivity policies with ABAAD, they will all participate in a gender-transformative programming training with ABAAD and hopefully begin to implement the learnings from that training, and one CSO will work with ABAAD to create referral pathways for survivors of sexual and gender-based violence</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="ENG"># and description of CSOs using a Gender and Social Inclusion lens during all phases of the programming cycle with specific attention to youth (SCS8)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="SCS082" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Lebanese partners CSOs have no policies or approaches yet that promote inclusivity.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ENG">As part of the gender capacity self-assessments, 3 CSOs have all requested support to create gender and inclusivity policies for their organisations. There have been delays in the implementation of the gender capacity development from ABAAD due to contextual challenges</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ENG">CSOs will design and begin to implement gender and inclusivity policies with ABAAD, they will all participate in a gender-transformative programming training with ABAAD and hopefully begin to implement the learnings from that training, and one CSO will work with ABAAD to create referral pathways for survivors of sexual and gender-based violence</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Programme Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="ENG"># of CSOs included in SPs (Strategic Partners) programmes (women-led)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="SCS061" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="1" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Partners are selected on the basis of their local legitimacy, creativity and ability to adapt, and the partnerships are based on trust, mutual learning, and horizontality. One partner is a recently-established CSO that in just a few years has gained great legitimacy in Lebanon, particularly with the families of the victims and other stakeholders related to the Beirut blast. They are incredibly well connected to international and national CSOs, to parliamentarians, to activists and to the protest movement that started in October 2019. A second partner is  one of the only CSOs operating in Northern Beqaa and works, through art, to engage youth and young people on civil and social issues. They are well connected in the region to some of the most isolated areas, and engage youth far beyond the area where they are based. They do different scale projects, and in the past have been funded by the EU and the US. They collaborate with the first partner  on the activist labs, complimenting each other with their different expertise. The third partner, based in Tripoli, is a new partner for PAX. They work in the Tripoli community on breaking taboos by creating open dialogue on sensitive issues through theatre and the arts. In a short time, they have created a really accessible and well respected safe space in the city. Each organisation we are working with are addressing issues on civic space through different methodologies.  Another partner  is a youth-led human rights organisation that PAX has been cooperating with since 2006. They started as a group of young volunteers and have developed into one of the key and recognised local human rights organisations in Lebanon. This partnership has developed into a strategic partnership in which we design projects and advocacy strategies together on the basis of the added value of each organisation.  PAX also has a partnership with a Syrian CSO that is active and registered in Lebanon. They are a key and large development actor, and the partnership is strategic, consisting of joint project design, implementation and evaluation. Two local partners are part of a consortium with PAX, 11.11.11 and Upinion that is co-designed and co-led by all 5 consortium partners.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ENG">For those organisations that are neither youth nor women led, we will work closely with them to ensure that activities, strategies and projects are implemented through a youth- and gender-sensitive lens</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ENG">The SCC Alliance strives to work with partners on increasing their organisational capacity and effeciency so that they can increase the impact they have within their communities. We will do this by providing financial core support to the partners to cover staff and rental costs, providing capacity development on request from partners on financial management, strategy building, gender transformative programming and so forth. As much as possible, we will facilitate partner-to-partner capacity strengthening so that partners can share their expertise, experience and knowledge between themselves to ensure it is very context specific and conflict sensitive. Some of our partners work in quite remote parts of the country and don&apos;t currently have much connection or relationships to other partners, so we see our role as facilitating and supporting these exchanges and capacity strengthening activities. In the case where  we work with an existing coalition of 5 organisations (2 local and 3 European)  the aim is to jointly work on adapting and renewing the work, joint programme development, fundraising and evaluation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="ENG"># of CSOs included in SPs (Strategic Partners) programmes (not youth or women-led)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="SCS063" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="1" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Partners are selected on the basis of their local legitimacy, creativity and ability to adapt, and the partnerships are based on trust, mutual learning, and horizontality. One partner is a recently-established CSO that in just a few years has gained great legitimacy in Lebanon, particularly with the families of the victims and other stakeholders related to the Beirut blast. They are incredibly well connected to international and national CSOs, to parliamentarians, to activists and to the protest movement that started in October 2019. A second partner is  one of the only CSOs operating in Northern Beqaa and works, through art, to engage youth and young people on civil and social issues. They are well connected in the region to some of the most isolated areas, and engage youth far beyond the area where they are based. They do different scale projects, and in the past have been funded by the EU and the US. They collaborate with the first partner  on the activist labs, complimenting each other with their different expertise. The third partner, based in Tripoli, is a new partner for PAX. They work in the Tripoli community on breaking taboos by creating open dialogue on sensitive issues through theatre and the arts. In a short time, they have created a really accessible and well respected safe space in the city. Each organisation we are working with are addressing issues on civic space through different methodologies.  Another partner  is a youth-led human rights organisation that PAX has been cooperating with since 2006. They started as a group of young volunteers and have developed into one of the key and recognised local human rights organisations in Lebanon. This partnership has developed into a strategic partnership in which we design projects and advocacy strategies together on the basis of the added value of each organisation.  PAX also has a partnership with a Syrian CSO that is active and registered in Lebanon. They are a key and large development actor, and the partnership is strategic, consisting of joint project design, implementation and evaluation. Two local partners are part of a consortium with PAX, 11.11.11 and Upinion that is co-designed and co-led by all 5 consortium partners.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ENG">For those organisations that are neither youth nor women led, we will work closely with them to ensure that activities, strategies and projects are implemented through a youth- and gender-sensitive lens</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ENG">The SCC Alliance strives to work with partners on increasing their organisational capacity and effeciency so that they can increase the impact they have within their communities. We will do this by providing financial core support to the partners to cover staff and rental costs, providing capacity development on request from partners on financial management, strategy building, gender transformative programming and so forth. As much as possible, we will facilitate partner-to-partner capacity strengthening so that partners can share their expertise, experience and knowledge between themselves to ensure it is very context specific and conflict sensitive. Some of our partners work in quite remote parts of the country and don&apos;t currently have much connection or relationships to other partners, so we see our role as facilitating and supporting these exchanges and capacity strengthening activities. In the case where  we work with an existing coalition of 5 organisations (2 local and 3 European)  the aim is to jointly work on adapting and renewing the work, joint programme development, fundraising and evaluation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="ENG"># of CSOs included in SPs (Strategic Partners) programmes (both yout- and women-led)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="SCS064" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="1" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Partners are selected on the basis of their local legitimacy, creativity and ability to adapt, and the partnerships are based on trust, mutual learning, and horizontality. One partner is a recently-established CSO that in just a few years has gained great legitimacy in Lebanon, particularly with the families of the victims and other stakeholders related to the Beirut blast. They are incredibly well connected to international and national CSOs, to parliamentarians, to activists and to the protest movement that started in October 2019. A second partner is  one of the only CSOs operating in Northern Beqaa and works, through art, to engage youth and young people on civil and social issues. They are well connected in the region to some of the most isolated areas, and engage youth far beyond the area where they are based. They do different scale projects, and in the past have been funded by the EU and the US. They collaborate with the first partner  on the activist labs, complimenting each other with their different expertise. The third partner, based in Tripoli, is a new partner for PAX. They work in the Tripoli community on breaking taboos by creating open dialogue on sensitive issues through theatre and the arts. In a short time, they have created a really accessible and well respected safe space in the city. Each organisation we are working with are addressing issues on civic space through different methodologies.  Another partner  is a youth-led human rights organisation that PAX has been cooperating with since 2006. They started as a group of young volunteers and have developed into one of the key and recognised local human rights organisations in Lebanon. This partnership has developed into a strategic partnership in which we design projects and advocacy strategies together on the basis of the added value of each organisation.  PAX also has a partnership with a Syrian CSO that is active and registered in Lebanon. They are a key and large development actor, and the partnership is strategic, consisting of joint project design, implementation and evaluation. Two local partners are part of a consortium with PAX, 11.11.11 and Upinion that is co-designed and co-led by all 5 consortium partners.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ENG">For those organisations that are neither youth nor women led, we will work closely with them to ensure that activities, strategies and projects are implemented through a youth- and gender-sensitive lens</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ENG">The SCC Alliance strives to work with partners on increasing their organisational capacity and effeciency so that they can increase the impact they have within their communities. We will do this by providing financial core support to the partners to cover staff and rental costs, providing capacity development on request from partners on financial management, strategy building, gender transformative programming and so forth. As much as possible, we will facilitate partner-to-partner capacity strengthening so that partners can share their expertise, experience and knowledge between themselves to ensure it is very context specific and conflict sensitive. Some of our partners work in quite remote parts of the country and don&apos;t currently have much connection or relationships to other partners, so we see our role as facilitating and supporting these exchanges and capacity strengthening activities. In the case where  we work with an existing coalition of 5 organisations (2 local and 3 European)  the aim is to jointly work on adapting and renewing the work, joint programme development, fundraising and evaluation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="ENG"># of CSOs included in SPs (Strategic Partners) programmes (youth-led)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="SCS062" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="2" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="ENG">Partners are selected on the basis of their local legitimacy, creativity and ability to adapt, and the partnerships are based on trust, mutual learning, and horizontality. One partner is a recently-established CSO that in just a few years has gained great legitimacy in Lebanon, particularly with the families of the victims and other stakeholders related to the Beirut blast. They are incredibly well connected to international and national CSOs, to parliamentarians, to activists and to the protest movement that started in October 2019. A second partner is  one of the only CSOs operating in Northern Beqaa and works, through art, to engage youth and young people on civil and social issues. They are well connected in the region to some of the most isolated areas, and engage youth far beyond the area where they are based. They do different scale projects, and in the past have been funded by the EU and the US. They collaborate with the first partner  on the activist labs, complimenting each other with their different expertise. The third partner, based in Tripoli, is a new partner for PAX. They work in the Tripoli community on breaking taboos by creating open dialogue on sensitive issues through theatre and the arts. In a short time, they have created a really accessible and well respected safe space in the city. Each organisation we are working with are addressing issues on civic space through different methodologies.  Another partner  is a youth-led human rights organisation that PAX has been cooperating with since 2006. They started as a group of young volunteers and have developed into one of the key and recognised local human rights organisations in Lebanon. This partnership has developed into a strategic partnership in which we design projects and advocacy strategies together on the basis of the added value of each organisation.  PAX also has a partnership with a Syrian CSO that is active and registered in Lebanon. They are a key and large development actor, and the partnership is strategic, consisting of joint project design, implementation and evaluation. Two local partners are part of a consortium with PAX, 11.11.11 and Upinion that is co-designed and co-led by all 5 consortium partners.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ENG">For those organisations that are neither youth nor women led, we will work closely with them to ensure that activities, strategies and projects are implemented through a youth- and gender-sensitive lens</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ENG">The SCC Alliance strives to work with partners on increasing their organisational capacity and effeciency so that they can increase the impact they have within their communities. We will do this by providing financial core support to the partners to cover staff and rental costs, providing capacity development on request from partners on financial management, strategy building, gender transformative programming and so forth. As much as possible, we will facilitate partner-to-partner capacity strengthening so that partners can share their expertise, experience and knowledge between themselves to ensure it is very context specific and conflict sensitive. Some of our partners work in quite remote parts of the country and don&apos;t currently have much connection or relationships to other partners, so we see our role as facilitating and supporting these exchanges and capacity strengthening activities. In the case where  we work with an existing coalition of 5 organisations (2 local and 3 European)  the aim is to jointly work on adapting and renewing the work, joint programme development, fundraising and evaluation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
