<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-17/DDA-3379/ETH-17/DDA-3379/H/INGO/6775</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Mobile Health and Nutrition (MHN) in Hudet, Moyale, Dolo Ado, Deghabur, Gashamo, Adadile, Khalafo, Erer, Shininle Woredas in , Liben, Jarar, Shebele, and Siti Zones-Somali region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children (SC) has been operational in the Somali region providing lifesaving medicines, building capacity of health workers, basic WASH services and supporting disease surveillance and disease outbreak response and coordination. The organization also has accumulated experience in supporting the health system through mobile health and nutrition team. In this proposal, Save the Children intends to implement interventions contribute to the response to the health and nutrition emergency situation through the establishment of mobile health and nutrition teams (MHNT). The aim is to enhance the coverage by health and nutrition essential services for the most vulnerable communities in Somali region pastoralists, IDPs, and hard to reach/ and not covered by any services. To promote filling up the immediate gaps of emergency response the prioritization of targeted woredas for additional MHNTs has been done jointly with RHB, ENCU and Health Cluster coordinator based on real needs and evaluation of coverage by the ongoing interventions with a focus on complementarities with nutrition response. Along the provision of basic primary health care (PHC), these teams will also contribute to the disease outbreaks, including AWD response, support routine immunization and eventual campaigns, bring maternal, newborn care and child services closer to the hard to reach areas of Hudet, Moyale,Dol Ado,Degahabur, Gashamo, Adadile, Khalafo, Erer and Shininle Woredas in Somali Region. The child services also include identification and treatment of common child hood illness. The MHNT is also expected to conduct nutritional screening, and manage of moderate acute malnutrition (TFU) and facilitate the referral of severe cases of illness and SAM with medical complication. Furthermore, the MHNT will contribute towards strengthening the disease surveillance system, outbreak risk monitoring, disease outbreak prevention and responses including community level AWD earlier cases detection and case management (community level) and control measures. Maternal health services will enhance the access to antenatal, postnatal and new born care coverage (ANC) including iron supplementation, provision of TT (Tetanus Toxoid) vaccination, identification and referral of high risk mothers, counseling on family plaining, breast feeding and HIV, Vitamin A and iron supplementation to lactating mothers, vaccination of the newborn along with managing other common child hood illness for the IDPs and local communities  in hard to reach areas of Hudet, Moyale, Dolo Ado Daroor, Gashamo, Adadile, Khalafo, Erer and  Shininle Woredas. The activities include the recruitment of staff and deployment of MHNTs, training of MHNT on management of integrated child hood illness, management of MHNT (reporting and movements schedules, chain of command, logistics) equipping the mobile health and nutrition team (MHNT) with required medicines and medical supplies, small diagnostic tools, recording and reporting tools, nutritional inputs for MAM and SAM, vehicles for field visits and referral, communication means. We will implement this Health and nutrition intervention directly while supporting the woredas health system and facilities through capacity building of staff, transport of medicines and supplies to the Health posts attached to the HFs, support of the work of HEWs, collection and transmission of health and nutrition reports to the Woredas health bureau and referral of patients when necessary. Early identification and immediate access to care of MAM and SAM patients through monthly screening of all children bellow 5 years of age, and pregnant and lactating mothers in all sites of each MHNT is essential for reducing avoidable mortality caused by acute malnutrition and illness. Save the Children also supports in same areas the functioning of SC  and access to safe water through water tracking in Adadile, Kebridar, Gashamo and Daroor woredas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-22" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-22" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ekin Ogutogullari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COuntry Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251(0) 478 510 297</telephone>
   <email>Ekin.Ogutogullari@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.93277841 43.32988331</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-09-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-02">434031.19</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-02">750873.96</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-6775">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-02">1184905.15</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302933797">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-10">947924.12</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303868610">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-12">213210.27</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
