<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-17/DDA-3379/ETH-17/DDA-3379/P/INGO/6897</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Protection Response for Most Vulnerable Groups in Somali Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed five-month project, will be a continuation of the emergency protection response project currently being implemented in Doolo and Jarar zones with funding from UN- OCHA. 

Under this project, Oxfam will  scale up the mobile protection teams (MPTs), composed of 3 Protection staff  and 1 staff from the Bureau of women and Children&#x2019;s Affairs (BOWCA) to continue  regular monitoring in the IDP sites in Gashamo, (Jarar zone),  Galadi  (Dollo zone). At least 2,000 IDPs will be targeted as direct participants in the protection assessment and monitoring.. The assessment will obtain information about protection issues, as  well  perspectives of IDPs on desired  solutions. The issues identified will be in line with the priorities outlined in the HRD Protection priority activities/indicators. The analysis will be shared with the Protection Cluster at both the national and regional levels through the Protection Working Group. Furthermore, the MPTs will identify individuals requiring specialised services and assistance and refer them to relevant organizations including Norwegian Refugee Council (legal assistance), GOAL and MSF (nutrition). 

To order to inform the referrals, services will be mapped in sites targeted under the protection monitoring process. Also, Oxfam  will follow up with the concerned organizations on the referred cases, maintaining a database and ensuring confidentiality throughout. Information from the service mapping will be shared proactively with IDPs during awareness sessions. These sessions will be conducted in close synergy with WFP, targeting the food distribution sites and beneficiaries covered. 
The MPTs will be supported to conduct awareness sessions in friendly spaces for women, men, girls and boys in targeted IDP sites. Relevant existing awareness raising materials produced by others will also be taken under consideration, especially those already produced by WFP while delivering the awareness sessions. Oxfam is proposing to introduce a shift from traditional fixed friendly sites to mobile ones: further discussion with site authorities and other  existing institutions (such as schools and health/feeding centres) and spaces will be identified as friendly safe for the target groups. Preference will also be given to those sites where food distribution is being undertaken by WFP. The safe spaces will target 1,000 women and 1,000 men with recreational activities and  500 girls and 500 boys.

Protection committees organized under the previous OCHA funded project  will be continually supported, while additional ones will be supported in the new location (Bokh). They will be partners in implementing the activities in the mobile friendly spaces, while also being trained on community-based protection. Furthermore, at least 120 staff of NGOs and government offices, in particular, BOWCA, and the Disaster Prevention and Preparedness Bureau (DPPB) will be trained on community-based protection.
Lastly, dignity kits will be provided to drought affected IDPs a total of 1,750 people will receive kits in each zone (1250 women and 500 men each in Doolo and Jarar). 

The project will be implemented in  Galaadi Woreda in Doollo, and Gashamo Woreda of Jarar. Oxfam will directly implement the project in Gashamo while OWDA will implement in Galaadi.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Manish Kumar Agrawal</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OI Humanitarian Programme Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 (0) 923775725</telephone>
   <email>MAgrawal@oxfam.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zerihun Endale</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 913 240976</telephone>
   <email>zendale@oxfam.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.93277841 43.32988331</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-08-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-26">280869.86</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-6897">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-26">280869.86</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303100116">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-02">280869.86</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="6305525608">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-31">1440.37</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
