<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-17/DDA-3379/ETH-17/DDA-3379/WASH/INGO/6716</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency WASH and AWD response to vulnerable IDPs and drought affected communities in Babile and Gursum Woredas of Fafan Zone, and Dollo Bay woreda of Afder Zone, Somali Regional state</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To address the dual impact of conflict and drought that have caused displacement of large populations in Somali region, the Danish Refugee Council (DRC) proposes to improve access to safe water, sanitation and Hygiene for internally displaced persons and hosting and drought-affected communities in Anod in Babile Woreda (Qoloji IDP site) and Gursum Woreda of Fafan zone and in Korhayle IDP site and Dollo Bay Kebele 01 and 02 of Dollo Bay woreda of Somali Region.
DRC&#x2019;s proposed action will meet emergency WASH for drought and displacement affected people in the above-mentioned areas of Afder and Fafan zone through extension of a permanent water supply system, construction of elevated tanks, provisions of water treatment chemicals, construction of water distribution points, NFIs and hygiene promotion.
The proposed DRC project will directly reach 30593 people in Fafan zone and 25,484 people in Dollo Bay woreda. In total, the action will benefit 56077 population in the targeted woredas of Fafan and Afder zones, of which 58% are IDPs. 
According to the IOM-led Displacement Tracking Matrix round 5 (June 2017), open defecation is practiced by more than 80% of the IDP sites. In Qoloji IDP site there are only 96 toilets for an IDP population formally registered at 32,952 persons. As the available latrines in the targeted IDP site is not enough for the population living in the camp additional 10 blocks of latrines with hand washing facility will be built to improve personal and environmental hygiene condition. In addition, 10 institutional latrines (3 by educational and health facilities in Qoloji site, 2 in schools in the Babile host community and 5 in Gursum) will be constructed to mitigate vector borne diseases, ensure privacy and security of women and children, and give easy access for disabled and elderly.
To meet need for adequate and safe water supply in a sustainable manner, DRC will also install river water treatment system, which will involve pumping of raw water from Genale river to onion tanks and flocculating the raw water before treating it with calcium hypochlorite. The treated water will be linked to one IDP site through 8km pipe extension and also provide sustainable water supply for 01 and 02 kebeles of Dolobay Woreda. This is expected to provide long-term sustainable water to these drought-affected areas. 
In addition, to promote good sanitation and hygiene practices and behaviors awareness raising activities will be done in all targeted woredas and IDP sites to reduce health risks and to foster resilient community. With community participation at the center, promotion activities will emphasize prevention of diarrhoea, proper hand washing, water treatment and water disposal among others. Promoting awareness on hygiene among community members, who are little informed about its importance, will be a key element of the intervention that will serve preventive and remedial to the spread of water related and water borne diseases like AWD.
Finally, WASH committees composed of men and women of all ages will be established and trained and will be encouraged to actively participate in groups so that they can voice the concerns and preferences of all men and women while implementing the WASH activities. 
The proposed project has been developed in consultation with the relevant regional and woreda authorities, such as the Regional Water Bureau (RWB) and DPPB, as well as the National and regional WASH Clusters, and that these relevant duty-bearers and key stakeholders support this proposal. DRC&#x2019;s proposed action will build upon long-term successful WASH interventions and presence from existing and previous emergency WASH.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-09" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-09" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anna Catherine de Laine</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programme</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 (0) 966 935 731</telephone>
   <email>a.delaine@drcethiopia.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">James Curtis</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 (0) 915 330 556</telephone>
   <email>j.curtis@drcethiopia.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.93277841 43.32988331</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-10-09"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-09">186380.61</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-09-09"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-09">565878.48</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-6716">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-09">752259.09</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302942750">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-13">601807.27</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303677756">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-23">150130.38</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
