<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-17/DDA-3379/CP/N/INGO/7637</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Nutrition response in drought affected nine woredas of Sitti, Jarar and Fafan Zones, Somali Region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children is proposing an emergency nutrition response to reduce the morbidity and mortality of under five children , pregnant and lactating women due to deterioration of the nutritional status among severely drought-affected communities in Erer, Gablalu, Ayisha ,Shinile, Harshin, Gashamo, Babile, Koran amp Daror woredas of Sitti, Jarar amp Fafan zone, Somali region. 
The project aims to improve the nutritional status of drought-affected communities, through the provision of life -saving and protective nutritional services. SC will implement the intervention focusing on the Community-based Management of Acute Malnutrition (CMAMfor the detection and rehabilitation of Severe Acute Malnutrition (SAM cases among under five children and Moderate Acute Malnutrition (MAM) cases among under five children and pregnant and lactating women (PLW). The project will also support and promote optimal IYCF-E practices of infants and young children under two years of age and support the nutritional needs and care of PLW. The project will take over and build on the workof the pervious EHF project which were under implementation in targeted Woredas from January 2017 and expected to endDecember 31,2017. Through this project Save the Children was able to   strengthen CMAM service ( 125 OTP, 13 SC amp 125 TSF sites) with the provision of CMAM materials, routine and second line drug for the treatment of SAM children,  Woreda health office (WHF) staff, Health Workers and Health Extension Workers  havebeen capacitated  with  CMAM ,IYCF and  nutrition supply chain management  trainings. WHFshave been supported with transportation of Nutritious products from the region to the HFs and during nutritional screening at the community level.  In addition to this CMAM reporting has been strengthened  from the HF to the zone level with the continues effort of onsite   supportive supervision and coaching, the recommend  IYCF practices  were advocated, promoted  , mother to mother support group  has been established, IYCF E corners where established Due to the mentioned accomplishments, experience and presence in the previous  project  SC  is best positioned to provide the below proposed interventions in this woredas.Some of the planned interventions include strengthening OTP and SC sites for the treatment of severe acute malnutrition, through supporting the existing government system in terms of gap filling, supportive supervision, on site coaching to overcome with high staff turnover in the area and availing of CMAM material, routine medications and logistical related support. SC will support government health posts and health centers to manage SAM cases through OTP Children admitted in OTP and treated with Ready to Use Therapeutic Food (RUTF) in a weekly basis, children with SAM cases with medical complications will be admitted in to the nearby stabilization center and treated with therapeutic milks Save the Children will also strive to strengthen the Targeted Supplementary Food program (TSFP) in all priority one woredas and all MAM under five children, Pregnant and Lactating Women (PLW) and OTP discharged children will be identified, targeted and provided with super cereals and plumy sub in monthly bases.  SC will promote the recommended practice of IYC-E practice, through strengthening of IYCF-E corner at the health facilities were lactating mothers will be be supported by skilled health workers and the established mother-to-mother support groups will also be strengthening for the purpose of convening key nutrition messages and experience sharing among mothers. Save the Children will implement this program in collaboration with regional Disaster Prevention amp Preparedness Office and World Food Program through sign tri-pirate agreement. Refresher trainings, capacity building including case findings, strengthening referral linkages, support of community mobilization efforts and defaulter tracing and on IYCF-E key messages will part of the</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ekin Ogutogullari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251(0) 478 510 297</telephone>
   <email>Ekin.Ogutogullari@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.93277841 43.32988331</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-07-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-19">1011334.65</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-7637">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-19">1011334.65</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303124927">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-24">809067.72</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304197020">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-09">167825.34</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
