<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FR-SIRET-4028868160030-02BKSAS</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FR-SIRET-4028868160030" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACTED</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Empowering marginalised girls in Afghanistan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is designed to increase access to and quality of basic education for marginalised girls in Faryab province, Afghanistan. It will address some of the main social, economic and practical barriers that prevent girls from accessing education in these remote, conflict-affected rural areas, where government provision is still unable to meet the scale of needs, and the majority of girls are currently out of school. This project will ensure at least 15,360 marginalised girls aged 6-19 can achieve basic educational outcomes, through supporting formal Primary school education, CBE basic literacy courses in villages, and through ACTED&#x2019;s innovative Youth Development Centres (YDCs), which provide a unique female-only space for girls&#x2019; social- and self-development; providing literacy/ numeracy courses and vocational training to enable both educational and economic empowerment.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022;	Output 1: 2,400 marginalised girls regularly attending primary schools
At least 2,400 girls in remote areas will be enrolled and regularly attending primary schools constructed through this project in areas where girls currently have no access to adequate school facilities. ACTED already has agreement with Faryab Department of Education (DoE) that this infrastructure will be handed over at the end of the project to ensure sustainable access to a complete cycle of primary education for girls in these communities. 
&#x2022;	Output 2: 12,240 marginalised girls achieve basic literacy/ numeracy skills 
By the end of the project, 12,240 girls will have graduated from literacy/numeracy courses, able to read and write in Dari to basic level and complete simple arithmetic. All graduates will receive certificates validated by Faryab DoE (Literacy Dept.), enabling them to (re)join formal schools. 
&#x2022;	Output 3: 720 marginalised girls completed vocational training courses
Through ACTED&#x2019;s YDCs, 720 marginalised girls will gain income generating means and skills through vocational training, improving economic independence by providing sustainable livelihoods.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
