<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x201C;Support to the blood transfusion system - Phase II&#x201D;</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">La presente proposta progettuale, di durata triennale, mira a sostenere l&#x2019;accesso al sangue e ai suoi derivati da 
parte dei pazienti che necessitano di trasfusioni, in particolare le donne in travaglio e in gravidanza, i neonati e i 
bambini con anemie gravi, in Sierra Leone. Il progetto costituisce la seconda fase, di consolidamento, del 
progetto in chiusura AID 011461 &#x201C;Creazione del primo Centro Trasfusionale della Sierra Leone/CTSL&#x201D; finanziato 
da AICS. Nell&#x2019;ambito di quel progetto &#xE8; stato costruito e reso operativo il primo centro trasfusionale regionale 
della Sierra Leone (Western Regional Blood Transfusion Center&#x2013;WRBTC)5
 presso l&#x2019;Ospedale Princess Christian 
Maternity Hospital (PCMH) a Freetown. Si tratta del principale ospedale pubblico materno della citt&#xE0;, costruito 
accanto all&#x2019;ospedale pediatrico Ola During Children (ODCH), entrambi con un vasto bacino di utenza e un alto 
tasso di mortalit&#xE0; dovuto alla carenza e alla gestione inadeguata del sangue. Il sangue &#xE8; indispensabile nei servizi 
di primo soccorso e di emergenza/urgenza, come nel caso delle complicanze durante il parto, in molti interventi 
chirurgici e trapianti, nella cura delle malattie oncologiche ed ematologiche. Il sangue, con i suoi componenti, 
costituisce un fattore unico e insostituibile di sopravvivenza. La sicurezza degli emocomponenti, oltre alla tutela 
della salute di donatori e trasfusi, costituisce l&#x2019;obiettivo primario di un servizio trasfusionale. 
Questa nuova proposta continuer&#xE0; a sostenere i servizi trasfusionali della capitale, operando presso il WRBTC e 
riabilitando gli spazi che ospitano la banca del sangue del Connaught Hospital, un ospedale generale pubblico 
molto importante di Freetown. In aggiunta, si amplier&#xE0; l&#x2019;impatto geografico dell&#x2019;intervento, tramite la 
costruzione di un nuovo centro trasfusionale regionale nel principale ospedale pubblico generale di Makeni, 
capoluogo della Provincia del Nord e il sostegno al nuovo sistema trasfusionale del paese. 
Il progetto &#xE8; stato scritto infatti congiuntamente al Ministero della Salute (MOHS), partner della prima e di 
questa seconda fase, e al responsabile del National Safe Blood Service (NSBS) program il cui National strategic 
Plan for blood safety indica la necessit&#xE0; di costruire quattro centri regionali per centralizzare le procedure 
trasfusionali, a cui dovranno fare riferimento le altre banche del sangue del paese. Questa proposta contribuisce 
quindi direttamente agli obiettivi del Piano, grazie alla costruzione del nuovo centro a Makeni, alla riabilitazione 
della banca del sangue del Connaught e al consolidamento delle procedure di raccolta, smistamento, 
lavorazione del sangue in tutti i siti di progetto, a partire dal WRBTC. La proposta prevede due risultati. R1 ha lo 
scopo di consolidare la produzione e la gestione del sangue mediante: a) Assistenza tecnica e formazione al 
personale dei Centri Trasfusionali di Freetown e Makeni e allo staff degli Ospedali che li ospitano, da parte di 
esperti6
 con lo scopo di continuare la produzione di emocomponenti o emoderivati (piastrine, plasma e globuli 
rossi), gestire correttamente il sangue e pi&#xF9; in generale i Centri trasfusionali. Verranno anche erogate delle 
borse di studio al personale dei centri di Freetown e Makeni per periodi di formazione in Italia presso il Centro 
Trasfusionale dell&#x2019;Ospedale San Raffaele (OSR) di Milano; b) fornitura di attrezzature e consumabili; c) 
riabilitazione leggera della banca del sangue del Connaught Hospital di Freetown e costruzione del Centro 
Trasfusionale a Makeni, in linea con gli standard internazionali; d) supervisione mirata alle banche del sangue 
periferiche e sostegno alla Governance del sistema a livello centrale. R2 riguarda il sostegno alla strategia 
nazionale di aumento della donazione volontaria del sangue, senza la quale i centri trasfusionali farebbero fatica 
a funzionare: &#xE8; focalizzato su campagne di comunicazione e sensibilizzazione rivolte alla popolazione</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This three-year project proposal aims to support access to blood and blood derivatives by patients in need of 
transfusion, particularly women in labor and pregnancy, newborns and children with severe anemia, in Sierra 
Leone. The project is the second phase, of consolidation, of the closing project AID 011461 &quot;Establishment of 
the first Transfusion Center of Sierra Leone/CTSL&quot; funded by AICS. As part of that project, the first regional 
transfusion center of Sierra Leone (Western Regional Blood Transfusion Center-WRBTC) was built and made 
operational at the Princess Christian Maternity Hospital (PCMH) in Freetown. This is the city&apos;s main public 
maternal hospital, built next to the Ola During Children&apos;s Hospital (ODCH), both of which have large catchment 
areas and high mortality rates due to blood shortages and mismanagement. Blood is indispensable in first aid 
and emergency/urgency services, such as complications during childbirth, in many surgeries and transplants, in 
the treatment of oncological and hematological diseases. Blood, with its components, constitutes a unique and 
irreplaceable factor of survival. The safety of blood components, in addition to the protection of the health of 
donors and transfused, is the primary objective of a transfusion service. This new proposal will continue to 
support the capital&apos;s blood services by operating at WRBTC and rehabilitating space that houses the blood bank 
at Connaught Hospital, a major public general hospital in Freetown. In addition, the geographic impact of the 
intervention will be broadened, through the construction of a new regional blood transfusion center in the main 
public general hospital in Makeni, capital of the Northern Province, and support for the country&apos;s new blood 
transfusion system. In fact, the project was written jointly with the Ministry of Health (MOHS), partner in the 
first and this second phase, and the head of the National Safe Blood Service (NSBS) program whose National 
strategic Plan for blood safety indicates the need to build four regional centers to centralize transfusion 
procedures, to which the other blood banks in the country will have to refer. This proposal therefore contributes 
directly to the objectives of the Plan, thanks to the construction of the new center in Makeni, the rehabilitation 
of the Connaught blood bank and the consolidation of procedures for collection, sorting, processing of blood in 
all project sites, starting from WRBTC. The proposal has two outcomes. R1 aims to consolidate the production 
and management of blood through: a) Technical assistance and training to the staff of the Transfusion Centers 
of Freetown and Makeni and to the staff of the hospitals that host them, by experts with the aim to continue 
the production of blood components or derivatives (platelets, plasma and red blood cells), properly manage 
blood and more generally the Transfusion Centers. Scholarships will also be provided to the staff of Freetown 
and Makeni centers for training periods in Italy at the Transfusion Center of San Raffaele Hospital (OSR) in 
Milan; b) supply of equipment and consumables; c) light rehabilitation of the blood bank of Connaught Hospital 
in Freetown and construction of the Transfusion Center in Makeni, in line with international standards; d) 
targeted supervision of peripheral blood banks and support to the Governance of the system at central level. R2 
concerns the support to the national strategy to increase voluntary blood donation, without which the 
transfusion centers would struggle to function: it is focused on communication and awareness campaigns aimed 
at the population to make them understand the importance of safe blood donation, as well as donation 
campaigns through mobile units, which will be accompanied by the necessary tests and controls on donors&apos; 
blood. In summary, the project will contribute to decrease the mortality rate, thanks to an increased availability 
of safe blood and blood</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AISPO - ASSOCIAZIONE ITALIANA PER LA SOLIDARIET&#xC0; TRA I POPOLI ONG/ON</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/04/0" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="12261" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12191" percentage="70" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medical services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end preventable deaths of newborns and children under 5&#xA0;years of age, with all countries aiming to reduce neonatal mortality to at least as low as 12 per 1,000 live births and under-5 mortality to at least as low as 25 per 1,000 live births</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end the epidemics of AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria and neglected tropical diseases and combat hepatitis, water-borne diseases and other communicable diseases</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support the research and development of vaccines and medicines for the communicable and non-communicable diseases that primarily affect developing countries, provide access to affordable essential medicines and vaccines, in accordance with the Doha Declaration on the TRIPS Agreement and Public Health, which affirms the right of developing countries to use to the full the provisions in the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights regarding flexibilities to protect public health, and, in particular, provide access to medicines for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-08">1791649.73</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AISPO - ASSOCIAZIONE ITALIANA PER LA SOLIDARIET&#xC0; TRA I POPOLI ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-17">1074989.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AISPO - ASSOCIAZIONE ITALIANA PER LA SOLIDARIET&#xC0; TRA I POPOLI ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
