<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5119006502-ZMB-13020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marie Stopes MDG 5</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Marie Stopes MDG 5</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase the opportunities for women and young people to exercise their sexual and reproductive health rights, thereby contributing to MDG 5 in Zambia (reduction in maternal mortality and universal access to reproductive health).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marie Stopes Zambia is a locally registered non-profit organization working to inform Zambians about SRHR and to provide comprehensive SRHR service. There is an unmet need for these services that the Zambian Government has not been able to meet. Marie Stopes could therefore support and complement the efforts done by the Zambian government to meet MDG 5. The organization is innovative in its methods to reach out to the rural population and have a track record of being able to provide tangible results.

The result strategy for development cooperation with Zambia (2013-2017) has improved health as a result area and one of the results under the result area is &#x201C;Increased awareness of and access to sexual and reproductive health services and the rights for girls and boys&#x201D;. Marie Stopes work is in line with the strategy and the specific SRHR result and also complements already decided Swedish interventions as their focus is more on SRHR services. MSZ is also special as it provides with a broader spectrum of services including safe abortion. The organization covers a large part of Zambia which few organizations do. Marie Stopes programme is considered relevant for Swedish priorities and results.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Marie Stopes Zambia &#xE4;r en lokalt registrerad icke vinstgivande ideell organisation som arbetar f&#xF6;r att informera zambier kring sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och r&#xE4;ttigheter (SRHR) och f&#xF6;rse landet med SRHR tj&#xE4;nster. Det finns ett icke tillgodosett behov av dessa tj&#xE4;nster som den zambiska regeringen inte har kunnat tillfredst&#xE4;lla. Marie Stopes kan d&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r st&#xF6;dja och komplettera de insatser som g&#xF6;rs av den zambiska regeringen att uppfylla millenniem&#xE5;let nummer 5. Organisationen &#xE4;r innovativ i sina metoder att n&#xE5; ut till befolkningen p&#xE5; landsbygden och har en historia av att leverera konkreta resultat.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marie Stopes Zambia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marie Stopes Zambia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="130" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population Policies/Programmes &amp; Reproductive Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1 - By 2030, reduce the global maternal mortality ratio to less than 70 per 100,000 live births.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.1 - Till 2030 minska m&#xF6;drad&#xF6;dligheten i v&#xE4;rlden till mindre &#xE4;n 70 d&#xF6;dsfall per 100 000 f&#xF6;rlossningar med levande barn.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.6 - Ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health and reproductive rights as agreed in accordance with the Programme of Action of the International Conference on Population and Development and the Beijing Platform for Action and the outcome documents of their review conferences.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.6 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och reproduktiva r&#xE4;ttigheter i enlighet med &#xF6;verenskommelserna i handlingsprogrammet fr&#xE5;n den internationella konferensen om befolkning och utveckling, Pekingplattformen samt slutdokumenten fr&#xE5;n respektive &#xF6;versynskonferenser.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">-3737.1311312945</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-10-01">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-28">-3737.1311312945</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida&apos;s support to Marie Stopes, MSZ, covered a 4-year period from 2014 to 2017. A no cost extension was granted from&#xA0; January 2018 to 30 April 2018 to spend the remaning funds and to ensure to avoid a gap period between the end of the support to the start-up of Phase II of Sida support to MSZ. The new support hence began on 1 May 2018.&#xA0;
Sida provided core support to MSZ for its country programme which has funded an increased and improved access to SRH service delivery via 4 key channels namely;
- Mobile Outreach service delivery, providing SRH services to women in peri-urban and rural communities.
- Static Centres, including youth focused Diva Centres, providing an assortment of SRH services including safe abortion services in urban communities.
- Social Franchises (privately owned clinics) supported by MSZ to provide SRH services in peri-urban communities
- Social Marketing, a technique of branding and marketing SRH products such as medical abortion drugs to clinics and pharmacies across the country.
Over the 4 years, the following results were recorded with regards to contraception:
1. MSZ provided 326,632 services to an estimated 326,632 women.
2. A total of 7761 women received tubal ligations, while 197,340 women received a LARC method of their choice.
3. Close to 159 000 short term contraceptive methods were provided to women and young girls.
During the period of January 2014 to December 2017, approximately 90% of MSZ&#x2019;s FP services were delivered through outreach at no cost to the client while 5% was delivered through Centres, and 5% through Social Franchised private clinics. MSZ also indirectly reached an estimated 67,500 safe abortion clients through the distribution of Medical Abortion (MA) drugs to selected registered pharmacies and clinics across the country. Of the total number of family planning clients, 60% earned less than $1.25 per day, while 13% were adolescent girls between the ages of 15 and 19.
With core funding from Sida , MSZ was also able to roll out its Telemedicine system as well as introduce the Diva Centres further improving access to SRH services for populations most in need.
By 2017, MSZ had seven outreach teams; two in the Copperbelt and one in each of the following areas: Solwezi, Central, Mpika, Nakonde and Luapula. In order to reach more remote areas, MSZ employed a &#x201C;camping model&#x201D; to reach the hardest to reach and underserved communities.
MSZ delivered Comprehensive Abortion Care (CAC) services in selected social franchise clinics over the four-year period. CAC services contributed 70% of CYP&#x2019;s generated under the SF channel. During the period under review, social franchise sites provided CAC services to 9,300 women in need of the service. In addition to CAC, MSZ also trained health providers in Post Abortion Care (PAC) in selected Blue Star Clinics. The number of PAC clients seen through the Social Franchise sites was 1000 during the four-year period.
An estimated 67,585 women purchased medical abortion products from pharmacies over the four-year period. 
During the four-year period, MSZ invested funding from donors such as Hewlett and Sida in researching the best ways to reach adolescents (urban and rural, married and unmarried). The proportion of adolescents accessing MSZ services increased from 7 percent to 13 percent.&#xA0;
In order to push policy issues regarding abortion through the Ministry of Health and Parliament, MSZ together with other civil society organisations with similar goals, established The Safe Abortion Action Group (SAAG) in 2015. The SAAG convened partners working to address safe abortion and assisted the government in revising the comprehensive abortion care guidelines to be launched in 2018.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51190065" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="2250000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Zambia 2018-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Zambia 2018-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
