<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5119006701-ZMB-15110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Office of the Auditor General OAG                 public administration</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Zambiska Riksrevisionen OAG                       offentlig f&#xF6;rvaltning</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen utg&#xF6;r ett tre&#xE5;rigt st&#xF6;d till Zambias riksrevision, Office of the Auditor General (OAG), f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra programmet &quot;Restructuring and Institutional Development Project, Phase Five&quot; (RIDP V) under 2015-2017. Sveriges bidrag &#xE4;r ca 40 procent av externa g&#xE5;vomedel, resterande andel kommer att ges av Norge, som blir s k Lead Donor. Insatsen har som &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;l att st&#xE4;rka OAGs administrativa och finansiella mandat, och &#xF6;ka kvalitet och omfattning (b&#xE5;de tematiskt och i antal) i OAGs revisioner, i syfte att bidra till mer effektiv och transparent f&#xF6;rvaltning av zambiska offentliga resurser och d&#xE4;rmed &#xF6;ka allm&#xE4;nhetens f&#xF6;rtroende och ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande fr&#xE5;n regeringsmakten i Zambia. P&#xE5; sikt f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntas resultaten bidra till &#xF6;kat demokratiskt samh&#xE4;llsstyre och minskad korruption i landet. Mer specifikt finns &#xE5;tta s&#xE4;rskilda programm&#xE5;l definierade i programdokumentet, som t ex omfattar expanderad revisionsverksamhet, intern styrning och personalv&#xE5;rd inom OAG, mer genomgripande anv&#xE4;ndning av ICT som verktyg f&#xF6;r revision s&#xE5;v&#xE4;l som kommunikation av resultat, och organisationsutveckling inom OAG vad g&#xE4;ller bl a finansiell styrning samt uppf&#xF6;ljning och utv&#xE4;rdering av dess arbete.

Tidigare faser av OAGs utvecklingsarbete har Norge samfinansierat med Holland, och hela tiden varit Lead Donor. Relationen mellan Sverige och Norge regleras i ett MoU, d&#xE4;r Norge tar en ledande roll i dialog och uppf&#xF6;ljning. Dock har Sverige liksom Norge ett specifikt avtal med Zambia, och bibeh&#xE5;ller d&#xE4;rmed administrativt ansvar f&#xF6;r det svenska st&#xF6;det i enlighet med insatsregeln.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The contribution is a three-year support to Zambia&apos;s Office of the Auditor General (OAG), to implement the programme &quot;Restructuring and Institutional Development Project, Phase Five&quot; (RIDP V) during 2015-2017. Sweden&apos;s contribution is about 40 per cent of external funding, the remainder will be provided by Norway, as the Lead Donor. The programme&#x2019;s overall goal is to strengthen OAG&#x2019;s administrative and financial independence and capacity, and increase the quality and scope (both thematically and in number) of OAG&#x2019;s audits. Further, the programme aims to improve accessibility of OAG reports, using ICT and other means to make reports more user-friendly for ordinary citizens as well as media, civil society and other stakeholders. These outcomes will contribute to more efficient and transparent management of Zambian public resources. In the long term, the expected results are increased democratic governance and reduced corruption in the country. 

More specifically, there are eight specific programme objectives defined in the programme document, including expanded audit activities, improved financial and human resource management within the OAG, more effective use of ICT as a tool both for auditing and communication of results, and enhanced monitoring and evaluation of its work.

In the earlier phases of OAG&#x2019;s development efforts, Norway and Netherlands have co-funded the programme, with Norway as Lead Donor. Now, Holland phased out its support, and Sweden will replace it. The relationship between Sweden and Norway is to be governed by a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU), giving Norway the lead role in dialogue and monitoring. However, both Sweden and Norway will have specific agreements with Zambia, which will ensure that Sida maintains administrative responsibility for the Swedish contribution.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intended outcome is to help OAG attain financial and administrative autonomy, and further enhance the scope and quality of its audits, in order to contribute to the prudent management of public resources and inspire the Zambians&apos; confidence in the accountability role of the OAG.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="12001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OAG/Office of the Auditor General</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="12001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OAG/Office of the Auditor General</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1304971.9431032233</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1519312.803132122</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1053001.053001053</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1304971.9431032233</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1519312.803132122</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1053001.0530010527</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-01">3914915.829309</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-09-28">1304971.9431032233</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-28">759656.401566061</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-28">759656.401566061</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-28">789750.7897507896</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-28">263250.2632502632</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-28">-1475.4533738378</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Restructuring and Institutional Development Project Phase Five (RIDP V) which commenced in July 2015 came to an end in December 2017. The project was co-financed with the Embassy of Norway who gave both financial and technical support through the twinning with the Nowegian SAI.
The RIDP V project consolidated some of the gains made in earlier phases of the project from RIDP I to IV and built on the capacity developed to conduct specialised audits while improving on the overall audit coverage. Some of the specific results gained during the project period include:
1. Capacity building: During the project period 493 staff were trained in various areas such as ACCA, CIMA, ZICA; Performance, IT, Forensic, and Regularity Audits; Quality Assurance, Human Resource Management, Records Management, Stakeholder Engagement and Financial Management. This resulted in increased competences among members of staff and consequently improved quality of work. The office also participated in capacity building workshops under Technical Working Groups under the Africa Organisation of Supreme Audit Institutions &#x2013; English Speaking (AFROSAI-E), International Organisation of Supreme Audit Institutions (INTOSAI) and Institution Development Initiative (IDI). As a result of increased capacities, the OAG were able to hold some courses in-house using members of staff as trainers. The OAG has also supported other African SAIs in competence development.2. Increased audit coverage:&#xA0; a number of audit programmes were undertaken as a result of increased competences and networking. This in turn helped to improve internal controls and systems in a number of public institutions. These audit included:&#xA0; &#xA0; -Water utility companies and Parastatles such as NAPSA;&#xA0; &#xA0; -Performance Audit of Ministry of Home Affairs &#x2013; Juvenile Justice System
&#xA0; &#xA0;&#xA0; -Ministry of Education: Education Development in Primary Education;&#xA0; &#xA0;&#xA0; -Ministry of Health&#x2013;District Medical Offices (DCMOs) and Distribution of Drugs;&#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; -Health Ministry of Agriculture&#x2013;Farmer Input Support Programme (FISP);&#xA0;
&#xA0; &#xA0;&#xA0; - Reconciliation of the Zambia Extractive Industry Transparency Initiative (ZEITI) declarations.Through the RIDP V project, the office managed to undertake some of the big audits, special audits and update its methods to inlcude emerging issues which were not going to be undertaken due to limited resources after the overall funding to the office was reduced resulting in only 69% of the budget being funded by GRZ Treasury in 2017 . With the skills gained in the use of Computer Assisted Audits (CAATs), the office has improved its analysis of data as was the case for the Payroll audits of selected institutions, forensic audits undertaken and for revenue collecting institutions. The use of (CAATs) helped improve the scope of the audits undertaken.&#xA0;The assistance received from the Governments of Norway and Sweden through the support to capacity development through RIDP V has helped keep the office to its current status of being one of the reliable public financial management oversight institutions in Zambia.&#xA0;
Audit methods are also continously upgraded to include compliance as well as development outcomes.
Strides have also been made to improve the OAG&apos;s adiministrative and financial autonomy through the enactment of the State Audit Commission Act No. 27 of 2016 and the Public Audit Act No. 29 of 2016, which are yet to be operationalised.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51190067" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
