<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12099A0101-ZMB-13020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RISE - empowerment of girls</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">RISE - st&#xE4;rka unga flickor</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Svenska ambassaden i Lusaka har approcherats av School of Public Health vid universitetet i Zambia f&#xF6;r finansering av en p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende forskningsstudie vars syfte &#xE4;r att hitta evidens att ekonomiskt st&#xF6;d och SRHR-kunskap minskar andelen ton&#xE5;rsgraviditeter. Forskare vid University of Zambia (UNZA) School of Public Health, i samarbete med forskare fr&#xE5;n Universitetet i Bergen (UiB), Norge, genomf&#xF6;r f&#xF6;r n&#xE4;rvarande en forskningsstudie f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka flickors egenmakt (RISE). Detta &#xE4;r en klusterrandomiserad studie (som p&#xE5;g&#xE5;r sedan 2016), som unders&#xF6;ker huruvida tidiga ton&#xE5;rsgraviditeter minskar och andelen flickor som slutf&#xF6;r &#xE5;rskurs 9 &#xF6;kar genom:

- Tillhandah&#xE5;llande av ekonomiskt st&#xF6;d till flickorna och deras familjer, och
- En kombination av ekonomiskt st&#xF6;d tillsammans med utbildning i sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och diskussionsm&#xF6;ten p&#xE5; lokal niv&#xE5; om sociala normer kan f&#xE5; st&#xF6;rre effekt.
Forskningsstudien har tre armar: 1) En kontrollarm, 2) En ekonomisk st&#xF6;darm och 3) En kombinerad arm med ekonomiskt st&#xF6;d, sexualitetsutbildning och diskussionsm&#xF6;ten p&#xE5; lokalniv&#xE5;. Studieenheterna &#xE4;r landsbygdsskolor i tolv distrikt i S&#xF6;dra och Centrala provinserna i Zambia. De st&#xF6;dber&#xE4;ttigade deltagarna &#xE4;r 5000 flickor inskrivna i klass 7 &#xE5;r 2016. De tv&#xE5; universiteten &#xE4;r partners i ett forskningskonsortium som finansieras av Norges forskningsr&#xE5;d och universitetet i Bergen. F&#xF6;rutom att generera bevis p&#xE5; effekterna av st&#xF6;d till flickor, st&#xE4;rker RISE-projektet ocks&#xE5; forskningskapaciteten hos masterstudenter och doktorander i folkh&#xE4;lsa vid University of Zambia. F&#xF6;r n&#xE4;rvarande deltar 7 masterstudenter fr&#xE5;n University of Zambia i datainsamling och f&#xE5;r handledning fr&#xE5;n RISE-projektet.

Sida har blivit ombedd att ge ytterligare finansiering till forskningsprojektet f&#xF6;r att m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra den ursprungliga planerade uppf&#xF6;ljningen av flickorna till 2020. Med nuvarande finansiering m&#xE5;ste projektet avslutas i slutet av 2018 vilket inte skulle ge tillr&#xE4;ckliga bevis f&#xF6;r att validera provresultaten.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The School of Public Health at the University of Zambia have requested financial assistance from Sida to fund an on-going research study (RISE) aiming to find evidence that financial support in combination with sexuality education empowers girls to avoid early pregnancies and drop out of school. Researchers at the University of Zambia (UNZA) School of Public Health, in partnership with researchers from the University of Bergen (UiB), Norway, are currently implementing the Research Initiative to Support the Empowerment of girls (RISE). This is a cluster randomized trial (running since 2016) which is examining whether early childbearing rates can be reduced and grade 9 completion rates increased in a rural Zambian context by:
- provision of economic support to girls and their families, and
- whether combining economic support with comprehensive sexual and reproductive health education and community meetings to address social norms, can have a greater effect.

The trial has three study arms: 1) A control arm, 2) An economic support arm, and 3) A combined arm with economic support, comprehensive sexuality education, CSE, and community meetings. The study units are rural schools in twelve districts in Southern and Central provinces. The eligible participants were 5000 girls enrolled in grade 7 in 2016.
The two universities are partners in a Centre of Excellence in Research funded by the Research Council of Norway and the University of Bergen. The primary objective of the Centre for Intervention Science in Maternal and Child Health (CISMAC) research consortium is to conduct excellent trials in low and middle income countries to generate evidence on how to effectively and equitably deliver health interventions to improve maternal and child health. In addition to generating evidence on the effects of the support packages, the RISE project is also strengthening the research capacity of Masters and PhD students in Public Health at the University of Zambia. Currently 7 master students from the University of Zambia are collecting/using data and being supervised from the RISE project. 

Sida has been requested to provide additional funding to the research project to enable the originally planned follow-up of the girls into 2020. With current funding, the project will have to end in 2018 due to insufficient funds which would not give sufficient evidence to validate the trial results.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the trial is to measure the effect of combining economic support with a community intervention to prevent adolescent childbearing in a low income country. There are three primary objectives:
1. To measure the effectiveness of a combined economic and community intervention on childbearing within 8 months of the end of the intervention period.
2. To measure the effectiveness of economic support alone and of a combined economic and community intervention on childbearing before the 18th birthday among girls.
3. To measure the effecetiveness of economic support alone and of a combined economic and community intervention on the proportion of girls who sit for the grade 9 exam.&#xA0;
The secondary objectives are several: to measure the effectiveness of economic support alone and of a combined economic and community intervention on pregnancy and childbearing within 2 years, before the 16th birthday, marriage before the 16th and 18th birthday, socioeconomic inequality of childbearing and marriage before the 18th birthday, enrolment in grade 8 and 10, school attendance and grade 9 exam scores, socioeconomic inequality in participation in the grade 9 exam, knowledge and experiences related to SRH, including modern contraceptives, attitudes and perceived community norms related to the value of educating girls, early marriage, modern contraceptive use and adolescent pregnancy, employment status.&#xA0;
The cluster randomized control trial has three arms. The clusters are rural schools with surrounding communities. The schools are at least 8 kms apart. The three arms are the following:
- The control arm consisting of girls from 31 schools. They will receive school materials such as pencils, books and pens as an incentive to participate.&#xA0;
- The economic support arm. Girls from 63 schools participate. In addition to the above mentioned school materials, these girls receive K30 monthly and their guardians an annual cash grant of K350. School fees of about K500/term are paid.
- The economic support arm combined with a community intervention. Girls from 63 schools are receiving the same support as group 2 above but will also be given SRHR education and discuss SRHR at community meetings during the intervention period.
The primary outcome is to study the incidence of births within 8 months of the end of the intervention period, incidence of births before the girls&apos; 18th birthday; and proportion of the girls who sit for the grade 9 exam. The final study interviewers will be unaware of the respondents&apos; intervention arm status.&#xA0;
The RISE project is also strenghthening the research capacity of Masters and PhD students in Public Health at the UNZA. Currently, 7 Master students are collecting and using date under the supervision of the project.&#xA0;
The project is deemed sustainable and feasible to scale up, should the Zambian government decide to do so.&#xA0; The findings will be relevant for programmes focusing on adolescent sexual and reproductive health in Zambia and similar contexts, which is a top priority for Sweden in its development cooperation with Zambia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNZA RISE/Cismac/The University of Zambia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNZA RISE/Cismac/The University of Zambia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="130" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population Policies/Programmes &amp; Reproductive Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.7 - By 2030, ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health-care services, including for family planning, information and education, and the integration of reproductive health into national strategies and programmes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.7 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla har tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsov&#xE5;rd, inklusive familjeplanering, information och utbildning, och att reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa integreras i nationella strategier och program.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.5 - By 2030, eliminate gender disparities in education and ensure equal access to all levels of education and vocational training for the vulnerable, including persons with disabilities, indigenous peoples and children in vulnerable situations.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">4.5 - Senast 2030 avskaffa skillnaderna mellan k&#xF6;nen inom utbildningsomr&#xE5;det och s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till utbildning och yrkesutbildning p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er f&#xF6;r utsatta personer, inklusive personer med funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning, ursprungsfolk och barn som lever under utsatta f&#xF6;rh&#xE5;llanden.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.6 - Ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health and reproductive rights as agreed in accordance with the Programme of Action of the International Conference on Population and Development and the Beijing Platform for Action and the outcome documents of their review conferences.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.6 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och reproduktiva r&#xE4;ttigheter i enlighet med &#xF6;verenskommelserna i handlingsprogrammet fr&#xE5;n den internationella konferensen om befolkning och utveckling, Pekingplattformen samt slutdokumenten fr&#xE5;n respektive &#xF6;versynskonferenser.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">287673.7549479885</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">317262.2383908459</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">407179.386950715</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">287673.7549479886</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">317262.2383908459</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">407179.386950715</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-01">1064392.893307</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-28">287673.7549479885</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-28">317262.2383908459</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-28">407179.386950715</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the trial was to measure the effect of combining economic support with a community intervention to prevent adolescent childbearing in a low-income country. This was done successfully.

Objective 1. To measure the effectiveness of a combined economic and community intervention on childbearing within 8 months of the end of the intervention period.

The findings indicated that there was a small effect of the economic support on incidence of births among all the participants within 8 months of the intervention period. And there was possibly a small added effect of the community dialogues and Sexual Reproductive Health and Rights Education based on the data collected up to the end of the trial.

Objective 2. To measure the effectiveness of economic support alone and of a combined economic and community intervention on childbearing before the 18th birthday among girls.

There was a small if any effect of the economic support, and overall, no evidence of the added effect of Sexual Reproductive Health and Rights Education and community dialogues.

Objective 3. To measure the effectiveness of economic support alone and of a combined economic and community intervention on the proportion of girls who sit for the grade 9 exam.

There was a moderate effect of the economic support on the probability of sitting for grade 9 exams and it was larger than the effect on childbearing within 8 months of end of intervention and childbearing before the 18th birthday. Reasons for this difference in effect were not explored in the study. The inclusion of Sexual Reproductive Health and Rights Education and community dialogue gave small added effect on this outcome.

The effects on childbearing may not be enough in themselves to recommend expensive interventions, however, other benefits of increasing school completion may be more justifiable. A cost-benefit analysis could provide a better basis for recommendation.

The project strengthened the research capacity of master&apos;s and PhD students in Public Health at UNZA, with 7 master students collecting and using data under the supervision of the project.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12099" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="2250000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Zambia 2018-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Zambia 2018-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
