<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11624A0102-ZMB-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Diakonia Zambia</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened Accountability Program II: Diakonia Zambia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Diakonia arbetar i Zambia med att st&#xE4;rka medborgares f&#xF6;rst&#xE5;else f&#xF6;r deras roll i, och hur de kan bidra till, den politiska, ekonomiska och sociala utvecklingen i landet. Diakonia arbetar ocks&#xE5; f&#xF6;r att &#xF6;ka f&#xF6;rst&#xE5;elsen f&#xF6;r vikten av j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och j&#xE4;mlikhet, samt att &#xF6;ka kvinnors deltagande i beslutsfattande.   

Under de senaste &#xE5;ren har Diakonia implementerat SAP-I programmet (finansierat av Sida), vars syfte har varit att se till att medborgare f&#xE5;r &#xF6;kad tillg&#xE5;ng till resurser. Diakonia f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;r nu att implementera en andra fas av projektet; SAP-II. Det nya programmet kommer att bygga p&#xE5; l&#xE4;rdomar av vad som fungerade/fungerade mindre bra under SAP-I, och en uppdaterad kontextanalys av Zambia. Diakonia ans&#xF6;ker om finansiering fr&#xE5;n Sida till ett v&#xE4;rde av SEK 41 400 000 f&#xF6;r perioden 2018&#x2013;2021, f&#xF6;r att implementera SAP-II. Ambassaden har allokerat SEK 1 000 000 f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra en oberoende utv&#xE4;rdering vid programmets slut (2021). 

SAP-II kommer att t&#xE4;cka ett st&#xF6;rre geografiskt omr&#xE5;de &#xE4;n SAP-I. Programmet kommer ocks&#xE5; att dubbla antalet samarbetspartner (fr&#xE5;n fem tio). Syftet &#xE4;r fortsatt att bidra till att medborgare f&#xF6;r &#xF6;kade m&#xF6;jligheter att p&#xE5;verka beslutsfattande, kr&#xE4;va transparens och ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande, och bidra till en mer r&#xE4;ttvis naturresursallokering. Diakonias l&#xE5;ngsiktiga m&#xE5;l med programmet &#xE4;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra livskvalit&#xE9;n f&#xF6;r samh&#xE4;llen (framf&#xF6;rallt f&#xF6;r kvinnor, ungdomar, fattiga och mest utsatta) i naturresursrika omr&#xE5;den i Zambia.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia is an international development organization made of two Swedish churches. The head office is located in Sweden. In Zambia, Diakonia works to increase Rights Holders (RHs) understanding of their role in political, social and economic development processes, the importance of achieving gender equality and increasing women&#x2019;s participation. 

Over the past years, Diakonia has been implementing their SAP-I programme (supported by the Embassy of Sweden) aimed to ensure that Right Holders (RHs) have increased access to resources through engagement with corporate and public sectors. Diakonia now proposes to implement  the SAP-Phase II (SAP-II) based on the achievements, lessons learned, best practices from the SAP-I and the current context in Zambia. Hence, Diakonia has applied to Sida for funding of SEK 41,400,000 for the period 2018-2021 to implement the SAP-II. The Embassy has also allocated a SEK1,000,000.00 for an independent end of program evaluation to be undertaken in 2021.

The SAP-II will see the expansion of the programme to new geographical areas while also scaling up coverage in additional sites in the previous targeted districts. The programme will continue to address challenges of vulnerable communities in predominantly rural areas by strengthening RHs participation in enhancing equality, transparency and accountability in national resource allocation. Diakonia&#xB4;s overall goal and expected long-term change with the SAP-II is to improve quality of life of communities (especially, women, youth, the poor and most vulnerable groups) in natural resource rich, rural and peri-urban areas of Zambia. The overall programme objective is to empower RHs to hold duty bearers accountable for equitable access and distribution of national resources.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia&apos;s overall goal and expected long-term change/impact with the SAP-II is to improve quality of life of communities (specifically women, youth, the poor and most vulnerable groups) in natural resource rich, rural and peri-urban areas of Zambia. This will be achieved through the empowerment of Rights Holders (men, women, youth) to hold duty bearers accountable for equitable access to and distribution of national resources.&#xA0;This will be implemented through ten (10) civil society organisations.
The SAP-II is also expected to lead to the following outcomes;
Program Outcome 1: Right holders (RHs), in targeted districts of Zambia are empowered to hold duty bearers accountable for equitable access and distribution of national resources (including natural resources);
Program Outcome 2: Targeted duty bearers (state institutions and corporates) are transparent and are accountable to right holders in the administration and governance of national/natural resources;
Program Outcome 3: Partner organisations have increased capacity to implement their mandates and effectively deliver rights based social, political and economic programmes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FCG Swedish Development AB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="10.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10.2 - By 2030, empower and promote the social, economic and political inclusion of all, irrespective of age, sex, disability, race, ethnicity, origin, religion or economic or other status.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">10.2 - Till 2030 m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra och verka f&#xF6;r att alla m&#xE4;nniskors, oavsett &#xE5;lder, k&#xF6;n, funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning, ras, etnicitet, ursprung, religion eller ekonomisk eller annan st&#xE4;llning, blir inkluderade i det sociala, ekonomiska och politiska livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.C" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.c - Adopt and strengthen sound policies and enforceable legislation for the promotion of gender equality and the empowerment of all women and girls at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.c - Anta och st&#xE4;rka v&#xE4;lgrundad politik och genomf&#xF6;rbar lagstiftning f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och &#xF6;ka alla kvinnors och flickors egenmakt p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">116592.2419522205</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">116592.2419522205</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-01">115069.501979</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-28">27965.4653779338</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-28">64989.3901059823</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/11624-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened Accountability Program II: Diakonia Zambia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/11624-decision-on-contribution.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened Accountability Program II: Diakonia Zambia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall, 2018 (June &#x2013; December) was dedicated to starting up the new program, SAP-II. Particularly, the year was used for setting up the partnerships and the operating structures for the projects implementation. This was successful as agreements were signed with 10 implementing partners during the period under review, partner inception workshops were held, and capacity assessments were concluded on all partners informing the risk assessment and the capacity building plans. However, the start-up phase faced big delays linked to that Diakonia&#xB4;s own capacity was limited. Particularly, contracts with partners were only signed in November, and funds were only disbursements in December, delaying implementation of many planned activities.&#xA0;
From a total of 16 assessed organizations, 14 organizations were selected and categorized as either an implementing or resource partner. However, contracts were only signed with the 10 selected as implementing. Agreements with the 4 selected resource partners were only formalized in 2019. Prior to the award of grants, the implementing partners were further divided into &#x201C;activity based partners&#x201D; and &#x201C;project based partners&#x201D;. The two categories specify how funds are disbursed, the level of monitoring, and capacity building needed. Assessments considered the organizations board composition, effectiveness of internal controls and liquidity in respect to statutory backlogs, recent audits, etc.&#xA0;
Through the appraisal of Diakonia&#xB4;s proposal and initial dialogue with the Embassy, Gender, Environment and Conflict Sensitivity were identified as critical areas which need to be mainstreamed in the entire program. These areas will be critical parts of the capacity building plans (these are individual action plans drawn from the assessment of each partner). Some concrete activities (discussed during the Annual Review Meeting) that Diakonia may put into the workplans are availing Diakonia&#xB4;s Gender Toolkit to partners to review their results frameworks, supporting partners in developing environment policies, and training in Do No Harm and availing Diakonia&#xB4;s Conflict Mainstreaming Toolkit.
In SAP-I, there were some challenges with coordination between partners working on attaining the same results, and the Embassy has followed-up with Diakonia how they are managing this in the new programme. As a result of the dialogue issue, Diakonia have considered and elaborated on the added value which comes from the Programme Coordination Committee in contributing to effective coordination. However, during the next field trip with Diakonia, the Embassy should pay attention to how partners on the ground work together and that this has improved from the previous program. One of Diakonia&#xB4;s main roles in the SAP-II is being &quot;the coordinator&quot;, so this really should/needs to work well for the programme to deliver on the intended results.&#xA0;
During the period under review, Diakonia initiated an innovative approach for the baseline study. Rather than hiring a consultant to do the work, Diakonia and implementing partners own the baseline process together as the partners are the ones collecting the baseline data and writing the document, together with Diakonia. The study is, however, delayed, as a result of the partner agreements and award of grants being delayed. As of now, Diakonia have completed the data collection exercise, targeting 4000 participants. Also, Diakonia and partners had completed the analysis of both quantitative and qualitative data and are currently finalizing the report. The Embassy has requested, as per the agreement, that Diakonia shall submit an updated results framework once the baseline is complete, as a pre-condition for the next disbursement. The Embassy is also providing support (through the procured NIRAS RBM consultant) in finalizing the baseline survey and the results framework.&#xA0;
Several of the challenges faced during 2018 were linked to that Diakonia had insufficient internal capacity due to lean staffing level. The office only operated with four full-time staff. To respond to this, Diakonia have now recruited two new staff: a second Programme Officer and a Grant and Compliance Officer. Yet, staff turn-over (both within Diakonia and the programme partners) continues to be a key risk that may jeopardize and delay programme activities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11624" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="2250000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Zambia 2018-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Zambia 2018-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
