<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11166A0101-ZMB-13020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBC Media Action, Tikambe II</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">BBC Media Action, Tikambe II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">BBC Media Action har ans&#xF6;kt om 21,685,500 SEK fr&#xE5;n Sida f&#xF6;r att kunna genomf&#xF6;ra projektet &#x201D;Tikambe Re-Loaded Project&#x201D; i Zambia (Lusaka, Centrala, Kopparb&#xE4;ltet och Norra provinsen) under perioden 2017-2020. Insatsen syftar till att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra ungas tillg&#xE4;nglighet till SRHR-information samt tillhandah&#xE5;lla, tillg&#xE4;ngligg&#xF6;ra och &#xF6;ka upptaget av SRH-tj&#xE4;nster riktade mot unga. P&#xE5; grund av unga m&#xE4;nniskors begr&#xE4;nsade tillg&#xE5;ng till SRHR-information- och tj&#xE4;nster &#xE4;r denna grupp s&#xE5;rbar i relation till ett antal risker, s&#xE5;som sexuellt &#xF6;verf&#xF6;rbara sjukdomar, HIV och o&#xF6;nskade graviditeter, n&#xE5;got som denna insats avser adressera. 

Projektets budget &#xE4;r 21,685,500 SEK, Sida finansierar hela beloppet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBC Media Action has applied to Sida for funding of 21,685,500 SEK to carry out the &quot;Tikambe Re-Loaded Project&#x201D; in Zambia (Lusaka, Central, Copperbelt and Northern provinces) during the period 2017-2020. The intervention aims at improving access to SRHR information for young people as well as the provision, access and uptake of youth-friendly SRHR services. It is intended to address limited SRHR information and services for young people which leave young people exposed to numerous risks in terms of sexually transmitted infections, HIV and unwanted pregnancies. 

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 21,685,500 SEK, Sida will fund the entire budget.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBC Media Action</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBC Media Action</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="130" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population Policies/Programmes &amp; Reproductive Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1193401.1934011932</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1193401.1934011932</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-05">1193401.193401</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">1193401.1934011932</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">As found by the evaluation, the Tikambe Project achieved it&apos;s intended results. BBC Media Action&apos;s own research into the impact of Phase II through a panel study showed that Tikambe was associated with higher SRHR knowledge and increased behavioural intentions to use condoms and contraceptives. The research showed young people reporting positive changes in their attitudes and behaviours leading to better decision making and choices in matters concerning their SRHR.

The research evaluation also highlighted that Tikambe appeared to reach its target of enhancing support from influencers and policy makers. Throughout Phase II Tikambe helped to create opportunities, both via the interpersonal and mass media components of the project, for young people to have conversations with influencers, stakeholders and policy makers through several outreach events and dialogue meetings with topics ranging from who can carry a condom to equal balance of power in relationships to parent-child communication on SRHR.
Results from the BBC Media Action endline panel study and qualitative research conducted in the extension also showed that those exposed to Tikambe had better awareness of and regard for support sources. Overall, there was an increase in the percentage of panel members who knew where to access youth friendly services, with 94% of panel members at endline saying they had heard about the existence of youth friendly sites in their community, compared to 76% at baseline.

The number of referrals completed, and joint actions developed between the schools and health facilities indicated improved coordination between schools and health facilities in supporting learners. The support of Youth Friendly Services (YFS) helped to reduce queues and improve privacy. Young people through the panel study as well as the additional qualitative study reported improvements in SRH services offered to them at health facilities. 
The Community Self-Assessment Process, where young people assess services, raised awareness on selected local and national SRHR policies among young people. BBC Media Action observed improved commitments and action from duty bearers to implement priorities advanced by young people. Two examples of improved representation and engagement of young people are that through the project a youth representative is sitting on the National Technical Working Group Adolescent Health after a National Dialogue Meeting on young peoples SRHR and that a representative from the project chaired the District Technical Working Group of Kabwe District. An example of the impact of this engagement is that following young people demanding more YFS in health facilities, the Kasama District Health Office procured 10 tents for provision of these services. An example for Central Province is that the Provincial Education Office passed a policy that mandated all schools have to have functioning school councils which learners could use as spaces to reflect on services provided by the school and as accountability spaces.

The Evaluation also found some positive and negative unintended results as follows:
Reported positive outcomes
&#x2022; The placement of trained volunteers in schools inspired teachers to learn from volunteers and use more interactive teaching methods than they are used to.
&#x2022; Through the process of establishing the referral system between schools and clinics, provincial education authorities experienced improved collaboration among different authorities including the police.
&#x2022; The project helped build a pool of engaged and skilled young people in local
communities.

Reported negative outcomes
&#x2022; According to key influencers met, information on contraception contributed to an observed increase of the sugar daddy phenomenon as young women now know they can engage in sexual relations without getting pregnant. It has also
made some parents feel helpless as their children get contraceptives without their consent.
&#x2022; The fact that some parents turn off the radio to avoid their children listening to the programme has deprived some young people in rural areas, who may be more vulnerable to SRHR risks, from accessing information to make informed choices.
&#x2022; The lack of clarity of the intention of the project has created anger among some parents who did not understand that the project was actually supporting government policies.
&#x2022; The placement of project volunteers who receive an allowance compared to the clinics own volunteers who do not, made the mobilisation of the latter more difficult. It should be noted that other projects also provide allowances.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11166" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
