<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11863A0101-ZMB-31191</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dairy Association of Zambia Digital Platform (DIMS)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Dairy Association of Zambia Digital Platform (DIMS)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Dairy Association of Zambia har skickat in en ans&#xF6;kan till Ambassaden i Lusaka om st&#xF6;d till ett v&#xE4;rde av 16 miljoner kronor, f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra sitt &#x201D;Digital Information Management System (DIMS)&#x201D; projekt. Projektet omfattar skapandet av en plattform som kommer att anv&#xE4;ndas f&#xF6;r att k&#xF6;pa och s&#xE4;lja mj&#xF6;lkprodukter och insatsvaror till mj&#xF6;lkproduktion. Plattformen kommer att bidra till att skapa merv&#xE4;rde och samarbete mellan olika akt&#xF6;rer i mejeriv&#xE4;rdekedjan.  

M&#xE5;let med projektet &#xE4;r att introducera och vidareutveckla en digital plattform f&#xF6;r sm&#xE5;skaliga mejerib&#xF6;nder, i syfte att ge dem b&#xE4;ttre tillg&#xE5;ng till mejeriv&#xE4;rdekedjan, marknadsinformation, finansiella tj&#xE4;nster, etc. Antagandet &#xE4;r att plattformen kommer att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra sm&#xE5;skaliga b&#xF6;nders produktionskapacitet, produktivitet, l&#xF6;nsamhet och finansiella inkludering, vilket i sin tur kommer attrahera fler investeringar till mejeriv&#xE4;rdekedjan. Genom effektiva digitala informationshanteringssystem och finansiella tj&#xE4;nster l&#xE4;ngs v&#xE4;rdekedjan hoppas projektet &#xF6;ka aff&#xE4;rsrelationerna och aff&#xE4;rstransaktioner mellan olika akt&#xF6;rer, inte minst mellan f&#xF6;retag och sm&#xE5;skaliga b&#xF6;nder, vilket kommer att fr&#xE4;mja l&#xE5;ngsiktig h&#xE5;llbarhet inom mejerisektorn.

Den specifika m&#xE5;ls&#xE4;ttningen &#xE4;r att:
i.	Utveckla en platform f&#xF6;r sm&#xE5;skaliga mejerib&#xF6;nders digitala informationshanteringssystem (DIMS) och finansiella tj&#xE4;nster (Financial Management Services, FMS),
ii.	Utveckla digitala mejeriexpansionsmodeller som skall laddas upp till den digitala plattformen. 

DIMS-projektet kommer att genomf&#xF6;ras tillsammans av ett antal partners, fr&#xE4;mst; Mobile Payment Solutions (MPS), olika banker och leverant&#xF6;rer av jordbruksinsatser som redan samarbetar med DAZ. St&#xF6;det fr&#xE5;n Sida kommer att anv&#xE4;ndas f&#xF6;r att starta upp sj&#xE4;lva plattformen. Kvinnor och ungdomar kommer att vara en s&#xE4;rskilt viktig m&#xE5;lgrupp som kommer att f&#xE5; st&#xF6;d genom bl.a. entrepren&#xF6;rsutbildning och diverse jordbrukstj&#xE4;nster. &#xC4;ven andra b&#xF6;nder &#xE4;n de sm&#xE5;skaliga kommer att dra nytta av projektet d&#xE5; &#xE4;ven dessa kommer f&#xE5; tillg&#xE5;ng till olika delar den digitala plattformen.     

Den totala projektbudgeten uppskattas till 21 miljoner SEK, varav 4 miljoner SEK kommer att finansieras av DAZ sj&#xE4;lva genom medlems- och andra avgifter. Agro Pay kommer att bidra med tekniskt st&#xF6;d till ett v&#xE4;rde av cirka 1,000 000 SEK. De &#xE5;terst&#xE5;ende 16 miljoner SEK kommer att finansieras av ambassaden.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diary Association of Zambia has applied to the Embassy of Sweden in Lusaka for funding of 16 million SEK to carry out the &quot; Digital Information Management Systems project (DIMS). The DIMS project will be initiated through creation of a platform that will be used for input  purchases and output sales&quot; during the period 2018 to 2020. The platform will be used as an aggregation centre for the operations and will create linkages into the dairy value chain.

The goal of this project will be to introduce and further develop a digital smallholder dairy farmer aggregation, transaction and information management/exchange platform which will enhance commercialisation of the dairy value chain. The project envisages to attain this goal by improving smallholder farmers&#x2019; dairy production, productivity, profitability and financial inclusion. This is meant to help increase smallholder milk volumes and quality entering formal milk processing and marketing channel and improve farmer profit margins/ so as to create a pull effect needed to attract more smallholder farmers and dairy value chain service providers, who will include women and youth, to invest in dairy production, processing, marketing and service delivery.  

The project seeks to support business relationships, through effective and efficient digital information management systems and financial services, along the value chain. This will promote long term sustainability of the sub sector.The specific objectives will be to:
i.	Develop an interface for smallholder dairy farmers&#x2019; digital information management systems (DIMS) and Financial Management Services (FMS); and
ii.	Develop digital dairy extension modules to be uploaded on the digital interface. 

The DIMS project implementation will be very collaborative and will involve a number of key partners, key among them; Mobile Payment Solutions (MPS), the banks and a number of dairy inputs and assets suppliers already collaborating with DAZ. The funding form Sida will be used to help start the provision of a sustainable information and transaction management service platform between small scale dairy farmers and all categories of agribusinesses (small, medium and large). Women and youth will be deliberately targeted and supported through entrepreneurial skills development in order to enable them participate in farm gate/last mile inputs distribution and service delivery. Anticipated services to be offered to women and youth entreprenuers include: bran/cake supply; transportation services; artificial insemination services; veterinary drugs supply; and other support services, among others. The indirect benefits will also spill over to non-small scale dairy farmers. These non dairy farmers  will also be able to access digital services at various levels in the different areas of provision. This  will translate into a community based service structure in the medium term where the MCCs have provided the entry point for opportunties for business development and growth.

The total project budget is estimated to be 21 MSEK of which 4 MSEK will be financed by DAZ and from membership fees, Milk levies while Agro pay will contribute in kind ( technical support and provision of digital gadgets estimated at 1,000,000 SEK. The rest (16 MSEK) will be financed by the Embassy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PROJECT OBJECTIVESThe anticipated outcome or overall objective of this project is to improve targeted smallholder farmers&#x2019; dairy production and productivity through a digital aggregation, transaction and information management exchange platform that will enhance commercialisation of the dairy value chain.
SPECIFIC OBJECTIVES
Specific project objectives or anticipated Intermediary outcomes will include the following:
1. Digitalised MCC transactions2. Reduced cost of doing business for targeted small-scale dairy farmers; 3. Improved access to information, inputs and equipment for small scale dairy farmers; and4. Improved financial inclusion for targeted small-scale dairy farmers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DIMS/Dairy Association of Zambia Digital Platform/DAZ</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DIMS/Dairy Association of Zambia Digital Platform/DAZ</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-18" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-18" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="31191" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="311" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1035625.5178127589</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1035625.5178127588</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-18">1035625.517812</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-28">1035625.5178127589</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/11863_AmendmenttotheAgreementDAZDIMS11863.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment to Agreement DAZ DIMS December 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/11863-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dairy Association of Zambia Digital Platform (DIMS)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/11863-decision-on-contribution.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dairy Association of Zambia Digital Platform (DIMS)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/11863_DecisiononAmendmentofContributionDAZDIMS11863.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Amendment of Contribution DAZ DIMS December 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">- In a bid to improve in governance and leadership skills, 37 leaders (29 M and 8 F) were trained against a target of 50 during the reporting period bringing the total number of those trained to 162 compared to 125 trained in the previous reporting period. As a result of these trainings, cooperative board members have started to meet as prescribed in the by-laws. Additionally, a total of 21 MCCs conducted their Annual General Meetings in 2019 as compared to 9 in 2018.
- Pasture demonstration plots were established following an assessment to identify suitable sites. A total of 32 pasture demonstration plots were established in all the 32 MCCs for the purpose of showcasing pasture growing for dairy animals. A total of 143 farmers (86 M, 57 F) established own pasture fields against a target of 500 representing 29% coverage. However, as a result of the drought which occurred in the 2018/19 farming season, 18 pasture demonstration plots in Southern province did not thrive due to water shortages.
- A total of 30 targeted MCCs were activated (2 MCC yet to be activated). further,&#xA0; 774 farmers were registered on the digital platform during the reporting period representing 95% of the target number of 816. Women accounted for 30% of the registered farmers while men represented 70%. Profiled information include age, number of cattle, national registration number, phone number etc. In addition, the MCC were able to send information on marketing (inputs), extension information (herd health disease, outbreaks, milk hygiene practices etc), and meetings electronically and directly to the registered farmers through an SMS.
- In order to respond to the effects of drought and livestock diseases (Foot and Mouth Disease). Trainings on disease prevention, calf management and on farm feed production were conducted. A total of 323 farmers (81 M, 242 F) were trained in dairy management against a target of 500 representing a 65% coverage. As a result of this intervention, no new infections were recorded (Foot and Mouth Disease) and farmers were more informed on disease prevention and management of secondary infections. Further, it was observed that the trained farmers adopted feed formulations strategies their animals especially during the drought periods.
- DAZ trained 174 farmers (69M, 105F) in savings and credit against a target of 200. as a result of these trainings, 42 savings groups were formed against a target of 30 representing 140%. The saving group members were at 846 (108M, 506F,232Y) against a target of 1000.Similarly, K293,526 was saved during the reporting period against a target of K90,000 representing 326% coverage.&#xA0;Five agro shops were operational in Kwanshama, Chibombo, Kampelembe and Mapepe while a youth milk transporting business is functioning in Kampelembe.
-DAZ managed to harness and collaborate well with other partners in the dairy sector during the implementation of the DIMS project. Some of the notable partners included&#xA0; We Effect, SNV, Agriterra, the Zambia Dairy Transformation Project (ZDTP), the SADC Trade Related Facility project, Green Innovation Centres for Agriculture &amp; Food Security and E-SLIP. These partners contributed to some of the above mentioned achievement recorded by DAZ during the implementation of the DIMS project.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11863" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
