<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11460A0101-ZMB-15118</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d till Riksrevisionen (2018 -2021)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to Office of the Auditor General (2018 -2021)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the African Organisation of Supreme Audit Institutions, AFROSAI-E, the Supreme Audit Institutions have&#xA0;improved their performances, including OAG Zambia. However, there are continuous challenges, hence to improve transparency and accountability, capacity building has to continue. AFROSAI-E offers training workshops and development of audit guidance materials. This increases participants to keep abreast with current methodology in the audit processes. Generally, continuous&#xA0;development of human resources is fundamental for any Supreme Audit Institutions throughout the world. This includes&#xA0;leadership and management as well as audit officers in areas such as IT auditing, financial, performance and compliance. Since the area&#xA0;of&#xA0;Public Financial Management is developing,&#xA0;foremost in&#xA0;relation to IT,&#xA0;Supreme Audit Institutions need to keep up with the changes. &#xA0;&#xA0;
The OAG seeks support for further capacity building, to be able to implement the Strategic Plan and to give assurance that at least 80% of public resources are applied towards development outcomes. There four main objectives of this project are:&#xA0;
1. To provide timely and value adding auditing services for enhanced accountability, transparency and integrity of government and the public sector for the benefit of society
2. To effectively plan, execute, monitor and evaluate programmes and provide management information for timely decision making and attainment of set objectives.
3. To efficiently and effectively manage human resources.
4. To efficiently and effectively provide financial and administrative services for organisational efficiency and attainment of set objectives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Office of the Auditor General (OAG) is the Supreme Audit Institution (SAI) of Zambia and draws its mandate from the Constitution (Amendment) Act No. 2 of 2016 under Article 250 and the Public Audit Act No. 29 of 2016. The role of the Office of the Auditor General (OAG) is to oversee and audit the management of public resources. It plays a fundamental role in controlling the use of public funds and to promoting sound Public Financial Management Systems, accountability and transparency. It audits the accounts of state organs, and state institutions, as well as provincial administration and local authorities. These tasks require specific competence in auditing public institutions and ongoing training of staff is a prerequisite. 

In 2017 the OAG developed a new Strategic Plan 2017-2021. The mandate of OAG has been expanded in accordance with the Constitution (Amendment) and the Plan has been developed to guide OAG to be able to fulfil this mandate. The Strategic Plan has also taken into account the priorities outlined in the Seventh National Development Plan. The implementation of the Plan depends both on given budget and disbursements from Government, as well as support from Cooperating Partners.
Sweden has supported OAG in Zambia through a program called Restructuring and Institutional Development Programme Phase Five (RIDP V) 2015-2017 in collaboration with Norway. The purpose of the support was to assist the office to build capacity in specialised audits and to improve its audit coverage and scope. Sweden contributed SEK 33,000,000 for the 3 year program. The support increased the audit coverage for programmes funded by Cooperating Partners. Sweden has been the main funder for this phase. The Norwegian Supreme Audit Institute has given technical assistance and they will continue until 2020. 

In August 2018, the Embassy received a draft proposal for a new phase; Restructuring and Institutional Development Programme Phase Six (RIDP VI) 2018-2021. The purpose of this phase is to &quot;source funding for the implementatin of selected activities that support the implementation of the OAG&apos;s 2017-2021 Strategic Plan&quot;. The proposal suggests that the project outcome will be &quot;Enhanced capacity of the OAG to deliver assurance services on the implementation of deveolpment outcomes by Government&quot;. The four project objectives have been adapted from the Strategic Plan. It is expected that the OAG will have enhanced its capacity to carry out its work in a professional, effective and efficient manner. The proposal consists of a Results Framework based on the four objectives.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">The Office of the Auditor General (OAG) &#xE4;r den h&#xF6;gsta revisionsinstitutionen i Zambia, vars mandat grundas i Zambias konstitution (2016), och i Public Audit Act No. 29 (2016). OAGs roll &#xE4;r att granska och utf&#xF6;ra revisioner av hur offentliga sektorn fungerar vad g&#xE4;ller styrning och anv&#xE4;ndning av statliga medel. De spelar en mycket viktig roll n&#xE4;r det kommer till att kontrollera hur statliga medel anv&#xE4;nds, fr&#xE4;mjandet av transparens och ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande. De granskar statliga organ och institutioner, provinsernas administration och lokala myndigheter; ett uppdrag som kr&#xE4;ver personal med h&#xF6;g kompetens och l&#xF6;pande kompetensutveckling.  

OAGs mandat har ut&#xF6;kats genom revideringen av konstitutionen 2016. F&#xF6;r att fylla sitt nya mandat har OAG tagit fram en ny strategisk plan f&#xF6;r 2017-2021. Implementering &#xE4;r beroende av st&#xF6;d fr&#xE5;n regeringen och givare. 

Sverige i samarbete med Norge har tidigare bidragit med st&#xF6;d till OAG genom programmet &#x201D;Restructuring and Institutional Development Programme Phase Five (RIDP V) 2015-2017&#x201D;. Syftet med st&#xF6;det var att bidra till att st&#xE4;rka OAGs kapacitet att genomf&#xF6;ra specialiserade revisioner, och f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra revisionernas omf&#xE5;ng. Sverige bidrog med totalt SEK 33 000 000 under tre&#xE5;rsperioden. Sverige var det huvudsakliga givarlandet; Norge bidrog fr&#xE4;mst med tekniskt st&#xF6;d, vilket kommer att forts&#xE4;tta fram till 2020.

Under augusti 2018 tog Ambassaden emot ett utkast av ans&#xF6;kan fr&#xE5;n OAG, r&#xF6;rande nytt st&#xF6;d: &#x201D;Restructuring and Institutional Development Programme Phase Six (RIDP VI) 2018-2021&#x201D;. Syftet med den nya fasen &#xE4;r att st&#xF6;dja implementeringen av OAGs nya strategiska plan, som i sin tur syftar till att st&#xE4;rka OAGs kapacitet att genomf&#xF6;ra genomgripande, effektiva och tillf&#xF6;rlitliga revisioner av statliga institutioner och program.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="12001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OAG/Office of the Auditor General</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="12001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OAG/Office of the Auditor General</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15118" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National audit</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">460278.0079167817</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1269048.9535633838</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1411555.208095812</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">932737.935617764</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">460278.0079167816</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1269048.9535633838</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1411555.2080958122</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">932737.935617764</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-01">4257571.57323</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">460278.0079167817</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-28">634524.4767816919</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-28">634524.4767816919</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-28">651487.0191211441</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-28">760068.188974668</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-28">466368.967808882</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-28">466368.967808882</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/11460_AgreementSidaOAG.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement OAG</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/11460_DecisiononContributionOAG.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution OAG</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This conclusion on performance is based on the 2019 annual report which also included a few highlights on 2020. The 2019 reports were submitted late and the annual review meeting was held in December instead of May,2020 due to the Covid 19 pandemic. Procurement for the 2019 audit could also not be concluded on time due to the need to follow the Government of the Republic of Zambia&apos;s&#xA0; (GRZ) public procurement rules amidst restrictions&#xA0;caused by the Covid 19.&#xA0;
Between November 2019 and May 2020, the office underwent changes in the top management. A substantive Auditor General was appointed by the President and ratified by Parliament in December, 2019. The Office had an acting Auditor General for over three years which was a concern among all stakeholders. During the same period, a substantive Deputy Auditor General for the Audit Division was also appointed by the President. In May 2020, the Deputy Auditor General for Corporate&#xA0;Services Division (who is the Controlling Officer) was replaced.&#xA0;
The Office of the Auditor General (OAG) plays an important&#xA0;oversight role in promoting transparency&#xA0;and accountability in the use of public resources through the annual and adhoc audits it carries out on the expenditure and revenue of Ministries and other Government spending agencies.&#xA0;
The Office of the Auditor General draws its mandate to audit all public finances from Article 250 of the Constitution of the Republic of Zambia. Article 212 of the Constitution requires the Office to submit the audit report on the Accounts of the Republic by 30th September of each year. This contribution supports the process and the printing of the OAG&apos;s&#xA0;main annual report.
The first strategic objective of the Office is to provide timely and value adding auditing services for enhanced accountability, transparency and integrity of government and the public sector for the benefit of society.&#xA0;In this regard, during the period between 2019 and 2020 the Office has been able to produce the following audit reports:
-The report of the Auditor General on the Accounts of the Republic for the Financial Year Ended 31st December 2018, published in September 2019.
-The Report of the Auditor General on the Accounts of Parastatal and other Statutory Bodies for the Financial Year Ended 31st December 2018.
-The Report of the Auditor General on the Accounts of Water Utility Companies for the Financial Year Ended 31st December 2018
As a result of the audits, the following were achieved:
The audit reports were tabled in Parliament and responsible erring institutions appeared before the Public Accounts Committee and other parliamentary sub-committees. Enhanced accounting system controls in client institutions were put in place as recommended by the audits.
In response to the Covid 19 pandemic, the OAG produced a special audit looking at how funds contributed by donors and other private sector partners were utilised.&#xA0;
The OAG also participated in&#xA0;&#xA0;the INTOSAI&#xA0;and AFROSAI-E working groups during the period. The workshops&#xA0;covered the following subject matters:
-Audit of Extractive Industries;
-Public Financial Management;
-Environmental Auditing;
-Financial and Compliance Auditing;
-Fraud and investigations.
The areas were relevant for Zambia&apos;s ambition to increase its capacity to audit revenue collection in the extractive industries. In addition, the knowledge gained was used in the process of implementing the Financial Audit Manual (FAM) and Compliance Audit Manual (CAM) at the OAG.
Under the result area two, increased audit coverage, the office covered 85% of government expenditure against a target of 82% in the year 2019.
The project also supported the OAG to procure&#xA0;ICT equipment which included 59 computers to facilitate&#xA0;their work.&#xA0; The auditor to laptop ratio has improved from [3 to 1] to [2 to 1]. The demand for computers increased in 2019 due to the recruitment of Auditors under the new directorate of Local Authorities.
Under staff development, 54 auditors under the Local Authorities Audit Directorate (LAAD) were trained in&#xA0; International Public Sector Accounting Standards (IPSAS);&#xA0;85 newly recruited staff trained on the audit flow process including the Financial and Compliance Auditing Standards (FAM and CAM);&#xA0; 21 auditors out of the planned thirty (30) were trained in professional courses such as ACCA, ZICA and CIMA;&#xA0;10 provincial audit staff were trained in procurement procedures; and 23 auditors participated in the Zambia Institute of Chartered&#xA0;Accountants (ZICA) tax updates. Continuous&#xA0;capacity development is one of the main contributions&#xA0;of the RIDP VI project. This aspect is important because Auditors are expected to be abreast with changes in the public financial sector. Further, in line with the decentralisation policy and increased mandate of work for the OAG, a number of tasks are being decentralised such as the procurement hence the training of provincial staff in procurement.&#xA0;&#xA0;
The&#xA0;Covid 19 pandemic resulted in staff working from home and official travels being halted. The effects on the operations of the office included rescheduling and restrategising&#xA0;the implementation of activities which required physical meetings in groups such as workshops, trainings, and audits. This resulted in reduced international and local travel as well as adjusting the way audits are conducted. Consequently, the work plan&#xA0;and budget had to be adjusted to facilitate for the procurement of more laptops for auditors, motor vehicles and PPEs for staff.&#xA0;
Other notable challenges included volatile exchange rates which negatively affected activities which required making payments in foreign currency such as subscription fees to international and regional bodies. Inadequate&#xA0;human resources has continued inhibiting the OAG in conducting all planned activities. Inadequate&#xA0;human resources also affected the audit coverage for revenue audits which was 71% against a target of 82%.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11460" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="2250000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Zambia 2018-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Zambia 2018-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
