<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5119008701-ZMB-25012</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Facilitet f&#xF6;r f&#xF6;retag f&#xF6;r utveckling i Zambia     Pilotfas</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia Business In Development Facility           Pilot phase</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">ATMS Foundation har inkommit till Sveriges ambassad i Lusaka med en ans&#xF6;kan om finansiering om 10 300 000 SEK till projektet &quot;The Zambia Business In Development Facility&quot;. 

ZBIDF har ett tv&#xE5;stegsansats. Det &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let &#xE4;r att &#x201C;minska fattigdom genom att etablera och st&#xF6;dja partnerskap med f&#xF6;retag som bidrar till Zambias utvecklingsm&#xE5;l&#x201D;. F&#xF6;r att bidra till detta &#xE4;r ZBIDFs direkta syfte &#xE4;r att bidra till fler etablerade partnerskap. Dessa partnerskap f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntas i sin tur bidra till uppsatta utveklingsm&#xE5;l och p&#xE5; s&#xE5; s&#xE4;tt bidra till det &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let. Specifika omr&#xE5;den har inte identifierats f&#xF6;r att m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra samarbeten med de mest lovande partnerskapen oavsett specifikt utvecklingsfokus. 

ZBIDFs ansats handlar om att m&#xE4;kla partnerskap mellan f&#xF6;retag, regeringen, CSOs och givare. M&#xE4;klaraktiviteter inkluderar att introducera akt&#xF6;rer f&#xF6;r varandra samt st&#xF6;d och assistans f&#xF6;r att partnerna ska n&#xE5; en &#xF6;verenskommelse. Senare stadier inkluderar att identifiera och mobilisera resurser, st&#xF6;dja parterna i att s&#xE4;tta upp strukturer f&#xF6;r styrning, f&#xF6;resl&#xE5; utg&#xE5;ngspunkter etc. Partnerskapen f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntas bidra till utveckling och fattigdomsminskning genom de projekt som de implementerar. 

Projektet &#xE4;r en pilot p&#xE5; tv&#xE5; &#xE5;r d&#xE5; ansatsen ska testas. F&#xF6;rutom att m&#xE4;kla partnerskap, ska ZBIDF &#xE4;ven testa olika modeller f&#xF6;r att ha en v&#xE4;lfungerande facilitet p&#xE5; plats efter tv&#xE5; &#xE5;r.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZBIFD has a wide overarching goal to &#x201C;reduce poverty by establishing and supporting partnerships with businesses that contribute significantly to Zambia&#x2019;s development goals&#x201D;.  ZBIDFs immediate objective is to contribute to more established partnerships that will contribute to targeted development objectives within the overarching objective. Specific areas of intervention have not been specified in order for ZBIDF to be able to work with the most promising partnerships, regardless their specific development focus.  

The approach of ZBIDF is to broker partnerships between businesses, government, CSOs and donors. Brokering activities include match-making, coaching and assisting partners in reaching agreement on a specific partnership. Later stages include identifying and mobilizing resources, supporting partners in setting up governance structures, agreeing on benchmarks etc. The partnerships in turn, are expected to contribute to development outcomes and poverty reduction through the projects they implement. 

The current project of ZBIDF is a 2-year pilot when this approach will be tested. Apart from brokering partnerships, ZBIDF will also try out different models in order to have a well-functioning facility in place after two years.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ATMS/African Training and Management Services Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="250" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business &amp; Other Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="25010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Policy and Administration</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">750739.8067027216</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">646554.2809011425</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">163409.1041897972</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">750739.8067027216</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">644033.1937408801</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">163409.1041897972</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-07-01">1749035.700228</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-09-28">750739.8067027216</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-07-28">33069.0567425528</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">610964.1369983273</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">163409.1041897972</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2016Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: Success in the 1-2 year time was to be demonstrated by the following;

&#x2022;	Partners have mobilised resources to support the partnership objectives.  
&#x2022;	The partnership shows resilience.
&#x2022;	There is increased awareness amongst sectors of the value and effectiveness of cross-sector partnerships.

Result area 1. Resources mobilised to support partnerships.

During the period under review the total value of funds raised to support partnerships amounted to $82,500. These funds were mobilised from the Government of Zambia through the Private Sector Development, Industrialisation and Job Creation Office ($50,000) for the innovation series which resulted in the development of nine partnership opportunities on the one hand whilst the International Labour Organisation contributed $32,500 towards the National Skills Development Partnership. The ILO has since committed to provide additional funds for a consultant to develop a national framework for work based learnerships.

Result Area 2. Number of active partnerships by sector

By the end of March 2017, the number of partnerships that were active were two, these being the Cassava to Flour Partnership and the National Skills Development Partnership (Annex 8). 

Result area 3. Level of awareness of cross-sector partnership benefits / tools / methods by sector

The level of awareness on the value of cross sector partnerships in very high in the agriculture sector as demonstrated by the number of partnership opportunities and the value of ZBiDF&#x2019;s work in the Consortium of Fresh Fruit and Vegetable Producers Partnership and the Cassava to Flour Partnership. This is the same with the Manufacturing Sector through which the TEVETA-ZAM partnership and the National Skills Development Partnership were being developed. 

Based on the success in implementing the innovation series on behalf of the Government of Zambia, the Secretary to Cabinet has adopted cross sector partnerships as a means to accelerate the implementation of Industrialisation and Job Creation strategy. The PSDIJCO is currently mobilising funds towards the implementation of a follow on innovation series for North-Western, Copperbelt, Luapula and Northern provinces. 

In 2015, the ZBiDF was requested by the University of Lusaka to provide content for a course titled &#x2018;sustainable development and value creation&#x2019;. This course is part of the courses delivered in the Executive MBA programme. The course has since been taught to thirty six students in two classes in 2016 (20) and 2017 (16). The course has been evaluated by the students as value adding. 
2.3. Intermediate Outcomes
 
Success in the 2-3 year timeframe was to be signified by the following;

&#x2022;	The partnerships are self-managed, efficiently and effectively delivering mutual benefits. 
&#x2022;	They are demonstrating progress towards development goals and partnership objectives.
&#x2022;	ZBIDF is sustained as a social enterprise and demand for services grows

Result area 1. Level of participation, resourcing, trust and commitment between partners. 

The experience during the period under review is that participation, trust and commitment have been high in all partnerships that are signed, however, on resources there has been very little movement as organisations are faced with challenges given the current economic situation. 

Result area 2. Efficiency and effectiveness of partnership arrangements.

The National Skills Development Partnership and the Cassava to Flour partnership have demonstrated efficiency and effectiveness in that despite the ZBiDF programme coming to an end there is constant communication among members. The Chairman of the Cassava to Flour Partnership has been instrumental in raising awareness of key stakeholders such as the Ministry of Trade Commerce and Industry which has mandated its statutory bodies to provide support to the cassava value chain.

Result area 3. Tangible and intangible resources invested by partners.

Whilst there is willingness amongst partners to invest resources this has been the biggest challenge to the partnerships.

Result area 4. Level of demand for paid ZBIDF services.

Progress in this result area was not in keeping with the expected delivery level. 

Progress in this result area was very low in that based on the recommendation of TPI, it was decided that focus be given to achieve the overall intention of developing impactful partnerships. Therefor development process of a business model that would support the sale of paid services by the ZBiDF was discontinued in the second quarter of the first year. This is demonstrated by the level of funds leveraged for sale of services i.e. $54,075.  The team has since developed a business model canvas to support this result area.  Regardless of this, the team marketed its services to many stakeholders resulting in business albeit small (less than $2000) from Solidaridad (an NGO that works with multiple stakeholders to develop sustainable land-use management in the lower Kafue basin).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51190087" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
