<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5119006601-ZMB-31120</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">iDE Scaling up Farm Business Advisers in Zambia</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">iDE privata jordbruksr&#xE5;dgivare i Zambia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural extension is vital for increased productivity and diversification among smallholder farmers. In Zambia, government agricultural extension services to smallholder farmers have remained insufficiently inadeqaute due to several factors which range from political to financial. Therefore, private led extension services are deemed by many development partners as the necessary and possibly more sustainable complement to the government extension system to ensure that the needed services are available to the smallholder farmers. iDE submitted a project proposal which is based on market based approach proposing to use a methodology known as the Farm Business Adviser (FBA). iDE has experience of using the FBA approach through the just ended Rural Prosperity Initiative which recorded some improvement in cash flow of iDE farmer group members  who received extension messages and invested in micro-irrigation technologies. It is therefore anticipated that with additional funding, iDE will succeed in its development work and reach more farmers. 
The challenge on the implementation will be to reorient the existing iDE extension staff from promotion of irrigation technologies to other value chains. The other challenge anticipated is the sustainability of this approach in the project area. It may prove to be difficult to sustain the FBAs to live on commission from sale of commodities to the beneficiaries/ farmers if the farmers think they are exploited. The farmers may opt to buy directly from the suppliers. Therefore, to find a win-win situation amongst the players (suppliers, agents and buyers) may be a challenge. This may lead to collapse of the FBA approach in the event that the project ceases. In order to reduce this risk, the Embassy will monitor the performance of the FBAs and will engage iDE in dialogue to innovate the FBA approach to suit the prevailing local business conditions if necessary and possible. 
Independent assessment of iDE by EMM corporate partners summarized that iDE organizational and financial management systems creates a reasonably moderate risk rating with no high level of fiduciary risk. Considering the risks identified by EMM, the project will be closely supervised in order for it to attain its objectives.
However, despite the identified risks associated with the FBA approach, the Embassy assesses that there are more opportunities than risks that may be of sustained benefit to the smallholder farmers. Therefore, with due consideration of these factors, the Embassy has decided to give a grant to iDE for a period of two years. Thereafter, iDE and the FBA approach will be evaluated before considering long term future collaboration.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">That	 Sida shall contribute to the iDE Zambia, Scaling Up Farm Business Advisors project during the period  2014 - 2015  with the following agreed sum per year  SEK  11,000,000  in  2014, SEK 11,000,000 in 2015, 
That 	 SEK 11,000,000 shall be allocated for this purpose from appropriation account 155022, budget 2014. 
That 	SEK 11,000,000 shall be allocated for this purpose from future appropriations within the received authorization frame 
That 	Lena Nordstr&#xF6;m, Ambassador, shall sign the agreement with the International Development Enterprises (iDE) on behalf of Sida in accordance with the attached draft agreement</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDE-UK/International Development Enterprises UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDE-UK/International Development Enterprises UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="311" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1603521.917229114</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1304971.9431032233</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1603521.917229114</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1304971.9431032233</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-04-01">3207043.834458</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-06-28">1603521.917229114</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-07-28">1304971.9431032233</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2016Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: The goal of the SHARED project was &#x2018;to contribute to the reduction of rural poverty through improved service delivery by Farm Business Advisors (FBAs)&#x2019;. We aim to do this by lifting 20,000 smallholder farmers out of poverty using market-led approaches to support subsistence level smallholders make the shift to more lucrative agricultural sub sectors and value chains that offer growing income opportunities. Core to our approach is supporting FBAs to become micro entrepreneurs, who support their own network of client farmers in accessing inputs, advice, credit and markets. The following is the summary of the results that were obtained in the last two years of the shared project; iDE
&#x2022; exceeded the target for average change in net farm income by 154%, realizing a net change of US$201.72 per participating household;
&#x2022;exceeded target for number of farm enterprises reached through FBAs by 118% as some 23,613 farm enterprises benefited from FBA support;
&#x2022;200 FBAs are actively transacting and earning, 100% of our target;  
&#x2022;FBAs earned some ZMW 2.4million in commissions or margins, 75% of the target for FBA earnings; 
&#x2022;iDE piloted a stock guarantee scheme with a good cross section of input suppliers to unlock timely access to inputs via FBAs;
&#x2022;iDE successfully piloted FBA aggregation services for maize, soy and cowpeas with three lead buyers/traders (Amatheon Agri Zambia, World Food Programme and Export Trading Group);
&#x2022;iDE completed  performance testing of the Sunflower solar pump (which was piggybacked on &#x2018;SHARED&#x2019; and are poised to support the development of commercial distribution channels;
&#x2022;136 FBAs were trained in safe handling and use of pesticides (68% of target).
Unfortunately, during this reporting period, gender aspects were not fully mainstreamed in the project. Therefore, the impact of the project on women participation the activities that iDE is promoting is under reported. However, the are numbers of women participating in some of the activities. 
 In achieving the above mentioned results, iDE worked with various stakeholders in the sector. some of the results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51190066" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
