<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11597A0102-ZMB-13020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Marie Stopes Zambia 2018-2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Marie Stopes Zambia 2018-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marie Stopes Zambia, MSZ, has a theory of change with an ultimate goal to improve women&apos;s health and reduce maternal mortality in Zambia. This is expected to be achieved through two main results: 1) Increased use of contraception and access to safe abortions among poor and marginalized women and girls; and 2) Enhanced SRHR policies and successful implementation of these. MSZ has formulated three results to be achieved within the framework of this specific intervention: 1. Increased access to modern high-quality contraceptives and safe abortion services, especially for marginalized women and adolescents. 2. Increased awareness of contraception and safe abortion through education and information to decision-makers at community level; to poor and marginalized women and young people. 3. Enhanced advocacy work to create an improved legal and policy environment for contraception and access to safe abortion.
MSZ programme activities thus include direct healthcare services in close collaboration with central and local health authorities, support to MSZ&apos;s health clinics and social marketing in local markets to ensure that medical abortion drugs are available at pharmacies. MSZ will also strengthen its partnership with the government through the establishment of contracts to provide specific services on behalf of the government, to further develop a digital communication model to facilitate the concrete availability of safe abortion, and to cooperate with the Ministry of Health&#x2019;s health clinics to provide youth-friendly SRHR services for young people. MSZ will also participate in advocacy work and conduct dialogue for political change in the area of access to safe abortion and for contraceptives and other reproductive health commodities. MSZ will engage in strategic partnerships for community engagement with local partners. The Sida-funded initiative is expected to ensure that 102,500 women and girls access SRHR services, 14,900 medical abortion pills are distributed and 16,000 safe abortions can be performed. The effort is estimated to prevent 455 maternal deaths, 48,000 unintended pregnancies and 27,700 unsafe abortions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Marie Stopes Zambia har inkommit med en ans&#xF6;kan om st&#xF6;d om 40 MSEK till att genomf&#xF6;ra programmet Scaling Up Access to Comprehensive SRHR for Women and Girls in Zambia under perioden 2018-2021. Insatsen syftar till att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra tillg&#xE5;ngen och utnyttjandet av h&#xE4;lso- och sjukv&#xE5;rdstj&#xE4;nster inom ramen f&#xF6;r sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa. MSZ arbetar brett med att bist&#xE5; de zambiska h&#xE4;lsomyndigheterna med att erbjuda kvinnor och flickor moderna preventivmedel, information och utbildning om sex, samlevnad och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa samt med tillg&#xE5;ng till mediciner, r&#xE5;dgivning och service kring s&#xE4;kra aborter. Ett tydligt fokus &#xE4;r p&#xE5; fattiga kvinnor, ungdomar och unga kvinnor b&#xE5;de p&#xE5; landsbygden och i urbana omr&#xE5;den och samt andra marginaliserade grupper som t ex funktionshindrade och hiv-smittade.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
Marie Stopes Zambia has applied to Sida for funding of 40 Million SEK to carry out the Scaling Up Access to Comprehensive SRHR for Women and Girls in Zambia during the period 2018-2021. The contribution aims to increase equitable access and utilization of sexual and reproductive health services. MSZ works in close collaboration with local and central health authorities to provide modern family planning services, information and education about SRHR and with provision of drugs, counselling and access to safe abortion services. A clear focus is to provide quality services to young women and girls in both urban and rural settings, in particular poor women and girls and other disenfranchised and hard to reach populations such as disabled and hiv infected women and adolescents.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MSI Reproductive Choices</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marie Stopes Zambia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="130" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population Policies/Programmes &amp; Reproductive Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1 - By 2030, reduce the global maternal mortality ratio to less than 70 per 100,000 live births.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.1 - Till 2030 minska m&#xF6;drad&#xF6;dligheten i v&#xE4;rlden till mindre &#xE4;n 70 d&#xF6;dsfall per 100 000 f&#xF6;rlossningar med levande barn.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.7 - By 2030, ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health-care services, including for family planning, information and education, and the integration of reproductive health into national strategies and programmes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.7 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla har tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsov&#xE5;rd, inklusive familjeplanering, information och utbildning, och att reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa integreras i nationella strategier och program.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.6 - Ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health and reproductive rights as agreed in accordance with the Programme of Action of the International Conference on Population and Development and the Beijing Platform for Action and the outcome documents of their review conferences.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.6 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och reproduktiva r&#xE4;ttigheter i enlighet med &#xF6;verenskommelserna i handlingsprogrammet fr&#xE5;n den internationella konferensen om befolkning och utveckling, Pekingplattformen samt slutdokumenten fr&#xE5;n respektive &#xF6;versynskonferenser.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1119285.5227413168</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">1165922.419522205</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1119285.5227413168</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">1165922.419522205</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-01">4556752.278376</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">528770.3973180766</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">528770.3973180766</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-28">542905.84926762</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">542905.84926762</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-28">582961.2097611025</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-28">536324.3129802143</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-28">582961.2097611025</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/11597-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marie Stopes Zambia 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/11597_DecisiononAmendmentofContribution-MarieStopes.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Amendment of Contribution Marie Stopes Dec 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/11597-decision.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marie Stopes Zambia 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MSZ interventions target three key marginalised groups, namely the rural poor, persons living with disability (PWD), and adolescents/young people. Despite the adverse effects COVID-19 had on most interventions, MSZ was able to recover from the poor performance recorded in 2020 reaching these communities. The proportion of adolescent clients increased from 12% in 2020 to 18%, the highest ever for MSZ, but still falls short of the committed target of 20%, which in part was due to COVID-19 related challenges in implementing adolescent demand generation activities; and also, a withdrawal from all media of messages on SRHR to adolescents during the election period. New adolescent-friendly initiatives such as the dedicated adolescent caravan used in outreaches in Lusaka and Ndola, training of public providers in adolescent friendly services, and increased demand generation activities for adolescents in outreach contributed to this strong performance.

In 2021, MSZ implemented the Multi-dimensional Poverty Index (MPI) survey as part of client exit interviews. Across all channels, MSZ recorded an increase in the average proportion of poor clients served at 43% in 2021 compared to 35% in 2020. Unfortunately, this is below the national average of 57.5%. However, at an individual channel level, outreach (74%) recorded a proportion of poor clients above the national poverty rates (57.5%).

Contact Centre Support in partnership with Restless Development Zambia (RDZ) continued with the additional human resources to staff the 5600 Toll-free contact centre. In 2021, the MSZ contact Centre recorded 6,134 calls, of which 2,632 (22%) were adolescent clients, up from 19% in 2020. A total of 641 adolescents were referred for services, an increase of 130% from December 2020; 131 for Safe Abortion/Post-Abortion care (SA/PAC) and 292 for Family Planning (FP), and the remaining 218 for other Sexual Reproductive Health related services.

In 2021 all target outcomes were achieved and exceeded. MSZ estimates (using the Marie Stopes International Impact 2 tool) that the services provided in 2021 will avert;

1) an estimated 94,400 unintended pregnancies, 79% above the planned target,

2) an estimated 42,100 unsafe abortions against an initial target of 30,470,

3) 665 maternal deaths against a 2021 target of 478 maternal deaths.

This significant achievement above the target is mostly due to a significantly higher uptake of intra-uterine contraceptive devices (IUCDs) as well as greater availability of implants than originally forecasted. Other innovations and implementation mechanism that led to achieving results included;

&#x2022; The continued implementation of the accelerated service delivery. In 2021 each of the three Sida supported outreach teams was split into two creating six teams thus allowing for more rural clients to be seen via continuous camping rather than every other week as was the case in the original project design.
&#x2022; MSZ continued supporting public sector strengthening with support from Sida. The focus is on increasing quality access to safe abortion/post-abortion care, Bilateral Tubal Ligation (BTL) and Long-Acting Reversible Contraceptives (LARCs) in public facilities.
&#x2022; MSZ trained 40 providers in SA/PAC/Post Abortion Family Planning (PAFP) and 14 in Family Planning full choice service delivery with a lightly higher focus on LARC.
&#x2022; An increase in SA services delivered through the public sector, and the increased number of girls and women accessing FP services, particularly LARCs. MSZ also provided post abortion care services.

Outreach remains MSZs most productive channel providing the highest number of long acting (48,171) and permanent methods (935) to rural girls and women. The Public Sector still provides more short-term (13,383) than LARC (5,734). Short-term methods remain the go to method among public providers because of their ease of provision allowing more clients to be seen than would be the case for LARCs.

While safe abortion is legal in Zambia, there are low levels of awareness and consequently access to the service. 2021 was also a difficult year for SA owing to a letter that was sent from the Attorney General (AG) to the Ministry of Health in March of 2021, which stated that the 2018 National Comprehensive Abortion Care Standards and Guidelines that were being used in the country were in contradiction with the law as provided for under the Termination of Pregnancy (ToP) Act of 1972. The provisions under contention were:

&#x2022; The guidelines provided for safe abortion to be provided across any health facility when the ToP act stated that these services could only be provided in a hospital.
&#x2022; The guidelines provided for any trained and skilled health care provider when the ToP act stated only Medical Practitioners could provide the service.

In response to this, Ministry of Health reached out to MSZ and other partners who hired a legal consultant to help review the guidelines and ensure that they remained within the law without hindering access to SA services to most would-be clients in need of the services. After 10 months of reviews and redrafting of the document, updated guidelines were finally developed and submitted to the Ministry of Health Public Health Directorate for approval and then submission to the Attorney General. Unfortunately, owing to changes in government and subsequently changes in people holding the role of Permanent Secretary, Minister of Health and Attorney General, the rate of progress of the process has slowed down. Additionally, in March 2022, the World Health Organization (WHO) released revised guidelines on safe abortion and the ministry of health has decided to update the national guidelines in accordance with the revised WHO guidelines before responding to the Attorney General&apos;s letter. Fortunately SA services have resumed even as the guidelines are being updated. 

Key lessons learnt during this period include;

&#x2022; There is need for greater domestic resource mobilization for Sexual Reproductive Health
&#x2022; High level national and sub-national ownership increased facility level buy-in
&#x2022; Onsite mentorship is essential for maximum retention of content and competency
&#x2022; Community engagement and support for SRH through local leaders is important for successful implementation of the programme

During this period MSZ was able to adapt and change implementation mechanism to ensure achievement of results in the face of the COVID-19 pandemic and the widespread stockouts of commodities. MSZ also has strong convening power in Zambia and is therefore able to engage in normative dialogue with the ministry of health and other stakeholders. MSZ works directly with the ministry of health and supports public health system strengthening and improved quality of care. Working through and supporting the public health system is a way of strengthening the capacities at these levels but also contributing to sustainable improvement in access and quality of health services and SRHR services for vulnerable groups.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11597" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="2250000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Zambia 2018-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Zambia 2018-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
