<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5119011001-ZMB-16010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technical assistance for implementing NSPP</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Teknisk r&#xE5;dgivning och st&#xF6;d implementering av NSPP</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Denna insats syftar till att st&#xF6;dja Zambias regering i att implementera en beslutad nationell policy for sociala trygghetssystem. FN i Zambia har presenterat ett gemensamt FN program med syfte att st&#xE4;rka s&#xE5;v&#xE4;l policy som utformning av p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende program inom sektorn, st&#xE4;rka system f&#xF6;r utbetalningar, st&#xE4;rkt kapacitet hos relevant personal (HR), st&#xE4;rkt kommunikation och p&#xE5;verkan f&#xF6;r utbyggnaden av sociala trygghetssystem, samt framtagandet av ytterligare evidence kring effekterna av sociala trygghetssystem i Zambia. 

Programmet har en f&#xF6;reslagen total budget p&#xE5; USDM $12 101 700 ( SEK 100 444 110) varav Sverige f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;s bidra med 25 miljoner kronor &#xF6;ver fyra &#xE5;r. Finland, Irland och Storbritannien planerar ocks&#xE5; att st&#xF6;dja programmet. Insatsen ses som delvis komplementerande till det planerade &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkta budgetst&#xF6;det till Zambias regering som fr&#xE4;mst syftar till skala upp systemet med kontantbidrag till fattiga och s&#xE5;rbara m&#xE4;nniskor. Denna planerade insats bereds parallellt men f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntas inte bli beslutad f&#xF6;rr&#xE4;n i b&#xF6;rjan av 2016.

De viktigaste kritiska antagandena bakom f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringsteorin &#xE4;r att Zambias regering fortsatt kommer att st&#xF6;dja en uppskalning av sociala trygghetssystemen och avs&#xE4;tter tillr&#xE4;cklig budget och personella resurser f&#xF6;r detta &#xE4;ndam&#xE5;l.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This contribution aims to support the Government of Zambia in implementing an agreed national policy for social security systems. UN in Zambia have presented a joint UN program aiming to strengthen both the policy design of ongoing programs in the sector, strengthen the system of payments, strengthen the capacity of relevant personnel (HR), enhanced communication and impact of the expansion of the social security system, as well as the development of further evidence on the effects of social protection schemes in Zambia.

The program has a proposed overall budget of the USDM $ 12,101,700 (&#x20AC; 100,444,110), of which Sweden proposes to contribute 25 million over four years. Finland, Ireland and the United Kingdom also plans to support the program. The initiative is seen as partly complementary to the planned targeted budget support to the Government of Zambia that aims to support primarily the scale up of the Zambian social cash transfer program. This planned contribution is assessed in parallel but is not expected to be approved until early in 2016.

The most important critical assumptions underlying the theory of change is that the government of Zambia continues to support the scaling up of social protection systems and hence allocate sufficient budgetary and human resources for this purpose.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF/United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF/United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B04" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1423605.7561126072</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">409045.7546894174</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">731250.7312507312</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">926309.4909325233</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1423605.7561126072</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">409045.7546894175</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">731250.7312507312</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">926309.4909325233</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-01">3535287.627679</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">1423605.7561126072</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-28">409045.7546894174</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-28">731250.7312507312</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-28">926309.4909325232</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/51190110-second-amendment.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Second Amendment</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/51190110-agreement-amendment-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technical assistance for implementing NSPP</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/51190110-agreement-amendment-2.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technical assistance for implementing NSPP</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/51190110-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technical assistance for implementing NSPP</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/51190110-decision-on-contribution.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technical assistance for implementing NSPP</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The UN Joint Programme on Social Protection gives technical assistance to the Government of Zambia to deliver results on the National Social Protection Policy. It is a joint programme with UNICEF, ILO, WFP, FAO and IOM as implementing partners. The overall objectives are to;
To expand social protection coverage
To strengthen integrated delivery systems
To support Communication creating a broader political support and commitment to social protection.
The UNJPSP has contributed to making social protection to become one of the top priorities for the Government. The programme has been instrumental in the dialogue between Government and Cooperating Partners, including the IMF in their discussions with the Government. The UNJPSP has been important in giving policy advices to government and raising awareness on social protection.
The programme consists of five pillars, in line with the National Social Protection Policy. Within the social protection sector there are many different programmes that have suffered from lack of coordination and efficiency. The UNJPSP has been highly instrumental in developing an Integrated Framework, which is a basis for increased coordination within the sector.
A great deal of the UNJPSP has been technical assistance for the scale-up of the Social Cash Transfer Program (SCT), which is also supported by Sweden. In 2017 the number of beneficiary households increased from 242,000 to 537,766 at the end of 2017. This has required a substantial support from the UNJPSP in the form of technical expertise in program design, as well as strengthening financial control.&#xA0;
Within the Social Security Pillar the UNJPSP has contributed expertise on social insurance schemes that provide prevention against poverty across life, such as maternity, illness and old age, primarily through ILO. There has been a focus on the informal sector since that is where the most vulnerable workers are found. Much of the technical assistance has been on pension reforms, maternity insurance and a health insurance. A draft National Health Insurance Bill has been finalized and presented to the Parliament. A Maternity Protection Policy Paper has been finalized and a chapter on Maternity Protection has been added in the Social Protection Bill. These are important steps to increase maternity protection, especially in the informal sector.&#xA0;
Under the Livelihood and Empowerment Pillar, the UNJPSP focuses on interventions that aim to increase household capacity to generate income. An assessment has been done of the programme Food Security Pack, as well as a a scoping exercise to design an improved Food Security Pack. Assistance has been given to strengthen coherence between agriculture and social protection and to improve collaboration between the Ministry of Agriculture and the Ministry of Community Development and Social Services.&#xA0;
The Social Protection Pillar intends to enforce systems that prevent and respond to violence, abuse, exploitation and neglect of poor and vulnerable populations. The UNJPSP has supported the strengthening of structures that address trafficking and migration-related issues. Several steps for improvements in this area have been taken.&#xA0;
One important part has been to develop access for people with disabilities.&#xA0;The work of UNJPSP with the Zambia Agency for Persons with Disabilities (ZAPD) has raised the capacity and profile of that agency and has played an important role in mainstreaming disability. This is reflected in the Social Cash Transfer Programme, where persons with disability are one of the target groups.
In November 2017 the programme was evaluated in a Mid-term Review done by the consultant Nicholas Freeland. He concludes that the UNJPSP has been successful on several fronts and has even exceeded its outputs in many areas. All the institutions that the consultant met under the review were highly positive about the capacity building achievements of the UNJPSP.The report mention specifically the role of the programme when it comes to;
- Social Cash Transfer scale-up&#xA0;
- Operationalisation of National Social Protection Policy
- Disability&#xA0;
- Drafting of the Social Protection Bill and the Social Health Insurance Bill
- Home Grown School Meals; UNJPSP has worked closely with the Ministry of General Education to improve the system of Home Grown School Meals
-Migrants; Developing a framework for diversion and case management</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51190110" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
