<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="KES" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>KE-RCO-105217-XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000002879</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="KE-RCO-105217" secondary-reporter="1" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya Private Sector Alliance</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Inclusive Business (SIB-K)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Driving private sector (together with civil society, Non-Governmental Organisations (NGOs) and Governments) towards being sustainable and inclusive. This is achieved by empowering and supporting enterprises to embrace sustainability in their business models, reduce their carbon footprint and negative impact on the planet, and increase their positive impact on people while generating profit.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private sector, government, civil society and academia</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">a. Increase awareness, knowledge and social dialogue on the importance and opportunities of Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR), sustainability and inclusiveness among Small &amp; Medium Enterprises (SMEs) and corporate. b. Expand and strengthen the application of sustainable inclusive business principles, strategies and practices within businesses and organisations (small, medium and large).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="40000002879" ref="KE-RCO-105217" role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya Private Sector Alliance</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000002879" crs-channel-code="11000" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Minister for Foreign Trade and Development Cooperation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is the date when the project started.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is designed to support the private sector in Kenya with a spillover impact on the public sector.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="12" percentage="100" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="KES" value-date="2019-09-01">25539136</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="KES" value-date="2019-09-01">25834368</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Logical-Framework_-SIB-K_-KEPSA-20200315100301.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Logical Framework</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-09-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="PCB19KE01" type="3"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthen the adoption of sustainable business practices</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expand and strengthen application of sustainable inclusive business principles, strategies and practices within businesses and organisations (small, medium and large).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing staff capacity through continuous training and staff development.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of team building sessions</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Two team building session held with the  management team</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of policy interventions/input submitted to/through KEPSA sector boards.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="1" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Team is actively involved in the Environment; Education; Gender &amp; Youth and Agriculture sector boards. SIB-K contributed to the Sustainable Waste Management Policy in 2019 and the ongoing Extended Producer Responsibility regulations 2020.
The SIB-K team participated and contributed in the development of the No Single Use Plastic Ban action plan on protected areas together with the KEPSA Environmental Sector Board. SIB-K&#x2019;s participation on the Environmental Sector Board led to the development of the Circular Economy sub-sector board under the Environmental sector board. The National Solid Waste Management bill and policy was approved by cabinet.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of organisations adopting SIB practices or changing their operations to become more sustainable and inclusive</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="20" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="53">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The EPR initiative garnered 33 businesses who committed to be part of the producer responsibility organisation, which will lead to increased collection and recycling of plastic packaging material. In order to guide this process SIB-K in collaboration with KAM developed a PRO business model. 13 business supported in the COAST Project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of consultancy activities carried out.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="4" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">SIB-K a knowledge centre at KEPSA implemented an assignment in collaboration with KAM funded by the Netherlands Enterprise Agency to develop a business model for an Producer Responsibility Organisation, the COAST project as well as the knowledge sharing session for women in the flower sector. Waste Management Study (Zimbabwe, Zambia, Malawi), Kenya E-Waste Study, Review of SUP Regulations in East Africa, WWF OPOB Conference, IUCN Documented Best Practices.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of staff trained</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="5" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">SIB-K team undertook an eight-week online course on Introduction to Circular Economy offered on the edX platform. Others underwent a training on project management. During a monthly meeting staff were trained in financial investment and health.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of businesses sensitized and engaged</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="5" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="35"></target>
     <actual value="52">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The first work shop was on e-waste where 4 business participated: Close the Gap, Kenya; WEEE Centre; Sinomet Kenya Ltd and Recykla International. 2 other workshops were conducted on single-use plastic and supply chain management. A total of 60 participants joined the discussions. 80% of the participants were satisfied with the webinar and acknowledged that the webinar increases awareness on policy hence lead to change in operations through a poll conducted.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of trainings carried out</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="7" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the  COAST Project, we trained 101 women and youth (10 training sessions) on the waste to value concept. 19 business cases were developed with 13 being provided a seed funding. 5 knowledge sharing sessions were held with various stakeholders in the flower sector leading to the documentation of recommended support required for the sector to ensure resilience post COVID-19.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of training sessions</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="7" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training sessions were executed on conducting tv interviews, circular economy, project management and Microsoft project.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased awareness on sustainable business practices.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased awareness, knowledge and social dialogue on the importance and opportunities of Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR), sustainability and inclusiveness amongst Small &amp; Medium Enterprises (SMEs) and corporates.</narrative>
   </description>
   <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Logical-Framework_-SIB-K_-KEPSA-20200315100301.pdf">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Logical Framework SIB-K</narrative>
    </title>
    <category code="A08"></category>
    <language code="EN"></language>
    <document-date iso-date="2019-09-01"></document-date>
   </document-link>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of publications</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">3 trend reports were published, the two reports were on single-use plastic, e-waste management in Kenya and circular economy. 2 policy briefs were documented on EPR Regulations 2020 and the National Waste Management Policy. 6 case studies were documented on be practices in reducing marine litter.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of businesses highlighted in the publication.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">5 businesses cases were highlighted within the trend report and 6 in documented case studies.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting SIB principles through mass media channels such as TV and newspapers</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of TV/ Radio appearances including interviews.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="10" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="23">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">23 TV and Radio interviews were conducted. The Kenya Tourism Federation joined the discussion therefore bringing into the discourse the role of the hotel industry in ensuring the environment is conserved. The aim here was to raise awareness on the single use plastic ban in restricted areas e.g. National Parks, Forests, Beaches and National Reserves. Other interviews focused on EPR Regulations 2020, Waste Management Policy as well as the adoption of sustainable business practises. SIB-K was hosted at Spice FM and BBC to deliberate in circular economy matters.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting SIB principles through mass media channels such as TV and newspapers.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of published newspaper and online articles on sustainability and inclusiveness</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="15" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
     <actual value="143">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">SIB-K published 143 articles (articles published in the newspaper and online platforms). The articles focused on the need to reduce the disposal of plastic in the environment. Other articles sought to raise awareness on the single-use plastics ban that took effect on the 5th of June 2020. This initiated a conversation on the need to find alternatives based on the list of items to be restricted in protected areas. This includes parks, national parks, national reserves, beaches and forests. The need to adopt resilient business practices was raised. Other conversations aimed to increase awareness on separation of waste at source and the transition to a circular economy.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of businesses that contribute and transform through the meetings and fora.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="15" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="40"></target>
     <actual value="123">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The first work shop was on e-waste where 4 business participated: Close the Gap, Kenya; WEEE Centre; Sinomet Kenya Ltd and Recykla International. 2 other workshops were conducted on single-use plastic and supply chain management. A total of 60 participants joined the discussions. 80% of the participants were satisfied with the webinar and acknowledged that the webinar increase awareness on policy hence lead to change in operations through a poll conducted. 71 businesses participated in the 1st webinar of a webinar series on PPPs in the sector organized in collaboration with 2030WRG.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of companies, academia, civil society and government agencies participating in the engagement.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="200" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="350"></target>
     <actual value="230">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2020 SIB-K annual conference was hosted on the 18th of September 2020, with a total of 230 registrations. Discussions were geared towards the shift to a circular economy as well as opportunities and risks presented to the private sector. The virtual event was attended by; Amb. Maarten Brouwer, Amb. Simon Mordue and Amb. Erik Lundberg and Dr. Ayub Macharia, Ministry of Environment and Forestry. Ms. Carole Karuga, our circular economy champion, led the call to the private sector to support the shift from a linear to a circular economy.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of speaking and moderating sessions.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="25" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="19">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">SIB-K participated in several workshop on e-waste, waste to value accelerator program organized by the Best Sellers Foundation, the eco-warrior awards, KOEE Litter Less Online Forum, a webinar on sustainable procurement with SSP, a business forum organized by the Strathmore Business School on waste management, setup of the COAST Project, Review of Dutch policy on Responsible Business Responsibility, webinar on single use plastic, webinar on the EPR 2020 Regulations, SNV&#x2019;s Research webinar on the impact of COVID-19 on food systems, and a webinar on Sustainability in the Wake of Covid-19: Perspectives from Business, Higher Education, Utility Management, Waste Management organized in collaboration with the Committee on Fiscal Studies (CFS) and the Global Challenge Research Fund (GDRF) one health initiative.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of companies reached via the portal</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure website has current and accurate sustainable inclusive business information and is interactive.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="500" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1000"></target>
     <actual value="7451">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The website was refurbished in 2019, an increase in reach has been experienced this year due to review and updating of content that is relevant to businesses and aligned to the thematic areas.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maintaining a sustainable inclusive business database.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Updating, cleaning and verifying data on businesses.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="600" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1500"></target>
     <actual value="1125">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The database was cleaned and classification done based on industry. On a monthly basis SIB shares sector relevant information. The database will be made comprehensive by including new KEPSA Membership (under the category of SMEs)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of social media impressions</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="600" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1500000"></target>
     <actual value="1716692">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project has surpassed the target on impressions on Twitter, LinkedIn, Facebook. The improvement can be attributed to the project&#x2019;s communication strategy to use online platforms as the major communication channels during the COVID-19 pandemic. The target has been revised upwards to 1,500,000 impressions.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of successful partnerships made between businesses/organisations.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-09-01" value="8" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="16"></target>
     <actual value="13">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">4 organisations were able to develop partnerships through the Partner Up Platform created on the web portal. The platform created an opportunity for businesses with an ask/need to partner with businesses or institutions that have the capacity to purchase a product or support an initiative during the COVID period. Sunworld Safaris, UCESCO, KOEE and SSP were able to build partnerships. We built partnerships with KAM, JKUAT, INCENTRO, WEEE Centre, Close the Gap, UoN, Alliance Francaise, Flipflopi Foundation, Intellecap,</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
