<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-235892</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">R&#xF8;de Kors i Danmarks indsats i Dohuk, Irak, 2014</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development objective: Populations affected by the violence in northern Iraq receive immediate, efficient and life-saving humanitarian assistance. Immediate objective: Immediate water and sanitation needs of the target beneficiaries are covered and their psychosocial well-being and resilience improved. The program will target 10,000 of the most vulnerable internally displaced persons (IDPs) in Dohuk province and address their immediate humanitarian needs through the Iraqi Red Crescent Society. There are 3 expected results. Result I: IDPs seeking safety in Dohuk province have safe and equitable access to water and sanitation facilities; 5,220 IDPs get access to adequate water for drinking, cooking and hygiene purposes. More specifically, 1,500 IDPs will benefit from 60 constructed or rehabilitated kitchens with electricity, 2,600 persons will benefit from 100 latrines, 220 persons will get access to no less than 20 litres of water per day over 3 months by water trucking, and 900 persons will benefit from rehabilitation of a water network (replacing water trucking). Result II: Affected men, women and children of all ages are aware of key public health risks and have adopted measures to prevent deterioration in hygienic conditions; 6,500 people will receive 1,000 hygiene kits, 10,000 IDPS will attend hygiene promotion sessions over 6 months, and cleaning campaigns will be run in 8 locations. Result III: The psychosocial well-being and resilience of target population has improved through the provision of community-based psycho-social support (PSP); The psychosocial needs of 2000 IDP children and 500 adults will be covered. Group sessions will be organized for IDPs in informal settlements and in communities. Distress and trauma experienced by the IDPs will be addressed. Children will be given opportunities to engage in play and recreational activities appropriate to their age. Target area: Northern Dohuk Governorate of Kurdistan Region of Iraq with a major influx of IDPs</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="2014-15313">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-235892-29043" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
