<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-228774</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General support to International Council of Voluntary Agencies ICVA, 2014-2015</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The International Council of Voluntary Agencies (ICVA) is an independent international alliance of non-governmental organizations involved in humanitarian aid. ICVA&#xBF;s task is to act as a global forum for international humanitarian NGOs, and manage the contact with the UN system. ICVA also acts as the voice of NGOs to donors in the humanitarian field.
ICVA is an active and visible actor in Geneva, where the headquarters are located. ICVA represent the members in all relevant local humanitarian fora.This ensures that ICVA has real influence on decision-making in these organizations and forums.

ICVA has also been an active participant in the development of norms and standards for humanitarian assistance. ICVA has over 75 members, many of which are from developing countries.
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs has supported ICVA with an annual core contribution of DKK 500,000 since 1998. In 2012 the contribution was increased to DKK. 750,000 based on the results the organization has achieved and the central position it occupies in the international debate on development of new certification and standardization systems and its role in the ongoing dialogue with the UN system.

The Danish contribution of DKK 1.5 million for the budget years 2014 and 2015 is given as an un-earmarked core contributions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="2018-30877">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief co-ordination and support services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-228774-28475" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
