<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-237790</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council&apos;s activities in Dafur, Sudan, 2014</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The purpose is to provide emergency agriculture support to areas in Jebel Marra in order to reduce mortality and improve the food security status of the most vulnerable households in these hard-to-access areas. The contribution from Danida is being used to meet the immediate food needs of more vulnerable persons in Jebel Marra area and enable them to restore their livelihoods. This intervention targets 10,000 households in Jebel Marra Area &#xBF; approximately 50,000 direct beneficiariesl &#xBF; who will have improved access to food. DRC has identified and targetted the most vulnerable communities and also the most vulnerable members within each community - identified by the community themselves, and then verified by DRC staff. This intervention prioritises support to vulnerable female headed households, followed by the more vulnerable male headed households. The main activities are: 1. Provision of agricultural production support for 10,000 extremely vulnerable households (50,000 beneficiaries) to enable them to contribute to their food requirement by their own means and restore and safeguard livelihoods. 2. Distribution of winter seeds and training to 10,000 extremely vulnerable farming households (50,000 beneficiaries). The winter seed distribution will further reinforce the communities&#xBF; food security capacity and contribute to minimizing the IPC forecasted decline into phase 4 food security status. Winter season crops include tomatoes, garlic, and onion, and beneficiaries will receive seeds adequate to plant 0.42 hectares of land. The project will preferentially use a seed vouchers system since some seeds are available in the neighbouring local markets. DRC had an experienced team of national and expatriate staff to bolster the existing team capacity in the Nertiti office for the first, and most urgent, weeks of implementation</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="2014-22873">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-237790-29206" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
