<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-240193</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nationally Appropriate Mitigation Actions (NAMA) Facility</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The NAMA Facility was set up by Germany and the UK in 2013. The overall objective set out for the facility is to facilitate transformation towards low carbon pathways in developing countries with reference to the internationally agreed goal to keep global warming below two degrees Celsius compared with pre-industrial levels. This facilitation is achieved by supporting the realisation of ambitious and innovative NAMAs (National Appropriate Mitigation Actions) in developing countries and emerging economies. 
Through the NAMA Facility, Denmark seeks to attribute to demonstration short-term of successful leverage of finance for implementation of ambitious and transformational NAMAs. The facility provides funding for technical support and institutional and regulatory capacity development combined with or closely linked to development financial instruments to leverage public and private finance. 
The NAMA Facility is at present the predominant international financing mechanism for supporting implementation of NAMAs in particular as the Green Climate Fund is not yet operational. The UK and DE have up until now allocated Euro 119 million and both countries pledged additional funding for 2015/2016 in December 2014 at COP20 in Lima. The Facility is open for other multi- and bilateral donors. Through Climate Envelope 2014 Denmark joined the NAMA Facility as an additional donor providing financing amounting to DKK 73.8 million for a third call announced by the Facility at COP20. The EU Commission also contributed Euro 15 million to the Facility.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="2014 - 18815">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-240193-29510" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-240193-34940" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
