<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-214475</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRCT Seminar on redress for victims of torture and ill-treatment</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2013, the annual UN Human Rights Council (HRC) resolution on torture and other cruel, inhuman and degrading treatment and punishment will take a thematic focus on rehabilitation within the wider framework of redress for victims of torture and ill-treatment. Redress is a highly specialised and complex theme compared to themes of most other resolutions at the HRC. One of the main obstacles during negotiations of past thematic torture resolutions has been the lack of an in-depth understanding of the topic among diplomats. This was most noticeable during the 2009 negotiationsTo prevent this scenario from repeating it-self in 2013, it will be important for the constructive conduct of negotiations that diplomats from countries that are key to a successful outcome increase their background knowledge and understanding of the topic. 
To address this need, the IRCT will facilitate the implementation of a 1/2 day seminar for Geneva-based diplomats and approximately 15 resource persons and other stakeholders on redress for victims of torture and ill-treatment. The seminar will focus on the two main components of redress: reparations and effective remedy. It will provide a space where diplomats can have an informal discussion with experts in this field from non-governmental organisations, academia and from Governments. Introductory briefings on each component will seek to provide all participants with a basic knowledge of the subject and the following open floor discussion will provide a space to shed further light on any doubt, questions of misunderstanding that participants may be left with. 
Finally, the seminar may also prove to be a useful venue for initial informal discussions on how to approach the negotiations in a manner that avoids the main political pitfalls presented by the thematic focus. 
The seminar will be hosted jointly by IRCT, the Association for the Prevention of Torture (APT) and the Permanent Mission of Denmark to the United Nations in Geneva.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-214475-27302" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
