<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-214455</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Framework Agreement 2013, Save the children</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Occupied Palestinian TerritoriesThis project has improved the psychosocial wellbeing of Palestinian children in East Jerusalem and Gaza and strengthened the overall coordination of education response amongst government, NGO and UN partners.
Pakistan: The project reached 8 flood affected vulnerable communities and 16 village committees and 16 children clubs were trained on disaster risk reduction (DRR), hazard vulnerability capacity assessment, life skills, and safety measures at community level. The project benefited over 11,000 women, children and men in targeted communities and enabled them to better prepare for upcoming disaster. Ethiopia: Reached 16,100 school-going children in 46 schools in the four intervention woredas (districts) of the North Wollo Zone in Amhara with school feeding and child centered disaster risks reduction activities in 2013 improving the school access and retention of the children and increased the awareness of DRR resilience, preventions and preparedness responses at community and zonal level. 
South Sudan: The project has increased access to inclusive, quality education in a safe learning environment for children and young people in Northern Bahr El Ghazal state and improved general psychosocial wellbeing of 1,000 returnee and host community children in 10 selected schools. It has also strengthened the management capacity of the county education authorities at state level. Somalia:The project has selected, trained and secured employment options of 150 vulnerable youth and reached out to app. 2500 youth through Training of Trainers trainings of 7 youth umbrella organizations in subjects like leadership, advocacyadvocacy and conflict resolution. Somalia &#xBF; This project reached 2500 Internally Displaced People and host community children in 10 schools with a programming approach combining basic education, child protection and Disaster Risk Reduction-resilient methods leading to a safer and better learning environment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="46.H.7-4-147.">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-214455-26727" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
