<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-223509</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bridge-building between Green Growth challenges in Africa 
and Danish expertise through increased and improved 
media coverage in Ghana, Kenya and South Africa.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the pilot project, implemented by International Media Support (IMS), is to increase knowledge and awareness among decision-makers in the private and public sector on the Green Growth challenges in Africa and of the development opportunities and green tech solutions to these offered by Danish expertise.
 
Specific Objective are to 1) increase awareness and knowledge among selected journalists and journalistic networks of the benefits of green/cleaner technology and advantages of new technologies offered by Danish Green Growth initiatives as solutions to development challenges; 2) build capacity of a selected group of journalists and journalistic networks in Ghana, Kenya and South Africa to report on solutions to development challenges within energy, environment and climate change on the continent, and 3) increase knowledge among Danish media, political and private decision-makers of the Green Growth challenges faced by countries in Africa as well as increased knowledge on the current public and political debates on Green Growth themes in Africa.
 
The project entails a five-phased implementation process, including a baseline study identifying current media coverage in selected African written media as well as the participation of journalists and editors from Ghana, Kenya and South Africa in a study tour to Denmark.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="104.Afrika.36.">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="22030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Radio/television/print media</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-223509-27883" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
