<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-218744</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peace and Stabilisation Respons (PSR) activities administrated by NIRAS 2013-15</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is in Denmark&apos;s interest that the international community plays an active role inhelping to ensure and promote peace, stability and democratisation. This cannot be accomplished solely through negotiations and resolutions; the international community also needs to field personnel and experts to assist in hotspots around the world. The Peace and Stabilisation Response (PSR) helps to ensure that Denmark has a prominent place when it is necessary for the international community to intervene. PSR was established in 1994 as the international humanitarian Service (IHB) &#xBF; but changed its name in 2012 to the Peace and Stabilisation Response. PSR is responsible for deploying experts and other qualified personnel to the civilian component of peace- and stabilisation interventions, humanitarian, conflict-preventing, peacekeeping operations or election observation missions around the world in the world&#xBF;s most fragile and conflict affected areas and the rising democracies. PSR is a roster under the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Denmark that receives and assesses calls for contribution for Danish experts to be deployed for international missions (Civilian Crisis Management Missions or Election Observation Missions) from, among others, the EU, UN, NATO and the OSCE. The Roster contains a database currently with 483 experts ready to be deployed at short notice around the world. The Danish PSR experts are a diverse group of election experts, crisis management experts, logisticians, legal experts, political advisors and many, many others who at short notice are ready to undertake international assignments. PSR is financed through the Danish Finance Act and headed by the Stabilisation and Security Policy Unit in the Ministry of Foreign Affairs. Since September 2008 the administration of the PSR has been outsourced to the Danish consultancy firm NIRAS while the MFA keeps the overall political and strategic responsibility and defines the priorities for secondments through the PSR.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="46.H.5.NIRAS.2013-15.">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sectors not specified</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-218744-27362" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-218744-28209" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-218744-28833" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-218744-29698" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
