<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-218911</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dignity DAPP 2013</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2013-2016 DIGNITY MENA programme &#xBF;Freedom from Torture &#xBF; in The Middle East and North Africa&#xBF; aims to contribute to the prevention of torture and the rehabilitation of victims of torture across the MENA region, with a special focus on 4-5 countries (Jordan, Egypt, Tunisia and Morocco. Libya was included until end 2015.) In two regional sub-projects experiences are shared among these countries as well as with other countries in the MENA region and Denmark. The target groups for the MENA programme are human rights activists (health, legal and other) in organisations/institutions, as well as reform agents within state-institutions such as Ministries of Justice. The ultimate beneficiaries are victims of torture and ill treatment and people deprived of their liberty. The MENA programme focuses on four types of interventions; 1) preventing torture by monitoring of prisons and other places of detentions, 2) reforming criminal justice institutions (especially prosecution services) to uphold obligations with regard to the prevention of torture, 3) documenting of torture cases for possible litigation, and 4) rehabilitation of torture victims. To the extent possible the interventions involve partnerships with relevant Danish NGO&#xB4;s, semi-state and state institutions such as the Danish Prosecution, the Danish Ombudsman and DIGNITY&#xBF;s own rehabilitation clinic. Occasionally also other European state institutions are involved. Cross-cutting activities on results-monitoring, dialogue, advocacy and gender also take place within the programme. Representatives from state institutions and CSOs in 10 MENA countries are participating in the activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-218911-27495" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
