<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-237804</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children&apos;s activities in South Sudan and Uganda, 2014</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With this intervention, Save the Children aims to contribute to the protection of rights, psychosocial well-being, and non-disruption of education for children and youth in Doro refugee camp and the surrounding host communities in Maban County. The intervention allows Save the Children to expand protection activities into the host community and aims to promote peaceful relations between the vulnerable populations in the host and refugee communities. Save the Children will establish two Child Friendly Spaces and rehabilitate five Child Friendly Spaces in Doro refugee camp. The project will also facilitate a series of meetings and activities between children, community leaders and stakeholders from both communities to discuss common child protection concerns and agree on ways forward. Enabling host community learners to attend school in Doro refugee camp primary, ALP and community-led secondary schools will also help facilitate closer relations between the host and refugee communities. Save the Children continues to promote quality in teaching and learning and supports the enrolment of host community teachers in Save the Children&#xBF;s ongoing in-service teacher training at various levels in Maban County. The intervention will support volunteer structures in the host community and providing technical and material support to the local authorities. 

In Uganda, this project intends to strengthen the existing intervention by implementing an integrated program, focusing on further reducing protection vulnerability, ensuring access to education and providing life skills to South Sudanese refugee children and host community in Arua, Adjumani and Kiryandongo refugee settlements in Uganda. The intervention will also integrate a response to malnutrition focusing on Infant and Young Child Feeding.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="2014-22822">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-237804-29208" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
