<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-230005</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Red Cross Denmark support to Syria and Lebanon, 2014</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will assist 82,613 people affected by the Syria crisis in Syria and Lebanon and enhance the capacity of Syrian Arab Red Crescent (PRCS) and Palestinian Red Crescent Society (PRCS) in Syria as well as Lebanese Red Cross (LRC) in Lebanon. In Syria, emergency and primary health care services will be provided to 46,513 persons while SARC and PRCS will assisted in decentralizing their response. By supporting two SARC clinics in Rural Damascus, health care services are ensured in areas where the public health care system has ceased functioning. This includes two clinics in Jeyroud and Sahnaya, A third clinic is planned in Tal Mneen. Three hospitals and two clinics run by PRCS will also be supported in Damascus, Homs and Aleppo, serving Palestinian refugees. Insulin will be provided for 9,000 insulin-dependent diabetics through SARC health care facilities in all 14 governorates. SARC&#xBF;s capacity to provide relief and humanitarian assistance will be sustained and enhanced by SARC HQ, two SARC branches in Rural Damascus and Deir ez-Zour and six sub-branches in four governorates. In Lebanon, emergency medical services will be provided to 19,200 Syrian refugees and vulnerable Lebanese in the Bekaa valley, which has the highest number of refugees in Lebanon, as well as in conflict-affected areas of Tripoli. The programme also supports the emergency services&#xBF; ability to respond following outbreak of violence and conflict. In this way, the project ensures humanitarian access in the most conflict-affected areas. Primary health care services will be provided to 16,900 Syrian refugees and vulnerable Lebanese through a mobile medical unit in the rural environs of Tripoli as well as through a health centre in the most impoverished area of Tripoli. The primary health care provided through the mobile clinic and the health centre includes maternal and paediatric health care and offers health awareness sessions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="46.H.7-1-210.">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-230005-28566" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
