<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-216978</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10th Replenishment of the Asian Development Fund (ADF XI)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Asian Development Fund (AsDF) is the soft window of the Asian Development Bank (AsDB) offering loans at low interest rates and grants to poor and fragile countries in the region. The fund was established in 1973 and is replenished with four years intervals. The total 10th replenishment covering 2013-2016 amounts to USD 12.4 billion and enables continuation of the fund&apos;s work to bridge the development gap in Asia and the Pacific with a focus on inclusive growth, environmentally sustainable growth and regional integration. Denmark will contribute with a 0.43 % share, which was also the case in the previous replenishment. AsDB is an efficient development organisation with a proven track record in reducing poverty in the region through AsDF assistance. 

The objective of the Danish contribution to the 10th replenishment of the AsDF (AsDF XI) is to enable the fund to continue its effort to reduce poverty in Asia and the Pacific through the AsDB&apos;s Strategy 2020 and its three complementary development agendas: i) inclusive growth, ii) environmentally sustainable growth, and iii) regional integration. To pursue its strategic agenda and make impact on the region&apos;s challenges, ADB will place emphasis on five drivers of change: developing the private sector, encouraging good governance, supporting gender equity, helping developing countries gain knowledge, and expanding partnerships with other development institutions, the private sector, and with community-based organizations.

Denmark will give particular emphasis on ensuring a comprehensive AsDF focus on conflict-affected and fragile states with Afghanistan and Pakistan as main priorities. It is also a clear priority for Denmark to maintain and strengthen AsDB&apos;s role as a regional financial institution with a clear development agenda and a continued high level of grants and soft loans to Asia&apos;s poorest and most fragile countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2013001209</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">73.C.106.g-11.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-216978</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-06" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-216978-27980" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
