<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-218906</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danmission DAPP 2013</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#xBF;Promotion of peace building, social cohesion and mutual understanding through interreligious dialogue&#xBF; through partnership agreement with Danmission (in close cooperation with National Council of Churches in Denmark and Muslimsk F&#xE6;llesr&#xE5;d). The aim is an enhanced role of interreligious dialogue as an integral factor of promoting peace building, social cohesion and mutual understanding within and between Arab and Danish societies. The activities will focus on Egypt, Syria, Lebanon and Denmark. In particular, young religious leaders will be involved in activities.

The activities in 2014 include the following programs: Syrian Youth Encounter (SYE), Revolution in the Arab World (Syrian Leaders), Contact Group for Muslims and Christians (National Council of Churches), and a strategic reserve. The strategic reserve has been used as a pool for DK-MENA partnership projects and thus supported four projects involving a great number of religious and civil society actors; 
o	Christians of the Orient, a project involving national workshops in Iraq, Jordan and Egypt, and a regional workshop on the topic of the future of Christians and other minorities in MENA. 
o	International Work and Study Camp (IWSC), a youth camp with 30 Muslim and Christian participants from Denmark and MENA with the aim of promoting peace through interreligious dialogue. 
o	Didactics of Dialogue and Reconciliation (DIDAR), a cooperation with Danish and Lebanese educational institutions with the aim of qualifying teacher students to facilitate religious dialogue and co-existence.
 As the two prior projects, SYE and Syrian Leaders, were financed by both DMFA agreement 5.-41 and 6.-13., they will be reported under agreement 6.-13.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">104.Arabiske Lande.6-13</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-218906</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-218906-27501" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
