<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-216487</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to JIPS, 2013-2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Displacement-affected populations are able to reach sustainable solutions supported by the well-informed, collective decisions and actions or responses of government, humanitarian and development actors. With an objective To facilitate and support governments, humanitarian and development actors to gather and analyse data in a coordinated manner, which informs collaborative responses to displacement. The targets groups of the project are people affected by displacement and their host communities; government departments, humanitarian and development organisations and profiiling coordinators. The indirect target group includes the entire humanitarian and development community who will benefit from improved availability of more reliable and accurate information/ better data sets. JIPS&#xBF; field support unit has supported 16 operations, contributing to the enhancement of the profiling process, the availability of disaggregated data, and the development of appropriate profiling tools, guidance and training. JIPS&#xBF; profiling training and capacity building occured during field support activities, and in 2014, through two Global Profiling Coordination Trainings (PCT)s, and by contributing modules to two training events conducted by IDMC. The information management unit has maintained and upgraded two online toolkits: The PARK (Profiling and Assessment Resource Kit www.parkdatabase.org) and the JET (JIPS Essential Toolkit http://jet.jips.org/). JIPS launched the Dynamic Analysis and Reporting Tool (the DART www.dart.jips.org) in 2014. On advocacy for profiling, members of the JIPS team has participated in 13 events including the sponsorship of the Special Rapporteur on the Human Rights of IDPS to an event in 2014. The JIPS Communication team published 3 &#xBF;Profiling At a Glance&#xBF; reports (Quito, Dehli and Mali ), a guidance for urban profiling and a quarterly newsletter.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-04-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-22" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unallocated / Unspecified</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-216487-27100" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-216487-29511" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-216487-30940" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-216487-32446" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
