<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-236974</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RDPP 2014-2018</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Regional Development and Protection Programme (RDPP) was launched in 2014 as a response to the refugee displacement in the region. The RDPP aims at addressing the protractedness of the crisis by combining development and humanitarian assistance to provide for longer-term solutions for refugees and host communities in Iraq, Jordan and Lebanon. The RDPP is a multi-donor programme funded by the EU, Ireland, the Netherlands, Czech Republic, Norway, Switzerland, the UK and Denmark. The total budget for the 4-year programme amounts to approx. 42 million Euros. The programme is managed by Denmark though Programme Management Units in Beirut and Amman. 
With the objective of ensuring that refugees are able to avail themselves of a durable solution and to support socio-economic development in host countries, benefitting host populations and refugees, and enhancing the capacity of refugees to contribute as positive development actors. 
The programme is structured in four thematic areas: research, livelihoods, protection and advocacy with a range of sub-categories supporting each thematic area. 
The research component is focused on supporting analysis and research on the impact of the Syrian displacement on the region and on policy framework in the region in a solutions-oriented perspective. The research is linked to the advocacy and policy dialogue component, which focus on support to dialogue platforms and development of advocacy papers to form the basis for dialogue on the displacement crisis. Some advocacy partnerships are focused around specific issues, such as sexual and gender-based violence. 
The protection component support partners in provision of legal assistance to vulnerable refugees and host community members, combatting child labour, SGVB, and capacity building of national authorities to address protection risks in the local communities. 
Finally, the livelihood component is aimed at enhancing the self-reliance of refugees and host community members through s</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The program will be implemented for the benefit of not only Syrian refugees, but also the hard-hit communities. Other refugees may be included if relevant in the present context. The program will consist of the following activities:
- Activities to strengthen refugee protection through individual counseling, capacity building of relevant authorities and civil society organizations in order to ensure that refugees are treated in accordance with international principles.
- Activities in favor of the social and economic development of communities that host refugees, including improving living conditions primarily through income and employment incentives among refugees as well as local host communities. It is expected, among other things to include technical training, support for the establishment of small businesses and shops etc.
- Implementation of independent analysis to ensure a more objective and accurate knowledge-base for the authorities and aid organizations&apos; future efforts in host countries. The analysis will include focus on social and economic consequences of the protracted refugee crisis in these countries. The analytical work is carried out by local and international institutional capacities in the host countries. The work is expected to be conducted by the World Bank and will to some extent include capacity building of local partners.
- Advocacy, policy dialogue and communication, which helps to ensure that neighboring countries&apos; governments and peoples remain prepared to keep the borders open for the refugees.
- Programme management, monitoring etc. In accordance with the general guidelines of the EU Commission&apos;s aid direct costs for program development and management is covered. It involves costs to pay for a program manager and two program officers, the operation of the program offices in Amman and Beirut, as well as the costs of any external consultants.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-09-26" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-16" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="720" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-236974-30258" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
