<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-237960</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Minor study: Assessing National and Regional Capacities for Implementing the Responsibility to Protect (R2P) in Ghana and West Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The research project, &#xBF;Assessing National and Regional Capacities for Implementing the Responsibility to Protect (R2P) in Ghana and West Africa, focuses on the operationalization of R2P specifically in Ghana but with a wider inference to the West Africa region. The project sets out to examine the state of readiness of various actors in Ghana and member states of the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) to ensure the implementation and operationalization of R2P. The focus will be on the implementing process of R2P in Ghana and the region, paying specific attention to the historical and local contexts. The project will also seek to create awareness on R2P, its principles and pillars.

The project is designed as a case study to be implemented in Ghana but will be enriched with experiences of other ECOWAS member states and a critical interrogation of the ECOWAS Conflict Prevention Framework and its relationship with R2P. The research results will further create the needed awareness among government entities, Civil Society Organizations (CSOs) and ECOWAS to ensure its application. 

The West Africa Network for Peacebuilding (WANEP) has been engaged to conduct the research. The process will include a competent research team headed by a Lead Researcher with a good background of peacebuilding practices in West Africa and supported by an External R2P Expert at specific periods in the research. 

WANEP will leverage on its partnership with ECOWAS as well as the government of Ghana to ensure that the results and recommendations emanating from the research influence state policy on R2P.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">104.DAN.8.L.1.ACC.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-237960</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-237960-29182" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
