<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-224743</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Component 3: The United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC) Contribution to the United Nations Integrated Regional Strategy for the Sahel</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the UNODC Contribution to the United Nations Integrated Strategy for the Sahel is to support the strengthening of capacities in the region and enhance the accessibility, efficiency and accountability of criminal justice systems in order to effectively combat drug trafficking, illicit trafficking, organized crime, terrorism and corruption. In this way, national and regional authorities will be better positioned to identify and dismantle the organized crime networks and terrorist groups active at the national and regional level, which is a key step towards deterring their activities.

At the national level, the actions of the programme seek to ensure that criminal justice and law enforcement authorities have the capabilities to arrest suspected criminals, intercept illicit goods and dismantle existing criminal networks, as well as to liaise with the agencies in other countries.

At the regional level, UNODC will assist countries in the Sahel region to effectively implement relevant international instruments, and to promote regional cooperation by strengthening collaborative ties at the national and regional levels. Put together, these efforts will contribute to the broader goal of reducing the negative impact on the Sahel as a whole, so as to make the region safer, more stable and conductive to social and economic development.

In supporting the targeted countries UNODC intends to help strengthen the capacities of relevant national and regional authorities in five interlinked areas: 1) National legislation and regional and international cooperation mechanisms; 2) border control and interdiction; 3) accountable, fair and efficient investigation, prosecution and adjudication of criminal cases; 4) scientific evidence in support of judicial investigations and proceedings, improved procedure, access and treatment in the judicial and prison systems; 5) rehabilitation of imprisoned and/or detained terrorists through harmonized policies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016001180</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">46.H.1-6-0-5-02.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-224743-31303" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
