<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-237815</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MSF activities in South Sudan, 2014</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the emergency intervention for internally displaced persons in Bentiu, Unity State in South Sudan, Doctors Without Borders (M&#xE9;decins Sans Fronti&#xE8;res (MSF)) aims to reduce morbidity and mortality through improved humanitarian conditions and direct medical action for the most vulnerable in and around the Protection of Civilians site, where people seek protection from the persistent armed violence in Unity State. The situation inside the Protection of Civilians site is characterized by difficult living conditions and massive medical needs. During the rainy season, the area is transformed into a swamp, with large areas of knee-deep sewage-laden water. Inadequate supply of clean drinking water and latrines contribute to a constant burden of diarrheal infection amongst the young population with a vicious cycle of infection causing weight loss (with weight loss in turn increasing the vulnerability to infection). MSF is providing clean drinking water and proper sanitation, primary and secondary health care, including mass vaccinations, therapeutic feeding of severe acute malnutrition, maternal and pediatric care, surgeries, and sexual and gender based violence consultations. Health monitoring of for example birth and death rates, hygiene, distribution gaps and outbreak surveillance is a key component in order to be able to adapt to the situation and react timely on outbreaks. When MSF first intervened, the population in the Protection of Civilians site was approximately 30,000 internally displaced persons from Bentiu and surrounding areas in Unity State. The main objective was to reduce morbidity and mortality by providing primary and secondary healthcare for the people within the Protection of Civilians site to respond to the water and sanitation crisis by constructing 100 latrines and to ease the nutritional crisis by providing nutritional treatment to approximately 700 severely acute malnourished children.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014-22854</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014001259</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-237815</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-237815-29211" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
