<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-216485</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to Save the Children in Syria, 2013</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The conflict in Syria is placing millions of Syrian people at risk and over half of the affected population is children who risk death, violence, illness, abuse, exploitation and neglect on a daily basis. This project has provided 10050 households (60300 individuals) with essential non-food items (NFI) to support their basis needs. The improvement of living conditions for the households have been achieved through distribution of 1900 household kits, 3700 full hygiene kits, 7000 consumable hygiene kits, 1330 bed nets, 500 cooking sets and 656 water kits. 
The project has also improved access to water, sanitation and hygiene services (WASH) for approx. 20623 people through life-saving water trucking, constructions of latrines, waste management and hygiene promotion. At the request of the WASH and health working groups, to reduce the risk of transmission, SCI redirected the existing hygiene and water kits in stock to Al Mayadin district, Deir Ez Zor, the area of highest polio case load. The kits including polio guidance notes and were distributed through an implementing partner to IDP families residing in collective shelters established at schools. Out of the 10050 households who received NFIs, 792 families (estimated 4752 persons at 6 individuals per family) from Deir Ez Zor benefited from the delivery of 752 hygiene kits and 40 water kits following the polio outbreak in November 2013. 
Successful and timely implementation of activities was challenged by insecurity within the project area. Incidents included: airstrikes, shelling, clashes between the regime and opposition groups and within various opposition groups, by insecurity at border crossings e.g. bomb explosions and threats, closure of borders and subsequent delays in moving stock through queues at the border points, and through threats and coercion by unregulated camp management at Qah Camp. Thus, this project was non-cost extended until 15 February 2014. Final accounts and final report submitted to Danida</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2013001058</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">46.H.7-4-150.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-216485</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="720" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-216485-27099" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
