<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-229540</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IMS DAPP 2014</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall aim of IMS&apos; Media Cooperation Programme is to enhance the democratic role of the media in the Middle East and North Africa. In support of this, IMS and its partners in the region work to a) further media freedom and safety for journalists; b) enhance the institutional capacity of organisations in the region that promote freedom of expression, media freedom and access to information; c) professionalise and diversify media content; d) further locally owned media development initiatives though networks and exchange.

The programme focuses on Tunisia, Egypt, Syria, Yemen, and Jordan, which each have a dedicated country programme addressing the specific and very varying challenges the media of those countries face. Other countries in the region are targeted through regional and thematic initiatives including documentary filmmaking, investigative journalism, and media law reform. 

In Tunisia, the programme seeks to increase the professionalism, pluralism and diversity of media available, and to enable partners to establish and implement stronger legal and regulatory frameworks for freedom of expression and media freedoms. In Egypt, the programme also seeks to increase the availability of professional, diverse media content, while also seeking to enable partners to stay safe and continue their work. In Yemen, the programme supports a variety of exiled media and seeks to provide for the safety of journalists on the ground in the country. In Jordan, the programme pays particular attention to gender equality addressing women&#xBF;s special needs and interests in the country&#xBF;s conservative areas. And in Syria, the programme addresses a large selection of issues including the safety of journalists, the availability of news and information to audiences both inside and outside the country, as well as the important aspect of coordination of international media development efforts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">104.Arabiske Lande.7-3.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2013001381</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-229540</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-229540-28513" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
