<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-230128</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministerial meeting on Somalia 2014</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The New Deal outlines a contract between the Federal Government of Somalia and the Somali people. The real test of the New Deal process for Somalia, and the vision of the New Deal Compact for Somalia are to build a sovereign, secure, democratic, united and federal Somalia.

The two-day HLPF Copenhagen will draw upon the content of the 2014 New Deal Annual Progress Report for Somalia, which will be co-authored by the Federal Government of Somalia and development partners, and presented in Copenhagen. 

The HLPF Copenhagen will keep Somalia high on the international community&apos;s agenda and will reaffirm all Somalis commitments towards the final steps of the Somali state formation democratic process. 

The overall goal of the HLPF Copenhagen is to maintain the constructive momentum towards a secure, stable and developed Somalia. The HLPF Copenhagen will review progress, take stock of achievements, identify challenges, and agree how to jointly address them. There will be a particular focus on Vision 2016; achieving progress against federalism, including the formation of interim administrations; finalizing and adopting the Federal Constitution, and preparations for national elections in 2016.

The HLPF Copenhagen will be chaired by His Excellency, Hassan Sheikh Mohamud, President of Somalia and co-chaired by the United Nations. Participants will comprise one Somali delegation, including Parliamentarians, selected line ministries, regional representatives, civil society, and the international community including the United Nations, World Bank, African Development Bank, African Union, League of Arab States, IGAD, OIC and bilateral partners.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-230128-28701" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
