<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-242578</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MS DAPP 2015</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MS Arab Regional Initiative is implemented from the office in Amman. Focal countries are Jordan, Lebanon, Egypt and Tunisia. The purpose is to harness the leadership of youth as agents of change to demand accountability from duty bearers and to increase active participation of youth and women in civil society structures and decision making processes with particular focus on refugees and other vulnerable groups. The thematic approach is built around 4 areas/clusters: Youth and women in civil society, Youth in local governance, Youth in conflict and Youth as social entrepreneurs, and aims at concentrating efforts and partners within areas, where MS has strong trademark and unique experience. The modality for bringing about change in the thematic areas is capacity development, empowerment and mobilisation of key stakeholders, duty bearers and rights-holders including partner organisations, grassroots, women rights organisations, civil servants, youth activists and vulnerable groups such as women and refugees. The engine is the Global Platform offering contextualised trainings with a range of topics varying from democratic governance and social accountability to youth leadership and social entrepreneurship. It has developed a systematic approach to organizational capacity support based on needs assessments of organisations and a constant monitoring of progress and results obtained. Six Global Platforms were created in Jordan and Lebanon aiming at providing youth-led, sustainable, safe, friendly and enabling spaces, fostering development of young leaders through participatory and decentralized approach while enhancing conflict resilience among them. Focus is to support refugees, internally displaced and people affected by conflict to be able to assert their rights to meet their needs and status as citizens as well as building social cohesion with surrounding communities to combat stereotypes and stigmas and build peaceful co-existence.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014001407</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015-13003</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-242578</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-18" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-242578-29697" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
