<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-235438</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Minor Study on South-South Cooperation to Open the Capability Trap</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective is to explore how South-South and triangular cooperation may contribute to opening the &apos;capability trap&apos; when capacities from comparable transition contexts are exchanged with a particular focus on post-conflict situations were the capacity deficits are normally particularly challenging.

Key activities:
1. Mapping existing South-South and triangular cooperation initiatives within and beyond the identified areas drawing on the work of the involved and associated partner organisations.

2. Undertaking a &apos;meta study&apos; of key lessons learned as an evidence base for theory development and policy development.

3. Analysing how and why recipient, emerging and emerged economies engage in South-South cooperation to develop key guiding principles.

4. Exploring ways in which donors have been and could in the future, engage in tripartite arrangements within different sectors and mapping of good practices in this context.

5. Analysing the role and potential of an increased involvement of the private sector and civil society in South-South exchanges.

Expected Outcome:
1. An evidence base on which to base Denmark&apos;s strategies for supporting South-South cooperation through trilateral partnerships in the future.

2. New insights into the experiences and outcomes of specific partnership models as well as specific opportunities and challenges within certain sectors, regions and/or modalities.

3. A better understanding of good (and bad)practices in relation to identifying, planning, implementing and evaluating South-South cooperation around capacity development in fragile and conflict-affected settings including the role of political economy dynamics.

4. An active network of knowledge institutions with a collective &apos;research&apos; agenda to further advance the field.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">104.Sydafrika.4.a.254</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-235438</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-235438-28980" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
