<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-228328</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP OCHA CHF CAR, 2014</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">After serious instability that leads to the change of regime in March 2013, the violence continued in December 2013. The country was thrown into a massive humanitarian crisis that is still very severe. There is an urgent need of humanitarian assistance and protection for the civil society in a conflict that is marked by a collapsed state, extended ethnic and religious violence, freedom of punishment and massive violations of human rights. The instability also undermines food security, and the UN warn against the possibility of a food crisis in the coming months as no one dares to sow their land while merchants and shepherds med animals have fled out of the country.
All 4.6 million people of the country are affected by the crisis and approximately 2.5 million have a need of humanitarian assistance. There are 698,000 internally displaced in the country and a little less than 290,000 refugees in the neighbouring countries. The crisis is estimated by the UN to be at the highest level (L3). Humanitarian access is for security reasons very difficult and it has been necessary to fly assistance - also food - into the country. The highest humanitarian priorities are lifesaving activities and stabilization of vulnerable groups resistance power. 
The UN&apos;s total appeal for CAR in 2014 is 551 million USD. Denmark contributed in 2013 with approximately 33 million kr. and in 2014 with 2.55 million kr. Denmark supported in December 2013 the humanitarian country fund (CHF) for CAR with 15 million kr. This grant has already allocated resources for the highest prioritised needs: Water, Health, protection and shelter. The majority of the activities are implemented by international NGOs (INGOs). A contribution to the CHF in 2014 will effectively be distributed to the actors who are able to implement humanitarian actions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014001045</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">46.C.41-3-154.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-228328</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="720" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-228328-28407" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
