<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://data.mcc.gov/" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:mcc="https://data.mcc.gov/ns#" xmlns:usg="http://foreignassistance.gov/iati#">
  <iati-identifier>US-18-NER-2750BXCOMD-IRRIG AGRI</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-18" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRRIGATED AGRICULTURE PROJECT (WATER TO MARKET)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger - IRRIGATED AGRICULTURE PROJECT (WATER TO MARKET): Through the compact&apos;s Irrigation and Market Access Project, MCC will partner with the Government of Niger to improve irrigation, including the rehabilitation and development of three large-scale irrigation systems, in order to increase crop yields, sustainable fishing and livestock productivity. The project will upgrade road networks to significantly improve access to markets and services, provide technical support for farmers, with a focus on women and youth, to improve performance of their businesses and establish market platforms to competitively position farmer groups in the marketplace. In addition, the project will reform policies and institutions, including the establishment of a national water resource management plan and natural resource and land use management plans, and create local capacities to increase understanding of best-practices to sustainably use and maintain irrigation, road and market infrastructure. The project will focus its interventions in the Dosso and Tahoua regions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-8" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Account - Niger</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States of America</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-26" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-26" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-29">26936993.99</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-29">46191329.5</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-29">29784210.33</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-29">21914322.81</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-01-25"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-29">17841061.77</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-05-25"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-29">26000306.69</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NER-2750BXCOMD" type="1"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NER-2750BXCOMD-AGRI" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NER-2750BXCOMD-IRRIG AGRI-0024" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NER-2750BXCOMD-IRRIG AGRI-0092" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NER-2750BXCOMD-IRRIG AGRI-0125" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NER-2750BXCOMD-IRRIG AGRI-0265" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NER-2750BXCOMD-MON &amp; EVAL" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NER-2750BXCOMD-NA" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NER-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN" type="3"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government will have delivered satisfactory evidence that it has prepared and adopted a road maintenance plan for the portion of the road network associated with the  Irrigation and Market Access Project, which plan will (i) address, at a minimum, the preventative, routine, and periodic maintenance of each of RN7 and RN35; and (ii) ensure the availability of funds for the continued maintenance post-Compact through the operation of any performance-based management and maintenance contracts to sustain the investments  from the Roads for Market Access Activity and the community-based maintenance system for the Sambera Rural Road</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government will have issued an appropriate legal instrument, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, (a) allowing for the creation of IWUAs; (b) permitting the IWUAs to manage, operate, and maintain, on a long-term basis, the perimeter systems in the Activity?s project areas; (c) affirming women?s eligibility to IWUA members and reserving a minimum percentage of seats on IWUA boards and committees for women; and (d) clarifying roles and responsibilities among such IWUAs, cooperatives, and ONAHA</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government will provide evidence it has issued a communication directed at the farmers and cooperatives confirming that the farmers and cooperatives have the right in the Project intervention areas to determine their own choice of crops, without Government mandate, consistent with water availability and the requirements for rational and equitable distribution of water within the perimeters</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government will provide evidence of its compliance with its international obligations implicated by the Activity (including, but not limited to, the Ramsar Convention).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government will provide evidence of its compliance with its international obligations implicated by this Sub-Activity (including, but not limited to, the Sokoto Agreement).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government will provide, for the applicable areas covered by the construction or works contract, evidence of integration of the land use plans into the applicable local commune-level development plans in a manner consistent with the requirements of the IFC Performance Standards, the stakeholder engagement strategy and Activity-specific stakeholder engagement plans</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government will, for the applicable area covered by such construction or works contract, (i) adopt and publish an arrete that is legally binding on the local authorities establishing local socially acceptable processes and criteria for land allocation, which Land Allocation Procedures will be consistent with the Land Allocation Core Principles agreed by MCC and the Government; and (ii) submit evidence satisfactory to MCC demonstrating that such arrete remains in full force and effect throughout the Compact Term.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
