<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://data.mcc.gov/" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:mcc="https://data.mcc.gov/ns#" xmlns:usg="http://foreignassistance.gov/iati#">
  <iati-identifier>US-18-NER-2750BXCOMD</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-18" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger-Compact</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCC&apos;s $437 million Niger Sustainable Water and Agriculture Compact will support improvements to three major constraints to economic growth and investment in Niger: lack of reliable access to water for agricultural use and livestock; lack of access to markets; and a fragmented and inefficient business regulatory system. In partnership with the Government of Niger, the MCC compact will strengthen Niger&apos;s agricultural sector by improving water availability, infrastructure, and market access, and has the potential to benefit more than 3.9 million people.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-8" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Account - Niger</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States of America</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-26" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-26" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administration &amp; Finance</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Open Data Team</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>202-521-3618</telephone>
   <email>opendata@mcc.gov</email>
   <website>data.mcc.gov</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1099 14th Street NW, Suite 700, Washington, DC 20005-3550</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-24">22068158</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-24">44943620</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-24">40000531</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-24">48592716</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-24">99464463</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-24">6209008</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/me-plan-niger-compact">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger Compact Monitoring and Evaluation Plan</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A03"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/report-niger-ca">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger Compact Constraints Analysis</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/agreement-compact-between-mcc-and-niger">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Compact between MCC and Niger</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <category code="A11"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.mcc.gov/where-we-work/program/niger-compact">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger Compact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A06"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/niger-kpi">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger Compact Key Performance Indicators</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NE" type="1"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NER-2750BX69GD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NER-2750BXCOMD-AGRI" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NER-2750BXCOMD-IRRIG AGRI" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NER-2750BXCOMD-MON &amp; EVAL" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NER-2750BXCOMD-NA" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NER-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-NER-2750BXDILD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">All Government entities involved in the implementation of the Program, including the Implementing Entities, are coordinating successfully with MCA-Niger, and dedicating the necessary staff and other resources to ensure successful implementation of the Program</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">All applicable conditions precedent in Annex II have been duly satisfied, deferred, or waived as provided in this Agreement</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Any Taxes paid with MCC Funding through the date ninety (90) days prior to the start of the applicable Disbursement Period have been reimbursed by the Government in full in accordance with Section 2.8(c) of the Compact</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Copies of reports from any technical auditors engaged by MCA-Niger</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Each of the Key Staff remains engaged, or if a position is vacant, MCA-Niger is actively engaged, to MCC&apos;s satisfaction, in recruiting a replacement</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCA-Niger has complied in all material respects with its obligations set forth in Section 2.1(d) with respect to establishment of a BCS and its obligations set forth in Section 2.3 with respect to the establishment of an M&amp;E Plan</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCA-Niger has delivered to MCC the following documents, reports, and information in form and substance satisfactory to MCC:  A completed Disbursement Request</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCA-Niger has delivered to MCC the following documents, reports, and information in form and substance satisfactory to MCC:  A completed Disbursement Request, including:  Detailed Financial Plan</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCA-Niger has delivered to MCC the following documents, reports, and information in form and substance satisfactory to MCC:  A completed Disbursement Request, including:  Fiscal Agent Certificate</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCA-Niger has delivered to MCC the following documents, reports, and information in form and substance satisfactory to MCC:  A completed Disbursement Request, including:  MCA-Niger Certificate</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCA-Niger has delivered to MCC the following documents, reports, and information in form and substance satisfactory to MCC:  A completed Disbursement Request, including:  Narrative Report</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCA-Niger has delivered to MCC the following documents, reports, and information in form and substance satisfactory to MCC:  A completed Disbursement Request, including:  Procurement Agent Certificate</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCA-Niger has delivered to MCC the following documents, reports, and information in form and substance satisfactory to MCC:  A completed Disbursement Request, including:  Quarterly Financial Report</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCA-Niger has delivered to MCC the following documents, reports, and information in form and substance satisfactory to MCC:  A completed Disbursement Request, including: Conditions Precedent Report</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCA-Niger has delivered to MCC the following documents, reports, and information in form and substance satisfactory to MCC:  A completed Disbursement Request, including: Indicator Tracking Table</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCA-Niger has delivered to MCC the following documents, reports, and information in form and substance satisfactory to MCC:  A completed Disbursement Request, including: Procurement Performance Report</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCA-Niger has developed a complete Implementation Plan.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCA-Niger must have submitted to MCC evidence that MCA-Niger or the appropriate Government entity has developed and adopted an environmental and social impact assessment, an environmental and social management plan, health and safety management plan, a resettlement action plan, or livelihood restoration plan,, and a TIP risk assessment with respect to such Activity</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCA-Niger will have developed and adapted an environmental and social management system (&quot;ESMS&quot;) (including a stakeholder engagement plan) in accordance with the MCC Environmental Guidelines as evidenced by (a) a resolution of the MCA Board; and (b) staffing plan, training plan, and budget for the ESMS</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCA-Niger will have developed and approved a comprehensive Social and Gender Integration Plan</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCC does not have grounds for concluding that any matter certified to it in the related MCA Disbursement Certificate, Procurement Agent Disbursement Certificate, or Fiscal Agent Certificate is not as certified</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">No act, omission, condition, or event has occurred that would be the basis for MCC to suspend or terminate, in whole or in part, the Compact or MCC Funding in accordance with Section 5.1 of the Compact</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">No material default or breach of any covenant, obligation or responsibility by the Government, MCA-Niger or any Government entity has occurred and is continuing under the Compact, this Agreement, or any Supplemental Agreement, or under any systems, rules, policies, plans, or guidance issued by MCA-Niger.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government has obtained MCC?s written consent to any modification or any systems, rules, policies, plans, or guidance issued by the Government or MCA-Niger, as the case may be, in fulfillment of any obligation set forth in the Compact or this Program Implementation Agreement?</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government has satisfied all of its payment obligations, including any insurance, indemnification, tax payments or other obligations, and contributed all resources required from it, under the Compact, this Agreement, and any Supplemental Agreement</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government must have submitted to MCC an initial draft Compact Closure Plan in accordance with the MCC Program Closure Guidelines</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government, or MCA-Niger as applicable, has made sufficient progress in implementing any systems, rules, plans, policies, or guidance issued by the Government or MCA-Niger, as the case may be, in fulfillment of any obligation set forth in the Compact, or this Program Implementation Agreement</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Implementation Plan Documents and the Fiscal Accountability Plan are current and updated and are in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, and there has been progress satisfactory to MCC on the components of the Implementation Plan for any relevant Projects or Activities related to such Disbursement</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activities to be funded with such Disbursement will not violate any applicable law or regulation</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">There has been no material negative finding in any financial audit report delivered in accordance with the Compact and the Audit Plan, for the prior two quarters, (or such other period as the Audit Plan may require)</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">There has been progress satisfactory to MCC on the M&amp;E Plan, ESMS, and Social and Gender Integration Plan for the Program, relevant Project or Activity, and substantial compliance with the requirements of the M&amp;E Plan, ESMS, and Social and Gender Integration Plan (including targets set forth therein?)</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger-2750BXCOMD Results</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private veterinaries selected (Male)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Process of Number of private veterinaries selected to provide veterinary services to the PRAPs communes. Veterinaries will support the vaccination campaign and offer proximity services to the local communes</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of private veterinaries selected to provide veterinary services to the PRAPs communes. Veterinaries will support the vaccination campaign and offer proximity services to the local communes Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of private veterinaries selected to provide veterinary services to the PRAPs communes. Veterinaries will support the vaccination campaign and offer proximity services to the local communes Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of private veterinaries selected to provide veterinary services to the PRAPs communes. Veterinaries will support the vaccination campaign and offer proximity services to the local communes Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private veterinaries selected</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Process of Number of private veterinaries selected to provide veterinary services to the PRAPs communes. Veterinaries will support the vaccination campaign and offer proximity services to the local communes</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of private veterinaries selected to provide veterinary services to the PRAPs communes. Veterinaries will support the vaccination campaign and offer proximity services to the local communes Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of private veterinaries selected to provide veterinary services to the PRAPs communes. Veterinaries will support the vaccination campaign and offer proximity services to the local communes Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of private veterinaries selected to provide veterinary services to the PRAPs communes. Veterinaries will support the vaccination campaign and offer proximity services to the local communes Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private veterinaries selected (Female)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Process of Number of private veterinaries selected to provide veterinary services to the PRAPs communes. Veterinaries will support the vaccination campaign and offer proximity services to the local communes</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of private veterinaries selected to provide veterinary services to the PRAPs communes. Veterinaries will support the vaccination campaign and offer proximity services to the local communes Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of private veterinaries selected to provide veterinary services to the PRAPs communes. Veterinaries will support the vaccination campaign and offer proximity services to the local communes Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of private veterinaries selected to provide veterinary services to the PRAPs communes. Veterinaries will support the vaccination campaign and offer proximity services to the local communes Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Veterinaries that complete training or re-training (Female)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of Number of veterinaries that complete training or re-training</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of veterinaries that complete training or re-training Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of veterinaries that complete training or re-training Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of veterinaries that complete training or re-training Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Veterinaries that complete training or re-training (Male)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of Number of veterinaries that complete training or re-training</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of veterinaries that complete training or re-training Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of veterinaries that complete training or re-training Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of veterinaries that complete training or re-training Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Veterinaries that complete training or re-training</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of Number of veterinaries that complete training or re-training</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of veterinaries that complete training or re-training Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of veterinaries that complete training or re-training Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of veterinaries that complete training or re-training Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Temporary employment generated in irrigation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Process of The number of people temporarily employed or contracted by MCA-contracted construction companies to work on construction of irrigation systems.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people temporarily employed or contracted by MCA-contracted construction companies to work on construction of irrigation systems. Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people temporarily employed or contracted by MCA-contracted construction companies to work on construction of irrigation systems. Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="252">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people temporarily employed or contracted by MCA-contracted construction companies to work on construction of irrigation systems. Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Temporary employment generated in irrigation (Male)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Process of The number of people temporarily employed or contracted by MCA-contracted construction companies to work on construction of irrigation systems.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people temporarily employed or contracted by MCA-contracted construction companies to work on construction of irrigation systems. Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people temporarily employed or contracted by MCA-contracted construction companies to work on construction of irrigation systems. Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="227">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people temporarily employed or contracted by MCA-contracted construction companies to work on construction of irrigation systems. Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Temporary employment generated in irrigation (Female)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Process of The number of people temporarily employed or contracted by MCA-contracted construction companies to work on construction of irrigation systems.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people temporarily employed or contracted by MCA-contracted construction companies to work on construction of irrigation systems. Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people temporarily employed or contracted by MCA-contracted construction companies to work on construction of irrigation systems. Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="25">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people temporarily employed or contracted by MCA-contracted construction companies to work on construction of irrigation systems. Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CRA Facility grants completed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of Total number of completed projects funded by CRA Grants Facility (i.e. grants have completed all activities described in grant agreement and closed out)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of completed projects funded by CRA Grants Facility (i.e. grants have completed all activities described in grant agreement and closed out) Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="65">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of completed projects funded by CRA Grants Facility (i.e. grants have completed all activities described in grant agreement and closed out) Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of completed projects funded by CRA Grants Facility (i.e. grants have completed all activities described in grant agreement and closed out) Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of grant agreements signed (Cooperatives and processor groups)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of Total number of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="19">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of grant agreements signed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of Total number of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="65">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="39">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of grant agreements signed (MSME cooperatives)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of Total number of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of grant agreements signed (Unspecified)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of Total number of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="NULL" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Value of grant agreements signed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of Total value of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total value of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="7500000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total value of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3735892">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total value of grant facility projects funded via grant agreements with BDS support Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amount leveraged (co-financing)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Outcome of Total value of grantee cash and/or in-kind contributions, grants, and/or loans received and counted as co-financing contribution by participating grantee types</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total value of grantee cash and/or in-kind contributions, grants, and/or loans received and counted as co-financing contribution by participating grantee types Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="750000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total value of grantee cash and/or in-kind contributions, grants, and/or loans received and counted as co-financing contribution by participating grantee types Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total value of grantee cash and/or in-kind contributions, grants, and/or loans received and counted as co-financing contribution by participating grantee types Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amount leveraged (co-financing (Cooperatives and processor groups)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Outcome of Total value of grantee cash and/or in-kind contributions, grants, and/or loans received and counted as co-financing contribution by participating grantee types</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total value of grantee cash and/or in-kind contributions, grants, and/or loans received and counted as co-financing contribution by participating grantee types Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total value of grantee cash and/or in-kind contributions, grants, and/or loans received and counted as co-financing contribution by participating grantee types Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total value of grantee cash and/or in-kind contributions, grants, and/or loans received and counted as co-financing contribution by participating grantee types Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amount leveraged (co-financing (MSME cooperatives)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Outcome of Total value of grantee cash and/or in-kind contributions, grants, and/or loans received and counted as co-financing contribution by participating grantee types</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total value of grantee cash and/or in-kind contributions, grants, and/or loans received and counted as co-financing contribution by participating grantee types Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-01-26"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total value of grantee cash and/or in-kind contributions, grants, and/or loans received and counted as co-financing contribution by participating grantee types Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total value of grantee cash and/or in-kind contributions, grants, and/or loans received and counted as co-financing contribution by participating grantee types Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
