<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-6-UKRS</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-6" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Home Office</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Resettlement Scheme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Vulnerable Persons Resettlement Scheme (VPRS) and Vulnerable Children&#x2019;s Resettlement Scheme (VCRS) concluded in February 2021, having seen over 22,000 refugees resettled across both schemes. Following this, the UK Resettlement Scheme (UKRS) launched reaffirming the UK&#x2019;s ongoing commitment to refugee resettlement, which continues to be an important component of the UK&#x2019;s humanitarian response. The UKRS is a multi-year commitment which sees the UK continue to offer a safe and legal route to vulnerable refugees in need of protection. It is accessible to refugees who have been assessed for resettlement by UNHCR against their resettlement submission categories, providing them a safe environment and the chance to rebuild their lives. The Home Office provides tariff funding for local authorities for the first 12 months for each resettled refugee support, including education and health funding, using ODA funds.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-6" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Home Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-6" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Home Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Home Office</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Home Office is the lead government department for immigration and passports, drugs policy, crime, fire, counter-terrorism and police.</narrative>
   </department>
   <telephone>020 7035 4848</telephone>
   <email>odatransparency@homeoffice.gov.uk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct Communications Unit, 2 Marsham Street, London, SW1P 4DF, United Kingdom</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="93010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
