<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-802353-Bethel Children&apos;s Home Association</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-802353" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopiaid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bethel Children&apos;s Home Association</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bethel Children&#x2019;s Home Association is a non-political, non- profit making and indigenous humanitarian organization; striving towards to ensure the welfare of orphan, abandoned children and destitute women. &#x97; This orphanage have been established in June 2008 and legally licensed. The organization began to operate in Oromia region, East shoa zone &amp; Adama City. Vision &#x97;&#xB7; To see children productive and responsible citizens after they have given the basic needs in their upbringing, they can be supportive and contribute their share in the society. &#x97;&#x97;&#x97;Goal The goal of this organization is that the lives of orphan and vulnerable children is saved through provision of safe home, nutrition, health and schooling services in order Mission Bethel Children&#x2019;s Home Association is dedicated to initiating, coordinating and facilitating and promoting community-based responses designed to alleviate socio-economic problems of helpless orphans of HIV/AIDS, abandoned &amp; other vulnerable children. Link for domestic adoptive parents (families) who would be willing to accept it as their adopted children by providing them parents care etc. Objectives To provide for most pressing economic, social and psychological needs of orphan and abandoned children in the group home care. To provide OVC&#x2019;s school material and uniform and get education opportunity. To provide access for children in the family like care to get quality education and health services. To promote gudifecha culture within the society and enhancing their understanding. To facilitate ways by which children in the orphanage can rejoin a family life and get dependable parental care through inland/domestic adoption. &#x97;To reunify orphan children to their extended family after completing the entire necessary prior reunification task. &#x97;To provide school material and uniform for children who are forced to quit their education because of serious problem and get education opportunity &#x97;To organize needy women in self -help groups and assist them in starting small- scale business activities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bethel Children&apos;s Home Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="16015" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="50"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="A01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="3"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction ref="Bethel Children&apos;s Home Association-Small Grants Programme">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">15000</value>
   <provider-org ref="Ethiopiaid"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="Bethel Children&apos;s Home Association"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
