<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-IRS-562339052-CorporateEngagementProgram</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-IRS-562339052" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CDA Collaborative Learning Projects, Inc.</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Corporate Engagement Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Corporate Engagement Program (CEP) promotes the development of positive, constructive relationships between companies and the local communities where corporate operations take place. The book Getting it Right: Making Corporate-Community Relations Work (published April 2009) encapsulates lessons learned during the first nine years of the program and draws on the experience of companies and local stakeholders in over 40 operating sites of international companies working under difficult circumstances. It presents a framework for company managers to analyze the consequences of their decisions for communities and practical management options for improving corporate impacts.  The evidence gathering that led to Getting it Right is the foundation of CEP&#x2019;s ongoing work to help companies sustain and improve social performance.

CEP engages individual corporations as partners, advising them about social responsibility strategy and incorporating conflict sensitivity and human rights considerations into their community relations approaches.  In this respect, we work with - rather than for - companies in the spirit of collaborative learning.  

CEP participates in global initiatives to establish and implement standards for responsible business and develops tools and guidance to help companies improve their relationships with their external stakeholders.  To broaden the impact of our knowledge, we also engage with a broad range of other actors, including civil society organizati0ns, multi-lateral institutions, and industry associations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CDA Collaborative Learning Projects</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dost Bardouille-Crema</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>1-617-661-6310</telephone>
   <email>dbardouille@cdacollaborative.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Alewife Center
Cambridge, MA 02140 USA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="32110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This program addresses the impacts of corporate operations on communities and conflicts.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2011-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-06-01">255600</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
