<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-IRS-562339052-DoNoHarmProgram</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-IRS-562339052" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CDA Collaborative Learning Projects, Inc.</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Do No Harm Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid agencies work in complex and uncertain environments. The Do No Harm Program (DNH) provides well-tested and rigorous analysis frameworks for reducing complexity and managing uncertainty.  The aim of DNH is to help assistance workers understand and deal with the complexities of providing assistance with better outcomes for the societies where assistance is provided.

Why &#x201C;Conflict Sensitivity&#x201D; and Do No Harm? First, it is our responsibility. If our aim is to help people, then we must avoid causing harm to them. Second, it leads to more effective programming. Having a better understanding of and relationship with a community makes everything better and easier, from planning and design through implementation, monitoring, and evaluation. Third, it is cheaper. It is far less costly to prevent or avoid conflict than to deal with its impacts later. Conflict destroys what we have built physically and socially and sets back the communities and our efforts.

Do No Harm Analysis.  Do No Harm&#x2019;s analytical frameworks perform two complementary functions: highlighting the information necessary to work in uncertain environments while also, and importantly, filtering out the unnecessary. Used by thousands of people around the world, DNH provides valuable insights that lead to developing better options and improved decision making.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CDA Collaborative Learning Projects</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marshall Wallace, Program Director</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>1-617-661-6310</telephone>
   <email>mwallace@cdacollaborative.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Alewife Center
Cambridge, MA 02140 USA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The program addresses the conflict sensitivity of all sectors of assistance to fragile states and conflict affected areas.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2011-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-06-01">428722</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
