<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12812A0101-AFR-15153</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FOJO 2018 Pre-study Media development</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">FOJO2018  F&#xF6;rstudie medieutveckling</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Kartl&#xE4;ggning/f&#xF6;rstudie inf&#xF6;r regionalt medieprogram inklusive analys av akt&#xF6;rer.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mapping of entry points for support to the media sector at regional level and mapping of actors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medieinstitutet Fojo/Linn&#xE9;universitetet</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medieinstitutet Fojo/Linn&#xE9;universitetet</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media and free flow of information</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">92014.7519101537</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">92014.7519101537</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-15">92014.75191</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-28">92014.7519101537</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fojo Media Institute was granted funding for a pre-study (agreement signed 2018-11-28), with the purpose of producing input to development of support to the media sector at a regional level in Africa. &quot;The report from the study is expected to present possible entry points, based on needs and on what other actors are doing in this area. Furthermore, the study will include identification of possible cooperation partners.&quot; The study also&#xA0;aimed at providing information and input regarding the elaboration of a specific comprehensive multi-partner program&#xA0;addressing shrinking civil space, coordinated by Civicus.
The report&#xA0;&quot;Challenges and entry points for regional media development support in Sub-Saharan Africa&quot;&#xA0;also includes a mapping of possible cooperation partners. The report is assessed as of good quality and in line with the ToR.&#xA0;
In addition to the final report of the study, Fojo has submitted a &quot;Final Narrative Report&quot; reflecting the process and lesson learnt.
A financial report and audit reporting is submitted (see memo on reporting).
Reporting conditions are fulfilled and the report is approved.
Process and methodology
During the pre-study, Fojo organised three roundtable meetings (in February 2019) with media experts and media&#xA0;representatives from each&#xA0;sub-region under study. Three international experts with different backgrounds and areas of expertise were&#xA0; engaged, with the aim to extract their joint competence.
The study&#xA0;is based on consultations with people from a wide variety of backgrounds.&#xA0;Gender balance was considered&#xA0;and gender equality covered in the roundtables.&#xA0;Perspectives from different stakeholders and places across sub-Saharan Africa have been considered. Also, a number of individual interviews have been held as well as reviews of relevant studies and literature.
Findings
Foja has investigated&#xA0;regional media initiatives and processes that can contribute to democracy and accountability.&#xA0;The study lists seven recommendations on entry points for donors:
1. Step up regional media support.
2. Focus on integrated, comprehensive regional approaches.
3. Stimulate regional coalition building.
4. Support regional innovative initiatives demanding accountability.
5. Prioritise regional support that promotes financial sustainability for the media.
6.&#xA0;Strengthen regional support for institution building, supporting self-regulation and ethics.
7. Fund regional processes that are anchored in national and local initiatives aiming at building trust and giving voice to the excluded.
Explanation of the seven points
1. Media can be seen as a pillar of governance and democracy. Global spending on media development is only 0,3% of total official development assistance. Therefore, support for media&#xA0;development is needed.
2. Most media development is focused on national processes - comprehensive regional approaches are needed. Focus areas that were investigated in the study are intertwined.
3. In order to ensure that African media organisations become viable players in the changing political, technical and economic landscape - regional coalitions are needed. Journalists and publishers cannot save journalism alone. Multi-stakeholder coalitions as well as regional and international networks are essential for the challenges within media. Coalitions can e.g. establish collaborative decentralised media newsrooms and platforms, which can provide opportunities to work more strategic and coordinated. Regional networks can also drive national
4. There&#xA0;is a&#xA0;need to support regional innovative initiatives demanding accountability as there&#xA0;are weaknesses in the areas of digital access, infrastructure, and ICT policy. Media should move beyond questions of freedom and independence in the political sphere, to find new and innovative strategies for enhancing the media&apos;s capabilities and invigorating citizen participation in the evolving digital landscape.
5. Financial sustainability has been low on the media development agenda. There is a vicious circle where, e.g. in South Africa 50% of the journalists have lost their job since 2000. The report suggests four ways for media development organisations and donors to deal with media financial sustainability in sub-Saharan Africa. There are 1) support revenue generating innovations 2) identify partners that can build private-public alliances and create awareness of the importance of media 3) to encourage strong media management skills, and 4) to find innovative ways of financially supporting media.
6. Professionalism, ethics and self-regulation are tied to each other. By&#xA0;addressing them jointly on a regional basis, citizen&apos;s trust in media can be improved and, as a consequence, financial revenues will follow. There is a need to build strong institutions and functional professional media associations.
7. There is an issue of lack of trust among citizens, both for media and civil society. Many people see them as representatives of power which creates lack of trust. There is a great need to keep these questions at the heart of development of social media and online media, as media/civil society coalitions are useful for the promotion of democracy, accountability and the defence of human rights.
Identification of possible cooperation partners
Fojo achieved to identify several possible cooperation partners across sub-Saharan Africa. They are presented in section 1.3.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12812" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061603" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="4725000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional Africa 2016-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt Afrika 2016-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
