<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5103006902-AFR-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFROBAROMETER 2018-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">AFROBAROMETER, 2018-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">AfroBarometern (AB) &#xE4;r ett n&#xE4;tverk som g&#xF6;r unders&#xF6;kningar av allm&#xE4;nhetens uppfattning av l&#xE4;get f&#xF6;r demokrati och samh&#xE4;llsstyrning i Afrika. AB arbetar nu i 35 l&#xE4;nder och planerar v&#xE4;xa till 40. M&#xE5;let &#xE4;r att synligg&#xF6;ra den allm&#xE4;nna opinonen, bidra till offentlig debatt om angel&#xE4;gna utvecklingsfr&#xE5;gor samt bygga institutionell kapacitet f&#xF6;r vetenskaplig forskning.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Afrobarometer (AB) is a network conducting surveys on popular perceptions concerning democracy and governance in Africa. AB currently works in  35 African countries and intends to cover some 40. The objectives are to voice and visualize the public opinion in the debate on important development issues and to build institutional capacity for scientific reasearch.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Afrobarometer&apos;s&#xA0;mission is that &quot;African Citizen&apos;s opinions about democracy and development are heard and made part of the public policy debate&quot;. To achieve that&#xA0;the Afrobarometer&apos;s&#xA0;long term goal&#xA0;is to produce data on public attitudes that can:
1. help citizens and civil society hold governments accountable;
2. increase government responsiveness to public opinion;
3.&#xA0; and provide insights to policy makers, democracy advocates, donors and others about the state of democracy and governance and its key drivers in order to inform the design and implementation of policy interventions.
Specific goals for&#xA0;2018-2022, broken down into the&#xA0;core sectors of&#xA0;surveys, communication/dissemination, capacity building/analysis and organizational development, are:
Within&#xA0;the surveys program to continue&#xA0;building&#xA0;the Afrobarometer database on African public opinion on democracy, governance, and economic development.
- Completing Round 7 surveys in 14 additional countries during 2018 for a total of 35 countries
- Delivering data sets for two additional rounds of national surveys (R8 and R9), each in
approximately 35 countries
- Restoring approximately one-quarter of countries to n=2400 sample size to facilitate subnational disaggregation, a key tool for engaging new and especially country level users
- Conducting additional pre- and/or post-election surveys and post-conflict surveys in selected countries (resources permitting)
- Further enhance the quality of Afrobarometer data by training partners and fully implementing EDC capabilities for real-time monitoring of fieldwork
- Conduct an internal assessment of AB sampling skills, protocols, processes and partnerships to produce recommendations for enhancements in R8, as well as guidance regarding the potential for increasing collaboration with national statistical offices
The communications program will focus on expanding the reach and impact of Afrobarometer data and products within the African policy ecosystem by:
- Develop reciprocal relationships for data use with at least two major governmental, intergovernmental or non-governmental users at the national, sub-regional or continental levels each year
- Conduct pilot stakeholder mapping exercises in at least four to six countries and work with national partners to develop more context-specific, demand-driven approaches to AB communications
- Activate an issues and events radar and respond to a growing number of identified topics in each successive year
- Increase network skills and output in data visualization, mapping tools and related methods to increase visibility
- Develop methods to improve tracking of use of AB data, especially within African governments and regional organizations
The capacity-building program will focus on building skills for production, analysis and communications of public opinion data to new users both within the network, and among a growing network of external partners by:
- Restoring at least one Afrobarometer Summer School per year
- Restoring at least one Afrobarometer training workshop per year
- Holding a Round 7 Debrief/Round 8 planning meeting, and doing the same between R8 and R9
- Building ongoing mentoring relationships with at least five participants in each workshop to ensure that the skills used are consolidated, put into practice, and produce results
- Where possible, opening up to one-third of training opportunities for participants from outside the network (students, media, state officials, civil society staff, staff of regional and sub-regional bodies, etc.)
- If resources permit, conducting a capacity needs assessment that identifies targeted and specific needs of national partners, core partners, and AB staff for skill and capacity development

The key goals and deliverables for Afrobarometer&apos;s organizational development process during 2018-2019 include:
- Formalizing current financial and administrative management practices through further development of financial management and human resources handbooks for the network and providing appropriate training for network partners, as well as development of bylaws the govern institutional decision making processes;
- Updating Afrobarometer&#x2019;s strategy and theory of change to establish a suitable framework for AB&#x2019;s work over the next five ears
- Securing appropriate OD expert services, reviewing OD recommendations, agreeing on a plan for implementation of recommended changes, and implementing the adopted plan
- Engaging legal expertise to undertake formal registration of Afrobarometer as a non-profit organization with a clear institutional address and home
- Securing fundraising expertise to assist in the development of a fundraising strategy and securing the support of a skilled development officer to assist the network in implementing it
- Re-establishing an international advisory board with clear role and mandate to support the network on both technical and fundraising issues; convene an annual meeting of the advisory board.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afrobarometer</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afrobarometer</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="10.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10.2 - By 2030, empower and promote the social, economic and political inclusion of all, irrespective of age, sex, disability, race, ethnicity, origin, religion or economic or other status.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">10.2 - Till 2030 m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra och verka f&#xF6;r att alla m&#xE4;nniskors, oavsett &#xE5;lder, k&#xF6;n, funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning, ras, etnicitet, ursprung, religion eller ekonomisk eller annan st&#xE4;llning, blir inkluderade i det sociala, ekonomiska och politiska livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">2388785.736777528</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">466368.967808882</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">2388785.7367775277</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">466368.9678088819</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-20">2823110.416191</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-28">760068.188974668</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-28">1085811.69853524</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-28">542905.84926762</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-28">466368.967808882</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/51030069-amendment-1-to-cdd-ghana.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment 1to the Agreement to CDD Ghana</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/amendment-no.-1-cdd-ghana-51030069.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment No. 1 CDD-Ghana</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/amendment-no-1-to-the-agreement-on-afrobarometer-between-sida.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment no 1 to the Agreement on Afrobarometer between Sida</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/sida-grant-agreement_cdd-07nov18_signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/51030069_BeslutAfrobarometer.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut Afrobarometer</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/beslut-om-andring-av-insats-afrobarometer-2018-2022-51030069.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beslut om andring av insats Afrobarometer 2018-2022 51030069</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/51030069_Beslutomandringavinsats.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om andring av insats</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/51030069_Beslutominsats.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/signed-decision-amendment-of-contr.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om &#xE4;ndring av insats</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The year of 2020 corresponded to the second year of implementation of the Survey Round 8. Due to the COVID-19-related restrictions surveys were put on hold during parts of the year. Until suspension, 18 of 35 surveys were completed, and five surveys were completed upon resumption of field work. The remaining surveys are expected to be finalized by 30 of June 2021.&#xA0; In addition a pre-election survey was undertaken in Uganda, as well as the first-ever telephone pilot survey in Namibia.
22 sets of country data were released and a 18-country merged data set. Dissemination of results were also taking place in the survey countries through different channels and formats.&#xA0;
An engagement (fundraising and communication) unit has been set up with a strategic plan for 2020-2024, generating increase of incomes already for 2020.
An International Advisory Council has been established. The Embassy was invited to suggest a Swedish member. Margot Wallstr&#xF6;m accepted to join the IAC.
Based on the survey data, 71 press releases, 83 dispatches, nine policy papers, three working papers, and 13 summaries of results were published.&#xA0;
In terms of strengthening outreach and networking, Afrobarometer has signed a MoU with APRM, the Center for Evaluation and Development (C4ED) and UN Office on Drugs and Crime Global Judicial Integrity Network.&#xA0;
The Analysis Unit works on mentoring as a way of increasing capacities for analysis, and new opportunities to publish - including Washington Post Monkey Cage blog.&#xA0;
The recently released SDG score card project was prepared during 2020 and a COVID-19 series was published as part of a wider range of thematic packaging of analytical pieces.&#xA0;
While in-person capacity-building activities had to be cancelled, activities such as preparing a Youth Bootcamp to train youth leaders on survey data as a basis for decision-making in their countries, and an analytic seminar on &quot;News media, social media and fake news&quot; for researchers.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51030069" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061603" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="4725000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional Africa 2016-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt Afrika 2016-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
