<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5103001203-AFR-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SfCG,Search for Common Ground</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">SfCG,Search for Common Ground</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Freds - och s&#xE4;kerhetsinsats i konflikt och postkonfliktomr&#xE5;den i      Afrika. Regional infallsvinkel till situationen i Stora Sj&#xF6; och       V&#xE4;stafrikaomr&#xE5;dena. Arbetar i &#xE5;tta l&#xE4;nder  i de tv&#xE5; regionerna.       Syfte: F&#xF6;rdjupa analys och strategisk utveckling hos utvalda          samarbetspartners kring fred och s&#xE4;kerhet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening peace and security in conflict- and post-conflict       countries in Africa; regional approaches to the Great Lakes and West  Africa. Work implemented in eight countries in the two regions.       Specific obj. deepen analysis and strategic developmend of selected   actors on peace and security issues. Mentor selected org. and thirdly to strengthen capacity to measure results.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Search for Common Ground</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">19364.567996618</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">40942.6642781726</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">19364.567996618</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">40942.6642781726</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-11-01">66362.639193</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-11-28">19364.5432149157</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">40942.6547874675</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2014Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: With this programme funding, SfCG has been able to provide guidance and capacity building to the eight country programmes, enabling them to enagage in strategic reflection exercises, learning and exchanges, and cross-fertilization missions. It has supported the country programmes and local partners to develop conflict sensitive programme strategies. Though Sida granted no-cost extension of the programme until 31 July 2015, SfCG did not implement activities after 31 December 2014 and all transfers from Sida made in 2015 actually correspond to 2014 activities or closeout costs that were invoiced late. So there were no activities implemented in 2015, and as a result, the 2014 narrative report is the final project report and this result register caputures results acheived until 2014.  

With a view to deepening the analysis and strategic development of selected actors on peace and security, it has engaged various stakeholders including state structures, CSOs, ex-combatants, armed forces, women and youth associations, and media institutions, which facilitated the integration of an ever-increasing diversity of voices in the local conflict transformation processes in the target countries.  With this support, local partner organizations are increasingly integrating conflict analysis and critical strategic development of programmes/projects in their area of work with better context analysis and data-driven approaches to the design, monitoring and evaluation of projects. They have been capacitated through various trainings, strategic meetings, and partnership building and networking. 

The intevention has also supported local partner organizations through collaborative development of tools and approaches to analyse and respond to conflict and manage programmes more effectively. A large variety of new tools have been generated and field tested from the experience of the country programmes and local partners with consultations of large group of stakeholders. Moreover, various activities have been implemented to build the capacity of the local parnters to effectively utilize the tools. The tools assist partners for strategic reflection and programme design on peacebuilding and also provide concrete guidance on navigating specific challenges, such as elections. Since SfCG is an open source organization, the tools were reproduced and shared with the largest set of beneficiaries. 

Besides, a series of capacity building initiatives in design, monitoring and evaluation have been conducted in order to strengthen the capacity of targeted partners to measure and reflect on the effectiveness of the results of their activities. 

With the objective of reinforcing SFCG and partners&#x2019; capacity to engage more strategically on emerging peace and conflict issues on the African continent, SFCG has been able to reflect on and assess emerging conflict dynamics, mobilize resources and staff to respond, and set up sustainable and relevant programming. Key achievements include the establishment of country programs in Central African Republic and South Sudan in response to the spiraling violence in those countries by working on grassroot reconciliation and violence prevention initiatives and building trust among communities; rapid mobilization to respond to the Ebola outbreak through media sensitization; the development of elections programming in anticipation of a series of electoral exercises in conflict-sensitive countries in 2015; and impelmentation of activities responding to increased activity by Boko Haram in northern Nigeria; and the continued implementation of cross-border programming.

Furthermore, the Sida support had also contributed to the core funding of SfCG activities in sub-saharan Africa. The intervention have strengthened the foundation of SfCG&apos;s work in west Africa and the Great Lakes region, ensuring that the efforts to strengthen peace and security were rooted in strong conflcit and context analysis. SFCG has expanded its programming in Sub-Saharan Africa significantly. This has included the development of new country programs, new project start-up, strategy development, partner development and targeted responses to crisis situations. To manage these new initiatives, SFCG has expanded its Africa support team to meet the needs of its diverse programs. SFCG has committed to strengthening its institutional support and management systems to build the capacityof both its staff and its partners. This has the long-term goal of strengthening organizational capacity in the field of conflict transformation and peacebuilding.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51030012" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
