<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5100009502-AFR-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACCORD, 2012-2017</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">ACCORD, 2012-2017</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACCORD is an independent conflict management NGO based in Durban,     South Africa, working i.a. on mediation on conflicts, technical       advice in certain countries, training and policy formulation. Sida is providing core support to the organisation. A partnership with the    Department for Conflict Resolution at Uppsala University is also      financed by Sida.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">ACCORD &#xE4;r en oberoende organisation som arbetar med                   konflikthantering, baserad i Durban, Sydafrika. De arbetar bl.a. med  medling i konflikter, tekniskt st&#xF6;d i vissa l&#xE4;nder, utbildning och    policyformulering. Sida tillhandah&#xE5;ller generellt organisationsst&#xF6;d   till ACCORD. Ett partnerskap med Avdelningen f&#xF6;r Konfliktl&#xF6;sning vid  Uppsala universitet st&#xF6;ds ocks&#xE5; av Sida.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of ACCORD is &#x201C;to promote and encourage the constructive resolution of disputes by the peoples of Africa and so assist in building political stability, economic recovery and peaceful co-existence within just and democratic societies.&#x201D;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACCORD/The African Centre for the Constructive Resolution of Disputes</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dev. country based NGOs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">15353.436098999</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">15353.436098999</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">14773.449157</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-06-28">15268.6851317325</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Throughout 2017 ACCORD has engaged in activities with the AU, UN, and RECs to support the work undertaken by these bodies to enhance their skills in mediation, negotiation and conflict prevention, and to strengthen their response to conflict prevention and early response.&#xA0;
In reinforcing the institutional capacity of AU and RECs, ACCORD has finalised rosters and trained pools of experts for deployment. They supported the AU border programme confidence building work by producing an action plan between Madagascar and Comoros. ACCORD has also documented the experiences of a number of African-led stabilisation missions leading to adoption of best practices. In supporting the 5th Panwise retreat ACCORD&#xA0; contributed to better understanding and division of labour between various actors involved in mediation at different levels (continental, regional, national, local). Technical support and advice was also directly provided to ECOWAS (lessons for mediation in 2016 Gambia), SADC (e.g. training resulting in enhanced capacity of mission management, leadership, dialogue and protection of civilians), IGAD (e.g. validated mediation guidelines), ECCAS (e.g. support to ongoing mediation efforts in CAR).&#xA0;
In terms of local and national capacities for peace, ACCORD has supported government and institutions in Liberia, South Sudan, CAR and South Africa with e.g. conflict mappings, trainings, and technical assistance.&#xA0;
In enhancing women&apos;s role in peace processes, ACCORD has for example worked to strengthen the AU Gender Directorate, and worked with AU on gender mainstreaming. With ECCAS they have developed an institutional mechanisms to advocate for increase participation of women in peace and security. They have also worked with a number of civil society organisations and networks to strengthen existing platforms and outreach. They supported gender perspectives in CAR and Mozambique efforts as well as the establishment of FEMWISE.&#xA0;
In enhancing the role of youth in peace processes, in addition to organizing an AU pre-summit on youth dynamics in Africa which raised awareness of youth issues and roles in peacebuilding, ACCORD has supported youth in Zimbabwe, Burundi, Liberia with trainings for increased engagement in peace processes.&#xA0;
Under the result area increased knowledge, policy support and integration of drivers of conflict, ACCORD has produced a large number of publications on issues such as mediation, elections and gender which has also translated into new training initiatives, interventions and seminars informing policy making and practice. ACCORD has been recognised as as one of the top 100 think tanks in the world.&#xA0;
In terms of Early Warning and Conflict prevention, ACCORD has undertaken a number of trainings with AU and RECs on early warning systems. They have been active participants in a number of events on prevention of conflict on the continent and continue to integrate stronger preventative approaches in their trainings and interactions.&#xA0;
The present support also included a compenent to support ACCORD&apos;s capacity on RBM, which had been identified as an area of weakness. Sida commissioned a consultant (through its framework agreement with Indevelop) who provided recommendations on RBM which were followed up throughout the activity period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51000095" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
