<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13146A0101-AFR-23183</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">PA - H&#xE5;llbar upphandling studie</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA - Sustainable procurement study</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida supports sustainable energy investments in Sub-Saharan Africa. There are currently numerous Swedish development strategies for Africa (bilateral, multilateral, regional and global) with goals related to targets as expressed in SDG 7 (sustainable energy for all). The SDG 7 have three main sub-goals: 
&#x2022;	By 2030, ensure universal access to affordable, reliable and modern energy services 
&#x2022;	By 2030, increase substantially the share of renewable energy in the global energy mix 
&#x2022;	By 2030, double the global rate of improvement in energy efficiency 
Sida&#x2019;s goal is to leverage capital investments in the sector and therefore, an increasing portion of the support involves incentivising the private sector to act and operate in the energy sector for universal access, more renewable energy and energy efficiency. It is electric energy that is mostly in focus in current Sida interventions.
Supporting private sector activities highlights the need to more firmly express the conditions for support. Therefore, Sida is looking to formulate requirements or advice that can be tailored to suit the African countries and be applied in Sida&#x2019;s own procurements and agreements but more importantly in procurements and agreements settled by other parties that we finance.
In Sweden and Europe, there exist procurement advice for energy. These are often relatively straightforward measures, basically ready to use also in Africa south of Sahara. Part of the ambition with this assignment is therefore to work with procurement advice related to energy that are compiled and presented by the Swedish Procurement Agency. Furthermore, it will be an ambition to amend and complement these advices to suit the African market and to find ways to verify and control compliance in South Saharan Africa.
Sida can also use &#x2013; and advice others to use &#x2013; catalytic/innovative procurement measures. This assignment therefore entails to guide Sida in developing methods and code of conduct for innovative procurement.
While the title refers to procurement advice, there are other arrangements when Sida can also benefit from having prepared formulations and work processes regarding the conditions for financing. The list of where and how advice can be applied include &#x2013; but is not limited to:
&#x2022;	In Sida&#x2019;s own procurements for the fulfilment of development strategies in Africa.
&#x2022;	When Sida writes agreements for issuing Swedish State Guarantees; that is &#x2013; including terms and conditions for the validity of the risk sharing guarantee.
&#x2022;	When Sida agrees to provide grant money for others to use in challenge funds of energy supply or end use services or equipment.
&#x2022;	When Sida agrees to provide grant money for others to use in public-private development projects with focus on energy supply or end use services or equipment.
&#x2022;	When Sida agrees to provide grant money for others to use in procurement of energy supply or end use services or equipment, sometimes to achieve objectives within other intervention areas such as health, education, peace keeping or democratic governance.
&#x2022;	In dialogue, when Sida provides advice, training and capacity building in the energy sector or in other sectors as well.

In this contribution, Sida has identified a few tasks for external consultants to carry out, leading the way towards formulations for procurement advice when investing in sustainable energy in Africa. 
The out-put is generally expected to be very short and concise formulations, linking as much as possible to other established sources, easy to grasp and use and possible to update with reference to the changing context in Sub-Saharan Africa. 
To reach at this, Sida has framed the task to include only three countries. Our suggested three countries are Kenya, Uganda and Zambia, although this will finally be agreed upon at the start up meeting. 
The tasks are:
Task 1: Advice how Sida can apply Swedish procurement guidelines, based on the Swedish Procurement Agencies work.
Task 2: Advice how Sida can complement and develop these advice
Task 3: Advice regarding how Sida can support processes for innovative procurement.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;dja framv&#xE4;xten av f&#xF6;rnybar energi</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="61009" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="61009" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other non-financial corporations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-23" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="231" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy Policy</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="23183" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy conservation and demand-side efficiency</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">37972.9356531345</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">37972.9356531345</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-23">37972.935653</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">37834.8522507595</value>
  </transaction>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13146" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1130103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Capacity development, partnership and methods that support Agenda 2030 for sustainable development 2018-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kapacitetsutveckling, partnerskap och metoder som st&#xF6;der Agenda 2030 f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar utveckling 2018-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
