<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12664A0101-AFR-41010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IGAD 2018-2019 Institutional Support to IDDRSI PCU</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">IGAD 2018-2019 Institutional Support to IDDRSI PCU</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">IGAD 2018-2019 Institutional Support to IDDRSI PCU

IGAD har ans&#xF6;kt till Sida f&#xF6;r finansiering om 15,000,000 SEK f&#xF6;r att st&#xF6;dja IGADs roll som koordinator f&#xF6;r IGAD Drought Disaster Resilience and Sustainability Initiative (IDDRISI) under ett&#xE5;rsperioden fr&#xE5;n 1 oktober 2018 till 30 september 2019.

M&#xE5;len med insatsen &#xE4;r att m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra f&#xF6;r IGAD sekretariatet att fullf&#xF6;lja sitt st&#xF6;d- och koordineringsarbete f&#xF6;r IDDRISI, genom att tillhandh&#xE5;lla ekonomiskt st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r att finansiera l&#xF6;ner f&#xF6;r viktig personal och driftkostnader hos IDDRSI. Dessutom f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntas denna insats att underl&#xE4;tta f&#xF6;r IGAD att f&#xE5; tillg&#xE5;ng till ytterligare svenskt bist&#xE5;nd som allokerats f&#xF6;r &#xE4;ndam&#xE5;let resiliens p&#xE5; Afrikas horn. 

I september 2011 beslutade stats&#xF6;verhuvudena fr&#xE5;n IGAD:s medelstater att skapa IDDRISI, i ett f&#xF6;rs&#xF6;k att med regionalt samarbete och koordinerade aktioner utrota n&#xF6;dsituationer av torka p&#xE5; Afrikas horn.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IGAD 2018-2019 Institutional Support to IDDRSI PCU

IGAD has made a request to Sida for funding of 15 000 000 SEK  to support its coordination role of the IGAD Drougth Disaster Resilience and Sustainability Initiative (IDDRSI) for a period on one year from October 1, 2018 to September 30, 2019.

The objective of the intervention is to enable IGAD Secretariat to continue its coordination and facilitation role of IDDRSI by providing support to cover salary costs of key IDDRSI staff and related operational costs. Moreover, this contribution is expected to support IGAD to be able to access additional Swedish funding allocated for resileine in the Horn of Africa Region.

IDDRSI is an outcome of a collective decision made in September 2011 by heads of IGAD member states in a bid to end drought emergencies in the horn of Africa region through regional cooperation and coordinated actions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of this intervention is to enable IGAD Secretariat to discharge its coordination and facilitation role of Drought Disaster Resilience and Sustainability Initiative (IDDRSI) by maintaining key IDDRSI staff. 
This contribution covered a period of one year (October 2018 - September 2019), and is meant to ensure continuity of IDDRSI Platform Coordination Unit (PCU) and provide the time and resources necessary for IGAD to increase its capacity to access additional Swedish funding for Horn of Africa Resilience (65 Million SEK, from 2019-2021).&#xA0;
The contribution covered salary costs of 18 IDDRSI staff (Regional staff &amp; national coordinators) as well as related operational expenses.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="47000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IGAD/Intergovernmental Authority on Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47000" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IGAD/Intergovernmental Authority on Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-27" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="410" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Environment Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="2.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1 - By 2030, end hunger and ensure access by all people, in particular the poor and people in vulnerable situations, including infants, to safe, nutritious and sufficient food all year round.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">2.1 - Senast 2030 avskaffa hunger och garantera alla m&#xE4;nniskor, i synnerhet de fattiga och m&#xE4;nniskor i utsatta situationer, inklusive sm&#xE5; barn, tillg&#xE5;ng till tillr&#xE4;ckligt med s&#xE4;ker och n&#xE4;ringsrik mat &#xE5;ret om.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.4 - By 2030, ensure sustainable food production systems and implement resilient agricultural practices that increase productivity and production, that help maintain ecosystems, that strengthen capacity for adaptation to climate change, extreme weather, drought, flooding and other disasters and that progressively improve land and soil quality.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">2.4 - Senast 2030 uppn&#xE5; h&#xE5;llbara system f&#xF6;r livsmedelsproduktion samt inf&#xF6;ra motst&#xE5;ndskraftiga jordbruksmetoder som &#xF6;kar produktiviteten och produktionen, som bidrar till att uppr&#xE4;tth&#xE5;lla ekosystemen, som st&#xE4;rker f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;gan till anpassning till klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar, extrema v&#xE4;derf&#xF6;rh&#xE5;llanden, torka, &#xF6;versv&#xE4;mning och andra katastrofer och som successivt f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrar mark- och jordkvaliteten.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1726042.5296879315</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1726042.5296879313</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">-16261.7674842828</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-27">1726042.529687</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-28">1726042.5296879315</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-28">-16261.7739991531</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The contribution supported IGAD/IDDRSI Platform Coordination Unit to discharge its responsibilities and the results achieved include:
Result Area 1: National Coordination and Monitoring of IDDRSI in IGAD Member States Strengthened
- With support from the Regional Experts, the National IDDRSI Coordinators have contributed to planning, monitoring and evaluation of various resilience projects in the Member States.
- Thorough analysis and discussion of the structure and function of existing national IDDRSI Coordination Mechanisms was done and recommendations were drawn for the establishment, operationalization and strengthening of national coordination mechanisms.&#xA0; Highlights of recommendations include the need for national coordination of all thematic areas included in IDDRSI strategy and country programming paper; the need to have a formal authority, mandate, and a dedicated secretariat.&#xA0;
Result Area 2.1: IDDRSI Platform Coordination Functions, including Programming, Knowledge Management, Capacity Building and M&amp;E Strengthened and facilitated
-&#xA0; Staff working within the framework of the initiative supported by Sweden, have sustained the PCU to deliver its role in coordinating the implementation of IDDRSI. During the project reporting period, the personnel supported by the project have sustained the coordination and implementation of IDDRSI through their involvement in actions ranging from knowledge management, programming, capacity building and resources mobilisation.
-&#xA0;Two of the staff supported under the project are based at the IGAD Climate Prediction and Application Centre. The two staff have been actively involved in the establishment and operationalization of the IGAD Food Security, Nutrition and Resilience Analysis Hub (IFRAH) - an analytical unit that focuses on coordinating food security, nutrition, resilience analyses and impact measurement.
Resource Mobilization: Staff supported with this contribution mobilized resources for resilience-enhancing flagship projects, in a variety of fields, including fisheries and blue economy valuation, food and nutrition security and river basin management. The Fisheries expert has mobilized resource worth of Euro 700,000 for three projects, and the Water Expert prepared a project on regional water initiative that was awarded 2.5 million by the World Bank.
In Sudan, the National IDDRSI Coordinator (NIC) has lobbied for fund allocation in collaboration with the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Republic of Sudan, where the Ministry of Finance has allocated budget in 2019. The budget allocation is an additional testimony of the commitment of the Government of Sudan to IDDRSI and its approach.
The NIC in Uganda has closely worked with the Office of the Prime Minister of the Republic of Uganda to facilitate the alignment of the AUC fund &#x2013; The New Partnership for Africa&#x2019;s Development (NEPAD) with PIA (Priority Intervention Area) 2: Market Access, Trade and Financial Services, PIA 3: Enhanced Production and Livelihoods Diversification and PIA 4: Disaster Risk Reduction of the Country Programming Paper. This was carried out for the project entitled, &#x201C;Agriculture and Food Insecurity Risk Management (AFIRM) that provided Euro 800,000 for the period of 2019-2022. In addition, a new interventions by Government of Uganda to the Country Program Paper (CPP) has facilitated the allocation of the KfW grant for Karamoja Drought Resilience Project. The support provided Euro 20 million, which will focus on water development in Karamoja 2019-2022. The KfW grant also includes Euro 18 million for rural development and post-harvest handling project 2019-2022.
The IFRAH Team spear-headed by its Coordinator, pursued the Letter of Agreement that was initiated earlier that was eventually signed in April 2019 with FAO by IGAD for the first year funding of about 360,000 USD for strengthening both the human and institutional development of IFRAH. In addition to activities on resilience, food security and Integrated Phase Classification (IPC) issues, the funding also includes the recruitment of staff i.e. Regional Resilience Analyst to lead RAU, Regional Food Security Analyst for FSNWG and Knowledge Management and Monitoring and Evaluation Associate who are now working for IFRAH in their respective capacities. The recruitment of these staff was a big boost for the rolling out of IFRAH including RAU to have the capacity to adequately support IGAD and Member States on resilience measurement, food security monitoring and analysis. In addition, a Data and Information Systems Analyst and a Statistician were recruited with a fund provided by this project, even though their salaries will be covered by the new IGAD-Sweden Project. The former is aimed to lead on issues of IPC capacity building for IGAD Member States and support on food and nutrition assessments and analysis in the region to feed into the yearly IGAD Regional Food Crisis Report that IFRAH will produce in collaboration with the Global Food Crisis Network.
Capacity Development: Some of the personnel supported by the project were involved in capacity building services, which greatly contributed to IGAD&#x2019;s role in coordinating the implementation of IDDRSI.
Three days training was organized for member states experts on how to assess the contribution of Blue Economy (BE) in the national economy. The Water Experts in the Agriculture and Environment Division (AED) contributed to the Cross -border dialogue. The Food Security expert of the AED contributed in the training organized for 55 countries of Africa on the electronic Biennial Review and reporting tools (e-BR) that allowed all countries to submit their reports electronically to the Regiona Economic Communities (RECs) for verification, correction and compilation regionally before submission to the African Union Commission/Department of Rural Economy and Agriculture (AUC/DREA) and the African Union Development Agency-New Partnership for African Development (AUDA-NEAPD) in relation to the Comprehensive Africa Agriculture Development Program (CAADP)/ Malabo Declaration biennial review reporting tools.
Partnership and Networking:&#xA0;The IFRAH Coordinator is co-chairing the Food Security and Nutrition Working Group on behalf of IGAD with FAO. The group is an information sharing platform that brings together member states, UN agencies NGOs and IGAD Specialized Centers.
IGAD is a member of Global Food Crises Network. The Network has been producing an annual report on food crisis for the past 3 years. The IFRAH Coordinator participated in a High-Level Event in Brussels at Belgium at the European Union Headquarters in April 2019. The event has been instrumental in bringing global attention to food crises and the need for coordinated and joint actions to tackle their root causes. The Coordinator used the opportunity to develop an IGAD Food Crises Report to be extracted from the global for follow up and action by the key players in the region. The report was jointly prepared and launched at the IDDRSI Platform meeting that took place early September, 2019.
Technical Staff in the Agriculture and Environment Division and the National IDDRSI Coordinators have participated in a number of national, regional and international meetings where they championed IGAD and IDDRSI. Some of these connections have provided opportunities to jointly develop resilience projects. For instance, in Sudan, new partnership was initiated on cross border intervention with Life and Peace Institute (LPI).
IGAD&#x2019;s Food Security Expert from the Agriculture and Environment Division is serving as a Focal Person for CAADP where he is representing IGAD in various continental meetings and networks. For instance, he participated in AUC and AUDA-NEPAD (African Union Development Agency - New Partnership for Africa&apos;s Development) in collaboration with RECs workshop, Johannesburg, South Africa 22-25 May 2019 on the Malabo Declaration Biennial Review Report and Advocacy Materials that allow efficient reporting for the 2nd Biennial Review Report with and appropriate structure Report and advocacy materials to showcase AU Member States&apos; progress towards achieving the Malabo Declaration Goals and Targets and stimulate actions for effective agricultural transformation by the year 2025. Moreover, he participated in FAO Regional Workshop for Africa Mainstreaming Sustainable Food and Agriculture (SFA) in the Implementation of the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) in the context of the Malabo Declaration, Addis Ababa, Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia, 28-30 May 2019.
Result Area 2.2:&#xA0;Updated IDDRSI programming frameworks (Strategy, RPP and CPPs) and Drought Resilience Platform documents; Country Investment Plans prepared
In a process that was initiated in October 2018, national teams of technical experts and senior policy officials, representing different sectors as well as various experts from the IGAD Secretariat and Specialized Institutions analysed the previous programming frameworks and noted what needed to be changed or added to achieve the improvement required to be included in the next phase. A series of cascading national and regional workshops were held to debate the different views and proposals and harmonise recommendations for inclusion in the text and composition of the new refined formulations. The refined regional and national programming frameworks were validated and subsequently launched during the IDDRSI Platform meetings, to provide guidance for the implementation of IDDRSI during the next 5 years (2019 &#x2013; 2024). The revision includes the addition of 8th Priority Intervention Area (PIA) focusing on Human Capital, Gender and Human Development.
Revised Regional Strategy:
https://resilience.igad.int/index.php/knowledge/technologies/documents/168-revised-iddrsi-strategy-2019&#xA0;
Revised Country Program papers:
https://resilience.igad.int/index.php/knowledge/technologies/documents?tag%5b0%5d=country-programming-paper-cpps://resilience.igad.int/index.php/knowledge/technologies/documents?tag%5b0%5d=country-programming-paper-c
Result Area 2.3: Effective and efficient implementation of IDDRSI flagship projects in the Member States
For the first time, regional resilience projects being implemented within the framework of IDDRSI prepared summary annual project reports which were edited and printed for circulation. In total, 14 projects were designed and printed. All coordination of production, editing and printing was funded by Sweden, while the graphic design and layout was supported with other partner funds.
Fisheries and Blue Economy is getting momentum in IGAD programs/projects. There is significant support from the IGAD secretariat and the management to enhance the sector to achieve food/nutrition security and resilience building in Arid and Semi-Arid Lands (ASALs).
With the support of African Development Bank (AfDB), project proposal was developed to carry-out an assessment of the fisheries resource base with a view of determining its contribution on food and nutrition security, resilience building in 3-transboundary river basins of Baro-Akobo, Omo-Turkana and Shebella-Genale in order to draft a management plan for the utilization of the resource. Major achievements in the Blue Economy sector are:
-Baseline reports for the 3 transboundary river basins produced. This report contains details of the fisheries resource base, socio-economic characteristics, fish value chain, gender dimensions, etc. This report will serve as a reference material for further investment in the 3 transboundary rivers bordering 4 IGAD Member States (MS).&#xA0;
-Fisheries Co-Management Plan for the 3 transboundary river basins fisheries developed. The co-management plan contains the challenges of the fisheries management in shared rivers, available indigenous management options and finally drafted co-management plan that will be implemented by bordering MS.
- Blue Economy Valuation Manual developed and adopted. The manual aimed at valuing the contribution of Blue Economy for the member states economy. The manual is a harmonized data collection tool and currently national consultants are using it.
Result Area 2.4:&#xA0;Efficient IDDRSI knowledge sharing platforms established
Sharing of knowledge and information related to the implementation of IDDRSI is a strategic function of the Platform Coordination Unit (PCU), which helps to identify resilience needs and informs programming. In this connection, a number of knowledge management (KM) tools have been developed; and have been applied with the support from the project under report.
Below are some of the key achievements during the project period:
Knowledge and skills in relation to monitoring the implementation of investment projects and program&#x2019;s using a web based application was enhanced for the stakeholders who attended the training. A successful capacity building training&#xA0;(Training of Trainees) was provided to National Drought Management Authority (NDMA) in Kenya during the first quarter of the year, which received an important accolade in the application of the Di-Monitoring where a testimonial was received from the CEO of the National Drought Management Authority in Kenya extolling the virtues of monitoring tool: The training enhanced the NDMA&#x2019;s knowledge, skill and capacity to fully utilize the application to track the Ending Drought Emergency (EDE) Framework and NDMA II Framework together with the NDMA II 2019 -2020 Work plan with a limited remote support from the IGAD technical expert.
A hands on application and use of Di-Monitoring tool was provided to District development planners and Physical planers in Nakapiripirit, Uganda and Lodwar, Kenya on 1-5 July and 08-12 July 2019 respectively. The training was organized with a close support and facilitation from the GIZ TC facility which is based in Lodwar and Moroto.
Capturing, accessing and sharing of spatial and non-spatial information to the various stakeholders became well-organized/enhanced. A web based platform (Geonode) to access and disseminate spatial information for the internal and external stakeholders created a convenient environment for users to access spatial documents and data sets in various format. The successful accomplishment of the development of a web based application (3W Mapping) activity, allowed IGAD to support Member countries on the process of mapping of &#x201C;Who&#x201D; is doing &#x201C;What&#x201D; and &#x201C;Where&#x201D; in the IGAD Region in an efficient way. The 3W mapping platform allowing IGAD and Member State to systematically store and visualize all the investment projects which are currently in various development stages for better programming, programming and coordination.
Priority Intervention Area (PIA) Icons: In line with the revision and the launch of the new phase of the Regional Program Paper (RPP) and Country Program Paper (CPP), new icons were designed, building on already existing ones and including a new one for PIA 8. The final selection was a result of a participatory exercise with the technical team from IGAD MS and IGAD. These were launched at the General Assembly with the printing of 8 banners in English and 8 in French.
Dissemination of RPP, Strategy and CPP: Following the successful completion of the documents, IGAD facilitated the design and printing of 100 copies each of the RPP, regional strategy and CPPs of six countries. Kenya was excluded as it had already completed its own process.
With regard to the actual event, the IDDRSI forum and Program Steering Committee/General Assembly (PSC/GA) programmes and event folders were also designed and printed (150 copies each).
The Knowledge Management (KM) Coordinator, supported by Sweden, edited and coordinated the production of a total of 5 folders with about 8-12 good practices each, which were produced in collaboration with FAO with funding from SDC. The KM Coordinator also supported Regional Pastoral Livelihoods Resilience Project (RPLRP) to produce 13 good practices and 3 success stories from Ethiopia, Kenya and Uganda.
The KM Team in collaboration with the SECCCI (Support for Effective Cooperation and Coordination of Cross Border Initiatives) Project funded by the EUT/UNDP initiated a web-based knowledge management platform for ensuring cross-border coordination and cooperation is established and functioning. The knowledge platform, which is near its completion will serve as a platform for share knowledge in wide areas of interest in the region.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12664" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061603" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="4725000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional Africa 2016-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt Afrika 2016-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
