<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13137A0101-AFR-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">KAIPTC, 2019 - 2021, Programme Support</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KAIPTC, 2019 - 2022, Programme Support</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Den planerade insatsen fokuserar specifikt p&#xE5; att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra kvinnors och ungdomars roll i processer kring fred och s&#xE4;kerhet. Detta kommer att uppn&#xE5;s genom forskning, kapacitetsbyggnad och policyp&#xE5;verkan. Den f&#xF6;reslagna insatsen syftar till att uppn&#xE5; f&#xF6;ljande resultat:

1.	&#xD6;kad kunskap bland politiska akt&#xF6;rer samt genus- och s&#xE4;kerhetakt&#xF6;rer f&#xF6;r implementeringsmekanismer med syfte att f&#xF6;rebygga terrorism, v&#xE5;ldsbejakande extremism och k&#xF6;nsbaserat v&#xE5;ld.
2.	St&#xE4;rkt f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;ga hos kvinnor, ungdomar, s&#xE4;kerhets- och genusakt&#xF6;rer f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rebygga terrorism, v&#xE5;ldsbejakande extremism och k&#xF6;nsbaserat v&#xE5;ld.
3.	F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad rapportering kring genomf&#xF6;randet av agendan f&#xF6;r kvinnor, fred &amp; s&#xE4;kerhet i Afrika. 
4.	Ett st&#xE4;rkt institut f&#xF6;r kvinnor, fred &amp; s&#xE4;kerhet, som fungerar som ett fullfj&#xE4;drat institut hos KAIPTC med en egen styrelse.

Den f&#xF6;reslagna insatsen &#xE4;r tre &#xE5;r (oktober 2019 - september 2022) och den totala kostnaden &#xE4;r 15 000 000 SEK varav 5 000 000 SEK &#xE4;r f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;rande under &#xE5;r det f&#xF6;rsta &#xE5;ret (oktober 2019 - september 2020), 5 000 000 SEK f&#xF6;r det andra &#xE5;ret (oktober 2020 - september 2021) och 5 000 000 SEK f&#xF6;r det tredje &#xE5;ret (oktober 2021 - september 2022).</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The planned contribution specifically focuses on enhancing the role of women and youth in peace and security, this will be achieved through research, capacity building and advocacy. The proposed intervention aims to achieve the following outcomes:
1. Enhanced knowledge among policy actors, gender and security practitioners on the implementation of mechanisms to prevent terrorism, violent extremism and gender-based violence
2. Strengthened capacity of women, youth, security practitioners and gender actors in the prevention of terrorism, violent extremism and gender-based violence 
3. Improved reporting on the implementation of the Women, Peace and Security (WPS) agenda in Africa
4. Women, Peace and Security Institute (WPSI) strengthened to function as a full-fledged institute hosted in KAIPTC with its own Council/Steering Committee  

The proposed intervention has a duration of 3 years (October 2019 - September 2022) and has a total cost of SEK 15 000 000 of which SEK 5 000 000 is for implementation in year 1 (October 2019 - September 2020), SEK 5 000 000 for year 2 (October 2020 - September 2021); and SEK 5 000 000 for year 3 (October 2021 - September 2022).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed intervetnion aims to achieve the following Objectives:
1. To enhance knowledge and skills among gender and security practitioners on the implementation of mechanisms to prevent terrorism, violent extremism and gender based violence:
The research on Women and Countering Violent Extremism and Terrorism in West Africa seeks to contribute to increasing awareness and understanding of the complexities surrounding women&#x2019;s involvement in terrorist organizations; the effects and changing roles of women as a result of terrorism and to reinforce women&#x2019;s capacities in early warning in the fight against radicalization and terrorism in selected West African countries (Burkina Faso, Mali, Niger and Nigeria). Through research and consultations, it is expected that comprehensive data will be generated to produce a training guide to help empower women and youth organizations engaged in education and sensitization against terrorism and violent extremism in these countries. &#xA0;
The research on the Gender Dimensions of ECOWAS-led Peacekeeping Missions on the other hand seeks to improve the knowledge and technical skills of peacekeepers on the importance of mainstreaming gender into ECOWAS-led peace support operations. The project will provide a situation analysis of the gender dimensions of ECOWAS mandated missions and its implications for the operational effectiveness of missions and asses the content of peacekeeping training programmes and engage policy makers and stakeholders to strengthen gender mainstreaming strategies in peace operations. It will further work towards enhancing the capacity of EWOAS to mainstream gender within its policies and structures.&#xA0;
Under this objective, the KAIPTC will also establish a platform for dialogues on violent extremism, terrorism and gender dimensions of ECOWAS PSOs. The dialogues will be informed by the knowledge management products and will bring together participants from ECOWAS and various members&#xA0;states to discuss the above subjects. Furthermore the dialogues will be organized in a way that will feed into the overall objectives of the project and ensure continuous reflection of outcomes from the discussions in trainings and others activities.
Expected Outcome under this objective is enhanced knowledge and capacity among policy actors, gender and security practitioners on the implementation of the Women Peace and Security Agenda in Africa.
2. To improve reporting mechanisms and processes on the implementation of the WPS agenda
Operationalization of the CRF is essential for proper and effective monitoring of countries&#x2019; activities and challenges in the implementation of their NAPs and other legal frameworks to support the WPS agenda. However, in order to assess data gathered, there is the need to have a structured system that will guide all countries in the manner of data collection. Once the system has been developed then there is the need for training national agencies and CSOs in charge of gathering the data on how to utilize it. In consultation with the Office of the Special Envoy on Women Peace and Security of the AU Commission, five countries in West Africa have been identified for the project. The decision to focus the initial training of West Africa is informed by the fact that with the exception of Cape Verde, all West African countries have developed NAPs on UNSCR 1325. The region shows much pro-activeness in addressing the WPS agenda, providing the right synergy for rolling out the CRF. Additionally, the region provides a good mix of both relatively stable democracies as well as post conflict democracies, bringing to bear the diversities across the continent. The countries identified for the purpose of this research are: The Gambia, Ghana, Liberia, Mali and Sierra Leone. Lessons learnt from these countries and best practices will then be transferred to other regions.
Strategic meetings will be held with the Gender Unit of ECOWAS as well as the Office&#xA0;&#xA0; of the Special Envoy on Women Peace and Security of the AU Commission for continuous inputs and engagements on these activities and further utilization of the outcome of these activities.
The support to member states on investigating gender based violence aims to enhance the skills of security agencies and or peacekeeping mission to effectively investigate gender-based violence. The premise is that if investigations are conducted effectively it may lead to a high prosecution rate which may breed confidence in victims to seek justice. Countries being targeted for the training are Gambia, Mali, Cameroun, South Sudan and Central African Republic.
Addressing the youth bulge will mainly be an engagement with youth groups to identify their peculiar needs within the peace and security arena and together design, develop and provide ToT for the youth leaders on how to address their needs. It is expected that the leaders will utilize the new knowledge and skills set to intervene and empower their members.
Expected outcome under the second objective is improved reporting on the implementation of the WPS agenda in Africa.
3. WPSI strengthened to function as a full-fledged institute hosted in KAIPTC with its own Council/Steering Committee
In-line with the 5yr Strategic Goal of the Centre to make WPSI a fully-fledged Institute there is the need to begin looking at the re-structuring of the Institute and equipping with the requisite staff to support the work of the Institute. A road-map has been agreed and approved by the Executive Management. There will be an understudy and engagement with similar institutions/organizations to appreciate their lessons learnt to ensure this restructure places WPSI in a position to deliver its mandate with a specific niche. It is anticipated that by the end of 2019 a Steering/Advisory Committee and a Marketing and Financial Strategy has been established/ developed based on engagements and lessons learnt.
The expected outcome under the third objecive is the strengthening of WPSI as a full-fledged institute hosted in KAIPTC.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KAIPTC/Kofi Annan International Peacekeeping Training Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KAIPTC/Kofi Annan International Peacekeeping Training Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-11" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.a - Strengthen relevant national institutions, including through international cooperation, for building capacity at all levels, in particular in developing countries, to prevent violence and combat terrorism and crime.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.a - St&#xE4;rka ber&#xF6;rda nationella institutioner, bland annat genom internationellt samarbete, i syfte att bygga upp kapacitet p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er, i synnerhet i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna, f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rebygga v&#xE5;ld och bek&#xE4;mpa terrorism och brottslighet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">528770.3973180766</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">582961.2097611025</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">528770.3973180766</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">582961.2097611023</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">-1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-11">1057540.794636</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-28">528770.3973180766</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-28">582961.2097611025</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/13137_AgreementbetweenSidaandKAIPTC.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement between Sida and KAIPTC</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/13137_Beslutominsats.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13137" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061603" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="4725000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional Africa 2016-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt Afrika 2016-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
