<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5105005501-AFR-23630</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa Power Pool (SAPP) 2012-19 Phase 3</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">South Africa Power Pool (SAPP) 2012-19 Phase 3</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Continued capacity development to Southern African Power Pool (SAPP)  2013-2015,</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Fortsatt kapacitetsutvecklingsst&#xF6;d till Southern African Power Pool,  fas 3.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="13000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Norway</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="13000" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Third Country Government (Delegated co-operation)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-02-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="23630" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Electric power transmission and distribution (centralised grids)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="236" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy distribution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="7.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">7.b - By 2030, expand infrastructure and upgrade technology for supplying modern and sustainable energy services for all in developing countries, in particular least developed countries, small island developing States and landlocked developing countries, in accordance with their respective programmes of support.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">7.b - Till 2030 bygga ut infrastrukturen och uppgradera tekniken f&#xF6;r att leverera moderna och h&#xE5;llbara energitj&#xE4;nster till alla i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna, i synnerhet de minst utvecklade l&#xE4;nderna och sm&#xE5; &#xF6;nationer under utveckling.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">616641.282318983</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">627529.5558244289</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">995989.3466835918</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">616641.2823189829</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">627529.5558244289</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">995989.3466835918</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-02-28">2566571.117116</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">616641.2516121106</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-09-28">632833.0004810565</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-10-28">-5303.373227015</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-07-28">582392.0135717082</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">413597.3615839987</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results related to the intended outcomes. The agreement between Norway and SAPP, which also guides&#xA0;Sidas&#xA0;engagement, includes 15 indicators, set to be achieved by 2015. However, with the extensions to 2019, the progress is still measured against these indicators, of which most have been surpassed already in 2015. The results up to April 2018 were the following; 1. Implementation of SAPP priority generation and transmission projects resulting in increased security of supplies. Result;&#xA0;Contracts to prepare the Alaska-Sherwood line and the Angola-Namibia interconnection projects were signed with the Transaction Advisers. SAPP commissioned a total of 12,833 MW from 2013 to 2017. As a result of additional generation, SAPP recorded a surplus generation of 2,957 MW in 2017 after having been in a deficit situation for the last 10 years. 2 Transparent rules for access to transmission facilities by different players in the electricity sector. Result; SAPP in 2016, revised its transmission capacity allocation criteria to allow market trades to have transmission capacity access ahead of non-firm bilateral contracts. SAPP also revised the market rules to reflect the revised criteria. This programme output was therefore achieved. 3 A working transmission pricing strategy that is clear and transparent. Result; The transmission pricing model was developed for SAPP. The financial impact is also being assessed, analysing the impacts on utilities. 4 More players in the electricity business in SAPP. Results; The electricity business in the SADC region has attracted a number of players, mainly on the generation side. A number of generation projects in the region are currently being implemented by independent power producers (IPPs). Enquiries have also been received from such IPPs for them to participate on the SAPP competitive markets. SAPP is reviewing its membership application guidelines and IUMOU in order to accommodate new players. Two IPPs from Zambia, namely Lunsemfwa Hydro Power Company and Ndola Energy, have been granted SAPP membership. 5 Increased trade volumes in the SAPP Competitive markets. Results; SAPP competitive market trade volumes have been going up since 2013 with 84,074 MWh traded in 2013/14, 508,264 MWh traded in 2014/15 and 1,059,540 MWh traded in 2015/16, 1,023,056 MWh in 2016/17 and 2,123,671 MWh being traded in 2017/18. SAPP introduced more competitive trading platforms in 2016 that include the month ahead, week ahead and intra day markets. This saw increased trade on the competitive markets. This programme output was therefore successfully achieved and there is room for continued growth. 6 A Working Balancing market (BM) and working ancillary services market that involves transformation of in kind imbalance settlements to a real time market. Results;&#xA0;The SAPP in 2014 decided to postpone the development of a balancing market (BM). Instead the SAPP decided to develop an intra day market (IDM) as precursor to the BM. The IDM was developed and commissioned in 2015. It was used for live trading from the 1st of March 2016. The SAPP also developed a mechanism for control area charges and other ancillary services charges. This was implemented from January 2014. SAPP plans to develop the BM starting in 2018/19. 7 A more efficient and sustainable regional electricity market for the SADC region. Results; SAPP developed and commissioned in 2015 its own trading platform (the SAPP-MTP) utilising this programme support. The SAPP-MTP has forward physical monthly (FPM-M), forward physical weekly (FPM-W), day ahead market (DAM) and Intra-day market (IDM). These markets will meet SAPP medium and short term trading requirements. The SAPP-MTP came with support and maintenance costs that are 50% lower than what the SAPP used to pay for the SAPRI system despite this being for only one market (the DAM). The new SAPP trading system is owned by SAPP hence making it more sustainable and flexible enough for SAPP to incorporate any future requirements. This programme outcome was therefore successfully achieved. 8&#xA0;Efficient utilisation of transmission facilities by all players in the electricity sector. Results; SAPP has incorporated the transmission capacity management in the SAPP-MTP. The approach used allows for counter flows to be taken into account when calculating available transmission capacity for future markets. This allows for efficient utilisation of transmission facilities. This programme outcome was therefore successfully achieved. 9&#xA0;Increased DAM Market Share of above 5% by end of 2015; SAPP competitive market achieved market shares of 1% in 2013/14, 6% in 2014/15, 14% in 2015/16, 11.3% in 2016/17 and 23.5% in 2017/18. This was as a result of the initiatives taken through the programme activities that include capacity building and the addition of new markets. The programme indicator was therefore successfully achieved. 10&#xA0;Increased participation on DAM to at least 10 participants by end of 2015. Results; The following participation levels were achieved; 2013/14 a total of seven (7), 2014/15 a total of eight (8), in 2015/16 a total of nine (9), in 2016/17 a total of nine (9) and in 2017/18 a total of 10. 2017/18 saw LEC and HCB participating on the market. Note that all the SAPP interconnected members except SNEL, LHPC and MOTRACO have participated on the competitive market. SNEL and LHPC have however indicated to start participating in 2018. 11 Adequate generation to meet demand by end of 2015; Results;&#xA0;SAPP has been commissioning new generation projects resulting in the generation shortfall going down from 2013. Generation shortfall was 7,709MW in 2013/14, 8,247 in 2014/15 and 5597 in 2015/16. In 2016/17 SAPP recorded a generation surplus of 919MW followed by another excess of 2,957 MW in 2017/18. The PDRI exercise assisted in screening some of the projects that were initially considered to be implemented earlier. The expected generation to be commissioned was overstated at the time this indicator was put in place. SAPP plans to add a total of 26,108 MW of new generation between 2018 and 2022 which is expected to enable SAPP to have adequate generation to meet current and future demand. 12&#xA0;Revenues generated from the SAPP competitive markets to be adequate to meet at least 100% of trading platform operating costs by end of 2015. Results; SAPP generated a total of USD168,320 in 2013/14 against costs of around USD380,000, USD1,013,008 in 2014/15 against costs of around USD380,000, USD2,119,080 in 2015/16 against budgeted costs of around USD200,000 USD2,046,112 in 2016/17 against budgeted costs of around USD200,000 and USD4,247,338 against budgeted costs of around USD200,000. The market was therefore able to generate enough revenues to meet demand from 2014 thereby achieving the programme performance indicator well before the set target of end of 2015. 13&#xA0;Two transmission projects, the Namibia-Angola interconnector and the Central Transmission Corridor in Zimbabwe, have reached financial closure by end of December 2014. Results; The scoping study for the Angola &#x2013; Namibia Interconnector was completed in March 2018. Detailed feasibility studies have commenced and are expected to be completed by April 2019. NORAD /Sida is co-financing the feasibility studies together with DBSA. The IGMOU is ready for signature. The Alaska-Sherwood line (which is a key component of the Central Transmission Corridor (CTC) project feasibility studies have commenced. This performance indicator target was not achieved on time mainly to the relatively slow start on the studies. The target commissioning dates are 2021. 14&#xA0;Project Development Readiness Index (PDRI) methodology and a database of assessed projects has been developed. Results; SAPP acquired the model for the PDRI exercise and the SAPP staff have been trained to carry out the exercise internally without assistance from external experts. This reduced the actual costs of the activity programme. The SAPP has so far done PDRI analyses exercises for Angola, Botswana, DRC, Lesotho, Malawi, Mozambique, Namibia, Tanzania, Zambia and Zimbabwe. The PDRI methodology and database of assessed projects is in place. A total of 105 participants have been trained and the utilities can evaluate projects independently. The project objective has been met 15 A model for transmission pricing that provides for locational signalling and access rules have been developed. Results; The transmission pricing model and losses pricing model were developed for SAPP by the consultant Mercados. SAPP is currently verifying the model by carrying out dummy runs using actual trade data. The financial impact is also being assessed by utilities and a way forward is expected around September 2018. The losses model is yet to be verified as this is waiting for the conclusion of the transmission pricing model. This programme output is therefore yet to be achieved.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51050055" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
