<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5406007602-AFR-31120</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AECF-African Enterprise Challenge Fund. Africa    Agribusiness Window</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">AECF-African Enterprise Challenge Fund. Africa    Agribusiness Window</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d till AECF challenge fund f&#xF6;r privatsektorledda                   jordbruksinvesteringar i Afrika.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to AECF challenge fund for private sector lead agribusiness   investments in Africa</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The AECF aims to facilitate pro-poor growth and poverty alleviation in Africa by making agribusiness, rural financial services and market systems work better for the poor. The fund expands entrepreneurs&#x2019; access to finance to stimulate innovation and find profitable ways of improving access to markets and the way markets function for the poor, particularly the rural poor and smallholder farmers. Specifically the Agribusiness Africa Window (AAW) aims to support business ideas in the fields of agribusiness, financial services, information and value chains that positively impact the rural poor. Business ideas being implemented in any African country.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AGRA/Alliance for a Green Revolution in Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="311" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.3 - By 2030, double the agricultural productivity and incomes of small-scale food producers, in particular women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers, including through secure and equal access to land, other productive resources and inputs, knowledge, financial services, markets and opportunities for value addition and non-farm employment.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">2.3 - Till 2030 f&#xF6;rdubbla jordbrukets produktivitet och inkomster f&#xF6;r sm&#xE5;skaliga livsmedelsproducenter, i synnerhet kvinnor, ursprungsfolk, familjejordbrukare, boskapssk&#xF6;tande nomader samt fiskare, inklusive genom s&#xE4;ker och lika tillg&#xE5;ng till mark, andra produktionsresurser och insatsvaror, kunskap, finansiella tj&#xE4;nster och marknader samt m&#xF6;jligheter till v&#xE4;rdeskapande och syssels&#xE4;ttning utanf&#xF6;r jordbruket.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Agribusiness Africa Window aimed at reducing poverty in Sub Saharan African countries by making&#xA0;agribusiness systems work better for the poor in rural areas. It intended to achieve this by encouraging&#xA0;and supporting the private sector to invest in agribusiness projects that benefit the poor as employees,&#xA0;out-growers/suppliers of produce and as customers or users of new and improved products or services. [NAT/GOAL] During the programme a total of 21 companies were awarded a mix of grant and repayable grant funding. Since inception the programme has cumulatively reached 805,884 rural households&#xA0;who were better able to access markets as&#xA0;producers and consumers of goods and services and creating a total net development impact of USD 461&#xA0;million. It has generated in average a net benefit per household of USD 183 per year as well as creating&#xA0;and sustaining 3,674 direct jobs of which a little under a half were for women. This was against an initial target of 2,500 direct jobs.&#xA0; &#xA0; [INST/NAT/GOAL] The window also had a good impact on business performances, measured by turnover and profitability, with 56% of AECF-funded companies that were three years old or older having had positive revenue growth rates from inception. The impact on market systems was measured by replication of agronomic or other practices associated with AECF projects. The most common type of systemic change, reported by 40% of AECF-funded companies, was business copying by others that did not benefit from the fund. [NAT/GOAL] The only call of proposals that was conducted, round 1 (R1) of the&#xA0; AAW made good progress on delivering business and&#xA0;developmental returns though these are concentrated disproportionately on a few&#xA0;businesses in Kenya and Ethiopia. Achievements are particularly sparse in West Africa.&#xA0; [INST/NAT/GOAL] While not all investments were as successful as hoped, it is important to remember that AECFaimed at starting races,&#xA0;rather than picking winners &#x2013; meaning it supported risky innovations and business models which have the&#xA0;potential to fundamentally change how value chains work. A good example is Esoko Networks, who when&#xA0;selected as an investee was still at a very early stage and had yet to prove its business model for something&#xA0;new to the market &#x2013; selling information to farmers. Despite the Esoko model and business failing, the&#xA0;market as a whole has learned that it is not commercially viable to sell market information to smallholders&#xA0;as a standalone product, and now we are seeing models that bundle information with other services and&#xA0;products like inputs, insurance, etc. to still sell information. Esoko was a critical test of the market to learn&#xA0;from and allow for new models to emerge. As part of the programme, the business initiatives supported by AECF (and the products and services&#xA0;delivered through them) must be commercially viable to ensure that the associated development impacts&#xA0;are sustainable in the long run. The programme expected that 30% of the projects will perform highly,&#xA0;40% will be average and 30% will fail, given the high-risk nature of the investments to be made. The&#xA0;programme was targeting five investees to be profitable, 23% of the total investees, by the end of 2018.&#xA0;Overall, the programme has been a success with 16 (76%) companies remaining in operations to date. [INST/NAT/GOAL] At the end of 2019, the total cumulative matching funds of USD 106.9 million was achieved against a&#xA0;target of USD 68.8 million. This represents a provision of matching funds at&#xA0;a ratio of 8.36 compared to the funds invested. It should be noted that one investee&#xA0;targeted the delivery of USD 25m in matching funds as it was seeking financing from IFC and it managed&#xA0;to secure USD 61m. Removing this outlier shows that the amount of matching funds raised was USD 45.9m, still significantly higher than the original planned raise of USD 28.9m and 3.76 times the capital&#xA0;invested. This is still likely to be an under-estimate as companies tend to stop reporting matching funds&#xA0;once they have drawn down their investment from AECF. The definition used by AECF on matching funds, include the funds contributed by the company, but also mobilized capital from the private sector, and other investors or donors. [INST/NAT/GOAL] The programme has supported several innovative business models that have started to gain traction, both&#xA0;in their markets and further afield. In Ethiopia, Agflow Poultry has demonstrated that backyard producers&#xA0;can reap the benefits of a superior poultry breed through a model where agents rear the day-old chicks&#xA0;to 45 days before distributing them in very small flock sizes to poor households. It produced 16,500,000&#xA0;day-old chicks in 2018, reaching 621,399 households, achieving significant income and nutritional impact&#xA0;at the regional level within Ethiopia. This model is being replicated in other countries across Africa. [INST/NAT/GOAL] Another example is Dryland Seeds in Kenya which has demonstrated that there is a niche market for drought-tolerant seeds that&#xA0;are more effective in dry areas of Kenya. Its model of using outgrowers to multiply seed and small packet&#xA0;sizes for smallholder farmers has increased the availability of appropriate genetics in a wide range of&#xA0;crops, improving resilience for dryland farmers. [NAT/GOAL] When modelling reach, it is not possible to identify individual beneficiaries in a cost-effective manner and&#xA0;so it is not possible to determine whether an individual is reached in one year or over a number of years.&#xA0;Therefore, annual reach cannot be cumulated across the portfolio. Instead, a concept of &#x2018;peak reach&#x2019; has been used where the highest reach in any one year for each project in the portfolio is aggregated. By the end&#xA0;of 2019, the portfolio had reached and estimated 805,884 rural households, over triple the target, with&#xA0;a total net benefit at the household level of USD 434 million. AAW R1 reached over triple its targets for&#xA0;the number of households reached and the total net benefit at the household level. Including USD 31&#xA0;million in wages earned by jobs created and sustained over the period and the total development impact&#xA0;is USD 461m from a total investment of USD 14 million. Across the portfolio, projects whose end beneficiaries are buyers of goods or services (consumer model,&#xA0;such as improved inputs) continue to reach a large number of households while generating a lower total&#xA0;net benefit per household. On the contrary, projects whose end beneficiaries are producing goods or services (producer model, such as outgrowers), have a smaller reach but generate a higher average total&#xA0;net benefit per household. [INST/NAT/GOAL]nWider market systems are conducive to agriculture sector and growth of&#xA0;agribusiness sectors.&#xA0;AECF invests to make systemic change in the business environment/market systems for agriculture and&#xA0;agribusiness. This is part of the market systems development approach of leveraging the incentives and&#xA0;resources of the private sector to drive benefit for the very poor, whilst stimulating changes that support&#xA0;the continuation of those benefits beyond the life of the project. Replication of business models was the most commonly occurring type of systemic change seen in this programme. The portfolio&#xA0;had several examples of replication, where competing businesses or similar businesses in other&#xA0;geographies copied the business practices modelled under the AAW R1 programme.&#xA0;In Ethiopia, the success of Agflow Poultry&#x2019;s novel agent model in reaching thousands of smallholders in&#xA0;the poultry value chain is already being copied by other AECF investees; New Horizons Mozambique and&#xA0;Yelo Egg in Zimbabwe. Agflow was also invited by the Rwandese government to replicate the business&#xA0;model in Rwanda, resulting in an expansion to Rwanda and the birth of the subsidiary, Uzima Chicken&#xA0;Limited, Rwanda. An agricultural enterprise not supported by AECF, Silverlands, is also copying the model&#xA0;in Tanzania.&#xA0;In Kenya, Mt. Kenya Gardens&#x2019; competitors have copied its extension and post-harvest practices. Kisima&#xA0;Farm has prompted new companies to register foreign potato seed varieties for sale in Kenya and the&#xA0;model has been copied by one of AECF&#x2019;s other investees in Tanzania. In Zambia, the Zambia National&#xA0;Farmers Union opened a chain of one-stop shops based on the model developed by Farmarama. The&#xA0;success of Reliance Financial Services in the Gambia saw forex bureaus expanding into savings, loans andremittances services. C. Dorman&#x2019;s success in Rwanda resulted in new entrants going into the certification&#xA0;of coffee farmers.Crowding-in occured when other businesses got into the market to take advantage of the space created by&#xA0;the AECF project. The implementation of the programme saw several examples of crowding in, such as&#xA0;new businesses selling inputs, agrochemicals and farmyard manure to supply Mt Kenya Gardens&#x2019; fruit&#xA0;growers. Dryland Seed also saw competitors crowding its market increasing volumes of seeds for drier&#xA0;areas. Mozambique Fresh Eggs has created a business for financiers to finance cages for poultry&#xA0;outgrowers. Farm Support has seen a number of competitors who previously imported acaricides, a&#xA0;pesticide, into Uganda, now becoming their distributing agents once it commenced manufacturing in country.&#xA0; During the implementation of the programme, the portfolio had a number of companies tackle legal and&#xA0;regulatory issues with governments. In 2014, Kisima Farms and its partner, Syngenta, helped the Kenya&#xA0;Plant Health Inspectorate Service move from a slow ELISA test-based system for checking for bacterial wilt&#xA0;to a faster Polymerase Chain Reaction (PCR) method. The same regulator also allowed the outsourcing of&#xA0;some services to private providers to speed the seed certification process. A regulatory change in Rwanda&#xA0;pushed by C. Dorman limits coffee buyers to specific regions to avoid poaching and side selling. In Nigeria,&#xA0;AACE Foods was involved in the development of a national standards for spices and a policy change that removed subsidies on imports of goods that could be produced locally. [NORM/NAT] To highlight other results and achievements resulting from Sida&apos;s support and as part of the establishment of the DCED results measurement process, AAW R1 also funded a series of learning papers that have directly contributed to improved results measurement within AECF as well as&#xA0;to broader learning agendas across the development ecosystem. All the papers are available on AECF&#x2019;s&#xA0;website (www.aecfafrica.org). They include learning papers on gender, jobs, additionality, and outgrower systems, amongst others.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="54060076" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
