<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5406007602-AFR-31120</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AECF-African Enterprise Challenge Fund. Africa    Agribusiness Window</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">AECF-African Enterprise Challenge Fund. Africa    Agribusiness Window</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d till AECF challenge fund f&#xF6;r privatsektorledda                   jordbruksinvesteringar i Afrika.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to AECF challenge fund for private sector lead agribusiness   investments in Africa</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AGRA/Alliance for a Green Revolution in Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="311" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall, in relation to beneficiary reach and businesses supported, the programme has reached or exceeded expectations. The number of households reached has exceeded the target by 33% and the target for net benefit per household has been exceeded by almost 100%. However businesses supported are still at a quite fragile stage overall and longer term business sustainability is far from assured. From the original 21 companies supported, 11 are showing continuing profitability. However 4 have failed and three others are seriously struggling to survive. Two others are re-examining and renegotiating their business model with AECF. AECF demonstrates the challenges and complexities of reaching smallholder farmers and while it has largely avoided the easy option of working with larger scale commercial farmers, for several partners smallholder farming is a minority part of the business. AECF should continually appraise the extent to which it is meeting its poverty alleviation mandate and where necessary intervene to alter or end projects which are not sufficiently addressing this mandate. During 2016/2017 period, AECF has undertaken a number of verification studies and has a better understanding of the poverty and inclusion impact of the AAW portfolio. The challenge for the AECF is to now use the lessons from these studies to improve the pro-poor and gender impact of existing competitions, like AAW, and to improve the design of new ones such as the proposed Women in Agribusiness competition. AECF AAW grantees are congregated&#xA0;in a few countries, particularly in East Africa, and within those countries, within a fairly restricted zone dominated by particular powerful and influential ethnic and political groups. This has partly arisen due to the structure of the challenge fund model which seeks bidders for funds rather than proactively seeking out potential investees. In order to maximise the poverty focus and minimise the risks associated with a bias towards any one group, a more nuanced future selection process for new competitions should be considered that is driven by political economy analysis and may include technical assistance to enable bidders from underrepresented groups (e.g. women owned businesses) to apply. During the last year the management transition from AGRA, and the Fund Manager KPMG, has been completed with management now residing in a single legal entity, AECF CLG (Company Limited by Guarantee), based in Nairobi, Kenya. This entity is now fully staffed and operational. Reporting on programme achievements in the last year though has largely been undertaken by the prior portfolio and fund managers, AGRA and KPMG, as they oversaw programme management through to May 2017.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="54060076" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
