<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41198890-PHL100581</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Phillipines - B-Ready II - humanitarian DIF</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">B-READY has now been tested in the Philippines, and has initial funding to be piloted in Sudan. To make the jump from &#x2018;pilot&#x2019; to &#x2018;preparing for scale&#x2019; B-READY needs to:
1.	Evidence the current B READY Model for iterative improvement, advocacy and impact: The project will cover 2 new locations in the Philippines, and continue in its current operational area to generate evidence including a Randomised Control Trial, to create iterative improvement, advocacy materials and build B-READY for adoption.
2.	Codification of the B READY Philippines and Global Scale Model includes mapping similar initiatives elsewhere for collaboration or learning, considering &#x2018;fertile&#x2019; areas for scale (financing, locations, actors, policy routes), choosing a strategic scale up trajectory based on lessons learned, and then a collaborative codification process linking the Philippines National Model, with a Global Scale Model and &#x2018;testing&#x2019; these with new funders and implementers to ensure greatest impact, cost-efficiency and ethical risk management.
3.	Building B READY for Sustainability at Scale by practically testing local and global sustainability pathways through government uptake (Philippines), private sector finance business models, global FbF, and pre-emptive financial tools/mechanisms currently under-discussion. Furthermore, there will be global advocacy, influencing and knowledge sharing, having B-READY and it&#x2019;s Scale Model featured in many appropriate forums, exposure visits, webinar presentations, socialisation workshops, targeted policy papers, and discussions with strategic actors to build new partners for adoption.

These three steps will enable the B-READY consortium to bring learnings from the previous pilots, codify the model to streamline for efficient scale, and build longer term sustainability across the Philippines and for future countries of implementation. Much of this work hasn&#x2019;t been possible to date through &#x2018;traditional&#x2019; funding that don&#x2019;t accept critical &#x2018;scaling&#x2019; activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUMMARY This is a one-year scale up project of an ongoing B-Ready project, in consortium with Oxfam Novib and Global Parametrics, funded by the Dutch Innovation Fund. The overall goal of the project is: Vulnerable Communities are better prepared to cope with the adverse effects of natural disasters through the Scale-up of B-READY. B-Ready empowers families with agency to prepare for disasters in ways that are suitable for them, whether that is evacuation, strengthening their home, or protecting livelihoods assets. B-READY saves resources, livelihoods and lives of vulnerable people by providing communities with the knowledge (forecasted impacts of disaster on their community), voice (co-defining triggers, HH to be supported), and the resources (cash) to reduce their vulnerability to disaster.  This project directly supports 4500 households or 22,500 people in 50 villages to reduce the effects of disasters, and increase their resilience.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since 1970, the number of annual disasters has more than quadrupled, with a current persistent funding gap of 40% of emergency appeals. Evidence in diverse contexts  shows that each Euro invested in preparedness saves four to seven Euros on response  and technological advances have improved our ability to predict disasters. Yet relief efforts remain predominately reactionary. The history of &#x2018;reactive&#x2019; disaster response, creates challenges for the humanitarian infrastructure to change the paradigm to proactive response.  

Vulnerable households globally, and in the Philippines, struggle to protect themselves from disasters. Vulnerability is determined by poverty, lack of information, and lack of resources: communities&#x2019; lack of disaster preparedness often stems from a lack of financial resources, and the inability to predict the impact of disasters.  

Specific challenges to pre-emptive action in the Philippines, includes:
&#x2022;	Lacking cost-efficient, scalable, and reliable methods to predict the specific local impacts of disasters. 
&#x2022;	Humanitarian finance built to respond post-disaster.
&#x2022;	A lack of effective, cost-efficient &amp; timely methods of supporting vulnerable people preparing for disasters. For example, the Philippines Government &#x2018;best practice&#x2019; of distributing food pre-disaster was noted by the disaster management official as &#x2018;not meeting the needs&#x2019; of people preparing for disaster .
&#x2022;	Central disaster predictions hampers communication, with timely post-disaster relief often delayed and inadequate. For example the high loss of life during Typhoon Haiyan was partly due to preparedness communication that provided a &#x2018;scripted text&#x2019; of a storm surge, rather than the real impact of an incoming tsunami .</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target groups for this solution are:
&#x2022;	Beneficiaries: This project will benefit 4,500 vulnerable households or 22,500 people in 50 villages in the Philippines. 60% of cash grants will be targeting women. Beneficiaries of the project will be vulnerable households defined by the Social Vulnerability Index (SoVI) including children, persons with disability, pregnant and lactating mothers, elderly, SOGIE (Sexual Orientation, Gender Identity and Expression), groups with low income, affected by conflict, or particularly exposed to hazards. Beneficiaries increase voice, agency, resources and knowledge to better prepare for disasters. 
&#x2022;	Local Governments will improve preparedness, disaster management, efficiency and transparency of disaster response with new forecasting technology showing local impacts, and the mechanisms established to disburse cash safely and quickly before a disaster strikes.
&#x2022;	CSOs gain capacity to keep governments to account for transparent, safe, and effective pre-emptive disaster response, aligned with humanitarian standards (for example through safeguarding scorecards, early action protocol participation).
&#x2022;	Local Financial Institutions support the transparent and efficient delivery of cash in communities and possible future pre-emptive financing products (insurance, remittances, loans, savings).
&#x2022;	National Government gain capacity to provide more effective, efficient and impactful preparedness programs through policy change, standards, financial oversight, and operational guidance for pre-emptive disaster action.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This programme is a readiness to scale programme of the 2020 B-ready pilot 

The Salcedo local government adopted B-READY in 2020, and is planning to use internal funds for future pre-emptive action. The mayor and governor are influencing other local and national government actors for B-READY adoption. For example the Philippines National Department of the Interior and Local Government (DILG) are issuing a resolution to ensure more local governments can benefit from pre-emptive action to disasters through their current government funding mechanism.

Economies of scale are evidenced in the parametric model. The concept of pre-emptive finance for social protection and preparedness, and its effective delivery once triggers are hit through local financial providers are proven. Other donors (e.g. ECHO) are already providing further funding. B-READY has won the SEED innovation competition, and is been promoted by UN Emergency Relief Coordinator as one of the top 3 innovative DRR projects globally.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To protect vulnerable households against disaster, B-READY provides knowledge of the local impact of the disaster, with cash grants, days before impact. This program combines three innovations: 
1. Impact-based disaster forecasting, 
2. Linking financial transfer technologies to social protection for pre-emptive action and 
3. A paradigm shift to pre-emptive response, aligning systems, policy and financing for greater overall disaster outcomes.

B-READY enables governments to predict the local impact of disasters, and provide pre-emptive cash to vulnerable families to save lives, alleviate suffering, and minimise economic losses. Families receive cash and know-how before a disaster, allowing them to effectively protect and prepare themselves and minimize the disaster impact.

Core components of the innovation are:
&#x2022;	Parametrics: provides a cost-efficient, objective, scalable, and reliable way to predict the impacts of disasters locally. 
&#x2022;	Locally owned action: Local actors respond pre-emptively to foreseen disaster impact, based on SOPs and impact thresholds defined together with communities.  
&#x2022;	Pre-emptive cash grants: Cash transfers are triggered based on &#x2018;impact thresholds&#x2019; through a digital local financial platform to provide a smart, efficient, transparent cash-grant, that provides families with the ability to prepare. 
&#x2022;	Sustainable pre-emptive finance: B-READY works on sustainable financing pathways for pre-emptive action that shifts available and growing (inter)national funding to pre-emptive action.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Until 2024 funding will be based on donors to support operational scale out across new contexts, and pre-emptive public/private sector financial scale models (there are 4 proposals developed).

After 5-7 years the project will plan to utilise sustainable funding models it is currently testing including:
1.	Country Government pre-emptive/DRR funding utilised for B-READY &#x2013; currently testing in the Philippines &#x2013; Likely.
2.	New pre-emptive/DRR financial instruments (e.g. guarantee fund) functioning at a global level &#x2013; joining current advocacy &#x2013; Likely, but size unknown.
3.	Delivery of private sector pre-emptive finance models (loans, insurance, savings, remittance transfer) &#x2013; currently evidencing in partnership with finance companies &#x2013; Moderate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="PH-SEC-FN200903004" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Philippines</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IATI contact</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>iati@plannederland.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1072 AC</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">60</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stadhouderskade</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief co-ordination; protection and support services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLANNL-D" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection and Assistance in Emergencies (Disaster Risk Management)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLAN AOGD 6" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">THRIVE - Protection</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-04-01">181797</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-04-01">20450</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-04-30">223827</value>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-02">134296</value>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-14">67951</value>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-04-29">181797</value>
   <receiver-org ref="PH-SEC-FN200903004" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Philippines</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB1483">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-09">109078</value>
   <receiver-org ref="PH-SEC-FN200903004" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Philippines</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0870 31-08-2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-31">4410</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0870 30-09-2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-30">3850</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Phillipines - B-Ready II - humanitarian DIF:  ()">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-10-31">7280</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Phillipines - B-Ready II - humanitarian DIF:  ()">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-30">1470</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Phillipines - B-Ready II - humanitarian DIF:  ()">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">2380</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0870 31-01-2022">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-31">490</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0870 28-02-2022">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-02-28">840</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0870 31-03-2022">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-31">1190</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41198890-PHL100534" type="3"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conditional and unrestricted cash</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: Multi-Purpose Cash</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people benefitting from conditional and unrestricted cash</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: Multi-Purpose Cash</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="CSH-I2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people benefitting from conditional and unrestricted cash</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="560.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </target>
     <target value="440.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="480.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">480 male headed households receive pre-emptive cash anticipating on Typhoon Rai.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
     <actual value="511.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">511 female-headed households out of 560 listed household participants received pre-emptive cash in preparation for Typhoon Rai (5pp per hh)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hazard, risk analysis and early warning</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: disaster risk reduction</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people covered by a functional early warning system</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: disaster risk reduction</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DRR-I3" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people covered by a functional early warning system</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3079.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">community members</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3079.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Salcedo - 10 villages (1,229 project participants validated) / Cotabato &#x2013; 10 villages are covered by the functional early warning system</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community and local level action</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: disaster risk reduction</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people participating in interventions that enhance their capacity to face shocks and stresses</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: disaster risk reduction</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DRR-I1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people participating in interventions that enhance their capacity to face shocks and stresses</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1250.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </target>
     <target value="1250.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </target>
     <target value="1250.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </target>
     <target value="1250.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="1238.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="1238.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="1238.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="1238.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Information, communication and public awareness</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: disaster risk reduction</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people reached through Information, Education and Communication on DRR</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: disaster risk reduction</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DRR-I2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people reached through Information, Education and Communication on DRR</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pre-emptive disaster response scale-up in 50 villages (10 in Salcedo, 10 in Oras, and 30 in Cotabato)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="129.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; 15 participants (7 women; 8 men) were trained on LMMMS                      
 &#x2022; 17 (13 women; 4 men) participants were trained by Paymaya as Money-In Money-Out (MIMO) merchants where project participants can claim cash within their barangays.
&#x2022;76 parents (54 women and 22 women) were trained and currently implementing Community Savings as part of their disaster preparedness.
    &#x2022; 21 participants (9 women; 12 men) attended the training on the development of Parametric Model for the municipality of Oras and was conducted with Global Parametrics</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Performance Plan Nederland as a development organisation</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender score of the program design and activities (scale 0-4)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0=Not measured; 1=Gender unaware; 2=Gender Neutral; 3=Gender Aware; 4=Gender Transformative. For measurement of KPI-6: Percentage of running programme activities that are gender-aware or gender-transformative</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.06" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="3.00" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender score of the program design and activities (scale 0-4)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <location ref="Phillipines"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of girls reached (under 18)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect beneficiaries</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.03" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of boys reached (under 18)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect beneficiaries</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.04" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young men (age 18-24) reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect reach of young men</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.08" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young women (age 18-24) reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect reach of young women</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.07" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Gender with Age Marker (IASC GAM)- design</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For humanitarian projects up to 12 months Plan International Netherlands uses the gender with age marker of IASC (https://www.iascgenderwithagemarker.com). 
1 = key programme actions do not address gender or age differences
2=  addresses only age differences 
3= addresses only gender differences 
4 = addresses gender &amp; age differences</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.14" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Gender with Age Marker (IASC GAM) - monitoring</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For humanitarian projects up to 12 months Plan International Netherlands uses the gender with age marker of IASC (https://www.iascgenderwithagemarker.com). 
1 = key programme actions do not address gender or age differences
2=  addresses only age differences 
3= addresses only gender differences 
4 = addresses gender &amp; age differences</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.15" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Gender with Age Marker (IASC GAM) - evaluation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">For humanitarian projects up to 12 months Plan International Netherlands uses the gender with age marker of IASC (https://www.iascgenderwithagemarker.com). 
1 = key programme actions do not address gender or age differences
2=  addresses only age differences 
3= addresses only gender differences 
4 = addresses gender &amp; age differences</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.16" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender transformative marker - implementation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scoring of the implementation phase by the gender transformative marker of Plan International; 
gender blind (1), gender neutral (2), gender aware (3), gender transformative (4)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.12" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender transformative marker - design</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scoring of the project design by the gender transformative marker of Plan International; 
gender blind (1), gender neutral (2), gender aware (3), gender transformative (4)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.11" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender transformative marker - evaluation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scoring of the project evaluation by the gender transformative marker of Plan International; 
gender blind (1), gender neutral (2), gender aware (3), gender transformative (4)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.13" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child Safeguarding Measurement marker</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through this indicator Plan measures the safeguarding measures taken at the start of the project. 
1 = no measure,  2 = protocol in place, 3= protocol &amp; risk assessment in place, 4= protocol &amp;  risk assessment &amp; management plan in place</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.17" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Potential reach from influencing-  number of persons</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0000.09" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Potential reach from influencing- number of girls (0-18 years)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0000.10" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
