<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41198890-MOZ100106</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cabo Delgado Joint Response 2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In order to ensure the sustainability of the action the following key barriers will be addressed: 
Physical &amp; infrastructural: Safe and accessible CFSs. 
Protection: Conducting child-centred risk mapping and ensuring Meaningful Child Participation. 
Social &amp; gender: Addressing discrimination due to gender, IDP status, disability and age through community sensitization. 
Institutional: Working with key stakeholders and community structures to ensure zero tolerance towards discriminatory practices such as: denying access; segregation; inequitable resource allocation; sexual or physical violence. 
Financial: Providing CFSs with learning and playing materials appropriate for children of different ages and abilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan has been responding to the crisis in Nampula since July 2020, with a dedicated humanitarian response team. In Cabo Delgado, Plan has an established satellite office focusing on Protection, WASH, EiE &amp; FSL response.

Protection activities will draw on resources and expertise from across Mozambique and broader Plan federation. CPiE activities will start immediately by conducting a rapid gender analysis, assessing the needs, risks and existing resources. Training of key community members, local authority representatives and DRA members will start within a month. Distribution of MHM items will take place following one month lead time for procurement. Plan will leverage existing partnerships with producers for quick and efficient delivery of kits and CFS equipment.

Capacity building, awareness-raising, and coordination will be ongoing from month 1 with CFS, PSS &amp; case management activities in place by month 2 to allow time to train community volunteers, procure equipment and outreach.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan will provide CPiE for 5,000 children (2400 boys, 2600 girls). Among the IDPs Plan will focus particularly on girls &amp; boys at high risk, UASC, adolescent girls &amp; children with disabilities. There haven&#x2019;t been reports of tensions between IDPs and host communities. However, to ensure a conflict-sensitive approach, Plan targets both IDPs (75%) and host communities (25%).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUMMARY
The Cabo Delgado JR will be implemented through a consortium led by Plan and membered by CARE, Cordaid, Oxfam, SOS CV and Tearfund in addition to local implementing partners. This is a 6 month slow onset Acute Joint Response, starting from 14 May 2021, funded by MFA through the Dutch Relief Alliance with a budget of &#x20AC;3.000.000, proposing a multi-sector approach with holistic Shelter/NFIs, WASH, Food Security and Livelihoods (FSL), and Protection programs. The JR will be implemented in Cabo Delgado (Mozambique), being the province with the highest needs and will prioritise the following districts: Mecufi, Chiure, Metuge, Montepuez, and Ancuabe. The overarching objective of the JR is to provide 101,185 affected people with life-saving and life-sustaining goods and services committing itself to 3 strategic objectives set out in the Mozambique HRP 2021: to safe lives, to sustain lives, protection.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since October 2017, NSAGs have severely disrupted the lives of thousands of people in Cabo Delgado province, Mozambique. Multiple towns and villages were attacked throughout the last four years, in which people were brutally killed and their houses left looted or burned.  
Following the escalation of the conflict in 2020, displacement has surged rapidly. While the number of IDPs was still 110,000 in March 2020, in the same year at least 527,000 people were being displaced in October (45% children). From October 2020 onwards, the violence in Cabo Delgado intensified, resulting in the displacement  of 670,000 people by the end of 2020. 70% of the internally displaced people has found refuge with host families in Cabo Delgado, Niassa and Nampula provinces. The remaining 30% reside in settlements and collective shelters or are still searching for a place to shelter.  
The conflict has disrupted agricultural activity and livelihoods, protection risks for the most vulnerable people have risen and the situation is compounded by tropical storms Chalane and Eloise, which hit three provinces at the end of 2020 and beginning of 2021. 1.3 million people are now in desperate need of humanitarian assistance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To holistically support the most vulnerable and at-risk children, Plan will provide a comprehensive CPiE intervention targeting 5,000 children (2400 boys, 2600 girls), adhering to SPHERE and CP minimum standards by amongst others:

-Establishment of community-based CP mechanisms in 5 resettlement sites hosting IDPs: 5 Child Protection Committees and 175 community members. This includes training on CP issues as identified by community members or via protection monitoring, Child Safeguarding &amp;PSEA, and provision of IEC material.
-Capacity strengthening of formal CP system: District Services of Health Woman and Social Action, Assistance office of Family and minor victims of domestic violence and district attorney office.
-Identification, documentation and case management of 60 UASCs with family-based alternative care &amp; FTR referral.
-Safe, inclusive, age and gender sensitive daily activities to 400 children in 5 CFS, with structured and free play, life skills sessions for at risk adolescents, and parenting programs. PSS will be provided as a community-based approach and CFSs will be established in collaboration with the government, community leaders and other partners (CARE) in Chiure.
-MHM support to 1000 vulnerable adolescent girls</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To holistically support the most vulnerable and at-risk children, Plan will provide a comprehensive CPiE intervention targeting 5,000 children (2400 boys, 2600 girls), adhering to SPHERE and CP minimum standards by:

-Establishment of community-based CP mechanisms in 5 resettlement sites, hosting IDPs: 5 Child Protection Committees and 175 community members (10 CFS facilitators, 25 Case workers, 50 PSS animators, foster families, 20 teachers, 10 community leaders and 3 Child Clubs). This includes training on CP issues as identified by community members or via protection monitoring, Child Safeguarding &amp;PSEA, and provision of IEC material.
-Capacity strengthening of formal CP system: District Services of Health Woman and Social Action, Assistance office of Family and minor victims of domestic violence and district attorney office.
-Identification, documentation and case management of 60 UASCs, with family-based alternative care &amp; FTR referral.
-Establishing CP referral systems in 5 communities.
-Safe, inclusive, age and gender sensitive daily activities to 400 children in 5 CFS, with structured and free play, life skills sessions for at risk adolescents, and parenting programs. PSS will be provided as a community-based approach and CFSs will be established in collaboration with the government, community leaders and other partners (CARE) in Chiure.
-PFA and focused PSS and referral to specialized MHPSS
-Information on (child) protection, helplines and multi-sectoral assistance at 5 protection helpdesks and the 5 CFS.
-MHM support to 1000 vulnerable adolescent girls

CARE and Plan will jointly address protection issues with CARE focusing on GBV while Plan address CPiE.

Considering the sensitivity of protection activities, the limited background and capacity of local NGOs on protection interventions, and the importance of ensuring the respect of humanitarian principles, Do No Harm, confidentiality and data protection, for now, Plan will ensure direct implementation of CPiE activities.
Plan will work through its office in Chiure, ensuring a rapid response, and receiving extra support through the Pemba office. The delivery model is based on service provision and in-kind support, drawing
from Plan&#x2019;s experience in CD since 2020. To enhance acceptability and sustainability of the intervention, Plan will closely coordinate with Provincial and district government and particularly with the CP District Reference Group in monitoring, supervision and strengthening of staff capacity and CP systems. The project will also work through community CP structures to ensure wider impact, scale, and sustainability: hereby enabling a participatory community-based approach.

Among the IDPs Plan will focus particularly on girls and boys at high risk, UASC, adolescent girls and children with disabilities, striving to address the following key barriers: Physical &amp; infrastructural Safe and accessible CFSs. Protection Conducting child-centred risk mapping and ensuring Meaningful Child Participation. Social &amp; gender Addressing discrimination due to gender, IDP status, disability and age through community sensitization. Institutional Working with key stakeholders and community structures to ensure zero tolerance towards discriminatory practices such as: denying access; segregation; inequitable resource allocation; sexual or physical violence. Financial Providing CFSs with learning and playing materials appropriate for children of different ages and abilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Mozambique</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-13" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-13" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IATI contact</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>iati@plannederland.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1072 AC</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">60</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stadhouderskade</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Focus on 5 districts within Cabo Delgado Province.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="25" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="75" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief co-ordination; protection and support services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLANNL-D" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection and Assistance in Emergencies (Disaster Risk Management)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLAN AOGD 6" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">THRIVE - Protection</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-11-13"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-14">25994</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-11-13"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-14">32506</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-15"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-14">415974</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-01">415974</value>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Mozambique</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB1474">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-31">357175</value>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Mozambique</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB1475">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-31">38000</value>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Mozambique</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2021-06-30T00:00:00.000">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-30">1995</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0873 31-07-2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-07-31">840</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0873 31-08-2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-31">945</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0873 30-09-2021">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-30">3850</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Cabo Delgado Joint Response 2021:  ()">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-10-31">547</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Cabo Delgado Joint Response 2021:  ()">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-10-31">630</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Cabo Delgado Joint Response 2021:  ()">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-30">17685</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Cabo Delgado Joint Response 2021:  ()">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-30">32500</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Cabo Delgado Joint Response 2021:  ()">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">280</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0873 31-01-2022">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-31">-11000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0874 31-01-2022">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-31">-32500</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0873 28-02-2022">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-02-28">-1551</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41198890-Cabo Delgado Joint Response 2021" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participation</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: accountability</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of crisis-affected people who are also involved in the design, implementation, montoring and/or evaluation of the programme</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humaniration support: accountability</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="ACC-I1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child protection</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: protection</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of children that received support specified to their needs</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: protection</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="PRO-I15" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of children that received support specified to their needs</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-13"></period-end>
     <target value="1625.00">
      <location ref="Chiure, Cabo Delgado"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; Case management services for (#?), other than UASC, especially Sexual and gender-based violence (SGBV), in IDP and host communities, including linking with- and strengthening of existing social services present in the district
&#x2022; Provision of group activities for child well-being, including PSS and PFA, in 5 Child Friendly Spaces (CFS) and by community based MHPSS structures 
&#x2022; Provision of MHM kits for 1000 (or 1500?) vulnerable girls and young women (IDPs &amp; host communities)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2382.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-13"></period-end>
     <target value="875.00">
      <location ref="Chiure, Cabo Delgado"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; Case management services for (#?), other than UASC, especially Sexual and gender-based violence (SGBV), in IDP and host communities, including linking with- and strengthening of existing social services present in the district
&#x2022; Provision of group activities for child well-being, including PSS and PFA, in 5 Child Friendly Spaces (CFS) and by community based MHPSS structures 
&#x2022; Provision of MHM kits for 1000 (or 1500?) vulnerable girls and young women (IDPs &amp; host communities)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1588.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity building (Protection)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: protection</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants showing an increased knowledge on the protection subject in focus</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: capacity building in protection</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="PRO-I6" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants showing an increased knowledge on the protection subject in focus</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-13"></period-end>
     <target value="125.00">
      <location ref="Chiure, Cabo Delgado"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; Capacity building of 10 CFS facilitators and 50 PSS animators on Child Protection, psychosocial support, incl PFA, Child Safeguarding, PSEA &amp; GBV                                                                                                                                                                                                        &#x2022; Capacity building of 25 Case workers on Child Protection, case management, Child Safeguarding, PSEA and GBV                                               
&#x2022; Capacity building of (#?) foster family members 
&#x2022; Capacity building of members of 5 IDPs Child Protection Committees on Child Protection, Child Safeguarding, PSEA and GBV, including provision of C-19 prevention kits
&#x2022; Training of 20 teachers in CP and provision of PSS and disability inclusion
&#x2022; Parenting sessions for 50 parents/caregivers on wellbeing, coping and recovery                                                                                                                                                                    
&#x2022; Capacity building of (#?) members of community-based MHPSS structures 
&#x2022; Training of SDSMAS professionals on MHPSS for children and adolescents</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="92.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-13"></period-end>
     <target value="75.00">
      <location ref="Chiure, Cabo Delgado"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; Capacity building of 10 CFS facilitators and 50 PSS animators on Child Protection, psychosocial support, incl PFA, Child Safeguarding, PSEA &amp; GBV                                                                                                                                                                                                        &#x2022; Capacity building of 25 Case workers on Child Protection, case management, Child Safeguarding, PSEA and GBV                                               
&#x2022; Capacity building of (#?) foster family members 
&#x2022; Capacity building of members of 5 IDPs Child Protection Committees on Child Protection, Child Safeguarding, PSEA and GBV, including provision of C-19 prevention kits
&#x2022; Training of 20 teachers in CP and provision of PSS and disability inclusion
&#x2022; Parenting sessions for 50 parents/caregivers on wellbeing, coping and recovery                                                                                                                                                                    
&#x2022; Capacity building of (#?) members of community-based MHPSS structures 
&#x2022; Training of SDSMAS professionals on MHPSS for children and adolescents</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="98.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-13"></period-end>
     <target value="0.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="37.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-13"></period-end>
     <target value="0.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="45.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection information dissemination</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: protection</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of persons with increased/appropriate information on relevant rights and/or entitlements</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: protection</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="PRO-I5" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of persons with increased/appropriate information on relevant rights and/or entitlements</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-13"></period-end>
     <target value="1600.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Awareness raising to children, adolescents, parents and other community members on CP concerns, Child Protection and psychosocial well-being, as well as MHM, through community-led sessions, in schools, at CFSs, Helpdesks and using community radio.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2725.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-13"></period-end>
     <target value="1150.00">
      <location ref="Chiure, Cabo Delgado"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="1879.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-13"></period-end>
     <target value="1170.00">
      <location ref="Chiure, Cabo Delgado"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Awareness raising to children, adolescents, parents and other community members on CP concerns, Child Protection and psychosocial well-being, as well as MHM, through community-led sessions, in schools, at CFSs, Helpdesks and using community radio.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="482.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-13"></period-end>
     <target value="1080.00">
      <location ref="Chiure, Cabo Delgado"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Awareness raising to children, adolescents, parents and other community members on CP concerns, Child Protection and psychosocial well-being, as well as MHM, through community-led sessions, in schools, at CFSs, Helpdesks and using community radio.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="332.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to separated/unaccompanied children</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: protection</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of unaccompanied and/or separated children who are reunited with their caregivers OR in appropriate protective care arrangements based on BIA</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: protection</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="PRO-I8" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of unaccompanied and/or separated children who are reunited with their caregivers OR in appropriate protective care arrangements based on BIA</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-13"></period-end>
     <target value="31.00">
      <location ref="Chiure, Cabo Delgado"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unaccompanied and separated children (UASC) services including identification and case management, linkages with agencies for Family Tracing and Reunification (FTR) and provision of family-based alternative care, including support to informal foster families.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="72.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-13"></period-end>
     <target value="29.00">
      <location ref="Chiure, Cabo Delgado"></location>
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unaccompanied and separated children (UASC) services including identification and case management, linkages with agencies for Family Tracing and Reunification (FTR) and provision of family-based alternative care, including support to informal foster families.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="50.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tracing and reunification</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of persons separated from their family who have re-established and maintained contacts AND/OR have been reunified with their families</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="PRO-I14" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of persons separated from their family who have re-established and maintained contacts AND/OR have been reunified with their families</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-13"></period-end>
     <target value="0.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Performance Plan Nederland as a development organisation</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender score of the program design and activities (scale 0-4)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0=Not measured; 1=Gender unaware; 2=Gender Neutral; 3=Gender Aware; 4=Gender Transformative. For measurement of KPI-6: Percentage of running programme activities that are gender-aware or gender-transformative</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.06" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender score of the program design and activities (scale 0-4)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-13"></period-end>
     <target value="4.00"></target>
     <actual value="3.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of girls reached (under 18)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect beneficiaries</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.03" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of boys reached (under 18)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect beneficiaries</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.04" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young men (age 18-24) reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect reach of young men</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.08" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young women (age 18-24) reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect reach of young women</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.07" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
