<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41198890-BFA100414</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burkina Faso Joint Response - Joint Budget C-19</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burkina Faso is experiencing an unprecedented humanitarian crisis that left 1.5m people requiring urgent assistance (HRP, July 2019). Circa 490,000 people have been uprooted from their homes as of 8 October, an increase of 68% since 23 September (OCHA,  Oct 2019). Plan&apos;s chosen area of intervention - the Centre-Nord - is the region grappling with the largest influx of IDP; as of 8 October, the Bam province hosts 46,872 IDP, the province of Namentenga, 27,195 IDP and the province of Sanmatenga &#x2013; the most affected, 169,409 IDPs, which represents respectively a 758%, 176% and 88% increase in two weeks (idem).

The precarious security situation in Centre-North is putting additional pressure on the already depleted resources of host communities. It has crippled Education services with 145 primary schools closed, depriving 26,266 children from their right to education (Ministry of Education, Oct 2019). It has exacerbated protection needs and constraints, with 151 cases of human rights violation registered in the Centre-North (67%) and Sahel (33%), including 45 assassinations, 10 cases of physical abuse, 4 of child abuse and 8 of sexual abuse and rape (UNCHR, Sept 2019). The Global Child Protection Area of Responsibility has highlighted abuse, exploitation, child recruitment by armed groups and physically endangerment as additional risks posed to children due to the crisis. As of June 2019, half of the IDP children are estimated to be in need of Psychosocial Support. As of 6 September, out of the 244 cases of UASC identified, 85 (43 girls) had not been reunited with their families (CPiE Sectoral Group, Sept 2019). Other CP issues identified with the potential of being aggravated by the crisis include concerns of child labour, child trafficking, out of school children and early and forced marriage as confirmed in Plan&apos;s NA. Thus, Plan will address the urgent needs limiting children and adolescents to enjoy their right to Education and Protection in this complex emergency.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUMMARY: The Burkina Faso JR will be implemented through a consortium led by Plan and membered by Cordaid, Save the Children, Stichting Vluchteling and Terre Des Hommes in addition to local implementing partners. The joint budget is allocated by the Burkina Faso Joint Response partners and set aside to facilitate regional meetings (including learning), capacity building of partners, travel and security costs as well as the salary of the Burkina Faso Joint Response Field Coordinator supporting the Joint Response as a whole. The budget is managed by Plan International, in its role as BF JR lead, but budget utilisation is subject to agreements within the consortium. So-called action plans are defined by the BF JR members during the BFJR kick-off workshop indicating, on headlines, utilisation of the joint budget. The joint budget supports the BF JR programme and project activities throughout the project duration of 6 months started on Dec 1st 2019.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The DRA partners have designed their response based on needs and gaps in line with cluster recommendations, their technical expertise and complementarity with other interventions to maximize impact. 

Protection
The Burkina Faso JR aims to provide access to quality Child and GBV protection services for the prevention and response to violence, abuse, neglect and exploitation for Girls and boys (0-12 years), adolescents (13-17 years) and young women and men (18-24 years)  affected by the humanitarian crisis in Kaya (Sanmatenga Province), Bouroum (Namentenga Province) and Yalgo, Tikare &amp; Sabce (in Bam province), the Centre-North region as well as in Titao Health District of Loroum province, Nord region.  
More specifically, the BFJR will respond to priority unmet CP needs of internally displaced children, youth and their families with Mobile Child Friendly Spaces (CFS) and Youth Friendly Spaces (YFS) set up as per SPHERE and Cluster standards. 

Education
The BFJR will support education activities in Kaya, Yalgo, Pissila and Kongoussi in the Provinces of Sanmatenga, Namentenga and Bam, Centre-North region. Teachers and community volunteers will be recruited and trained to facilitate numeracy and literacy classes for children aged 6-12. These children will be supported with age appropriate numeracy and literacy sessions in 6 Temporary Learning Spaces (TLS) in order for girls and boys to access safe, quality non-formal learning opportunities. Where possible, children will be referred to Plan International&apos;s formal EiE projects to ensure reintegration of children in schools. Moreover, primary school age children affected by conflict will be supported with school supplies to support their access and retention in school.
The Education component of this response is closely tight into the protection activities with the unified goal of ensuring children and adolescents can survive, thrive, learn and be protected during this emergency. 

Health
The BFJR will provide an integrated Health and Protection response in Titao Health District where social and health services are mainly closed due to the high influx of arriving IDP&#x2019;s and the low presence of other health actors (especially on primary and maternal health care, SGBV treatment and case management). The BFJR will provide free access to primary and maternal health care (including treatment for SGBV victims) in 4 mobile clinics and 4 reopened health care facilities (HCF).

WASH
The BFJR will respond to critical WASH needs by providing water and hygiene promotion to lower the risks of waterborne illness and provide life-saving access to water. Activities will be implemented in the towns of Titao and Ouindigui, loroum province, Nord region as well as Djibo, Soum Province, and Dori, S&#xE9;no Province in Sahel region.
In Djibo and Dori (Sahel region) a total of 7 boreholes and 2 solar water pumps for 2 boreholes will be installed providing safe dirnking water to 4200 people and in total 14700 people will receive hygiene kits as part of community hygiene promotion activities.
In Nord region the BFJR will rehabilitate 5 handpumps and 4 solar waterstations (each installed with 8 taps) to provide safe drinking water to 10500 people. Moreover, hygiene kits will be provided as well as WASH kits (household essential articles) to secure water collection and storage to 500 most vulnerable households. Protection will be integrated through the provision of Menstrual Hygiene Management kits to 400 vulnerable women/girls as part of community hygiene promotion activities. 

FSL
The BFJR will support affected displaced and host communities through gender and age sensitive life-saving food livelihood interventions in Djibo, Soum Province, and Dori, S&#xE9;no Province in Sahel region through the distribution of food vouchers for 3 meals per day and 5 food groups, during 3 months. 

MPC
The BFJR will support 2580 people in 430 vulnerable households (HHs) in Kongoussi, Tikar&#xE9; and Sabc&#xE9;, Bam province (Centre Nord) to meet their food needs through unconditional cash transfers</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This response will ensure all vulnerable groups are reached including children and youth, unaccompanied and separated minors, CAFAAGS, GBV survivors, women and girls at risk of sexual exploitation and trafficking, vulnerable indigenous, pregnant and lactating women, elderly and persons with disabilities.		

IDPs are the most vulnerable population, in particular young girls and women who in some cases engage in prostitution as the only means to respond to their basic needs.  SRH and GBV prevention and response activities will be accessible to both displaced persons and vulnerable host community members in rural and urban areas. Due to the higher exposure to GBV risks and needs of SRH women and girls will be specifically targeted. SRH activity will focus on pregnant and lactating women. Most vulnerable people will be identified in collaboration with community members and local authorities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Burkina Faso</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IATI contact</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>iati@plannederland.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1072 AC</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">60</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stadhouderskade</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="44" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="56" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief co-ordination; protection and support services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLANNL-D" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection and Assistance in Emergencies (Disaster Risk Management)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLAN AOGD 6" significance="1" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">THRIVE - Protection</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-01-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-01">36500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-01-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-01">90246</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-09">25876</value>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-04-04">78019</value>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Burkina Faso</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB1082">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-05-31">24582</value>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Burkina Faso</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB1083">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-05-31">50485</value>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Burkina Faso</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-19">90246</value>
   <receiver-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2020-02-29T00:00:00.000">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-29">1080</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2020-04-30T00:00:00.000">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-04-30">647</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2020-09-30T00:00:00.000">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-30">65000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="kosten oktober 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-10-31">-32500</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2021-05-31T00:00:00.000">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-31">-27418</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41198890-BFJR" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
