<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41198890-ZMB100159</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sanitation in Peri Urban Areas in Zambia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.	During the inception phase quick scan on market will be performed to define the potential and the willingness of people to invest in sanitation services.
2.	 A quick stakeholder mapping and coalition building will be done. 
3.	A baseline to determine the different income groups  the program focuses at. 


4. 	Identify and train leaders to stimulate demand for improved sanitation services 
7.	Integrate awareness, technical options and financing means will be integrated into one sanitation marketing approach 
8.	(Re-)establish local savings(VSLA) groups
Financing mechanisms: 
9.	Assessment functioning existing MFIs; indicate need for technical support
10.	Link MFI&#x2019;s with VSLA groups (if needed)
	 
11	Introduction of new MFI&#x2019;s in Kabwe
13.	Re-organizing Guarantee Funds

14.	Assessment Community Based Enterprises; indicate need for support
15
16.	Introduce new low cost technics, training on low-cost technics, support low-cost designs etc.
17.	Introduce Business Support Trajectory (training &amp; support concept used in other WASTE countries)

18.	Assessment involvement local council, indicate need for support
19.	Assessment functioning local consultants, indicate need for support
20.	Activities depend on assessments
21.	Monitor project activities (All)
22.	Evaluation, also comparing the results achieved since the baseline

23.	Training material capitalizing on the experience of  SPA program
24.	Working paper specifically about the challenge of targeting the poor, lessons learnt</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1020 poor peri-urban households (6,120 people). The project will pay special attention to the differences between men, women, boys and girls, such as in their needs, ability and willingness to pay, access to finance options.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F The establishment and strengthening of small enterprises (construction and pit-emptying) will create an supportive enabling environment for financial sustainability.
I First, investing in strengthening the commitment and ownership of government entities will increase the institutional sustainability. Second,  making use of and strengthening local expertise  TA support to stakeholders will increase the financial sustainability of the program and make it less dependent on grants. The introduction of new low cost sanitation options will make community based organizations more competitive.  make the project tgrants .
E the concerns are:
1.	Groundwater pollution due to faecal in the two communities. Field water sampling tests by the Health Centre staff using Hydrogen Sulphide (H2S); and 
2.	Groundwater pollution due to Zinc mining and this is the major pollutant ranked the highest in the world.  
The measures the project has put in place from inception is the promoting ecological sanitation facilities in areas with high water table like Nakoli and parts of Katondo. This is a component that WASTE Zambia is managing. There is demand for ecosan toilet because people have been sensitised and are aware of polluting groundwater.  
T Technical sustainability will be ensured by construction of  sustainable toilet facilities using simple technologies that can be locally maintained. Spareparts are locally available. 
S Focus on not only poor households but also on vulnerable groups like poor women and disabled, will make the project inclusive.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUMMARY 
In Zambia open defecation is common in urban areas, especially in informal settlements. Access to sewerage there is low. As a result, the great majority of urban residents use on-site sanitation systems and the management of faecal sludge is a growing challenge.  
Plan Zambia and WASTE Zambia want to establish sustainable sanitation service systems, including the construction of applicable and sustainable toilet facilities, the establishment and strengthening of small enterprises and creating an supportive enabling environment in financial, administrative and technical perspective.
The beneficiaries are 1,020 poor peri-urban households (6,120 people) living in Kabwe Municipal Council. The project has started 1 August 2018 as an extension of preliminary programs and started with an inception phase. During the inception phase assessments were performed to find out if people were willing to invest and able to make informed choices.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Sanitation in Peri-urban Areas in Africa (SPA) program was implemented by Plan and WASTE in Benin, Ethiopia, Malawi, Kenya and Zambia between 2008-2015. In Zambia the program started in 2011 and ran till mid-2014 in 3 cities. The goal was to support local stakeholders of the sanitation value chain  (with the development of an inclusive and sustainable sanitation system for households in low-income areas in Kabwe, Ndola and Siavonga. 
The project yielded good results, and it was found worthwhile to further develop and improve the diamond model.
 The actual program focuses on behavior change and further strengthening of the Diamond business model with more focus on lower income households in peri urban areas in Central Zambia (Kabwe Municipality), and define how it can provide sustainable sanitation services focused on the poor. It requires a lot of time and effort to motivate people to change behaviour and prioritise investing in a sanitation facilities. The development of adequate financial mechanisms, which are accessible for  low income households, has been challenging and still needs further improvement. Awareness, technology and financing need to be better attuned to achieve better results and enhance demand and better chances for upscaling.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The general objective of the project is the establishment of sustainable sanitation service systems which includes the construction of applicable and sustainable toilet facilities, the establishment and strengthening of small enterprises (construction and pit-emptying) and creating a supportive enabling environment in financial, administrative and technical perspective. The strength of the intervention lies in the complementary cooperation between WASTE and Plan Zambia. WASTE will focus on the strengthening of the financial instruments that enable affordable sanitation services for the poor while stimulating their self-reliance when installing toilets. 
WASTE will also strengthen the sanitation marketing of pro-poor services and products that matches the needs and purchasing power of poor households.
Plan Zambia will focus on demand creation and behaviour change. By the end of the project, the vision is to have influenced in a positive way the behaviour and attitude of the people living in Kabwe Municipal Council and that they have moved up the sanitation and hygiene ladder. Only then, people are willing to invest in household sanitation services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The previous SPA program (2008-2015) and the recommendations of the external evaluation, formed the fundament under this SPAII program. The program focused on linking demand to supply and to local funding, establishing agreements on loan and credit schemes between financiers, entrepreneurs and clients (end-users). MoUs were signed between the local government, local funders, clients and small scale businesses describing each role, responsibilities and tasks. The project also has been funded by the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs and was implemented in 5 countries, including Zambia. In Zambia important local players were Ministry of Health, district councils, Harvest Help Zambia (training entrepreneurs) and CetZam, a MFI. One of the conclusions of the end evaluation was that there was no attention for demand creation and therefore Plan Zambia has been involved in the new project. This project is only implemented in Zambia, in Kabwe municipality. Actually no MFI has been involved yet. Stakeholders that are involved are Lukanga Water and Sewerage Company, Kabwe Municipal Country, government line ministries and  Community Based Enterprises.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="ZM-RNGO-10101472014" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Zambia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41172933" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Waste</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IATI contact</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>iati@plannederland.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1072 AC</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">60</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stadhouderskade</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="14022" percentage="40" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sanitation - large systems</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14050" percentage="60" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Waste management / disposal</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLAN AOGD 5" significance="1" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">THRIVE -Early Childhood Care and Development (including WASH) (ECCD)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLANNL-C" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water, Sanitation &amp; Hygiene</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-01">245328</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-01">94672</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-24">135000</value>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Netherlands</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-01">94672</value>
   <receiver-org ref="ZM-RNGO-10101472014" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Zambia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB807">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-30">50000</value>
   <receiver-org ref="ZM-RNGO-10101472014" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Zambia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB1288">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-21">44672</value>
   <receiver-org ref="ZM-RNGO-10101472014" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Zambia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0764: &#x20AC; 8.860,95 (31-8-18)">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-31">8861</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0764: &#x20AC; 2.931,25 (30-9-18)">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-30">2931</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0764: &#x20AC; 921,06 (31-12-18)">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">921</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0764: &#x20AC; 612,50 (31-1-19)">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-31">612</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0764: &#x20AC; 612,50 (27-2-19)">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-27">612</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0764: &#x20AC; 918,75 (31-3-19)">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">919</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0764: &#x20AC; 92.091,00 (30-4-19)">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">92091</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0764: &#x20AC; 1.093,61 (31-5-19)">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-31">1094</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0764: &#x20AC; 357,50 (30-6-19)">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">358</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0764: &#x20AC; 73.063,35 (31-7-19)">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-31">73063</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0764: &#x20AC; 1.111,98 (31-8-19)">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">1112</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0764: &#x20AC; 262,50 (31-10-19)">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">262</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0764: &#x20AC; 612,50 (30-11-19)">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-30">612</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="NLD0764: &#x20AC; 190,00 (31-12-19)">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">190</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2020-01-31T00:00:00.000">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-31">708</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2020-06-30T00:00:00.000">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-30">12000</value>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population is making progress towards the use of safely managed sanitation services</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is conducted in line with the sanitation ladder as defined by the Joint Monitoring Program by Unicef and WHO</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people (and % of people) who reach basic and/or safely managed service levels of sanitation of the JMP ladder</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benchmark for this sub-programme is &#x2026; [Limited / Basic / Safely Managed]</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="SDG_OC02" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5300.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased involvement of consumers in improving WASH conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of households that have invested in WASH facilities in their household or contributed user fees to WASH services during the last year</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Investment in WASH facilities includes both construction and operation &amp; maintenance</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="SDG_OC05" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of households that have invested in WASH facilities in their household or contributed user fees to WASH services during the last year</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1060.00"></target>
     <actual value="1020.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Performance Plan Nederland as a development organisation</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender score of the program design and activities (scale 0-4)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0=Not measured; 1=Gender unaware; 2=Gender Neutral; 3=Gender Aware; 4=Gender Transformative. For measurement of KPI-6: Percentage of running programme activities that are gender-aware or gender-transformative</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.6" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3.00"></target>
     <actual value="3.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of boys reached (under 18)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect beneficiaries</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.4" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1000.00"></target>
     <actual value="1096.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of girls reached (under 18)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect beneficiaries</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.3" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1300.00"></target>
     <actual value="1322.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young men (age 18-24) reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect reach of young men</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.8" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="110.00"></target>
     <actual value="108.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young women (age 18-24) reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect reach of young women</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.7" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="125.00"></target>
     <actual value="117.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Led Total Sanitation</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of new household latrines constucted by the communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Construction of latrines contributing to Open Defecation Free communities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0104.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1060.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people living in Open Defecation Free communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of Open Defecation Free community members</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0104.3" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5300.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity training for private sector</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of private sector businesses reached with capacity training</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specify capacity training</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="4000.1.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of private sector workers reached with capacity training</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specify capacity training</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="4000.1.3" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity training for service providers</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of service providers reached with capacity training</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specify capacity training</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5000.1.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.00"></target>
     <actual value="1.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operational support for service providers</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of drinking water companies/utilities reached with operational support</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH operational support</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5300.1.3" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of drinking water companies/utilities reached with operational support</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.00"></target>
     <actual value="1.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of service providers reached with operational support</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specify operational support</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5300.1.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
