<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41198890-YPI100016</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sulawesi Joint Response</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Given that this was a first phase emergency response, the priority for the action was to deliver aid to as many of the most vulnerable people as possible. Recognizing that disaster affects men, women and children differently, the project set vulnerability criteria that ensures inclusiveness. Among the criteria is female-headed and child headed families. This ensured that these groups were not marginalised during the distribution and were given assistance wherever possible.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 28 September 2018, an earthquake with magnitude 6.0SR occurred at 13.59 (UTC+7) followed by a 7.7SR (updated to M 7.4) earthquake at 17:02, causing damage and casualties in Palu City, and regencies of Donggala, Parigi Moutong, and Sigi in Sulawesi, Indonesia. This triggered a near-field tsunami which struck Talise beach in Palu City and beaches in Donggala and some settlements and buildings on the beach. Estimations from the National Disaster Management Authority (BNPB) suggest that in total around 2.4 million people were exposed to earthquake intensity V MMI and above in nine cities/regencies in Central Sulawesi (Banggai, Banggai Kepulauan, Donggala, Morowali, Palu, Parigi Moutong, Posos, Tojo Una-una, and Toli-toli)  616,684 people in Palu City, Donggala, and Sigi regencies were exposed to earthquake intensity VI and above. As of 10 December, the death toll was 2,101, with 1,373 people missing and over 130,000 displaced across Central Sulawesi, of which 109,000 were distributed among 431 sites . More than 65,000 houses were severely damaged or destroyed . The total cost of material damage was estimated at USD 910 million.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International proposes a 6-month emergency response project that aims to ensure earthquake affected girls, boys, and their families are supported with appropriate and timely humanitarian assistance in a safe, dignified and protective environment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUMMARY
Plan International Indonesia, &#x2018;Yayasan Plan International Indonesia (YPII)&#x2019; implements the DRA Sulawesi joint response with local partner &#x2018;Yakkum Emergency Unit&#x2019;. 
The program aims to support the earthquake and tsunami-affected girls and boys and their families with real time humanitarian assistance in a safe, dignified and protective environment. The objective is to 1) Meet the immediate emergency shelter needs of the most vulnerable affected communities, particularly families with moderate and severely damaged houses and 2) Create safe, inclusive, and stimulating Child-Friendly and Women and Adolescent Girl-Friendly Spaces in order to strengthen the protective environment for girls, boys and their caregivers.
This response reached 2,150 households in Palu, Sigi and Donggala District with shelter kits and hygiene kits. Later, phases in the emergency response allowed YPII to reach a total of 10,590 individuals through Shelter/NFI, WASH and CPiE activities over a course of 7 months.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter
The provision of shelter kits for families was done based on the rapid needs assessment conducted by ERT in first 2 weeks of the emergency. Plan International and partners ensured that the relief distribution was effective, timely and responded directly to the identified needs. Relief distribution targeted female and/or child headed households, low-income families with children under 5 years old, families with lactating or nursing mothers, families of persons with disability and caring for the elderly, as well as families not receiving assistance from other organisations and having limited access to services. These beneficiaries were selected based on the assessments, coordination with other organizations and discussions with the communities.

Protection
PLan International supported the rehabilitation/ repair of 6 static Child Friendly Spaces in the targeted areas which have been running CFS activities for 3,192 children (1845 girls and 1347 boys) in these villages. Plan International has furthermore conducted training on CFS management, Psychosocial First Aid and Psychosocial support for 90 CFS animators, of which 32 animators are supported by DRA funding. Prior to technical trainings, induction on child rights and protection, Plan safeguarding policy and gender-sensitive programming were also given to local animators to ensure the animators understand the standards when facilitating child sensitive activities at the CFS. The activities included awareness raising activities on child rights and protection, community organising and technical support for Village CP committee through Community-based Child Protection Mechanism (CBCPM), and menstrual hygiene promotion activities at the CFS participated by adolescent girls, adolescent boys, women and men in the neighbourhood.  Reproductive health and MHM awareness raising was done in 6 targeted communities. The people participated in the reproductive health and MHM sessions have been informed on key messages about hygienic practices (including menstrual hygiene), responsible sexual behaviours and Sexual Transmitted Infections. 
Menstrual Hygiene Management awareness raising was also participated by boys and men in ways to break the taboos and stigmas attached to menstruation. The stigma associated with menstruation has evidently led to an overall culture of silence around the topic in the project areas, resulting in limited information on menstruation and menstrual hygiene which generally affect sexual and reproductive health. Misinformation can have ramifications on the girls and women&#x2019;s dignity. 

In addition, Hygiene kits have been distributed to head of households with children under 18 years old supported by hygiene promotion on key messages on reproductive health and MHM aimed at male and female adolescents using interactive discussion methods to raise awareness of how to act positively and supportive towards teenage girls who are menstruating/experience menstruation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Rapid Needs Analysis has identified the different needs of the different groups in the affected populations, such as shelter, food, electricity, gas. Priorities will be given to the most vulnerable groups affected by earthquake and tsunami, including (1) households with severe and moderate damaged house; (2) households with babies and under-fives; (3) households with pregnant woman; (4) households with disability members; (5) woman-headed household; (6) child-headed household and elderly.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall WASH, shelter, health, protection and livelihoods needs remained significant throughout the crisis and the Joint Response activities have been in line with the directives coming from the Government of Indonesia (GoI). According to the most recent data released by the National Agency for Disaster Management (BNPB), as of January 2019, some 133,631 people remain displaced across Central Sulawesi. Of the thousands more who left the province or found refuge with host families, indications are that increasing numbers are returning to Central Sulawesi. The government-led response continued to focus on humanitarian needs during the transition phase, which was implemented up until 23rd February 2019. The Government of Indonesia&#x2019;s National Development Planning Agency, BAPPENAS, has been leading recovery planning with several related assessments underway and the development of the Master Plan for Reconstruction currently under consultation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project will be implemented within 6-month with the first month will be for the general setup, recruitment, and other logistical/administrative tasks to be done. The distribution of NFIs will be done as quickly possible by mobilising YPII prepositioned relief items at the Jakarta warehouse.
Setup and operation of Child Friendly Space and Adolescent/Women Friendly Space will be conducted by the fourth month after preparatory setups (recruitment, site selection, logistical preparation etc).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To fill the gaps in shelter and child protection in emergencies targeting two the most affected districts, Palu and Sigi. The project objectives are: (1) to meet immediate emergency shelter needs of the most vulnerable affected communities, particularly families with moderate and severely damaged houses; (2) to create a safe, inclusive, and stimulating Child-Friendly and Women and Adolescent Girl-Friendly Spaces in order to strengthen the protective environment for girls, boys, and their caregivers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-IDN041N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="ID-NJP-024100158053000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Indonesia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-16" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-16" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IATI contact</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>iati@plannederland.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1072 AC</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">60</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stadhouderskade</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="40" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="60" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief co-ordination; protection and support services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLANNL-D" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection and Assistance in Emergencies (Disaster Risk Management)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLAN AOGD 6" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">THRIVE - Protection</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-04-05"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-10-05">356410</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-21">336422</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-IDN041N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-28">38207</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-IDN041N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-10-05">356410</value>
   <receiver-org ref="ID-NJP-024100158053000" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Indonesia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB783">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-14">250000</value>
   <receiver-org ref="ID-NJP-024100158053000" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Indonesia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB1089">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-05-31">96879</value>
   <receiver-org ref="ID-NJP-024100158053000" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Indonesia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prevention and response to violence</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: protection</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of persons reached by the implementation of specific prevention measures</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 1080 children reported here are 100% overlap with indicator PRO-I15</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="PRO-I1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-05-16"></period-end>
     <target value="540.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="31.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This number of beneficiaries were reached through child friendly activities (both location-based and mobile) implemented by YEU in Sigi and Donggala. The recreational activities also include introduction to key topics to build children&apos;s self confidence and awareness of of themselves and their social interactions</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-04-04"></period-end>
     <target value="540.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">100% overlap with other CP activities/ indicators of this project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1845.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This number of beneficiaries were reached through child friendly activities (both location-based and mobile) implemented by YEU in Sigi and Donggala. The recreational activities also include introduction to key topics to build children&apos;s self confidence and awareness of of themselves and their social interactions</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-05-16"></period-end>
     <target value="540.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="1347.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This number of beneficiaries were reached through child friendly activities (both location-based and mobile) implemented by YEU in Sigi and Donggala. The recreational activities also include introduction to key topics to build children&apos;s self confidence and awareness of of themselves and their social interactions</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-05-16"></period-end>
     <target value="540.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="105.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child protection</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: protection</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of children that received support specified to their needs</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="PRO-I15" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-05-16"></period-end>
     <target value="540.00">
      <dimension name="Age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="femlae"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">stablish Child Friendly Spaces (CFS), either static or mobile, based on needs and availability, to provide a safe space for children and young people to access services including psychosocial support (PSS), psychological first aid (PFA), structured, recreational learning and social and creative activities. 
&#x2022; Provision of psychosocial support (PSS) and psychological first aid (PFA) to affected population of girls and boys including adolescents and youth by trained members of the community as well as staff.
&#x2022; Identification and referral of unaccompanied and separated children to available services including family tracing and reunification by trained staff and volunteers.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1845.00">
      <dimension name="Age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">100% overlap with othe CP activities under this project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-05-16"></period-end>
     <target value="540.00">
      <dimension name="SEX" value="male"></dimension>
      <dimension name="age" value="UNDER 18"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="1347.00">
      <dimension name="SEX" value="male"></dimension>
      <dimension name="age" value="UNDER 18"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Non-food items</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: shelter</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people provided with non-food items</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We will provide 2150 HH (estimated at 8600 individuals) with NFI items as part of the shelter/NFI kits. Therefore 100% overlap/double counting</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="SHL-I4" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-04-04"></period-end>
     <target value="2150.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="1966.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">These are 100% overlap with SHL-R1 (individual hh shelter)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-05-16"></period-end>
     <target value="2150.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="3139.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">These have 100% overlap with SHL-R! (individual shelter)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-05-16"></period-end>
     <target value="2150.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="3413.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">These have 100% overlap with SHL-R! (individual shelter)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-05-16"></period-end>
     <target value="2150.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="2072.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">These have 100% overlap with SHL-R! (individual shelter)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individual household shelter</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian support: shelter</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people having access to basic, safe and dignified shelters solutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We will provide 2150 HH (estimated at 8600 individuals) with shelter items as part of the shelter/NFI kits. 8</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="SHL-I1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-05-16"></period-end>
     <target value="2150.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="3139.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-05-16"></period-end>
     <target value="2150.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="3413.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="18+"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-05-16"></period-end>
     <target value="2150.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="female"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="1966.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="female"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="female"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-05-16"></period-end>
     <target value="2150.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="2072.00">
      <dimension name="age" value="under 18"></dimension>
      <dimension name="sex" value="male"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Performance Plan Nederland as a development organisation</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young women (age 18-24) reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0000.7" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-04-04"></period-end>
     <target value="2690.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young men (age 18-24) reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0000.8" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-04-04"></period-end>
     <target value="2690.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of boys reached (under 18)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0000.4" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-04-04"></period-end>
     <target value="2690.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">over all activities of this project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="225.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender score of the program design and activities (scale 0-4)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0000.6" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-04"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-04-04"></period-end>
     <target value="3.00"></target>
     <actual value="3.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of girls reached (under 18)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0000.3" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-04-04"></period-end>
     <target value="2690.00"></target>
     <actual value="342.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
