<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41198890-SDN100216</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Obligation to Protect (O2P) Sudan Agents of Change Unite against FGM/C Sudan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By changing social norms this project is driving a permanent change in the way people see FGM/C. Once social norms in a community change, that change is usually irreversible, meaning FGM/C prevalence rates will continue to drop after the project has ended.

By connecting and strengthening local organisations, youth groups and women&#x2019;s groups, the project is installing structures that will remain in place after its completion. These organisations are acting in networks to jointly influence change at government and national levels. Furthermore, By creating safe spaces for girls and young women, they will be able to discuss their problems and get the support they need to claim their rights.

The project is also strengthening the linkages between the various types of change makers. This will improve cooperation in stopping FGM/C and give girls and young women access to important actors at local, state/district and even national level.

Once they are adopted, specific legislation and policies on FGM/C will continue to be effective. By training parliamentarians and improving the relationship they have with the communities, these parliamentarians will get a better overview of how laws are implemented and the impact that the laws have. This, in turn, will have a structurally beneficial impact on girls and young women in those communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FGM/C is a violation of human rights and an extreme form of violence and discrimination against women. It involves the partial or total removal of the external female genitalia, or other types of injury to the female genital organs for non-medical reasons. It is viewed as a traditional practice, regardless of the fact it is very painful and risky for the health of girls and women. It can also cause many complications during menstruation, pregnancy and childbirth, and can even result in death.
FGM/C is practiced in its severest form in the White Nile State In Sudan, where its prevalence is over 80 per cent. About 22% of prenatal deaths in infants born to women with FGM/C can be attributed to it.
The practice still goes on because of traditional beliefs about controlling female sexuality, social pressure and the importance of initiation rites. It is mainly the girls&#x2019; grandmothers and religious figures that ensure the practice is continued. Males in the family are sometimes not even aware that it goes on.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUMMARY 
Female Genital Mutilation/Cutting (FGM/C), an extreme form of violence against girls, is rife in Sudan. This project, which is being carried out by Plan and its partner Association of European Parliamentarians with Africa (AWEPA), aims to eradicate this practice in Sudan within a generation. 
To underscore the kind of optimum outcomes that will be crucial for the permanent eradication of FGM/C, this project is being carried out at individual, community and institutional levels. It teaches communities about girls&#x2019; rights and that FGM/C is illegal. It also encourages local organisations like youth and women&#x2019;s groups to challenge norms and attitudes, and it supports parliamentarians in implementing effective legislation. The project, which started in January 2014 and will run till December 2017, is part of the O2P (Obligation to Protect) programme that&#x2019;s being implemented in Sudan, Egypt, Kenya and Ethiopia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Some 50,000 girls, 15,000 women, 45,000 boys and 20,000 men between the ages of 10 and 18 in White Nile State will benefit from this project. The girls have been identified by Plan as vulnerable to FGM/C. The boys are important because they are seen as the defenders and future guardians of the changed social norms and for the elimination of FGM/C.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands&apos; Embassy in Sudan supports the promotion and protection of human rights, giving priority to the defenders of human rights, and underscoring the freedom of the media and gender equality. The UNICEF/UNFPA  Joint Programme against FGM/C is strengthening the structure of the government at national and regional levels, while this project works at community level and targets groups that are not covered by the above-mentioned initiatives, namely: girls, boys, local organisations and parliamentarians. White Nile State is a region of Sudan in which FGM/C has not yet ben tackled by stakeholders, such as UNICEF, even though its practice there is alarmingly high.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project&#x2019;s activities are at three levels.

Individual level
- Trainers trained in 4 days on the Saleema manual and guidelines for 80 community promoters and change agents (grandmothers, midwives, religious leaders and village elders) in two workshops (for 48 participants from eight localities).
- 4 exchange visits  and 10 community members shown around model villages in which FGM/C has been stopped.
- Annual seminars  in eight localities to discuss FGM/C attended by 10 key community and tribal leaders and relevant local-level commissioners. 
-Sixteen girls&#x2019; clubs, youth clubs and other associations trained on FGM/C, child rights, drama and theatre communication and support these 80 participants to serve as community agents among their peers. 

Community level
- At national level six workshops for religious institutes, and at state level  four workshops for 300 persons.
- Two trainings on advocacy and policy analysis and legislation for 60 representatives from local organisations on women and children&#x2019;s rights, academics, and journalists.
-One training for 50 youth representatives on human rights frameworks on FGM/C, the role of children&#x2019;s parliament members and youth parliament at White Nile State level.
- Interaction on FGM/C between the children&#x2019;s parliament and the legislative council  during the International FGM/C eradication day celebration and the Zero Tolerance to Sexual and Gender Based Violence campaign at White Nile level. For 60 members of the children&#x2019;s parliament and 40 from the youth parliament. 

Institutional level
- A workshop for the National Council for Child Welfare (NCCW), being the legislative department of the Ministry of Justice and Women&#x2019;s Centre for Human rights for follow up commitments made in the international conference in the Great Lakes on Sexual and Gender Based Violence and the UN declaration on FGM/C. 
-Training on lobbying in legislative proces for (mainly female) parliamentarians and legislators at state and national levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To eliminate FGM/C, the social norms and values that fuel its continuation must be changed. Furthermore, legislation against FGM/C must be improved and enforced. Men and boys will have to lobby for this and girls must be empowered to stand up for their sexual and reproductive health rights, and supported in doing so too. Individuals and local organisations are being trained to act as human rights defenders, meaning the project is tackling FGM/C at individual, community and institutional levels.

In the context of this project:
- people, including girls, boys, local youth and women&#x2019;s groups are being empowered to oppose these violations and are being trained as human rights defenders;
- local development organisations, women groups and agents of change are lobbying to change the norms and values that justify and continue these harmful practices 
- the legal and protection systems of counties in Sudan are being strengthened and parliamentarians are being influenced.

All activities in the project are inter-connected. Individual and community initiatives are being supported by a legal framework and local organisations are playing a watchdog role in case of violations that have already happened or are about happen, and take the necessary actions against these violations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ahfad UNIVERSITY Babikir Badri Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child Rights Care Society  Sudan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Council of Child Welfare</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-OCHA-HPC8588" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Sudan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">the White Nile state Council of Child Welfare</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IATI contact</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>iati@plannederland.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1072 AC</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">60</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stadhouderskade</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ending violence against women and girls</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="PLAN AOGD 4" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DECIDE - Sexual and Reproductive Health and Rights (SRHR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLANNL-A" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection against violence (including gender based violence)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">380389</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-03-01">380389</value>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Netherlands</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">380389</value>
   <receiver-org ref="XM-OCHA-HPC8588" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB666">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-05-31">44000</value>
   <receiver-org ref="XM-OCHA-HPC8588" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB667">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-06-29">240000</value>
   <receiver-org ref="XM-OCHA-HPC8588" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB668">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-02-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-02-17">51521</value>
   <receiver-org ref="XM-OCHA-HPC8588" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB669">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-14">44868</value>
   <receiver-org ref="XM-OCHA-HPC8588" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41198890-NLD0610" type="3"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs deal with violations of rights of children and youth, including networks</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0314.2 Number of CSOs that deal with rights of children and youth.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0314.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">0314.2 Number of CSOs that deal with rights of children and youth.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50.00"></target>
     <actual value="50.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0314.3 Number of initiatives undertaken by CSOs or networks, related to rights of children and youth</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0314.3" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policy makers interact with children, youth or adults</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0651.1 Number of interactions between policy makers and children and youth (per type of policy maker)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0651.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">0651.1 Number of interactions between policy makers and children and youth (per type of policy maker)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="14.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policy makers know the rights of children and youth and are willing to act accordingly</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0652.1 Average assessment score policy makers on knowledge of rights of children and youth and willingness to act [Score 1-10]</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0652.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">0652.1 Average assessment score policy makers on knowledge of rights of children and youth and willingness to act [Score 1-10]</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rights training for communities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2200.1.1 Number of rights training for communities delivered (specify)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2200.1.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">2200.1.1 Number of rights training for communities delivered (specify)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5.00"></target>
     <actual value="5.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">also religious leaders trained</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rights training for CSOs</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3100.1.3 Number of CSO officials reached with rights training</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Rights Defenders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="3100.1.3" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">3100.1.3 Number of CSO officials reached with rights training</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="76.00"></target>
     <actual value="76.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rights training for policy makers</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6000.1.1 Number of rights trainings delivered to policy makers (specify)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="6000.1.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">6000.1.1 Number of rights trainings delivered to policy makers (specify)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Influencing policy makers</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6200.1.1 Number of advocacy initiatives for policy makers</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="6200.1.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">6200.1.1 Number of advocacy initiatives for policy makers</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6200.1.2 Number of lobby initiatives for policy makers</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="6200.1.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">6200.1.2 Number of lobby initiatives for policy makers</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Performance Plan Nederland as a development organisation</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of children and youth reached (m/f)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0000.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1061.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="6435.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender score of the program design and activities (0=Not measured; 1=Gender Blind; 2=Gender Neutral; 3=Gender Aware; 4=Gender Transformative)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0000.6" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community knowledge and attitudes enable children, youth or adults to claim their rights</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0252.3 Change of knowledge in community leaders regarding the rights of children and youth (specify)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0252.3" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">0252.3 Change of knowledge in community leaders regarding the rights of children and youth (specify)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="120.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0252.2 Number of opinion makers (community leaders) who have knowledge of violation of rights of children and youth (specify)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0252.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="134.00"></target>
     <actual value="134.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rights training for children, youth or adults</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1200.1.1 Number of rights trainings delivered to children, youth or adults</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1200.1.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">1200.1.1 Number of rights trainings delivered to children, youth or adults</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="25.00"></target>
     <actual value="25.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1200.1.2 Number of children, youth or adults who have participated in rights trainings</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1200.1.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5000.00"></target>
     <actual value="5189.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children, youth or adults influence decision making in families and communities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0112.1 Number of children and youth who state that their opinion counts in decision making processes in their families and communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0112.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0112.2 Number of children and youth who are involved in influencing others in their families and communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0112.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0112.3 Changes observed in the extent to which children and youth can advocate for themselves [scale 0-10]</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0112.3" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children, youth or adults act according to their rights</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0118.1 Percentage of children, youth or adults who act in line with the rights of children and youth</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0118.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0118.aa Contraceptive prevalence rate - modern methods</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0118.aa" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0118.ab Contraceptive prevalence rate - condom uses (adolescents 15-24; m/f)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0118.ab" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0118.ac Contraceptive prevalence rate - condom uses (young parents; m/f)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0118.ac" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Facilitation of linking and learning between policy makers</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6400.1.1 Number of networking initiatives taken, involving policy makers (specify)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="6400.1.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6400.1.2 Number of policy makers targeted for networking</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="6400.1.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6400.1.2 Number of policy makers targeted for networking</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="6400.1.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
