<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012026-01-1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency integrated intervention to address the humanitarian crises in Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">L&apos;intervento ha come obiettivo principale l&apos;assistenza alle vittime della crisi umanitaria in Somalia  causata dai frequenti shock climatici. Luglio 2019 ha segnato il livello pi&#xF9; basso di raccolti agricoli a partire dal 1995, il 70 sotto la media, con conseguenze umanitarie disastrose sulla popolazione. Le abbondanti piogge dell&apos;ultimo mese hanno tuttavia provocato inondazioni nelle aree agricole, distruggendo sia gli insediamenti umani sia la produzione agricola Inoltre la mancanza di strutture igienico sanitarie di base ha causato il diffondersi del colera, della malaria e di altre malattie trasmissibili. Si stima che circa 5.4 milioni di Somali si trovino in condizione di insicurezza alimentare e necessitino di interventi urgenti per la sopravvivenza. L&apos;intervento prevede attivit&#xE0; di emergenza anche volte al rafforzamento della resilienza con approccio DRR (Disasters Risk Reduction), di chi si trova in situazioni vulnerabili, aumentandone la capacit&#xE0; di fronteggiare futuri shock climatici, economici e sociali.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Main objective of the intervention is supporting the response to the humanitarian crisis in Somalia caused by climate shocks. Harvest in July 2019 has been 70 below the national average, the poorest harvest since 1995, with serious consequences on local population. The recent rains caused flooding of the agricultural areas, worsening famine in the country. Lack of basic health and hygiene facilities promote the spreading of transmissible sicknesses such as malaria, cholera and respiratory disease. Recent estimates indicate around 5.4M people facing acute food insecurity and in need of emergency life-saving assistance. The interventions will comply with the DRR (Disasters Risk Reduction) approach, building the communities&apos; resilience and reducing their vulnerability to climate-related events and other economic and social shocks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11001" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11001" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012026/01/1" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2020000102" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-08" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-08" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MATERIAL RELIEF ASSISTANCE AND SERVICES</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, achieve access to adequate and equitable sanitation and hygiene for all and end open defecation, paying special attention to the needs of women and girls and those in vulnerable situations</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, achieve universal and equitable access to safe and affordable drinking water for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end hunger and ensure access by all people, in particular the poor and people in vulnerable situations, including infants, to safe, nutritious and sufficient food all year round</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end preventable deaths of newborns and children under 5&#xA0;years of age, with all countries aiming to reduce neonatal mortality to at least as low as 12 per 1,000 live births and under&#x2011;5 mortality to at least as low as 25 per 1,000 live births</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end the epidemics of AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria and neglected tropical diseases and combat hepatitis, water-borne diseases and other communicable diseases</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, reduce the global maternal mortality ratio to less than 70 per 100,000 live births</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eliminate all harmful practices, such as child, early and forced marriage and female genital mutilation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-02">3000000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2020</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-18">3000000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2020</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
