<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-19/DDA-3379/SA1/WASH/INGO/13087</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency WASH Response in two Woredas of Shebele Zone (Adadle  Kelafo), Somali Regional State of Ethiopia for IDPs and Host communities affected by drought</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shebele zone of Somali region is one of the worst droughts affected zones in Somali region. According to the DTM 14 (February 2019), there are over 36,257 droughts induced IDPs spread in 33 sites in 8 woredas. The DTM 15 indicates that the IDPs in Somali region are in critical situation for WASH service,  in Shable zone of Adadle and Kelafo affected climate induced having 15 sites of 18,039 individuals in Adadle and 3 sites having 5,823 individuals in kelafo weredas respectively.In Adadle weredas highly affected eleven kebeles were selected are Farburo, Ano-malabley, Go&#x2019;ane, Birleys, Malka salh, Cidhi, Hodan, Harsog, Todob, Cali-Hudle, and Kulmis. In kelafo weredas three kebeles selected were Washaqo, Kabxanlow, and Fatabayo 
ADRA conducted rapid needs assessment in April 2019, it revealed that the IDPs and host community in Adadle and Kelafo woredas of Shebele zone have critical shortages of water supply, and sanitation and hygiene coverages. People are using untreated water from open and unsafe sources such as unprotected ponds and rivers. 

The prime objective of the action is to increase access to safe water for IDP sites falling within the 17 convergence woredas, IDP sites reported to access less than 5 liters of water per person per day as well as those accessing 5-10 liters/person/day among the communities affected by Drought through Provision of Emergency water trucking from nearby potable water source(s) to critical water shortage IDP sites in partnership with RWB&#x2019;s deployed water tankers managed at Woreda level while assuring the Rehabilitation, maintenance and operations of existing non-functional water schemes as an Exist strategy for water Trucking, The project will also encompass the provision and distribution of water treatment chemicals (Bishan Gari) in sachets and distribution of Non Food Items (NFIs-buckets) for targeted households through supporting the Transportation/distribution costs for essential WASH NFIs amp water treatment chemicals. The emergency WASH also involves. Sanitation and Hygiene promotion works through awareness creation by conducting training sessions for WASHCO members, system care takers and beneficiary communities. 
(1) Under the emergency water trucking component, a total of 7,569.45 m3 of potable water will be distributed over 45 calendar days by making 180 trips benefiting persons residing in 2 project woredas (Adadle amp Kelafo) at subsistence water share i.e.  5 L per person per day. ADRA will implement the emergency Water in partnership with Woreda Water Offices - through using RWB&apos;s deployed Water Tankers managed. for water Trucking to Washaqo Kebele with 210 HHs, Kabxanlow kebele with 189 HHs and Fataboyo kebele with 230 HHs IDPs. Adadle wereda the selected sites for water trucking are Farburo kebele with 895 HHs, Harsog kebele with 170 HHs and Todob kebele with 171 HHs.
 (2) kelafo Woreda two HDWs non-functional will be rehabilitated. The target sites in kelafo Woreda are Kabxanlow with 189 HHs and Fataboyo 230 HHs IDPs kebeles. These above sites are selected for two HDWs Rehabilitation for each kebeles in Kelafo.  

 (3) ADRA will promote Sanitation and Hygiene education for targeted communities through provision of sanitation materials and construction of latrines. For the sanitation and hygiene activities targeted kebeles are Farburo with 895 HHs, Harsog with 170 HHs, Todob with 171 HHs, Malka salah with 145 HHs, Cudhi with 122 HHs, cali Hudle with 105 HHs and Kulmis with 130 HHs.Adadle wereda the selected sites for latrines construction are Farburo kebele with 895 HHs, Harsog kebele with 170 HHs and Todob kebele with 171 HHs.  

(4) To respond the current emergencies by delivering educational IEC/BCC materials,and hygiene promotion activities. ADRA will distribute 16,000 bars of body and laundry soaps.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adventist Development and Relief Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adventist Development and Relief Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zerihun Awano</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251911508568</telephone>
   <email>zerihunawano@adraethiopia.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.93277841 43.32988331</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-10">209123.71</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-10">42650.23</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400298068">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-07">293.52</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adventist Development and Relief Agency</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400345766">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-09">232.22</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adventist Development and Relief Agency</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-13087">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-10">251773.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adventist Development and Relief Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304097760">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-12">251773.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adventist Development and Relief Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
