<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-19/DDA-3379/SA1/A/INGO/13089</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Livestock-based Emergency Response Project in Adadle, Hargelle and Gode Woredas of Somali Region, Ethiopia.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The livestock-based Emergency Response Project focuses on responding to the dire need of pastoralist and agro-pastoralist communities in the target woredas due to the challenge on the shortage of pasture and inability to recover from the effects of the protracted drought in the previous periods. 
The 2019 Humanitarian Needs Overview (HNO) shows that 34% of the total population in Somali Region require humanitarian and protection assistance out of whom 38% are estimated to be in acute need. Most of the woredas in Shebele and Afder Zones are characterized by severe to a critical need. Shortage of pasture, prevalent livestock diseases compounds the challenge of pastoralist and agro-pastoralist communities whose lives and livelihoods are dependent on livestock and livestock products. 
The project mainly aims to protect the lives and livelihoods of drought-affected pastoralist communities in Gode, Adadle and Hargelle Woredas of Somali Region. The planned interventions are based on the livestock and crop roadmap for humanitarian assistance developed by DRM/ATF and issued in March 2019. It also follows the Somali Region multi-sector convergence exercise and prioritized interventions by the agriculture cluster. 
VSF-Suisse is planning to provide supplementary feeding for core breeds of livestock for 1500 households in Adadle Woreda of Shebele Zone and Hargelle Woreda of Afder Zone. Each household will receive concentrate feed for 5 shoats for 3 months. The feed will be procured from local feed producers having the capacity to provide the needed amount of feed with the desired quality parameters. A laboratory test will be made to the feed samples prior to the procurement to the beneficiary households. 
The feed intervention will be integrated with voucher-based livestock treatment intervention for 1500 households. This involves awareness raising among beneficiary households, distribution of vouchers to beneficiaries, refresher training for Community Animal Health Workers (CAHWs), identifying private veterinary pharmacies (PVP), signing MOU with PVPS, linking the PVPs with the CAHWs, facilitation of the delivery of veterinary drug to the target kebeles, technical backstopping and continuous follow-up. 
The project also involves supporting government-led livestock vaccination. This intervention aims to ensure that 85-90% of the livestock population in the target have the expected herd immunity and contain the disease. VSF-Suisse provides technical and logistical support for the government-led vaccination. 
Construction of fodder stores in Gode Woreda and capacity building on feed management will also be the other integral component of the project. VSF-Suisse will facilitate the establishment of fodder producers as cooperatives to be the owners and facilitators of the fodder stores. After being officially established and registered by the government, the cooperatives will collect contribution money from the members based on the annual gain/profit. The contribution will be used for maintenance and administrative costs. The cooperative will have bylaw based on which they nominate a fodder store management committee. Moreover, they will be linked to a commercial animal feed processer in Gode and/or Jigjiga. 
In all of the interventions proposed, protection will be mainstreamed into the activities. Protection principles such as age, gender and diversity will be integrated into the planning of the initiatives Accountability to the affected population will be ensured in all phases of the project starting from the planning, beneficiary selection and implementation of the activities on the ground. Moreover, the project works towards ensuring the accessibility of services to the most vulnerable community members.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">V&#xE9;t&#xE9;rinaires Sans Fronti&#xE8;res Suisse</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">V&#xE9;t&#xE9;rinaires Sans Fronti&#xE8;res Suisse</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Kebadu Simachew Belay</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251935986659</telephone>
   <email>kebadu.belay@vsf-suisse.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.93277841 43.32988331</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-29">240874.82</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-29">49125.78</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-13089">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-29">290000.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">V&#xE9;t&#xE9;rinaires Sans Fronti&#xE8;res Suisse</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304133298">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-01">290000.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">V&#xE9;t&#xE9;rinaires Sans Fronti&#xE8;res Suisse</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
