<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-19/DDA-3379/SA1/NFI/ES/INGO/13030</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency shelter and non-food assistance to conflict affected IDPs in Benishangul Gumuz and somali regions.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Despite recent political reforms, Ethiopia is struggling with recurrent internal conflicts. Community clashes are common in several parts of the country and nearly 3% of the population are displaced in 2018. The displaced population, who have often fled with nothing more than personal possessions, as well as returnees who are going back to partially or completely destroyed houses and lost livelihoods, require continued lifesaving and recovery assistance to sustain their lives and rebuild their livelihoods

The proposed intervention will provide life-saving assistance to 33000 internally displaced persons impacted by inter communal conflict and are in critical need of emergency shelter and Nonfood items(ES/NFI) in Benishngul Gumuz and Somali  regions. 

The project will be implemented through a coordinated response by ES/NFI Cluster members. NRC will target beneficiaries through a combination of in kind and cash interventions. Cash-based assistance will be provided in project locations where quality materials are available on the local market and can be purchased directly by beneficiaries. Due to poor quality and unavailability of plastic sheets in the local markets, NRC will provide plastic sheets (in kind) for  ES/NFI cash beneficiaries . Where cash based assistance is preferred, NRC will ensure consideration of protection risks and benefits. NRC applies an age, gender and diversity lens to all phases of the project cycle and will work closely with protection experts to maximize benefits and mitigate protection risks. NRC works in close collaboration with protection partners and on advice from internal protection adviser to ensure adherence to protection principles and do no harm.

For shelter repair kit beneficiaries in Benishangul region, NRC will opt for a beneficiary led reconstruction approach, whereby the organization will provide shelter materials, and technical support for the rehabilitation / reconstruction  of shelters by the beneficiaries. Preferably, the materials will be provided through vouchers, or in kind, depending on market access and conditions. Beneficiaries will be tasked with the responsibility of collecting materials ( in case of vouchers) and for the erections ( they will have the option to engage / contract the builders) with technical support from NRC shelter assistants, recruited from their communities &#x2013; particular attention and support will be provided for the most vulnerable.. A provision for skilled artisan labour has been made for in the costing. Before the intervention, HLP issues will be assessed thoroughly and NRC will work closely with the government and communities to ensure security of tenure.

NRC has extensive experience in shelter and NFI interventions (both in kind and cash) and will use lessons learned from previous interventions to ensure quality programming. Under this project, NRC will provide life-saving Shelter and NFI assistance to 6000 Internally displaced HHs in  Benishngul gumuz(67%) and Somali (33) regions priority locations. Exact areas of distribution will be identified through joint assessment by ES/NFI Cluster members and in coordination with regional, zonal and local government authorities. People who have been internally displaced in 2018 and 2019 will be prioritized.  During Project implementation NRC will strictly adhere to the recently adopted Targeting guideline, including undertaking protection risk analysis and working with affected communities to identify and mitigate their protection risks and measures to ensure meaningful access to the most vulnerable. NRC is committed to mainstream protection and gender elements during assessment, targeting, distribution and monitoring processes. 

The project will be implemented over a period of 7 months and NRC has the full support of the regional, zonal and woreda authorities for the implementation of the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Biruk Gebru</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251923798497</telephone>
   <email>biruk.gebru@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eden Solomon</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251911824165</telephone>
   <email>ede.solomon@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zia Hassan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Program</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251945628284</telephone>
   <email>zia.hassan@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benishangul Gumz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.50292442 35.44030702</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.93277841 43.32988331</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-12">455236.24</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-12">657264.16</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-13030">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-12">1112500.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304102276">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-16">890000.32</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304853315">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-24">222500.08</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
