<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-19/DDA-3379/SA1/N-H-P/INGO/13076</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Emergency Protection, Health and Nutrition response to IDPs and drought affected communities in East and West Hararghe of Oromia region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the 2019 Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP), 4.8M Internally Displaced People (IDPs) and host communities are targeted to provide health assistance. It is expected that those displaced in 2018, may remain displaced at least for the first half of 2019. IDPs are more at risk of infectious diseases and outbreaks due to the poor living conditions. Health service disruption, and loss of medicines and medical supplies. 3.4 million people will be at risk of various disease outbreaks including AWD, measles, scabies, yellow fever, pertussis, and high caseloads of malaria in 2019 (HRP). Based on the EPHI report as of 19 June 2019 Nationally 642 Cholera cases were reported of which 299(46.5%) cases and 2 deaths were reported from Oromia region, West Hararghe zone, Oda Bultum (171), Chiro (80), Gemehis (12), and Mieso woredas (36).

The overall goal of the health response project is to contribute to the reduction of morbidity and mortality through improved access to basic Primary Health Care (PHC) and referral services for vulnerable drought and conflict affected communities (IDPs and host communities). This will be realized by establishing MHNT and provision of basic free of charge primary health care, conducting awareness creation on prevention of major re-portable diseases (AWD, Measles, Scabies and Malaria), improving the capacity of health staffs and availing basic essential drugs and also strengthening the early warning, surveillance and referral system to benefit the affected people and support government on cholera management. Based on assessment conducted by International Medical Corps in collaboration with East Hararghe zonal and woreda offices from 14-25 March 2019 it was found that in the past six months a total of 703 Measles cases and 22 deaths with CFR of 3.1%.  Also increment of scabies cases in all woredas, (within the last six months 18,928 individuals were affected by scabies case, this number confirmed and reported to next level, this is due to lack of water for hygiene and sanitation practices also low socio-economic status and shortage of anti-scabies medication at all level. A total 18 health facilities were Damaged by conflict at Babile and Chinaksen woreda this can affect the health service access for vulnerable groups, like children and pregnant and lactating women..  
 The interventions under the Nutrition sector will comprise prevention and treatment of malnutrition through management of Acute Malnutrition and Infant and Young Child Feeding in Emergencies (IYCF-E). The major activities planned  include a need based support of OTP/SC materials, routine drugs, SC care takers food ,rehabilitation of damaged health facilities with OTP/SC material provision, regular monitoring and supportive supervision , provision of on the job trainings for quality service provision, logistic support on RUTF and supply transportation from woreda to the respective health facilities, ensure quality screening and TSFP implementation through increased coverage/ FDAs  or IMAM approach.

The preventive nutrition section will focus on IYCF through complimentary feeding demonstration, celebration of breast feeding week, nutrition education and counselling at community and breast feeding corners established at the health centers. To design context specific IYCF messaging  International Medical Corps will conduct focus group discussion with mothers and  key  influential  to identify  culture and practices  that serve as Barriers and busters to IYCF and maternal care in the community.at the start of the project.  The complimentary food cooking demonstration on how to diversify children&#x2019;s diet using locally available foods and nutrition education on the importance of nutrition and balanced diet, ANC follow up and taking supplementations will be comprised under the IYCF sub sector.  
The nutrition activities will be measured using the standard indicators as recommended by the UNOCHA gui</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Genet Jarso</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 911512713</telephone>
   <email>gjarso@InternationalMedicalCorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lutful Gofur</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 (0) 115572800</telephone>
   <email>lgofur@InternationalMedicalCorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.50798643 38.76521270</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="35" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="54" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="11" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-29">806825.94</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-29">66837.65</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-13076">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-29">873663.59</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304133297">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-01">698930.87</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304577068">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-23">146352.73</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
