<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-19/DDA-3379/SA2/P/INGO/14695</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Child Protection and GBV in emergency response in Gedeo zone, SNNP region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project contributes to the overall objective to enhance the safety and wellbeing of women and children returnees in Gedeo Zone in SNNP region through emergency psychosocial support intervention and case management support through strengthening BoWCA&#x2019;s capacity. To achieve the overall objective, the action has specific outcomes that focus on the provision of psychosocial support through Safe Healing and Learning Spaces (SHLS) and, strengthening CP and GBV response and referral services, including strengthening case management capacity, safe and survivor-centered GBV procedures and coordination mechanisms. In particular, the project aims to improve and strengthen existing CP and GBV multi-response services at the Woreda Women and Children Affairs Office (WWCA). Under this action, the IRC will renovate and equip existing SHLSs to provide psychosocial support services to vulnerable children through trained SHLS facilitators. The project also aims to strengthen the capacity of BoWCA to support UASC in need of alternative care and family tracing support. The IRC will conduct capacity building trainings on CP and GBV case management and GBV Information Management System (GBVIMS) to BoWCA staff to improve services being provided to UASC and GBV survivors. Additionally, the IRC will conduct review meetings and on job training with BoWCA to improve their capacity in CP and GBV response service provision. The IRC will also translate Clinical Care for Sexual Assault Survivors brief guidelines and CP and GBV case management tools into the local language and train Woreda health and BoWCA staff on the basic principles of child protection and clinical management of rape. The key issues that this project aims to address include gaps in proper technical and institutional capacity of BoWCA limited awareness of communities on available services and the absence of standard tools, and operating procedures that help to facilitate quality service provision for CP and GBV survivors. The CP and GBV response services include improving the psychosocial support for children, strengthening case management support including on FTR and alternative care for UASC through targeted capacity-building for local service providers, material support for UASC and their caregivers and cash support for dignity kits. The IRC will also strengthen the referral pathways to improve institutional capacity and to strengthen quality service provision and coordination among CP and GBV and other actors. The IRC will strengthen the capacity of community based organizations including child rights clubs and provide support to increase community awareness on CP and GBV issues through community wide sensitization and outreach activities. 

The IRC has drawn lessons working in partnership with different government structures including BOWCA, Health centers, schools and other service providers and will replicate the good practices in Gedeo Zone for successful project planning and implementation in the target areas. In addition, the IRC will implement integrated CP and GBV activities in the targeted areas which will bring synergy and maximize impact on the overall protection of women and children. Recognizing protection concerns faced by children are related to gender issues and deep rooted cultural norms and practices that put children at risk of GBV, the GBV team will closely coordinate with child protection team especially in mobilizing the community to bring attitudinal change that promote gender equality and building the capacity of service providers to better respond to the needs of children, women and girls.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee INC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee INC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anbessie Wake</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acting Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 (011) 6636735</telephone>
   <email>Anbessie.Wake@rescue.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNNP</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.46580872 36.80646946</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-24">250000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-14695">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-24">250000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee INC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304481096">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-05">250000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee INC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
