<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-19/DDA-3379/SA1/WASH/INGO/13032</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency WASH Response in Kercha woreda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">From April to July 2018 a localized conflict in Gedeo and West Guji zones caused the displacement of an estimated 958,175 people. As of 13 February 2019, an estimated 619,071 individuals are still displaced across both zones. Among IDPs,91 % are in host communities and 9% are living in collective sites. Gedeo and West Guji DTM Rapid Response Assessment (RRA) round 5, conducted from 1-13 February 2019, captured data on internally displaced people (IDPs) in 60 collective sites and 240 host communities spread across 15 woredas in Gedeo and West Guji zones. The report reveals that Gedeb, Kercha, and Bule Hora are the woredas currently hosting the largest numbers of IDPs. Kercha is host to 80,238 displaced people. Of these 12,844 (16%) are in collective sites and 67,394 (84%) are in host communities. Since RRA round 5, a large decrease of 53,532 displaced individuals in Kercha has been observed. Some of the IDPs are settled at kercha Town and are sharing the existing water system. The existing system has less capacity to address the water demand for both town and IDP population. There is a need to improve the existing water supply system of the town by developing a new durable solution like new water source development, construction of water storage and expansion system.
The overall objective of this project is to provide a lifesaving emergency WASH response for Kercha woreda at kercha town from kercha Inshe spring source. The project will improve access to safe water and reduce diarrhea and infectious diseases in the affected areas. Furthermore, women and girls will benefit from the implementation of this project as they are the primary individuals responsible for collecting water in every family. 
The project will be implemented for six months and will directly benefit 10,473 (M=5,341 and F= 5,132) IDPs and 4,527 (M= 2133 and F= 2394) host communities with the development of new WASH infrastructure. The project will also improve the hygiene and sanitation condition of the community by raising awareness on basic hygiene and sanitation practices using Behavior Change Communication (BCC) approaches, including sensitization of key individuals in the community and in collaboration with the local health office.
The people are living in 
1. Kercha town IDPs with 10,473 people 
2. Kercha town host community with 4,527 people
CRS and its longstanding partner, the Ethiopian Catholic Church and Social Development Coordinating office of Awasa (ECC-SDCOA) will engage with woreda officials and local community leaders while also mobilizing the health Development Army and Health Extension Workers.
The project aims to work
1. Spring maintenance work 
2. Construction of 50m3 reservoir
3- Construction of 25 m3 collection chamber. 
4. Construction of 5 water points
5- Supply and installation of a generator amp pump.
6- Construction of generator/pump house. 
7. Supply and installation of the pipe system
8. Once the new scheme goes operational, the project will provide management training to local WASH Committees.
As part of a hygiene promotion campaign, the WASH response will also raise general awareness of the targeted 15,000 individuals through campaigns and hygiene promotion events. Targeted distribution of point of use water treatment chemicals and hygiene kits (soap, buckets, wash basin, jerrycans) will go to families who are considered most at risk of AWD due to their water source.
This project will be a supplementary project in which CRS and ECC-SDCOA are implementing in kercha town, large gravity system for with major activities includes three spring capping, construction of 50m3 reservoir, renovation of the 25m3 collection chamber, construction of 5 water points and 2,600-meter pipeline including pressure and distribution lines.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Catholic Church - Social amp; Development Commission of Hawassa(ECC-SDCOHA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-29" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zemede Abebe</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head Of Program</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251911507305</telephone>
   <email>zemede.zewdie@crs.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.50798643 38.76521270</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-01">161376.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-01">52910.26</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-13032">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-01">214286.54</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304081899">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-08">214286.54</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
