<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-19/DDA-3379/SA1/H/UN/12998</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Sexual and Reproductive Health services for internally displaced persons in East Hararghe and East Wollega zones of Oromia Region and Faffan zone of Somali Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Ethiopia climate change and conflict are the main hazard profiles affecting millions of people in the country. The previously drought affected people are not yet fully recovered from the effect of the drought. They are still in need of humanitarian assistance. Moreover, the ethnic-based conflict in the different parts of the country displaced millions of people who are critically in need of humanitarian assistance. Based on the 2019 Ethiopia Humanitarian Response Plan, 8.86 million people are in need of humanitarian assistance of which 8.3 million people are targeted for emergency food and non-food assistance. The Government of Ethiopia and the humanitarian community present the 2019 Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP), which seeks US$1.314 billion to reach 8.3 million people with emergency food and non-food assistance. In the HRP plan for 2019, 4.8 million people are targeted for health and 0.74 million for protection with a budget requirement of $ 143 million and $13.4 million respectively. Clusters have identified priority districts for humanitarian program interventions in 2019. The average priority for the whole cluster have been taken and hot spot districts are identified as priority 1, 2 and 3. Hence, the total number of hot spot priority districts, as per the 2019 classification, are 467, of these 253 districts as classified as hot spot priority one districts, 151 as priority two and the remaining 63 as priority three. Compared to the 2018 hot spot classification, the number of priority one districts in 2019 increased by 37 districts.

According to IOM Round 15 Displacement Tracking Matrix (DTM) report that was conducted from January -February 2019 indicated a total of 2,227,109 IDPs in 1,197 sites. Conflict was reported as the primary driver of displacement (1,663,396 IDPs), followed by displacement due to climate induced factors (508,723 IDPs). The majority of the IDPs (1,166,878 are found in Somali Region and 859,290 in Oromia region)

In humanitarian situations particularly in internally displaced persons women and girls mostly lacks availability of  sexual and reproductive health services and related life-threatening complications of pregnancy and childbirth attributable to malnutrition that must be addressed. In this project, UNFPA is planning to provide sexual and reproductive health and clinical management of rape survivor&#x2019;s services for conflict induced IDPs in selected 8 woredas in East Hararghe and East Wollega zones of Oromia region and Faffan zone of Somali region. UNFPA is a pipe line manager of emergency RH kits for the emergency response, there might be a possibility of using the emergency RH kits to the health cluster prioritized other zones and districts besides to the selected districts based on the emerging needs and situations.  From the total requested budget, more than $ 100,000 will be used for the 184,176 IDPs response hosted in Babile and Tulu Guled districts for emergency RH kits procurement and capacity development trainings. 
Project Goal: To contribute to the reduction of maternal and neonatal mortality and morbidity in selected IDP sites and IDPs surrounding host communities
Project Objective: To enhance availability of lifesaving reproductive health, maternal health and sexual violence services for IDPs and affected host communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopian Midwives Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alemayehu Bogale</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SRHRiE Programme Analyst</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 115444260</telephone>
   <email>bogale@unfpa.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bettina Maas</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA representative</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251-115444019</telephone>
   <email>maas@unfpa.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.50798643 38.76521270</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.93277841 43.32988331</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-05">231500.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-05">268485.57</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-12998">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-05">499985.89</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304091449">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-11">499985.89</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
