<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-19/DDA-3379/SA2/NFI/ES/INGO/14751</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Life Saving Emergency Shelter Repair and Emergency Shelter Non-Food Items Response for Returnees in Babile Woreda of East Hararghe Zone, Oromia Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia has not yet fully recovered from the consecutive drought that resulted in massive livestock loss in pastoral regions and crop failure in the agro-pastoral areas. More than 7.8 million people are dependent on direct food assistance, while an additional 3.6 million people are supported through public works under the Productive Safety Nets Programme (PSNP). Despite the benefit of the belg/ kirmet rains, immediate recovery of these communities will not be immediate, nor will it be expected without concerted assistance. The food security situation is further worsened by the ongoing conflict along the border areas between Oromia and Somali region, and the recent inter-communal violence along the border areas of Gedeo (SNNP) and West Guji (Oromia) Zones. According to the Displacement Tracking Matrix (DTM) round 17, there are some 145,217 HHs IDPs (877,537 Individuals Internally Displaced People (IDPs) across the Oromia region in 460 sites due to conflict drought and other disasters. A total of 2,235, 290 people are displaced across the country accordingly the DTM 17 conducted on May, 2019. The crisis has placed significant strain on existing Shelter infrastructure and practices, particularly in  remote areas where returned IDPs have integrated into communities with already limited access to basic services. The safety and well-being of returned IDPs depends on effective and timely humanitarian intervention to meet urgent needs. 	
ZOA designed this project in response to the tremendous Shelter Repair and reconstruction and Emergency Shelter and Non-food Item (ES/NFI) response needs of returned IDP communities of Babile woreda. Through this project ZOA has planned to address a total of 800 HHs (4000 Individuals ) returned IDPs ( 400 Girls, 320 Boys, 2080 Women and 1200 Men). 50 % of total project beneficiaries will benefit from ES/NFI kits and the remining 50% will benefit from Emergency Shelter repair kits. The overall objective of this Shelter intervention is aimed at delivering a holistic shelter repairing  and reconstruction (including construction of model repaired shelters) and ES/NFI services to save lives and reduce vulnerability of returned IDPs due to poor shelter service and to protect and restore their livelihoods. The ES/NFI intervention will be a combination of cash (30%) and 70% in-kind. The shelter repair kits will also consist of Cash for local materials and labor with the remaining assistance in kind. Additional activities include facilitation of Building Back Better (BBR), HLP and Protection mainstreaming trainings for target groups, local government authorities and local community members market assessment and post distribution monitoring of shelter repairing kits and cost construction monitoring. 
The project is also in line with the gap analysis and prioritization by the National Shelter Cluster and the official request from East Hararge Zonal and Woreda Disaster Risk Management Offices (DRMO) for intervention. ZOA Ethiopia will use emergency response surge team, that will be based in Harar at East Harerghe DRMO, in order to reduce office running cost that will have impact on the cost effectiveness and timely response of the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chris Maclullich</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 911-207 908</telephone>
   <email>c.maclullich@zoa.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mahlet Tekalegne</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Manager of Programme Quality</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 920-808-208</telephone>
   <email>m.tekalegne@zoa.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.50798643 38.76521270</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-22">208340.77</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-14751">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-22">208340.77</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304465612">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-27">208340.77</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
