<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-19/DDA-3379/SA2/NFI/ES/INGO/14623</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ES/NFI support to IDPs/IDP returnees and Host communities affected by protracted and multiple Humanitarian crisis in Wachile woreda of Borena Zone, Oromia Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the midyear review (MYR) of the 2019 HRP, September 2019, Ethiopia has been challenged by inter-communal violence, resulted internal displacements (IDPs). Although spontaneous as well as organized returns have been registered since August 2018, the Government-organized return operation in May 2019 was unprecedented. According to Government, 2.1 million IDPs were returned, and significant number of IDP camps were decommissioned.

Localized small-scale displacements have always existed in Ethiopia from clashes between communities over limited resources and over politically triggered tribal conflicts, which has been experienced in the last three years. Recently, sporadic conflicts and killings by armed groups has challenged the implementation of HelpAge International programs in Borena.

Although the Government and humanitarian actors have been supporting IDPs, returnees and host communities, the need on the ground has not been met and the situation is dire for the most vulnerable households, including OPs amp PwDs. Displacement exposes vulnerable people to protection risks, food insecurity, and inadequate shelter/NFI, which pose a risk of disease outbreaks. This project intends to support 6 cholera prone communities in Moyale where a total of 81,000 plus communities are residing, and 9 critically affected IDP/IDP returnee sites and surrounding host communities accommodating gt2000 individuals.

HelpAge has been operational in Borena for the last two decades. Currently, HelpAge is implementing an integrated humanitarian response project in four woredas of the Zone, focusing on provision of water supply through rehabilitation of malfunctioned water sources, drilling of deep well, construction of inclusive shared household/public latrines for people who have mobility challenges (i.e. - through construction of ramps, handrails, elevated seat, wider doors), and WASH awareness for the most vulnerable community groups.

The proposed project aims to assist a total of 4,768 people residing near or within the host communities as well as in designated IDP camps. all the beneficiaries are living in Wachile woreda which has been critically affected by conflict and living in a protracted displacement. The major activities of the current project include:- distribution of Emergency Shelter NFI kits. While implementing the proposed activities, protection will be mainstreamed through identification of protection risks of most vulnerable groups and their protection needs will be supported available service providers using the existing service providers map. These may include, specific protection concerns such as, social interaction (with family, neighbors and his/her career), psychosocial support, referral to available and appropriate service providers and provision of NFIs. This will be based on actual needs of individuals or groups of OPs, PwDs and other vulnerable groups. In addition, protection mainstreaming will be done through capacitating relevant government and INGO actors on inclusive programming.

The project will be implemented over a 5-month period and will require USD 150,000 to achieve its objectives and intended inclusive protection mainstreamed. ES NFI activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sisay Seyoum</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251935402670</telephone>
   <email>sisay.seyoum@helpage.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.50798643 38.76521270</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-04">150000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-14623">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-04">150000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304487181">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-10">150000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
