<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-19/DDA-3474/PAK/FS-WASH/NGO/12136</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Lifesaving Services to Drought Affected Families Through Multi-sector Response Approach in Chaghi District</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The decade-long drought has adversely impacted the province of Balochistan with Chaghi and Killa Abdullah districts declared as drought emergency.  In Chaghi, two union councils (Chaghi amp Brabchah) are targeted for life-saving interventions. The affected families are faced with an acute shortage of WASH facilities, food, agriculture, livestock, and livelihood. According to BRDS&#x2019; needs assessment, there is an urgent need for WASH and food security interventions to address the WASH and food security related problems of the affected populations. 
Therefore, the proposed project aims to ensure that the affected families have access to improved and safe WASH facilities and access to sufficient food through recovery of their agriculture and livestock-based subsistence on a sustainable basis.  To ensure access to improved WASH facilities, the project aims to develop 6 communal water supply facilities in the two focused UCs. Similarly, 2 harvesting reservoirs will be erected in the UCs, followed by pavement of 6 water ponds to reduce water waste and ensure water availability for both drinking and irrigation purposes. Likewise, to discourage open defecation, 178 latrines will be provided for the affected families in the 2 UCs the arrangement of water supply schemes and latrines will be linked with the delivery of 200 health and hygiene awareness sessions in the focused UCs. 
In addition, to ensure food security and recovery of the livelihoods of the affected families, 750 poultry packages will be distributed among the families per the selection criteria. 1500 agricultural packages (crop and vegetable seeds) will also be provided to 1500 beneficiary families to promote kitchen gardening and agriculture. Approx. 8000 livestock will be vaccinated with the support of the livestock department. 6000 tractor hours will be distributed to prepare the agricultural lands of the affected families per the selection criteria. Moreover, the beneficiaries will be provided 38 trainings in poultry management and livestock, and 175 trainings in kitchen gardening to ensure their food security and livelihoods. Thus, through the above interventions, the project will make sure the affected families have access to WASH facilities their food security is ensured and their livelihoods are revived on a sustainable basis. It will also promote value addition at the local level as a means of diversifying farmers&#x2019; revenues on selling agriculture products and stimulating seed demand in the local market. 
To ensure realization of the overall objective of the project, we will ensure maximum transparency and visibility in the project. The beneficiaries will be entitled to information regarding the interventions. They will be made aware of the selection criteria for the activities. A robust complaint mechanism will be developed to enable the affected populations to have their say and register their complaints. Moreover, the project aims at promoting gender and age equality. The above interventions are designed in a way to ensure all genders and ages have equal benefits, share and decision-making in the project. The project also ensures protection and environment protocols to ensure protection of the beneficiaries and adherence to the environment. Thus, the project not only aims to provide WASH and food services, but also aims at promoting gender and age equality, environmental protection, and protection of the beneficiaries.
Lastly, to ensure the project is implemented smoothly in the focused areas, close and continuing coordination will be maintained with all the stakeholders. The coordination and collaboration with varied stakeholders will ensure complementarity in the interventions, which will help to achieve the specific cluster objectives, allocation strategy objective, and Pakistan&#x2019;s drought response plan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Balochistan Rural Development Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Balochistan Rural Development Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-09" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mir Haider Shahwani</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chief Executive Officer (CEO)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0812862230 (cell No. 03448287375)</telephone>
   <email>ch.brds@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Salman Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Manager Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0812862230 (cell No. 03327912688)</telephone>
   <email>program.brds@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK7">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Balochistan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>28.32720000 65.89310000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="43" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="57" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-06-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-04">335526.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-04">164473.68</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-12136">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-04">500000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Balochistan Rural Development Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304043045">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-14">300000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Balochistan Rural Development Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304634367">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-08">200000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Balochistan Rural Development Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
