<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-19/DDA-3474/PAK/WASH/NGO/12006</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving WASH situation in drought Affected areas of Killa Abdullah</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to NDC Overall 76% of the surveyed population currently have access to improved water sources, with 24% forced to rely on unimproved sources of drinking water. Overall 38% of respondents indicated that they feel that the drinking water available is insufficient for their household needs. Alarmingly over 50% of respondents in Balochistan reported walking for more than 30 minutes to access what is unsafe drinking water. 
The proposed project will be implemented in drought affected areas of Killa Abdullah. The proposed project is inline with PHPF strategic priorities and priorities Pakistan drought response plan. The overall beneficiaries will be 6825 school children (from 25 target schools), 2600 individuals of en-catchment area of (04) health facilities and 8,100 population from (05 communities). The total target population would be 17525 (with 49% female and 51% male). Complete WASH package will be made available in target institutions. This will include safe and clean water provision, latrines, group hand washing   and operation and maintenance and  hygiene awareness session. The interventions will also include drinking water schemes rehabilitation at community level. The target UCs and drought affected areas of Killa Abdullah namely (Aramzai Masezai, Peer Alizai, Aramzai kakuzai, Gulistan NO,01, Norak sulehman kheil, Abdul Rehmanzai, Inayat Ullah Karez, Darozai) has been identified in consultation with district authorities. The need assessment is identifying specific needs of target communities whose WASH facilities are badly affected by existing drought. The proposal is based on addressing water needs of affected population which are also inline with NDC assessment.  
Since Women and girls are the most affected population due to scarcity of water and drought, therefore need assessment and project proposal clearly indicates the inclusion of vulnerable groups in all the indicators. 
 WESS has given due consideration to gender aspect by selecting GEM-Gender and Age Marker of WFP. In this regard 04  girls schools and 08 boys schools will be provided the WASH services. Whereas community water supply schemes&apos; beneficiaries will cover all the age quantile of women/girls. The interventions will ensure gender aspect with the approach of &quot;DO NO HARM&quot;. WESS safeguarding and protection policies/procedures are  compliant to safeguarding of staff and beneficiaries. WESS has sound  complaint mechanism at two levels that is registering complain through dropping their complaint into a complaint box placed in field office and text complaint on cell phone. Only Manager of the programme will check this complaint box on daily basis. Apart from this WESS team will conduct sessions in communities to aware them about both the complaint reporting mechanism. WESS will remain intact with PDMA and all cluster lead during and after project implantation for productive coordination. WESS will apply participatory monitoring and evaluation regarding selection of input, output, and outcome indicators. This will be assess jointly with the communities with set frequency of time. The beneficiaries selection will base on vulnerability criteria i.e. the focus would be on those individuals and groups with diminished capacity and who hardly cope, resist and recover from the effect of drought. In this regard the focus would be on single headed women, widows, person with disability,  minority among others. WESS will also take into account personal factors (household composition, special needs of a person/household, health status, etc.), socio-economic factors (level of poverty, loss of livelihoods, assets, etc.) and the person/household&#x2019;s capacity to recover during the analysis phase. WESS will also focus on risk factor of the project and comply with all procedures to avoid any delay.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-09" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-08" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-08" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amanullah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Manager ME</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0812863826</telephone>
   <email>amanullah@wess.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK7">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Balochistan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>28.32720000 65.89310000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-05-09"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-08"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-11">248431.53</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-12006">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-11">248431.53</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304023840">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-03">248431.53</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
