<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-19/DDA-3474/PAK/FS/NGO/11956</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Combating Food Insecurity Through Sustainable Livelihood approaches of Training on poultry and livestock, animal food/vaccination provision along side organizing Veterinary Camps and Improved Agricultural Based Activities through Distribution of Seeds and establishment of Kitchen Gardening with feasible areas for Rehabilitation/Building Water Resources/ Reservoirs in the Drought affected Communities of  Three UCs (1- Gulistan -1, 2- Gulistan-2 3- Darozai) Tehsil Gulistan District Killa Abdullah, Balochistan.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project interventions are aimed to identify and to support the droughts affected families having lost their agriculture and animals during the devastating prolonged drought situation in District Killa Abdullah and near by areas not only their means of lives but to the gamut deteriorated the survival of inhabitants. The project interventions are based upon the rapid assessment being conducted by YO after government promulgation of Drought Affected Areas of Balochistan. The interventions will help the affected families to restore, rehabilitate and improve their food security through a sustainable and more realistic approach of provision of livelihood support based activities, improved agricultural based interventions while ensuring the manipulated income being generated opportunities from the livelihood interventions in the form of Feed, vaccination and organizing Veterinary Camps by establishment of local committees  Likewise, these committees will ensure the proper identification, selection, organizing, management and distributions of animal food and agriculture packages,  to the vulnerable families (including, Male, female, Children, Transgender, and disabled). The project will enable the communities to rehabilitate and restore their income generating activities, 
whose demo graphical statistical are    

 UCs Killa Abdullah 	Total Population	Male 	Female	Male Children 	Female Children 
Gulistan I 	                       15,992 	                   8,193	                     7,799	                       2,628 	                       2,426 
Gulistan II	                       22,378 	                11,464 	                   10,914 	                       3,677 	                       3,394 
Darozai	                       22,140 	                11,342	                   10,798	                       3,638 	                       3,358 

. Youth Organization in the said project, with financial support of UNOCHA, will provide support to1500 vulnerable droughts effected families and 300 beneficiaries Training upon livestock and Poultry (100 each UC Total 300) (Total 3900 beneficiaries) to rehabilitate their food security in all the proposed and most devastated sectors of Agriculture and Livestock to become food secure.
In each Drought affected village of these UCs packages will be allocated for the most vulnerable families to help restore their food security as in accordance with their available potential and previous experience. Detail of food security packages for each villages are

1.1. Distribute (5000) poultry Packages (Including poultry feeds and vaccination to dis aggregated people as means of livelihood and nutrition at household level. 
1.2. Distribute (500) kits for poultry (Baskets and Water Kits etc)
1.3. Organize (40) camps (Focus on vaccination and deworm with the collaboration of relevant line department for 8000 livestock. 
1.4. Conduct 2 Training of dis aggregated people from community on poultry management to enhance their knowledge and skills on community based poultry management. 
1.5. Conduct 2 Training of dis aggregated people from community on livestock management to enhance their knowledge and skills on community based livestock management. 
1.6. Conduct 2 Training of dis aggregated people (Women) from community on kitchen gardening to enhance their knowledge and skills on kitchen gardening and ensure food security. 
1.7. Establish 50 kitchen gardening along with provision of kitchen gardening toolkit for dis aggregated people (Women) from community to practice food security measures at HH level. 
1.8. Livestock support: Target groups for the project include subsistence livestock holders, small scale agriculture farmers and women headed households.
1.9. Crops Support 
1.10. Rehabilitation/building of 09 water resources.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-24" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-23" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-23" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syed Jaffer Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>03130185190</telephone>
   <email>jaffar@youth.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK7">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Balochistan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>28.32720000 65.89310000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-05-24"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-23"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-22">325003.94</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-11956">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-22">325003.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304032969">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-10">195002.36</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304261280">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-15">130001.58</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
