<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-CVR-13078513-IP-1-2020-1759</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DK-CVR-13078513" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DUF - Danish Youth Council</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Redefining the future</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of this pilot project is for PSCF to reach more students and strengthen the interconnectivity between the students at the 9 different universities at the West Bank. We want to strengthen PSCF as an organisation mainly by increasing awareness from the broader student body. Secondly this increase in awareness should lead to an increase in the number of volunteers. Therefore, one of our main activities will be the establishment of a platform where the students will be informed about the work of PSCF and where they at the same time can communicate across the different universities, autonomous of the student councils. Furthermore, we will host workshops that are aimed to help the students strengthen their communication skills and the dialog between the different universities.  We learned from our Preparatory Study this February that the Palestinian students are more likely to volunteer in an organisation where they are able to improve their skills - both for job-preparation and academically. Therefore we believe that these activities will not only raise awareness of PSCF but bring more volunteers to PSCF and thereby making PSCF a more sustainable organisation. DSF and PSCF have been partners for more than five years and has throughout this period evolved a fruitful and progressive partnership benefiting both parties. The shared experience and understanding are important enabling factors that help the partnership reach the milestones of the years to come.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-88135628" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DSF - Danske Studerendes F?llesr?d</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-13078513" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DUF - Danish Youth Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-13078513" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DUF - Danish Youth Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2020-09-15">83530</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2021-01-01">83530</value>
  </budget>
  <related-activity ref="DK-CVR-13078513-DUF_GUP" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
