<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-CVR-13078513-IP-2-2021-0966</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DK-CVR-13078513" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DUF - Danish Youth Council</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambian Adolescent Girls Advocacy - ZAMGA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The purpose of the preparatory study is to develop and prepare a pilot project together with our new partner organization, Tambwe Legcay Foundation. The objectives will be to lay out a detailed timeline for the pilot project, as well as share knowledge on effectient methods to develop and finalize the pilot project together. The project is entitled Zambian Adolescent Girls Advocacy, hereafter called ZAMGA. Together with Tambwe Legacy Foundation, we intend to focus on an advocacy project whose objective is to empower, promote and campaign for the basic human rights of adolescent girls in Zambia. We chose to focus on adolescent girls as our taget group, because they are the most stigmatised,vulnerable and discriminated youth group in Zambia. They are denied education, are victims of forced marriage, physical and/or psychological abuse. One of our main objectives are to: - Empower adolescent girls with tools and ressources necessary to make informed decisions - Promote the rights of adolescent girls in their local communitities - Influence local stakeholders such as churches, schools, clinics and different private and government institutions into actively taking a stand against gender-based inequality</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-13078513" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DUF - Danish Youth Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-13078513" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DUF - Danish Youth Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-29883319" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FUN - Foreningen for Unge Nydanskere</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-12" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-28"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-12"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2021-07-28">47985</value>
  </budget>
  <related-activity ref="DK-CVR-13078513-DUF_GUP" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
