<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-CVR-13078513-IP-5-2021-0940</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DK-CVR-13078513" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DUF - Danish Youth Council</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Volunteerism and Expansion of Democratic ideas</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">VU seeks to find an international partner in Argentina to enhance volunteerism and participation in the local democracy. We have prior to our trip established contact with two potential partners, Coordinadora Grupo Joven Fundaci?n Libertad and Jovenes Libertad. Both organisations share democratic and liberal views and also the same goals regarding engaging the youth in active participation in local projects. We wish to establish a successful partnership with an argentine organization. We want a long-term partner that shares our vision and goals with an equal division of responsibility. The vision of our project is to contribute to a positive development amongst the argentine youth and spread ideas about democracy. We aim to strengthen the democratic participation with a specific focus on electoral participation and also participation of the youth in Argentine society. We are an organisation with great competences hence to international projects, therefore we hope to provide our partner with tools to work towards our common goal. We therefore hope that this partner identification trip will lead to long and prosperous projects between VU and our new partner.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-13078513" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DUF - Danish Youth Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-13078513" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DUF - Danish Youth Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-59182110" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">VU - Venstres Ungdom</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="AR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-09"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2022-02-01">31923</value>
  </budget>
  <related-activity ref="DK-CVR-13078513-DUF_GUP" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
