<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-CVR-13078513-IP-6-2021-1384</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DK-CVR-13078513" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DUF - Danish Youth Council</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">70th International Federation of Medical Students  Associations(IFMSA) August Meeting General  Assembly in PANAMA.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IFMSA August meeting is one of the biggest youth-led events with more than 1000 delegates from all over the world. It takes place twice a year to engage youth in matters of global health. It features training, workshops, and serves as a network platform for medical students worldwide to learn, discuss, and exchange knowledge. MEDSAR and IMCC are all members of IFMSA. MEDSAR hosted the IFMSA March Meeting 2020 1 year ago in Kigali, Rwanda. Since then, all other IFMSA meetings were held virtually due to COVID19 pandemic. This August meeting will have a hybrid format where some delegates will attend virtually. During the network activity, we aim to acquire skills about organizational recovery from COVID19 pandemic, capacity building from different sessions, Meeting our partners from IMCC, and presenting the outcomes of a recently finalized partnership project called YEAN Project. In addition to that we will get an opportunity to learn from projects running in other National Member organizations(NMOs), network and exchange knowledge and culture. At the end of this networking activity, we will gain the knowledge to sustain our organization, run an upcoming partnership project (Youth Education Activities on Sexual and Reproductive Health project, YEASRH) and share the experience gained to the rest of medical students in our organization.We will also acquire skills and experience to host our upcoming international events, namely SCORA exchanges amidst the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-13078513" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DUF - Danish Youth Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-13078513" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DUF - Danish Youth Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-30865219" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IMCC - International Medical Cooperation Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-29" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-07" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-29"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-07"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2021-07-29">48885</value>
  </budget>
  <related-activity ref="DK-CVR-13078513-DUF_GUP" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
