<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-24685</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Industrial Union of Donbass</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Industrial Union of Donbass (the company or ISD), one of the largest Ukrainian steel trading and holding companies, has approached IFC to finance its modernization program for its Ukrainian facilities.  The project consists of investments in ISDs existing plants in Ukraine to:     -  improve their environmental performance and bring them up to World Bank Group standards, including a time-bound program to close open-hearth furnaces; and    -   modernize and de-bottleneck operations to improve their competitiveness.      ISD, together with its subsidiaries in Ukraine and Hungary, produced 9.2 million tons of steel in 2005. The company&apos;&apos;s total revenues were about $3.5 billion in 2005.  ISDs main steel subsidiaries in Ukraine are OJSC Alchevsk Iron &amp; Steel Plant (AMK), OJSC Dneprovsky Iron &amp; Steel Plant (DMK), and OJSC Alchevsk Coke.  ISDs subsidiaries outside Ukraine are Dunaferr in Hungary, and recently acquired Huta in Poland.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project is expected to have a positive development impact in several areas:   -  It will further improve the competitiveness of a major steel producer in Ukraine.  The project should enable ISD to produce better quality and value products for the domestic and export markets.  ISD-Ukraine does not depend on tariffs, especially as it is export oriented.     -  By implementing an action plan to meet IFCs environmental guidelines, the project should have a substantial positive impact on the environment by decreasing the emissions, improving the use of gases and better recycling of dust emissions.     -  Efforts by ISD, an industry leader, to improve transparency through having an international audit of its financial statements, will have far reaching effects on the business practices of the rest of the Ukrainian private sector, and the attitudes of foreign investors regarding Ukraine.   -  Steel plants often have a huge impact on the local community by virtue of:   --the large number of people directly employed, normally between 10,000 and 60,000 per plant; and    --the historical dependence of nearby towns for services, especially in former Soviet Union and East Europe.     -  AMK and DMK are important to the development of the economies where the plants are located as they are town-creating enterprises and employ a significant portion of the regions workforce.  AMK and Alchevsk Cokes combined staff is 25,300.  AMK still supports some of the social infrastructure in the town of Alchevsk, with a population of about 190,000 people.  DMK with 19,000 employees is also one of the key employers in its town which has a population of 300,000.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INDUSTRIAL UNION OF DONBASS CORPORATION</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-24685" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2006-06-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2006-08-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Main sponsor contact: Mr. Sergei Yelizarov    Telephone number: +380444576861   Email address: yelizarov@fppr.org.ua    Information Billboard at main plant offices at AMK, DMK, and Alchevsk Coke, respectively.</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="UA-Ukraine">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AMK and Alchevsk Coke are located in the town of Alchevsk, with a population of about 190,000 people. AMK supports some of the social infrastructure in the town. AMK is only 120km from the port of Mariupol and 650km from Odessa.  DMK is located in the town of Dneprovsky with a population of about 300,000 people. DMK is sited on the Dnepr river.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>49.0000000000 32.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AB - Integrated Steel Works</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $100.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2006-06-27"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2006-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2006-06-27">100000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2006-06-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2006-06-27">100000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INDUSTRIAL UNION OF DONBASS CORPORATION</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/24685/industrial-union-of-donbass">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
