<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5512003102-MDA-32130</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EBRD Women in Business Programme Moldova</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">EBRD Women in Business Programme Moldova</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen &#x201C;Women in Business Programme in Moldova&#x201D; &#xE4;r en forts&#xE4;ttning p&#xE5; tidigare samarbete med Europeiska Utvecklingsbanken (EBRD) f&#xF6;r st&#xF6;d till kvinnligt f&#xF6;retagande i Moldavien som genomf&#xF6;rdes under 2011 &#x2013; 2016. Insatsen komplementerar Sidas p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende regionala st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r &#x2019;Women in Business&#x2019; i l&#xE4;nderna inom det Europeiska Partnerskapet (EAP). Syftet med insatsen &#xE4;r att bidra till ekonomisk utveckling med kvalitet och inkluderande utveckling i Moldavien genom att fr&#xE4;mja kvinnors deltagande i landets ekonomi och styrka konkurrenskraften hos sm&#xE5; och medelstora f&#xF6;retag (SME) som leds av kvinnor. Projektet kommer att ge teknisk r&#xE5;dgivning och kapacitetsutveckling till kvinnliga entrepren&#xF6;rer.  F&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade resultat &#xE4;r en &#xF6;kad konkurrenskraft hos de SME:s som deltar i programmet, f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad tillv&#xE4;xt, skapande av arbetstillf&#xE4;llen samt &#xF6;kad produktivitet och innovation. Dessutom kommer programmet genomf&#xF6;ra aktiviteter som syftar till att utveckla den lokala marknaden f&#xF6;r konsulttj&#xE4;nster f&#xF6;r expert och r&#xE5;dgivning f&#xF6;r SME:s i Moldavien.  
The contribution is going to promote Green Economy and environmentally safe production, and pays a specific attention to environmental impact and &#x201C;greening&#x201D; of the industrial production. The project integrates the conflict perspective and will operate in the Security Zone and Transnistria, a self- proclaimed independent state on the territory of Moldova. The contribution will support therefore confidence building measures through working with women-managed SMEs in this zone, as well as in the administrative-territorial unit of Gagauzia in Southern part of Moldova.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The contribution &#x201C;Women in Business Programme in Moldova&#x201D; is a continuation of the EBRD WiB Fund for Moldova 2011-2016 and complements the on-going Regional Sida WIB for EaP countries. The Overall Objective is to stimulate the transition to a more competitive and inclusive economy in Moldova by strengthening women-led SMEs and promoting women&#x2019;s participation in business and enhance the role of women in economic governance. It aims at assisting women entrepreneurs in Moldova to have a real and fair chance of success by enhancing the competitiveness of their businesses. The contribution is going to promote Green Economy and environmentally safe production, and pays a specific attention to environmental impact and &#x201C;greening&#x201D; of the industrial production. The project integrates the conflict perspective and will operate in the Security Zone and Transnistria, a self- proclaimed independent state on the territory of Moldova. The contribution will support therefore confidence building measures through working with women -managed  SMEs in this zone, as well as in the administrative-territorial unit of Gagauzia in Southern part of Moldova.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Overall Objective of the proposed Programme is to stimulate the transition to a more competitive and inclusive economy in Moldova by strengthening women-led SMEs and promoting women&#x2019;s participation in business. It aims at assisting women entrepreneurs in Moldova to have a real and fair chance of success.
The Specific Objectives of the Programme include:
1. Promote inclusion and sustainable growth by targeting groups that are underrepresented in the local SME sector, specifically women-led businesses.
This will be evidenced through better overall outputs for the beneficiaries and economy, including increased revenues, new jobs, poverty reduction and better perspectives for women entrepreneurs. It is also proposed to implement activities aimed at increasing the awareness and engagement of male entrepreneurs and other stakeholders (FIs, state institutions, etc.) to highlight and address the specific challenges women-led businesses face and the opportunities and returns of promoting women&#x2019;s economic empowerment. The corresponding capacity building, networking, visibility and communication efforts will facilitate the sustainable inclusion (including the financial inclusion) of women entrepreneurs who are looking to achieve scale and further develop their enterprises.
2. Strengthen women-led SMEs&#x2019; competitiveness and empower women entrepreneurs via advisory support for business growth and innovation in the face of increased competition on local and international markets.
This will result in increased productivity and sales, diversification of markets and engagement with the provisions and opportunities presented through the Deep and Comprehensive Free Trade Areas (DCFTA), implementation of modern production technologies, upgraded product and services ranges, as well as business processes. The proposed training, mentoring and networking will add value to the provision of advisory services and will address crucial knowledge and behavioural gaps of women entrepreneurs enabling them to build and expand their business relations and gain their individual and collective empowerment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="46015" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EBRD/European Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="46015" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EBRD/European Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moldova (the Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Industry</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="32130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Small and medium-sized enterprises (SME) development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja utvecklingsinriktad politik som st&#xF6;der produktiv verksamhet, skapande av anst&#xE4;ndiga arbetstillf&#xE4;llen, f&#xF6;retagande, kreativitet och innovation samt uppmuntra att mikrof&#xF6;retag liksom sm&#xE5; och medelstora f&#xF6;retag v&#xE4;xer och blir en del av den formella ekonomin, bland annat genom tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.3 - Promote development-oriented policies that support productive activities, decent job creation, entrepreneurship, creativity and innovation, and encourage the formalization and growth of micro-, small- and medium-sized enterprises, including through access to financial services.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/55120031-amendment-no-2.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment 2</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/55120031_SignedAgreement2018-07-02.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement contribution EBRD Women in Business</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/55120031_Amendment1toSida-Ebrdagreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Amendment No.1 to EBRD Women in Business programme</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/55120031_SignedDecisiononcontribution.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution EBRD Women in Business programme</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55120031" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
