<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5503009701-MDA-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Fotbollsskolor, Moldavien</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Open Fun Football Schools, Moldova</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cross regional project promoting peaceful co-existence, gender        equality and community development through civil society and local    authorities in Moldova including the Transnistria and Gagauzia        regions.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Regionalt projekt som fr&#xE4;mjar fredlig samexistens, j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och   samh&#xE4;llsutveckling genom det civila samh&#xE4;llet och de lokala           myndigheterna i Moldavien, inklusive Transnistrien och Gagauzien.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCPA/Cross Cultures Project Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moldova (the Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">261776.0854879322</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">160352.1917229114</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">130497.1943103223</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">127972.8861099749</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">261776.0854879322</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">160352.1917229114</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">130497.1943103223</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">127972.8861099749</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-09-01">767671.804949</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">261776.0854879322</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-07-28">160352.1917229114</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">130497.1943103223</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-28">127972.8861099749</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2016Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: The contribution was implemented according to the indented outcomes and planned results. The partner met the targets set in the RAF with no serious deviations.     1. Mobility and cooperation (including Transnistria and Gagauzia).   Direct cooperation with existing football clubs, local schools and authorities in the OFFS locations  ended up with supporting the trained coach volunteers and football clubs to organise regular follow-up sport activities for children and adults (reflected in the 236 follow-up/spin-off football events attended by almost 18.000 children during the project period). The project has created strong and viable networks both in terms of cross regional integration, cross sector cooperation, and has contributed significantly to the construction of organizational structures enabling girls&#x2019; and women&#x2019;s participation in football across Moldovan society (14 districts across the country including nine districts in the Transnistria region and 5). In the project period the FMF has set up a new regional structure with 4 regional development offices, including one in Tiraspol, which coordinate 35 regional associations &#x2013; 5 of which are located in Transnistria. The regional offices have been set up with a particular focus on grassroots football and the local OFFS partnerships in the regions have been a strategic tool to achieve this. Considering the context and the generally poor institutional communication and collaboration between Moldova and Transnistria, this is a unique connection and line of communication. Apart from the regional structures of the FMF, the networking and contacts to the Transnistria region among others were facilitated by instructors in the national OFFS instructor team themselves from Transnistria    2. Gender equality in sports   In the project period a 77% rate of girl&#x2019;s participated in OFFS activities and a 56% rate of female volunteers educated as leaders and coaches. As a result, the number of educated female coaches in Moldova is unique compared to all other countries in Europe, and it is fair to say that the mobilization of girls and women within the OFFS plays a major part in this. There is still a lot of resistance amongst certain communities to the female football, but there is an increased acknowledgement that that there is need to implement female programs within the structures of the clubs. A new National League U14 established in the Center and North of Moldova 2015. A new Regional League U16 established in South of Moldova 2015. Football festivals LYG for girls U12/U13 was organised, including teams from Center, North, South and East (Transnistria) of Moldova with participation of more than 800 girls each year. As well, six club formation seminars for female clubs were conducted by FMF and OFFS Moldova.           Unfortunately the target of 100 females obtaining A-C coach license proved too be unrealistic. However, in the project period, the FMF decided to make a new D-license coach education for grassroots coaches which is based on the OFFS trainer education, and in the project period 294 females obtained this license to become grassroots coaches.     3. Child protection/juvenile crime prevention  The planned cross-sectorial community networks for promoting child protection/juvenile crime prevention initiatives were organized in Moldova 2014, and since then 3 cross sector network seminars and 2 lessons learned seminars were organized. In the seminars the participants representing the school, sport and police sectors were introduced to concrete methodologies in cross sector juvenile crime prevention and discussed the experiences and lessons learned connected with their implementation in local communities across Moldova. The most productive step has been to include community police officers as OFFS-leaders pairing up with technical OFFS-leaders at the local level, and facilitate actual interaction and cooperation between the local actors and stakeholders across sectors. An agreement between OFFS Moldova and the General Inspectorate of Police (GIP) of 2015 establishes the common commitment to building capacity within the GIP and FMF to develop and implement a series of initiatives. A main target is to involve delinquent minors with deviating behavior and those at risk (who abandon the domicile and the educational system, who display aggressive behavior etc.), in various sports, cultural and educative activities, to promote a healthy way of life and ensure harmonious development of the children. After a pilot implementation in 2015, in 2016 each OFFS has been assigned a local community police officer to co-lead the implementation of OFFS and follow-up network activities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55030097" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
