<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10142A0101-MDA-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conslutancy support to the civil society core-support programme</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Konsultst&#xF6;d till k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;dsprogrammet f&#xF6;r det civila samh&#xE4;llet</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim for this procurement is to contract consultancy support for the core-support programme. The procurement will be done jointly with Kiev. Within the ToR are; system-based audits, recommendations, support of implementing these recommendations during the pre-core phase, support to ongoing core support partners through trainings etc. Consultants will also assist the embassies in follow-up on the organizational development during the core support period.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Under 2014 p&#xE5;b&#xF6;rjade ambassaden ge st&#xF6;d till civilsamh&#xE4;llet i form av k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d och fem organisationer genomgick systemrevisioner och 4 organisationer fick f&#xF6;rberedande k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d. Ambassaden tar under juni 2016 beslut om k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d till dessa organisationer. Under h&#xF6;sten 2016 kommer ytterligare 5 organisationer p&#xE5;b&#xF6;rja arbetet mot k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d med systemrevisioner och m&#xF6;jliga f&#xF6;rberedande k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d. 

Upphandlat st&#xF6;d kommer bist&#xE5; ambassaden att fatta beslut samt ge brett organisatoriskt st&#xF6;d till organisationerna.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nordic Consulting Group A/S</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moldova (the Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">35490.6984906985</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">214930.8432293105</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">5534.3224864899</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">35490.6984906985</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">214930.9582988124</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">5534.3224864899</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-01">259861.625664</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-28">9421.155961156</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-28">26069.5366795367</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-02-28">39061.9890914112</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-28">49729.9594955353</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-28">79938.4470220013</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-28">46200.4867439934</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-28">5534.2717245318</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is completed and the results were achieved according to the Activity Plan and the Consultancy Contract. The project was implemented by Nordic Consulting Group - an international consultancy company with the aim to support the Embassy to implement its core support programme for CSOs in Moldova. The Embassy&apos;s assessment is that the the results achieved in 2017-2018 are sustainable and supported the CSOs beneficiaries to develop internal capacities to promote positive changes in Moldova.&#xA0;The overall approach of the assignment as explained in NCG&#x2019;s original proposal and in the inception report has been premised on: 1) an organisational development model, based on Results Based Management (RBM), focusing on how the CSOs aim to improve their capacity and seek to increase the effects and impact of their interventions, and 2) a Human Rights Based Approach as fundamental guiding principle of any assistance to the CSOs (technical support, on-distance advice and feedback, and training), as well as on how the CSOs apply HRBA in their own work.&#xA0;
The following achievements were met:&#xA0;
&#x2022; Efficiency/systems-based audits on 8 CSOs&#x2022; Capacity assessments (surveys and consultations) with 10 CSOs&#x2022; Support to gender analysis in 9 CSOs&#x2022; Gender mainstreamed results assessment framework for 9 CSOs&#x2022; Strategy/results assessment framework support to 5 CSOs&#x2022; Support to development of policies (anti-corruption, integrity, human resource management, HRBA, gender equality) to 3 CSOs.&#x2022; Support to M&amp;E and reporting to 3 CSOs&#x2022; Support to governance structures in 10 CSOs including both management and boards.

Progress of individual CSOs
Centre Resonance
Team members participated at both training sessions on gender mainstreaming. However, the team member that participated at the first event had only started her work with Centre Resonance (first day at work) and on the other occasion, the team member was not aware that the participants were expected to prepare a gender analysis; this had not been communicated to the person who only participated the first day. This has contributed to the fact that Centre Resonance has had difficulties in preparing the expected tasks &#x2013; both the gender analysis and RAF gender mainstreaming. Another difficulty for the team has been the language issue, which has led to communication difficulties with the people who are supposed to carry out the analysis but also in preparing the documents. It has been difficult to engage CR team members to work with gender equality due to the above-mentioned issues and/or due to the fact that it has not been seen as a priority for the management. Even though the organization targets women, the organization needs understanding of gender mainstreaming and especially the issue of intersectionality.
EcoContact
Active participation and very dedicated team member. For the gender analysis, EcoContact&#x2019;s representative (Ecaterina Valcu) realized the CSO did not have sufficient data for the analysis; EcoContact then prepared and sent out a survey to their stakeholders (more than 150) and presented the results based on the survey results and existing data. She was also very interested in receiving additional material on how they can integrate gender issue in their work and has been the driving force within the organization. The organization would benefit additionally from more specific training and support on links between gender and environment and increasing internal capacities on gender equality.
EcoVisio
Very active and interested participants, even though the organization had limited knowledge on gender equality. During the time they worked on developing gender analysis, EcoVisio hired a new staff member who had more knowledge and experience on working with gender issues, whom successfully and with great dedication completed the tasks of preparing the gender analysis and integrating a gender perspective into the organization&#x2019;s RAF. However, the organization would also benefit from more specific training on gender and environment as well as increasing internal capacities on gender equality.
Eastern Europe Foundation
Participated at the first training and had previously (prior to the trainings and tasks) sent their gender analysis and plan, to which NCG had provided feedback. The organization did not send representatives for the follow up training nor were they active in any other sense related to gender mainstreaming tasks.
Expert Grup
Expert Grup has had very active team members, but it has been a long process for the CSO to understand its impact on gender equality as it primarily works with policy monitoring and research. NCG has provided consultations and feedback on both gender analysis and what to take into consideration when mainstreaming the RAF and has had good communication with selected CSO representatives. However, Expert Grup has had difficulties in &#x2018;convincing&#x2019; its staff members that the analysis and mainstreaming should be done within each aspect of the CSO&#x2019;s work. Finally, the management of Expert Grup took on the responsibility of finalizing the task and a final gender analysis was sent whereas they wanted to discuss directly with Sida regarding the mainstreaming of their RAF. Support to Expert Grup needs to be focused on gender and policy research and monitoring, but also building the team&#x2019;s understanding of gender equality.
Gender Documentation Centre Moldova (GenderDoc M)
GenderDoc M was initially hesitant doing a gender analysis as the organization works with human rights, but after meeting with the GenderDoc team and providing written feedback, the CSO finalized its task and continued with mainstreaming their RAF. The management of the CSO has taken an active role in gender mainstreaming involving a wider team comprising of team members from different departments of the organization which has shown a great dedication to the issue and for improving organizational results as regards to gender equality. They would need support in including an intersectionality perspective into their analysis and planning, but could also be used as a resource for training and strengthening other CSOs understanding of LGBTQI issues.
Institute for Human Rights in Moldova (IDOM)
IDOM is the only CSO that has not completely finalized its task even though it was one of the first organizations to finalize the gender analysis. The CSO team representative was very active at the training sessions and diligent in performing his tasks; however, the management presumably failed to provide the necessary support in finalizing these tasks. Another important aspect is that the organization&#x2019;s RAF is quite complicated and unnecessarily big which poses difficulties in mainstreaming it, not least considering the capacities of team members in gender mainstreaming. The suggestion is that the CSO needs more support in working with its RAF and gender mainstreaming, as well as building organizational capacities to work with gender equality.
Independent Centre for Journalism (IJC)
Dedicated team members and management who both took on the role of finalizing the analysis and mainstreaming. Very attentive to NCG recommendations and feedback and open to using existing sources and material on gender and media. The team would benefit from more specific support in relation to gender and media in its further work on raising awareness and influencing policy development.
Legal Resource Centre Moldova (LRCM)
Very dedicated team and ready to learn. Provided one of the best initial gender analyses considering their level of knowledge and competencies on working with gender equality. Open for feedback and recommendations, but have also provided good input on how they can further work on mainstreaming gender into their activities and internal capacity building. They are also open to collaboration with others and have reached out to WLC for knowledge sharing and cooperation purposes. Could benefit from additional gender mainstreaming support.
Women&#x2019;s Law Centre (WLC)
Very good knowledge and understanding at the level of CSO on gender equality, even though the organization has not done a gender analysis so far, but has issues a range of publications on the perceptions of women and men&#x2019;s roles and responsibilities in the Moldovan society. The support to WLC was mainly focused on how to incorporate the aspect of intersectionality in the analysis and mainstreaming. WLC is open to sharing its knowledge and competences with other CSOs, and can be used as a valuable resource. Both team members and management show great dedication and desire to drive this issue.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10142" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
