<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5512002901-MDA-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Rights Programme in Transnistria II</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">M&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter i Transnistrien II-programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on the recommendations formulated by Thomas Hammarberg in the Report on Human Rights in the Transnistrian region of the Republic of Moldova (2013), the contribution aims to strengthen human rights in the Transnistrian region of the Republic of Moldova and is 4 concrete areas:
1) non-discrimination and social inclusion of children and adults with disabilities
2) enhancing gender equality and combating violence against women
3) support to improve prevention, treatment and care services for PLHIV, PWIDs and people in prison and
4) consolidation of a coordination and monitoring platform for Human Rights in TN.
The main outcomes per each domain of intervention are the following: 1. to achieve an increased number of women and men, as well as children with disabilities, enjoying the range of community-based services for ensuring the effective exercise of their rights on an equal basis with others; 2. to enhanced protection to victims and potential victims of domestic violence and empowerment of individuals to prevent and address the problems at their roots in the Transnistrian region; 3. to scaled up access to quality and integrated prevention, treatment and care services for people living with HIV, TB and people who inject drugs in the civilian and prison sectors of the Transnistrian region; 4. the establishment of coordination and monitoring platform for human rights interventions in TN.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen st&#xF6;djer &#x2019;de-facto&#x2019;-myndigheterna i den Transnistriska regionen i Moldavien att implementera rekommendationerna i den rapport som Thomas Hammarberg tog fram 2013 p&#xE5; FN:s uppdrag.UNPD har tillsammans med UNAIDS, UNODC och OHCHR skickat en ans&#xF6;kan till den svenska ambassaden om finansiering av 10 388 894 SEK f&#xF6;r att implementera projektet &#x201D;Joint Action to Strengthen Human Rights in the Transnistrian Region of the Republic of Moldova II&#x201D; under perioden 2016-2018.

Insatsen syftar till att st&#xE4;rka m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter i den Transnistriska regionen i Moldavien (TN) och best&#xE5;r av fyra komponenter: 1) icke-diskriminering och social inkludering av barn och vuxna med funktionshinder, 2) &#xF6;ka j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och motverka v&#xE5;ld mot kvinnor, 3) f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra f&#xF6;rebyggande, behandling och v&#xE5;rd f&#xF6;r personer med HIV, personer som injicerar droger och personer i f&#xE4;ngelse, 4) konsolidering av en koordinations- och uppf&#xF6;ljningsplattform f&#xF6;r m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter i TN.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP jointly with UNAIDS, UNODC and OHCHR had applied to the Embassy of Sweden for funding of 10 388 894 SEK to carry out the project &#x201C;Joint Action to Strengthen Human Rights in the Transnistrian Region of the Republic of Moldova II&#x201D; during 2016 -2018. The intervention will support the de facto authorities to address the recommendations formulated by Thomas Hammarberg in the Report on Human Rights in the Transnistrian Region of the Republic of Moldova conducted in 2013.    

The contribution aims to strengthen human rights in the Transnistrian region of the Republic of Moldova and is based on 4 components: 1) non-discrimination and social inclusion of children and adults with disabilities 2) enhancing gender equality and combating violence against women 3) support to improve prevention, treatment and care services for PLHIV, PWIDs and people in prison and 4) consolidation of a coordination and monitoring platform for Human Rights in TN.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-17" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-29" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moldova (the Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.1 - Avsev&#xE4;rt minska alla former av v&#xE5;ld och d&#xF6;dligt v&#xE5;ld &#xF6;verallt.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.1 - Significantly reduce all forms of violence and related death rates everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.b - Promote and enforce non-discriminatory laws and policies for sustainable development.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.b - Verka f&#xF6;r och genomdriva icke-diskriminerande lagstiftning och politik f&#xF6;r en h&#xE5;llbar utveckling.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">618182.6681470227</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">596632.0346320345</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">-16289.9985884448</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">618182.6681470228</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">596632.0346320346</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">-16289.9985884448</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-17">1196618.710921</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-28">618182.6681470227</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-28">596632.0346320346</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">-16290.0235621139</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project operated in a complex, sensible and sometime unpredictable context, but proved flexibility during the implementation and encouraged three scale partnerships among state and non-state actors at the: local level, national (cross-river) and international.
Altogether, the project managed to reach majority of its targets, if judging through existing set of indicators. In majority of the cases the project significantly contributed to: 1) Augmentation of the local, national and international partnerships between the key actors; 2) Strengthening the competencies of existing duty bearers and rights holders; 3) Institutionalisation of the new services and entities and 4) Increasing the visibility of the tackled human rights aspects.
The project succeeded to address these difficult issues from several perspectives: improved the dialogue and collaboration of responsible authorities from different sectors (health, LEA (law enforcement authorities), social, prison and civil sector), as well as nongovernmental entities on both banks and promoted an integrated service approach in the region; improved knowledge of decision-makers and health professional to use human rights principles and commitments and international standards.
It addressed stigma and discrimination towards most HIV-affected and vulnerable populations, covering thousands of people and built knowledge and competencies of&#xA0; health, prison, civil society personnel on integrated HIV/TB/drug addiction through trainings, site visits and through providing access to international standards and best practices.
The implemented activities enhanced the collaboration between the both banks of the river Nistru, allowed the specialists from both regions to know each other, to work together and to improve their knowledge and capacities. The normative framework was fully assessed from the lens of human rights and gender and alignment to international standards proposed. The project for the first time allowed to have the health situation in prisons assessed and measures proposed, as well as to involve militia (police) in the prevention work, as well as broader communitarian police approaches.
Some of the initiatives did not generated expected results, despite the efforts of the partners, which delivered all planned activities (e.g. review and adjustment of the de facto policy and normative framework), while one initiative (work in TN prisons) was blocked, although at the initial stage it was promising in terms of effectiveness.
The project was and remained mostly cost-efficient during the delivery, but was affected bythe so called elections in TN region, which represented a serious bottleneck, which caused substantive delays, especially in the initiatives based on the involvement of de facto authorities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55120029" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
