<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12043A0101-MDA-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core support EcoContact</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">K&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d EcoContact</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EcoContact focuses its activity on three main strategic directions and the fourth dimension is specifically dealing with the organizational development, as follows:
A. Implementation of the Aarhus Convention on Access to Information, Public Participation in Decision-Making and Access to Justice on Environmental Matters.
B. Sustainable development with a focus on: Green Economy, Climate Change/DRR, Waste/Chemical Management Water, Environmental Education.
C. Environmental legislation; and
D. Organizational development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core support to Civil Society Organisation EcoContact. The support aims to strengthen the organization and contribute to their activities. The core support activities includes the five programs run by EcoContact:

-	Create an environmentally resposnsible society
-	Implementation of the Aarhus Convention
-	Sustainable development with a focus on green economy, climate change/DRR, waste/chemical management.
-	Environmental legislation
-               Organizational Development</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">K&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d till den Moldaviska civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationen EcoContact. St&#xF6;det syftar till att st&#xE4;rka organisationen och bidra till deras verksamhet genom flexibel finansiering som kan anv&#xE4;ndas f&#xF6;r b&#xE5;de projekt och l&#xF6;pande kostnader f&#xF6;r verksamheten. K&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;deverksamheten innefattar utvecklande och st&#xE4;rkande av EcoContact&apos;s fyra program: 

-	Create an environmentally responsible society
-	Implementation of the Aarhus Convention
-	Sustainable development with a focus on green economy, climate change/DRR, waste/chemical management.
-	Environmental legislation
-               Organizational Development</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EcoContact A.O.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EcoContact A.O.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moldova (the Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">250900.9942004971</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">150306.1580600472</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">150523.9041445433</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">250900.9942004971</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">150306.1580600472</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">150523.9041445433</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">573965.525177</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-28">250900.9942004971</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">150306.1580600472</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-28">150523.9041445433</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/agreement-ecocontact-signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement Core Support EcoContact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/doc-ecocontact-signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution EcoContact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2019, EcoContact implemented several &quot;innovations&quot; in its activities. One of them is conducting in-depth training on enforcement of environmental legislation specific for legal professions (prosecutors, judges, lawyers). This cooperation developed into a further cooperation on developing a complete curricula on this topic to be permanently taught at the National Institute of Justice. This is a remarkable result, especially by its sustainable nature.
Other novelty was the implementation of the sub-granting scheme for smaller NGO, especially form rural areas (but not only). The sub-granting has been accompanied with capacity development measures (organizational development but also thematic consultations).
Despite this new elements in EcoContact&apos;s work, activities conducted previously continues and in some cases have been up-scaled. The progress has been duly documents in the RAF. Organizational capacities of EcoContact continue to improve, organization applies RBM and follows internal documents.&#xA0;
&#xA0;
The progress towards outcomes per areas of intervention
A. Implementation of Aarhus Convention
Two new cases on environmental matters were identified and addressed in 2018-2019. Most recent one, in June 2019 together with the Environmental Protection Inspectorate, addressing the illegal waste discharge issue on Balcani road connecting Chisinau and community Truseni. This illegal damping place contained industrial and construction waste. Based on the request of EcoContact, the State Road Administration developed feasibility study and obtained all necessary permits for addressing this issue.
The other request on the process of respecting of environmental legislation was addressed to Zernoff company, that was based on the complains from the local population about the air quality, as a follow up of emissions of the company. The cases that have been started in a court in year 2018 are in the process and that can take several years before the decision will be taken.
Environmental Justice &#x2013; a new thematic area embraced by EcoContact. For the first time the organization developed specific workshop activities in this field through Summer and Autumn schools&#x2019; format. The events were attended by judges, prosecutors and law faculty students.&#xA0;
At the same time at level of targeted legal drafting support - the modification for the Chapter on environmental crimes of the Penal Code were provided in a partnership with the Prosecutor Working Group.
In 2019 EcoContact has advanced its activities on Strategic Environmental Assessment and Environmental Impact Assessment implementation processes in Moldova. One process was supported on the level of the elaboration of Green City plan in municipality Chisinau and another one is in the preparation stage. This direction shall remain as a priority for 2020 as well.
Public consultations were a first entry point in the process of environmental decision making, during 2019. In total 28 consultation events were organized during 2019 year with more than 750 participants, out of which 56% were women. Most of events were conducted in the communities of the Lower Dniester area and Lapusna River Basin. Creation of Lapusna river basin committee,&#xA0;Lower Dniester National Park and on drafts of normative acts were the main subjects that have been discussed with stakeholders.
During 2019 EcoContact has developed and issued a total of 17 publications on environmental matters. Strategic environmental assessment, Green Economy, Water management, Health and Environmental problems, preparedness to disasters &#x2013; there are the main topics. Additionally, to the publications 15 visibility materials (posters, banners) were developed for the implemented projects as well as 2 online maps were developed.&#xA0;
One of EcoContact&#x2019;s priority is the identification, consultation and monitoring the environmental cases / infringements. Thus, earing 2019, EcoContact monitored 4 cases, the target for this year being fully achieved (100%).
&#xA0;
B. Sustainable development
The support to the stakeholders on SD meters is provided through continuous coaching and consultation. In the last year, EcoContact offered to 28 localities from Hincesti, Leova, Nisporeni, Stefan Voda and Causeni coaching support in implementing environmental law at local level. Mostly, the communities benefited from the consultations and support in the field of application of water,&#xA0;waste law; law on transparency; law on Public Administration etc. The support continues and in 2020 by spreading its coaching to other 16 communities additional to 28 existing ones.
During year 2019 EcoContact has organized 20 events on SD related topics. 415 participants have attended these events, from which 51% were women.&#xA0;
In 2019 EcoContact has launched the Call for Proposals for Small Grants Scheme for NGOs &#x201E;Active Citizens for Environmental Protection&#x201D;.&#xA0;
Fifteen organization applied, following the technical and qualitative evaluation, the total 8 projects were proposed for support that was later approved by the Evaluation committee (that included Board members and donor representative). Grant agreements will be signed for the implementation period February &#x2013; October 2020.
The staff of EcoContact was very active in different formal and non-formal structures created by authorities at local, national regional and international level for consultation of regulatory and legal framework and for general consultation of environment-related issues. EcoContact contributed to 26 working groups.
&#xA0;
&#xA0;
C. Environmental legislation
During 2019, Ministry succeeded to approve at all levels (Ministerial, Governmental and Parliament) only 5 normative acts. From 7 developed normative acts 5 were developed with:
a) support of EcoContact - the Guidelines on the execution of the procedures regarding the environmental impact assessment approved by the Decree of MARDE - no. 1 /2019.
b) comments from EcoContact on the drafts and involvement in public consultations,
c) EcoContact has one of priority topic &#x2013;PRTR, based on the accumulated information, training materials and training / consultations provided to different companies we commented the draft the Guidelines for facilitating the implementation of the PRTR, approved by Decree of MARDE.
During 2019, EcoContact offered 10 opinions on the different drafts of normative acts, above 50% of comments were taken in consideration by the author (MARDE). The opinions were provided in written form, during Working Group meetings or public consultation. The Mayoralty of Chisinau also&#xA0;accepted the online consultation by applying the specific dedicated soft on its webpage. Such web applications will be further recommended for use by other public authorities to ensure the accountability for public involvement.
In 2019 EcoContact, succeeded to elaborate the draft Law on modification of the Law on Establishment of Natural protected areas 1538/1998, the draft Law on creation of the National Park &#x201C;Lower Dniester&#x201D; and the draft law on Industrial Emissions that is transposing the UE Directive nr.2010/75 EU.
For all drafts the supportive documents were elaborated, especially: The Local Council Decision (14 decisions) for supporting the creation of the National Park &#x201C;Lower Dniester&#x201D;; Scientific Argumentation for creating the National Park &#x201C;Lower Dniester&#x201D;. The last one should be approved by scientific community of Moldova and the Regulatory Impact Assessment for the draft law on industrial emission.In partnership with World Bank 10 internal Regulation of the Divisions of the Environmental Agency were revised and improved.
In 2019, the MARDE approved the Guideline on the execution of the procedures regarding the environmental impact assessment. In 2019 EcoContact revised above 20 normative acts from construction ( quality on construction, building, rods), on environment ( water, flora, fauna, subsoil), on normative acts, on transparency from the relevance point of view with EIA, SEA and Ecological Expertise (EE). We elaborated recommendations for modifying all of them for ensuring that mechanisms of SEA, EIA and EE are conducted properly on qualitative &amp; professional level and with involvement of all stakeholders.
Another priority activity of EcoContact is offering pro-bono the legal consultations. The main beneficiary of legal consultations during 2019 were: environmental NGOs (up to 10 NGOs were consulted: Biotica, Icar Dedal, Environmental Consultation Centre Cahul, National Environmental Centre, Environmental Movement, Arborete, Renastere Rurala, AJTMM, IDEP, Speranta, Public Law Centre. The requests came on implementing and interpretation of the environmental legislation.&#xA0;
Another category of EcoContact&#x2019;s beneficiaries are the companies (the total number is about 20) which are interested to apply correctly the environmental legislation.
&#xA0;
&#xA0;
EcoContact is implementing Gender Action Plan, and all the documents elaborated by EcoContact are considering gender equality aspects (papers developed and legislation consulted).
The work with Environmental Justice subject is seen by EcoContact as a contribution to promotion of the Human Rights Based Approach in environmental sector and is given a special attention during the training activities with beneficiaries.
&#xA0;
Financial Report is very clear but the core-support budget hasn&apos;t been fully executed, in some cases because of not conducting several activities or conducting differently activities, postponement of activities or disbursement ot grantees.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12043" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
