<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-14427A0103-MDA-15153</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Internews: Support to Moldovan media and innovative media literacy efforts</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Internews: Support to Moldovan media and innovative media literacy efforts</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the Project is promoting the development of an independent, professional media that provides citizens with access to a diversity of perspectives, and to reduce the media sector&#x2019;s vulnerability to political and financial interests.&#xA0;The objectives, indicators and measures of implementation are described clearly in the Results Framework, Narrative concept and the budget.
The design of the activities, and the implementation approach have been developed as a direct result of the organisational capacity assessment conducted by Internews on all key partners in February 2020 with support from Sida and the Media-M project. The activities are structured in the following groups planned to be implemented during 24 months:&#xA0;
Activity 1. Media Expertise for Key Partners
Internews will provide expert media consultants to four key partners to provide support across various functions. The experts work side-by-side on a daily basis with staff over a long period of time and help them overcome apparent deficiencies. Such targeted and personalised assistance is not possible in the case of more general training that is usually attended by various media professionals representing different outlets.
Activity 2. Subgrants schemes
2.1. Subgrants to Key Partners will be awarded to a number of key partners based directly on the results and recommendations of the organisational capacity assessment conducted by Internews.&#xA0;
2.2. Based on recent assessment of the organization, one more partner (additionaly to the group from 2.1) will receive support for improvement of capacity to produce and promote content by upgrading and modernising production equipment and workstations.
2.3. Media Information Gaps Grants Pool - aim to support worthy pilot projects and nascent efforts to develop innovative content offerings so that they become platforms for intelligent and balanced public discussion on issues of national importance. The primary focus of these small grants is to support and enhance media literacy in Moldova. It will address issues including but not limited to the economic, political, and social problems that promote transparency and accountability, and may also impart relevant media literacy information for targeted vulnerable communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Detta st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r mediesektorn genom Internews f&#xF6;rbereds som ett normalt bidrag. Insatsen syftar till att st&#xF6;dja vissa medier och civilsamh&#xE4;llets organisationer i arbetet med att utveckla intern kapacitet och strategier.
Projektet f&#xF6;ru&#xE4;ntas fylla en viktig funktion i att st&#xE4;rka den oberoende mediesektorn och civilsamh&#xE4;llet. 

Insatsens totala budget uppg&#xE5;r till  6 084 907 SEK.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This support for media sector through Internews is prepared as a normal contribution. It aims at supporting some media outlets and civil society organizations to develop its internal capacities and strategies. 
The project is expected to play an important role in strengthening the independent media sector and civil society.

The interventions&apos; total budget is 6 084 907 SEK.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Internews Europe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Internews Europe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moldova (the Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media and free flow of information</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.10" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.10 - 0 S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till information och skydda grundl&#xE4;ggande friheter, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning och internationella avtal.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.10 - Ensure public access to information and protect fundamental freedoms, in accordance with national legislation and international agreements.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/14427_Agreement02.10.2020.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement for Internews: Viable Media Outlets and CSOs in Moldova</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/14427_Decisiononcontribution.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution for Internews: Support to Moldovan media and innovative media literacy efforts</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The partner organization provided all the reports for 2020 and plans for 2021 in time. The details of implementation process and overview on each beneficiary partner (media outlets), were discussed during annual meting.
Supported non-state media outlets developed necessary organisational, editorial, and business plans and strategies. Internews team contracted experts on strategic planning (social media, crowd funding, etc) in this regard and assisted the organizations.
Supported non-state media outlets funded crucial staff positions, courses, office rent, and other operational costs and endeavours; acquired necessary equipment, supplies, licenses, and other materials. Tailored mentorship programme was provided to some beneficiaries to improve the editing policy.
In 2021, Internews will continue to provide technical expertise to four Key Partners &#x2013; ZdG, Agora, PRO TV, and RISE Moldova - to support various organisational, business, and editorial initiatives. The expertise that will be provided is based on the organisational capacity assessment (OCA) conducted on all Key Partners in January-February 2020 with the support of the MEDIA-M project and Sida.
Internews intends to assess the same five Key Partners (ZdG, Agora, PRO TV, RISE Moldova, and SP) for the fourth time in April-May 2021. The multi-part (business and editorial) Organisational Capacity Assessment will be carried out by international experts to identify the improvements in performance by Key Partners as a result of the targeted grant support and long-term coaching and mentoring provided during the first year of the assistance. Based on it, recommendations will be provided for targeted grant support and long-term coaching and mentoring for the next year of assistance.
The selection of Media Information Gaps Grants Pool (MIGG) was scheduled for the second implementation year (for March 2021).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="14427" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
