<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12136A0102-MDA-15130</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core-support Legal Resource Centre Moldova (LRCM)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Core-support Legal Resource Centre Moldova (LRCM)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core-support is provided to LRCM for 2018-2021 to develop internal capacities to manage results, monitoring and reporting skills and to contribute to the promotion of accountable justice and CSOs in Moldova. According to the RAF - which is the fist strategic document based results based management developed by LRCM, 2 main objectives are to be supported as following:
1. consolidated rule of law and democracy in Moldova as a result of this objective the following results are targeted:&#xA0;- judges would be appointed and promoted in a transparent and merit-based manner;- judges would be more independent, impartial and accountable;- judiciary is effectively organized and managed;- human rights in Moldova are better respected;- CSOs are strengthened to effectively and freely engaged in public polices and assist/engage citizens.
2. LRCM would be a sustainable NGO and an organizational role model for other CSOs from Moldova. This objective will be managed through the following interventions:1. LRCM would me managed efficiently;2. LRCM&apos;s communication, visibility and advocacy skills would be improved;3. LRCM&apos;s staff would be professional and united;4. Financial,environmental sustainability and conflict sensitivity would be improved;5. LRCM&apos;s would be adequately equipped and its cyber security would be at high level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core-support is provided to LRCM for 2018-2021 to develop internal capacities to manage results, monitoring and reporting skills and to contribute to the promotion of accountable justice and CSOs in Moldova. According to the RAF, 2 main objectives are to be supported as following:

1. consolidated rule of law and democracy in Moldova as a result of this objective: 
- judges would be appointed and promoted in a transparent and merit-based manner;
- judges would be more independent, impartial and accountable;
- judiciary is effectively organized and managed;
- human rights in Moldova are better respected;
- CSOs are strengthened to effectively and freely engaged in public polices and assist/engage citizens.

2. LRCM would be a sustainable NGO and an organizational role model for other CSOs from Moldova. This objective will be managed through the following interventions:
1. LRCM would be managed efficiently;
2. LRCM communication, visibility and advocacy skills would be improved;
3. LRCM staff would be professional and united;
4. Financial, environmental sustainability and conflict sensitivity would be improved;
5. LRCM is adequately equipped and its cyber security is at high level.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">K&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d planeras f&#xF6;r LRCM f&#xF6;r &#xE5;ren 2018-2021 med syfte att att utveckla intern kapacitet f&#xF6;r hantering av resultat, &#xF6;vervakning och rapportering samt f&#xF6;r att bidra till fr&#xE4;mjande r&#xE4;ttsstaten och det civila samh&#xE4;llet i Moldavien. Enligt RAF ska tv&#xE5; huvudm&#xE5;l st&#xF6;djas, enligt f&#xF6;ljande: 

1. Konsoliderad r&#xE4;ttsstat och demokrati i Moldavien genom: 
- Domare ska utses och befordras p&#xE5; ett tydligt och meritbaserat s&#xE4;tt. 
- Domare ska vara mer oberoende, opartiska och ansvariga. 
- Domstolen &#xE4;r effektivt organiserad och f&#xF6;rvaltad. 
- M&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter i Moldavien respekteras b&#xE4;ttre. 
- Den enskilda organisationen LRCM st&#xE4;rks f&#xF6;r att p&#xE5; ett effektivt och fritt s&#xE4;tt engagera sig i framtagandet av offentliga policys samt ge st&#xF6;d till och engagera medborgarna. 

2. LRCM ska vara en h&#xE5;llbar enskild organisation och en organisatorisk f&#xF6;rebild f&#xF6;r andra enskilda organisationer i Moldavien. Detta m&#xE5;l kommer att hanteras genom f&#xF6;ljande: 
1. LRCM ska ledas p&#xE5; ett effektivt s&#xE4;tt 
2. LRCMs kommunikation, synlighet och representation f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttras. 
3. LRCMs anst&#xE4;llda ska vara professionella och &#xF6;verens/enade 
4. Finansiell, milj&#xF6;m&#xE4;ssig h&#xE5;llbarhet och konfliktk&#xE4;nslighet f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttras. 
5. LRCM &#xE4;r tillr&#xE4;ckligt rustat och deras digitala s&#xE4;kerhet h&#xE5;ller h&#xF6;g standard.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centrul de Resurse Juridice din Moldova</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centrul de Resurse Juridice din Moldova</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-10" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-10" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moldova (the Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Legal and judicial development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">-53560.1441080111</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-01">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-28">-53560.1849152957</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/12136-grant-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/decision-lrcm.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020 was fully affected by COVID pandemic, therefore the activities implemented by the partner were re- prioritised; re-shuffled and in case of need postponed for 2021. During the entire year, the Embassy was in close contact with the organisation to evaluate the risks but also the likelihood of objectives to be achieved, considering the restrictions and the impossibility to have in-person events.
In the implementation year, the organisation went thorough institutional changes as more than half of the staff was fired after an internal review; the board was updated with new members and some important projects that supported a large part of the activities ended. As the current strategy comes to its end, the organisation was evaluated externally to assess the achieved progress but also the way forward. During the evaluation the political closeness to the pro-presidential party was discussed&#xA0;and risks&#xA0;related to this fact were assessed.&#xA0;The organisation also prepared a fund-raising Plan to evaluate the tools that could help to find needed resources for the organisation (the document was part of the Agreement with Sida).
All the annual reports were submitted to the Embassy with considerable delay, that is why the conclusion of performance is done in September 2021. The most important results are the following:&#xA0;
Justice and Anticorruption Forum.&#xA0;In September 2020, the LRCM hosted one of the most important communication platforms in the field of justice&#x2014;the Justice Reform and Anticorruption Forum. The forum participants discussed the priorities of the justice reform and the fight against corruption in the Republic of Moldova as viewed both by the Government, the Parliament and justice sector representatives from one side and by civil society and development partners from the other side. The forum was watched online by over 5,000 people. The LRCM prepared a summary of the event discussions. The 2021 Forum is scheduled to take place on 11-12 November 2021.
Training program for training of lawyers and journalists.From July through November 2020, the LRCM organized five training sessions on the freedom of expression for 17 legal professionals who would consult and defend the press. The trainings aimed at improving protection of the press and facilitating journalists&#x2019; access to information of public interest. A high number of the trained lawyers are already collaborating with independent media, such as ZdG and TV8.
Applied Democracy School.In February 2020, LRCM, in collaboration with EFOR Romania, hosted another edition of the Applied Democracy School. During the four-day school, 22 students had the opportunity to learn more about elections, justice, fight against corruption, human rights, and civil society. The participants also learned about internet manipulation techniques and how to protect themselves online.&#xA0;
Civic Coalition for Free and Fair Elections.In 2020, the LRCM was elected as member of the Board of the Civic Coalition for Free and Fair Elections (CALC). In this capacity, together with other members of the CALC Board, the LRCM monitored the election campaign and the presidential election of November 2020, reacted to violations and called on the Central Election Commission to ensure better voting conditions. In 2021 we also allocated an important part of our efforts to active participation in CALC during the parliamentary campaign.
MIP amendments.LRCM&apos;s Manual of Internal Policies was modified in June 2021 and several new policies were included, such as budgeting guidelines, project and risk management guidelines, IT security. A new chapter concerning the internship in our organization was also included. A green policy was integrated in our manual of internal policies in 2019, containing the main highlights about how to manage the office environmentally friendly and how to organize the events with respect to this category of rules. Gender equality is also governed by our manual of internal policies since 2020. The topic was covered during a training for the staff on gender equality and gender mainstream.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12136" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150105" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="6400000000" strategy-end-date="2027-12-31" strategy-start-date="2021-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with the Eastern Europe 2021-2027</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa 2021-2027</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
