<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-14147A0102-MDA-15180</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core support Women&apos;s Law Center 2020 -2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Core support Women&apos;s Law Center 2020 -2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Sverige kommer att st&#xF6;dja Kvinnors lagcentrum (WLC), en civil organisation fr&#xE5;n Moldavien, f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;randet av k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;dsaktiviteter f&#xF6;rsedda av WLCs Strategiska plan och RAF under april 2020 &#x2013; december 2022. K&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d beviljas f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka den institutionella kapaciteten och f&#xF6;r att st&#xF6;dja genomf&#xF6;randet av WLCs medell&#xE5;ng sikt Strategisk plan 2019&#x2014;2024 i bek&#xE4;mpning av v&#xE5;ld i hem och k&#xF6;nsrelaterat v&#xE5;ld i Moldavien. Det huvudsakliga m&#xE5;let och f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade resultat av k&#xE4;rnaktiviteterna &#xE4;r att Kvinnors lagcentrum bidrar med att bygga ett samh&#xE4;lle d&#xE4;r m&#xE4;nniskor kan leva fria fr&#xE5;n v&#xE5;ld och &#xF6;vergrepp och &#xE4;r s&#xE4;kra och skyddade i deras familjer och relationer. Det h&#xE4;r &#xE4;r det andra k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;det som erbjuds till WLC fr&#xE5;n Sverige.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden will support Women&apos;s Law Centre (WLC), a civil society organisation from Moldova, to implement core support activities provided by WLC&#x2019;s Strategic Plan and RAF during April 2020 - December 2022. Core support is granted to strengthen institutional capacities and to assist the implementation of WLC&#x2019;s medium term Strategic Plan 2019-2024 in fighting domestic and gender-based violence in Moldova. The main objective and expected result of core activities is that the Women&#x2019;s Law Center contributes to building a community where people live their life free of violence and abuse and are safe and protected in their families and relationships. This is the second core support offered to WLC by Sweden.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is the second WLC&apos;s intervention supported by Sweden in Moldova.The intervention is based on the institutional Strategic Plan 2019-2024. Sweden will support WLC via core support in 2020-2022. The objectives, indicators and measures of implementation are described clearly in the RAF and the institutional budget. The main objective is to support further institutional development of WLC with the final scope for the organisation: to be financial sustainable, to enhance institutional mechanisms and routines to ensure results&apos; sustainability over time, to deliver professional services for domestic violence victims and to advocate and promote best legal and institutional standards in preventing and fighting domestic violence at the national level.&#xA0;
Given the context and the field where the organisation is active, the lessons learned and the strategic goal, WLC&apos;s activity in the next six years (2019-2024) will focus on the following areas of intervention:
1. Prevention
Strategic objective 1: Raise public awareness about violence against women
Strategic objective 2: Build the capacity of professionals in the justice, social assistance and health care sectors
Awareness-raising events and information campaigns will be arranged aimed at changing social and behavioural norms and increasing the knowledge of different population groups (women in rural areas, older women, men and young people) about causes and consequences of gender-based violence and domestic violence, available legal remedies, assistance and protection services available to victims of gender-based violence and domestic violence. Youth hubs, librarians&apos; network, media outlets, individual professionals (through small grants) and survivors of DV will be involved in these activities as strategic partners (example: 16 days campaign, national conference on fighting DV, etc). &#xA0;&#xA0;
Capacity building of professionals will be organised to help them change their attitudes, perceptions and behaviour and will promote a cross-sector approach to domestic violence, communication between professionals throughout their intervention, and referral of identified cases to specialised services. With priority to address the&#xA0;acute need to build the capacity of judges, prosecutors, lawyers, police officers, social workers, psychologists and doctors to respond effectively to cases of domestic violence, including at the local level.&#xA0;
2. Protection
Strategic objective 3: Develop and consolidate services provided to victims of violence against women
WLC&#xA0; will continue to make efforts to develop holistic services for victims based on their needs, including: free telephone line for legal counselling of victims of gender-based violence and domestic violence; primary legal aid; qualified legal aid; social assistance, including economic empowerment of survivors of domestic violence; psychological counselling.
The&#xA0;assistance to women in detention (Rusca prison) will continue through legal counselling to convicted women, individual psychological counselling, therapy through art, legal assistance to women accused of DV crimes. &#xA0;
3. Researched based policies
Strategic objective 4: Policy development through direct contribution, lobbying and advocacy on the basis of evidence from research and analysis
WLC&apos;s strategic priority in the coming years will remain the promotion at policy and legislative level of initiatives based on the respect for the rights of victims of domestic violence, ensuring their free access to justice, ensuring their access to high-quality specialised services of assistance and protection and the exercise of due diligence by authorities. One of the main objective is to continue active advocacy for Istanbul&#xA0; Convention&apos;s ratification and its proper implementation in the Republic of Moldova as well as lobbying for the alignment of the legal framework with international standards (examples: Femicide Report, Economic Abuse Report, etc.).&#xA0;
&#xA0;4. Organisational development
Strategic objective 5: Increase the efficiency and effectiveness of the organisation
From 2016 to 2019, WLC being supported by Sweden, invested enormously in the development of the organisation and each team member. The organisation developed internal operational procedures, built the capacity of team members, and set up comprehensive mechanisms for the management, monitoring and evaluation of implemented activities. In the next strategic cycle, WLC aims to continue the development of the organisation by maximizing the team&apos;s potential, increasing its efficiency and effectiveness including of the board, promoting the organisational values and culture within the team. Financial sustainability and diversification of funding sources will continue to be one of the strategic priorities. Conflict and environment perspective will be strategic priorities to be developed and integrated.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Womens Law Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Womens Law Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-02-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moldova (the Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ending violence against women and girls</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.1 - Avsev&#xE4;rt minska alla former av v&#xE5;ld och d&#xF6;dligt v&#xE5;ld &#xF6;verallt.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.1 - Significantly reduce all forms of violence and related death rates everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">329524.5368373189</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">329524.5368373189</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-01">306882.851775</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-28">329524.5368373189</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/14147_AgreementWCL.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core support Women&apos;s Law Center 2020 -2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/14147_AmendmentWCL.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core support Women&apos;s Law Center 2020 -2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/14147_DecisionAmendmentWLC.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core support Women&apos;s Law Center 2020 -2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/14147_DecisionWLC.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core support Women&apos;s Law Center 2020 -2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WLC commitment and advocacy work on national level has determined political leaders, members of Parliament and Government to prioritize the issue of domestic violence and step up to ratification of Istanbul Convention. Prevention and combating violence against women and girls has become a national priority in 2021. Thus, on October 14, 2021 Parliament of Republic of Moldova endorsed Council of Europe Convention on preventing and combating violence against women and domestic violence (Istanbul Convention).In addition, WLC designed and organized a big public campaign about the impact and benefits of the Istanbul Convention ratification targeting members of Parliament, members of Government, political parties and various legislative platforms. Within this framework, 8 explanatory cards with the benefits of the Convention aimed at bringing the benefits of the ratification of the Istanbul Convention closer to the general public.

The 2 Law Package on compatibility of Moldovan legislation with the Istanbul Convention  at the Ministry of Justice, authority responsible to promote
amendments to the codes has been included in the Government Action Plan for years 2021-2022.7 The draft law amends key provisions related to domestic violence in the Criminal Code, Criminal Procedure Code, Civil Procedure Code, Contravention Code, etc.

WLC disseminated among the general public information on measures available to prevent acts of violence against women. WLC&apos;s awareness raising activities reached 2.253.575 citizens in 34 districts of the Republic of Moldova, including Transnistria region and UTA Gagauzia. The number of reached citizens has almost doubled in 2021 compared to activities in 2020 (1.253.575 citizens in 24 districts of the Republic of Moldova).

Greater connectivity and national collective action on preventing and combating GBV and domestic violence. WLC as a lead organization together with member organization of National Coalition prepared the Alternative Report for the III Universal Periodic Review Process (UPR). The report describes the progress made by our country in terms of preventing and combating gender-based violence and formulated recommendations based on the challenges faced by women in accessing justice and assistance and protection services.

Agents of change are empowered and have increased capacities to build communities free of gender-based violence and modeling collective action to change social norms around domestic violence. Over 2021, WLC empowered through trainings, workshops, supporting local initiatives through (small grants) various agents of change, such as librarians, young people, grassroots activists, journalists to help the communities enhance its response to gender based and domestic violence. It is also designed to help improve the way people react, act and help the members of communities to report GBV and access the services for people affected by gender based violence and domestic violence.

In 2021 WLC assisted and supported 859 women experiencing domestic violence with its range of services: legal, psychological, social assistance and economic empowerment. WLC appointed lawyers who represented the interests of victims and continues to represent them in 49 cases, which means that approximately 6% of all victims of domestic violence registered in 2021 received qualified legal assistance. Of the total number of cases, 56% are criminal cases, 24% are misdemeanor cases and 16% are civil cases, 4% are requests to the ECtHR.In 2021, the ECtHR issued one( 1) decisions on the request made by the CDF lawyer in the interest of a victim of sexual violence. 12 victims benefited from economic empowerment. The vocational counselor identified the vocational needs of each beneficiary. Thus, 7 people benefited of professional training studies (psychologist / psychotherapist, confectioner, nail artist), 3 people benefited from technical support for the realization of hand-made products and works (making wax candles, painting paintings on canvas, embroidery machine). 

WLC strongly focused on building the capacity of professionals to respond effectively to cases of domestic violence. Throughout 2021, WLC organized 43 training sessions on application of domestic violence legislation (10 trainings in 2020) for 1180 professionals : judges, prosecutors, their assistants and counselors, police officers, doctors, social workers, paralegals, etc. Among the participants, 694 were women (134 in 2020). The intervention response of WLC in 2021 has strongly expanded compared to 2020, with a triple increase in its intervention capacity compared to 2020.

In 2021 a new generation of future prosecutors and judges, graduates of the National Institute of Justice participated in the public lesson Womens access to Justice. Istanbul Convention organised by the National Institute of Justice in partnership with WLC on the importance of ratification of the Council of Europe Convention on preventing and combating violence against women and violence. This activity was designed both as awareness raising activity and increasing the capacities of the professionals to respond properly to GBV. 35 future judges and 40 future prosecutors graduates of the National Institute of Justice were provided with information and insights on the provisions of IC and the measures necessary to be undertaken by the state.

National Social assistance system aware and empowered to collect the data on GBV. In 2021 WLC supported Ministry of Health, Labour and Social Protection (MHLSP) efforts in strengthening the capacities of the specialists at territorial level in the field of social assistance responsible for completing the statistical form no. 9 &quot;Domestic violence.

WLC have released the First National Analysis of Femicide cases in Republic of Moldova. Analysis of Femicide cases for the years 2016-2019 have broadened analysis of gender-based violence and domestic violence. The aim is to provide a national context and trends, a concise overview describing the phenomenon, its prevalence in the country, the different social contexts in which it occurs and the prevailing risk factors. Femicide continues to be a pressing issue in Moldova and requires immediate attention to address the societal root causes of oppression and violence against women. There are a number of emerging trends that have been highlighted throughout this report that must be addressed. The aim of the study is to know the peculiarities of femicide in the Republic of Moldova, to improve the institutional response mechanisms to cases of gender-based violence and domestic violence.

WLC worked to identify the best way that information technologies can be used to support women experiencing domestic abuse. WLC cooperated with a group of women specialized in IT, who conducted an analysis of the problem and proposed several IT solutions for consideration. In 2021, WLC worked to develop a mobile application allowing emergency calls and containing information about legal remedies and services for women suffering from domestic violence. The work will be finalised in 2022.

Different Models. Different speeches (TED TALK 2021) - a unique event to raise awareness about postive gender roles, social norms and gender-based violence was organised by WLC in 2021 entitled  Altfel de modele. Altfel de Discursuri (Different Models. Diferent speeches). The speeches of the 8 participants (actor, priest, women police officers, couple of entrepreneurs, young father, librarian, young girl activist) focused on topics such as: gender equality, the role and power of the community, family harmony, the role of the church in preventing domestic violence, but also education and relationships between parents and children. All - to draw attention to preventing and combating the phenomenon of domestic violence and gender-based violence, given that in society there are still preconceptions and stereotypes, which hinder the harmonious development of each. The event had public live stream.

Social Hub - Social hub is a new concept promoted by WLC to involve as many young people as possible to promote zero tolerance to domestic violence throughout the country. In 2021 we involved 15 young people, while in 2020 we involved a group of 10 boys and girls. WLC discussed the causes of domestic violence and gender stereotypes, as well as solutions to address these issues and ways to prevent the phenomenon. In 2021 we extended the initiative by adding the subgranting component. Participants in the social hub were invited to submit small grant proposals on domestic violence prevention, best and sustainable ideas being supported and implemented in 2021. Thus 10 youth led initiatives were implemented by 14 young people, out of which 11 girls and 3 boys in 6 regions Chiinu, Orhei, Briceni, tefan-Vod, S&#xEE;ngera, H&#xEE;nceti. More than 1500 young people were informed about gender equality and gender based violence, thus becoming aware of gender inequalities and gender based violence and getting info and tools to become active agents in promoting human rights in their communities, and in preventing and combating gender based violence.

The Practical Guide for Paralegals is a new tool developed jointly by WLC for paralegals. The guide aims to generate a deeper understanding of the phenomenon of domestic violence, to encourage new thinking, and to cultivate zero tolerance for violence. This practical tool was developed on the basis of the most frequently asked questions by paralegals during the trainings and mentorate sessions. The guide covers practical aspects of intervention and referral. The Guide will focus on how to address multiple needs of survivor in the manner that will ensure the safest and most effective way. The Guide includes an updated list of support organizations, and model of documents and other relevant instruments.

Training manual on forensic doctors intervention in cases of domestic violence was developed and published. The training manual was set to cover the theoretical aspects of the optional Course on domestic and gender-based violence taught at the University of Medicine and Pharmacy Nicolae Testemitanu to 6th year medical students and to medical practitioners within their Continuous Medical Training program.

The standard operating procedure (Standard Operating Procedure on the response of the Forensic Medicine Centre to cases of domestic violence, including as a form of violence against women) is set to align the intervention of Forensic Medicine Centre (CML) employees to the relevant national and international legal framework, in particular to provisions of Law No. 45 on preventing and combating domestic violence, with regards to the competencies of CML judicial experts and the procedure to be followed when conducting forensic medical, psychiatric and clinical-psychological interventions /procedures on domestic violence victims.

WCL empowered, via a 2 day workshop, 20 mass media representatives (TV, Radio, online media, bloggers, etc) by enhancing their knowledge and emphasizing the important role of media in reporting about violence against women and domestic violence in a gender-sensitive and non stereotyped manner (for example, by depicting the case as crimes of passion). WLC awarded 6 professional journalists, out of 19, with the most prominent articles / journalistic reports, on topics of success stories of women victims of domestic violence, the rehabilitation process of aggressors, gaps and shortcomings in the system, the importance of ratifying the Convention in Istanbul, and gender stereotypes and prejudices. All awarded journalists are women.

WLC organized trainings for 25 librarians in order to deepen their knowledge about the complexity of the phenomenon of domestic violence : what forms of violence take place, what protection tools exist for the victim, what stereotypes fuel domestic violence and what control tactics the aggressor and the victim&apos;s survival strategies. Due to Grant Programme 2021 dedicated to Librarians, 11 librarians implemented 11 community projects by organising 44 activities with participation of 417 people. Activities reached out 1766 people from 31 communities throughout the country.

First International Conference on Preventing and Combating Violence against Girls and Women - the event has a hybrid format was with the participation of 40 high-ranking speakers, such as the President of the country, Ms. Maia Sandu and other representatives of public authorities, valuable international and national experts in the field, development partners, inspirational activists, public leaders, mass media representative. Conference was built on the 4 Pillars of Istanbul Convention and aiming to address issues related to the international and national context of violence against girls and women and domestic violence, the problems faced by girls and women, the commitments of the authorities, but also the need to involve everyone in creating a healthy society for each and every one.

IMPULS Programme - out of the 5 beneficiaries receiving grants, 3 beneficiaries representing public authorities had also participated in the first year of IMPULS program implementation, having decided to continue the work begun in the previous year and to implement follow-up projects that would further develop the results achieved therein. Two new agents of change joined the program, a representative of an NGO in Transnistria and the coordinator of the Life without Violence National Coalition, with project proposals focused on providing trainings and informative session for both the victims of domestic violence and the specialists providing them with assistance.

Support for the MIA - the Embassy supported in 2021 via WLC 4 short term national experts to help the new management of the MIA to design the new priority policies in the field of internal affairs; to assess the results and progress in areas like migration, financial accountability, anti-corruption, strategic planning, etc.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="14147" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150105" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="6400000000" strategy-end-date="2027-12-31" strategy-start-date="2021-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with the Eastern Europe 2021-2027</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa 2021-2027</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
