<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12719A0101-MDA-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One UN Joint Action in Human Rights in the Transnistrian region 2019-2022 (III)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">One UN Joint Action in Human Rights in the Transnistrian region 2019-2022 (III)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention&apos;s objectives are based on Thomas Hammarberg&apos;s report on human rights in the Transnistrian region delivered in 2013 and its follow-up conclusions formulated in 2018. This intervention is built on the results and lessons learned in the previous project supported by Sweden in 2016-2018 in the Transnistrian region of the Republic of Moldova (a breakaway region).&#xA0;&#xA0;
The project intends to foster commitment at the level of the decision-makers in the Transnistrian region and civil society for human rights-oriented reforms in general and particularly in the area of disability, child&#x2019;s rights, Roma, rights of people living with and affected by HIV, rights of prisoners, and people in prisons, vulnerable women and rights of people who use drugs, facilitating the establishment of multidimensional cooperation, cross-river knowledge exchange and development based on best practices existing on both banks of River Nistru (the left bank being the Transnistrian region). The Confidence Building approach represents the main tool to connect professionals, individuals and institutions (when possible) from both banks to build trust between parties in the protracted conflict (the Transnistrian post conflict situation). &#xA0;
The actual assessment is that duty bearers (in areas mentioned above), including service providers at multiple levels lack knowledge of human rights of the vulnerable ones and implementation capacity, encountering human and economic resources capacity gaps. The rights holders are not aware of their rights and do not participate in the decision-making processes affecting their lives. Hence, the involvement of the civil society in developing regulatory frameworks, in changing perceptions, in developing and piloting transferable services to the de facto authorities, in monitoring the implementation of human rights commitments of the duty bearers and advocating for ensuring the social inclusion of the most vulnerable ones is imperative. It is of paramount importance to enhance the capacity of organizations from both sides for joint programme work, as it is quite limited, based on priorities and development needs of both sides of the Nistru river. Thus, the programme will contribute to reducing inequalities for women, men and children in the Transnistrian region (impact) by ensuring that vulnerable human rights holders are empowered to exercise their rights and duty bearers respect, protect and fulfil human rights to a larger extent (outcome).
The project&#x2019;s integrated approach targeting to work at the individual, institutional and societal levels by increasing the capacities of rights holders to exercise their rights (Output 1), increasing the capacities of duty bearers to fulfil their human rights obligations (Output 2) and enhancing the human rights culture in the Transnistrian region (Output 3) will lead to creating an enabling environment for an effective exercise of human rights of vulnerable groups in the Transnistrian region.
The following results are expected to be achieved:Output 1. Increased capacities of vulnerable rights holders to exercise their human rights- Enhanced human rights skills and knowledge of vulnerable rights holders- Strengthened institutional capacity of partner CSOs and informal groups - Improved service delivery of CSOsOutput 2. Increased capacities of duty bearers to fulfil their human rights obligations- Enhanced human rights compliant regulatory framework in the region - Strengthened human rights institutions: Ombudsman institution - Improved service delivery of duty bearersOutput 3. Enhanced human rights culture in the Transnistrian region- Enhanced human rights capacity of the media- Raised human rights awareness
The work on redressing the human rights situation in the Transnistrian region is aligned with a number of SDGs: SDG1 (no poverty), SDG3 (good health and wellbeing), SDG4 (quality education), SDG5 (gender equality), SDG10 (reduced inequalities), SDG16 (peace, justice and strong institutions). The Programme also aims to contribute to the implementation of the National Human Rights Action Plan 2018-2022. Taking into account the role of the Bureau for Reintegration Policies in identifying and including of human rights priority issues on the negotiation agenda, the project will periodically update the Bureau for Reintegration Policies during the project&apos;s Steering Committee meetings and ad-hoc when needed with regard to the developments in the human rights field generated with the support of the Programme and the human rights situation in Transnistria in general.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP, UNODC, UNAIDS, OHCHR, UNICEF and IOM have applied to Sida for funding of 29 089 484 SEK to carry out the &quot;One UN joint action to strengthen human rights in the Transnistrian region of the Republic of Moldova&quot; during the period 2019-2022. The Programme&#x2019;s integrated approach, based on Thomas Hammarberg&#x2019;s findings from 2013 and 2018, intends to work at the individual, institutional and societal levels by increasing the capacities of rights holders to exercise their rights (Output 1), increasing the capacities of duty bearers to fulfil their human rights obligations (Output 2) and enhancing the human rights culture in the Transnistrian region (Output 3). This will lead to a favorable environment for an effective exercise of human rights of the following vulnerable groups in the Transnistrian region: people leaving with HIV, Roma communities, people who use drugs, domestic violence victims, children in contact with the law, inmates and former inmates. The UN Agencies partnering within the One UN Fund will implement the intervention jointely with local CSOs from both banks of Nistru river to increase confidence and trust between people and relevant stakeholders.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNDP, UNODC, UNAIDS, OHCHR, UNICEF och IOM har gemensamt (genom ett One UN uppl&#xE4;gg) s&#xF6;kt finansiering 29 089 484 SEK f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra &quot;FN: s gemensamma &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rd f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka de m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheterna i Transnistrien-regionen i Republiken Moldavien&quot; under perioden 2019&#x2013;2022. Programmets integrerade tillv&#xE4;gag&#xE5;ngss&#xE4;tt (One UN programming), &#xE4;r baserat p&#xE5; Thomas Hammarbergs rekommendationer fr&#xE5;n 2013 och 2018, och avser att arbeta p&#xE5; individuell, institutionell och samh&#xE4;llelig niv&#xE5; f&#xF6;r att uppn&#xE5;:
Resultat 1: att &#xF6;ka m&#xE4;nniskors f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;ga att nyttja och bli medvetna om sina r&#xE4;ttigheter.
Resultat 2: se till ansvariga beslutsfattare uppfyller de krav som st&#xE4;lls p&#xE5; dem vad g&#xE4;ller m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter.
Resultat 3: &#xF6;ka f&#xF6;rst&#xE5;elsen och kunskapen vad g&#xE4;ller m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter.

Denna ansats kommer att leda till en gynnsam milj&#xF6; f&#xF6;r ett effektivt inf&#xF6;rande av m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter f&#xF6;r f&#xF6;ljande s&#xE5;rbara grupper i Transnistrien-regionen: m&#xE4;nniskor som lever med HIV, romer, personer som anv&#xE4;nder droger, offer f&#xF6;r v&#xE5;ld i n&#xE4;ra relationer, barn och ungdomar med kriminell bakgrund, f&#xE5;ngar och tidigare kriminella vuxna. De FN organ som deltar i &#x201D;One UN&#x201D;-fonden kommer att genomf&#xF6;ra projekten i samarbete med lokala enskilda organisationer (EO) fr&#xE5;n b&#xE5;da sidorna av Dnestrfloden, i syfte att &#xF6;ka f&#xF6;rtroendet mellan m&#xE4;nniskor och relevanta akt&#xF6;rer.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moldova (the Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="10.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10.2 - By 2030, empower and promote the social, economic and political inclusion of all, irrespective of age, sex, disability, race, ethnicity, origin, religion or economic or other status.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">10.2 - Till 2030 m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra och verka f&#xF6;r att alla m&#xE4;nniskors, oavsett &#xE5;lder, k&#xF6;n, funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning, ras, etnicitet, ursprung, religion eller ekonomisk eller annan st&#xE4;llning, blir inkluderade i det sociala, ekonomiska och politiska livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3 - By 2030, end the epidemics of AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria and neglected tropical diseases and combat hepatitis, water-borne diseases and other communicable diseases.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.3 - Senast 2030 utrota epidemierna av aids, tuberkulos, malaria och f&#xF6;rsummade tropiska sjukdomar samt bek&#xE4;mpa hepatit, vattenburna sjukdomar och andra smittsamma sjukdomar.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">972782.2840766083</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1225666.1997676364</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">934116.6378926567</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">972782.2840766083</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1225666.1997676366</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">934116.6378926567</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">3076331.602491</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-28">972782.2840766083</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-28">1225666.1997676364</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The interaction with the Sustainable (Community) Development Platform (SCDP) wasreactivated and steps undertaken to expand its membership to 30 CSOs and 6 initiative groups,representing or working with Programme&#x2019;s target vulnerable groups - people living with HIV/AIDS, people using drugs, Roma, victims of domestic violence&#xA0; etc. Based on the internal need assessment undertaken at the end of the previous phase, the institutional capacity building process was initiated. In the reported period, the capacities of right holders were developed in two directions: 1) institutional capacities and 2) thematic knowledge. Thus, around 100 representatives of NGOs from 9 localities from the left bank have increased their capacities in the area of IT literacy, leadership and team motivation and effective communication. Participants included representatives of PwDs, Roma community, organisations working with PLWH, PWUDs, or victims of domestic violence, as wellas media. Also, as a result of the Programme&#x2019;s interventions, the capacity of the members and partners of the Sustainable (Community) Development Platform to work together and plan joint actions was increased through coordination meetings, organized on the left and right banks of the Nistru River. Children&#x2019;s capacities in applying preventive measures of conflict behaviour among adolescents, have been raised at the &#x201C;A.S. Makarenko&#x201D; school. The abilities of local specialists to provide better qualitytraining to children in this institution were improved by renovating and equipping a training room which provides space for interactive learning and leisure activities.Additionally, in the reported period representatives of vulnerable groups have improved access to community services. 95 persons had access to PrEP (pre-exposure prophylaxis) on HIV, a doubled result compared to the target. 35 women living with HIV were part of the mentoring program, aimed at empowering women through capacitating them on knowing and fulfilling their rights, decreasing self-stigma and being psycho-socially supported. Based on the referral scheme established duringthe previous phase of the Programme, over 193 PWUD and SW were referred by the de-facto structures to CSOs in Ribnita, Camenca and Bender. Also, through the calls received at the &#x201C;Trust Line 0800 99800&#x201D; for victims of domestic violence, supported by the Programme, 34 SOS cases of women victims of domestic violence were opened, and those cases were referred to or managed together with specialised NGOs from Transnistrian region. The awareness of the population on both banks of the Nistru River, especially the vulnerable groups, was increased on the subjects related to the rights of PwDs, Roma community, people living with HIV/AIDS and victims of domestic violence. This was achieved through organization of five communication campaigns, 124 Facebook posts and two articles/human stories on UNDP Exposure web site and one - on UNAIDS regional website, as well as four photo galleries on UN Flickr web platform. Additionally, the awareness of the duty-bearers has been increased by developing, editing, printing and disseminate 6000 booklets on HIV and LEAs and guiding procedures for police officers in Russian and Romanian languages. In line with the Programme&#x2019;s output of increasing the capacities of duty bearers to fulfil their human rights obligations and in preparation for the adjustment of the human-rights-compliant regulatory framework, 50 policy documents in the area of HIV/AIDS were reviewed in a consultative manner and validated by stakeholders on the left bank. Also, the first draft of the new National HIV strategy forthe period 2021-2025 was developed with the participation of about 150 national stakeholders from both banks of Nistru River. The draft report on the normative framework in the Transnistrian region pertaining to justice for children in contact with the law was finalized in June. The report closely scrutinizes compliance of the framework with international standards and norms, and&#xA0; points at gaps in policies and processes that need to be addressed.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="12719" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.0" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
