<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5503003601-MDA-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Engaging Citizens, Empowering Communities</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Engaging Citizens, Empowering Communities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;det syftar till att st&#xE4;rka det civila samh&#xE4;llet i Moldavien f&#xF6;r    att fr&#xE4;mja en demokratisk utveckling. EEF &#xE4;mnar bidra till &#xF6;kat       inflytande i beslutsfattande processer genom att st&#xE4;rka deltagandet i lokala kommuner, genom att bla fr&#xE4;mja professionell och kvalitativ    media, transparata och fria val, bemyndiga unga medborgare. EEF       beviljas k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d pga god intern styrning och f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;ga uppn&#xE5; resultat.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the intervention is to strengthen CSO in Moldova to  promote democratic development. EEF contributes to increased          influence in decision-making processes by enhancing participation in  local communities, by promote qualitative media, transparent &amp; free   elections, empower young citizens etc. EEF awarded core support       because of good internal control &amp; ability to achieve results.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">East Europe Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moldova (the Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">886406.9494304835</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">921206.1659399373</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">728873.5987405065</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">794474.036990023</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">321190.5568865775</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">886406.9494304835</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">921206.1659399373</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">728873.5987405065</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">794474.036990023</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">321190.5568865775</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">-176649.1166491166</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">3906857.391895</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-06-28">886406.9494304835</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-06-28">460603.0829699687</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">460603.0829699687</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-07-28">364436.7993702532</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-11-28">364436.7993702532</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-05-28">296584.5325234599</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">497889.5044665631</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-28">321190.5568865775</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-28">-176649.0721890722</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2016Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: During the reporting period EEF awarded and successfully managed 202 grants to Moldovan NGOs using the joint contribution of the Government of Sweden, Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Denmark, European Union, United Nations Democracy Fund, Swiss Agency for Development and Cooperation, UN Women and United States Agency for International Development through FHI 360. Apart from grants, EEF provided technical assistance to relevant partner NGOs and facilitated cooperation and dialogue between civil society and the Government. During the project implementation, EEF worked and coordinated closely with the Prime-minister&#x2019;s Office, the National Anti-Corruption Center, the Central Electoral Commission, State Chancellery, Ministry of Youth and Sports, Ministry of Social Protection and Family, Ministry of Education, Ministry of Economy, Local Public Authorities, and international organizations, such as EU Delegation to Moldova, OSCE Mission to Moldova, UNDP Moldova, UN Women, Council of Europe, UNICEF, EBRD, FHI 360, USAID and others.   Rooted in the principles of human rights and gender equality, the program entailed seven interconnected components, which were implemented through a combination of grants, technical assistance and direct operating activities.    Major results achieved:  At the impact level, the project made a tangible contribution to the civil society participation in governance and local community development. According to the USAID Civil Society Development Index, the Advocacy Indicator of Moldovan CSO improved from 4.1 in 2012 to 3.9 in 2015. The Index provides concrete examples of successful advocacy projects implemented with program support.     Building on its coalescing experience, EEF enabled major NGO platforms to influence and oversee the implementation of key public policies in such areas as human rights, justice, equality and non-discrimination, social protection, civil society development and anti-corruption.  The National Participation Council, supported during 2012-2014, mapped on a monthly basis 180 policy and decision making documents, supporting members to rapidly identify key policy areas that may require civil society input.  NPC participated in key decision making processes and intervened with over 199 notes and comments in order to promote the public interest and ensure the quality of the policies. Approximately 12% of NPC contributions were accepted by the cabinet of Ministers.  The NGO Council, supported during 2014-2015, facilitated the advocacy efforts of NGOs around the 7 priorities articulated by Moldovan civil society: contracting of social services, percentage designation mechanism, gender equality, volunteerism, transparency of media ownership, anti-corruption legislative package, anti-tobacco legislation. These advocacy efforts led to the approval by the Government and Parliament of corresponding policies.   The Consortium for monitoring the implementation of the EU Association Agenda, supported in 2016, prevented and conciliated various gaps existing between the Moldovan Government commitments under the EU-Moldova Association Agreement (including the DCFTA) and policy priorities in 2016, while endorsing targeted reforms and policy dialogue between stakeholders. This platform provided expertise to the government on the following areas: business environment, banking and energy, public procurement, decentralization and public administration, local democracy and local autonomy, fiscal decentralization, judiciary and human rights.   Four thematic NGO platforms (Roma, persons with disabilities, older people, youth), supported in 2016, managed to produce 30 key policy analyses from the perspective of equality and non-discrimination, comprising about 20 key public policies. Most of the submitted analytical notes and policy recommendations are still under consideration by respective decision makers. All NGO groups are actively engaging with decision makers in policy debates to ensure policy recommendations are adopted. To date, the platforms influenced and convinced the public institutions to integrate the recommendations into three selected public policies: The National Employment Strategy 2017-2021, Gender Equality Strategy 2017-2021, Roma Action Plan in the Social and Education fields related to Holocaust.   In 2013-2015 EEF supported seven think-tanks to develop innovative approaches to government effectiveness and transfer expertise to relevant actors in the area of strengthening good governance. Examples of think tank expertise used by the Government include but are not limited to the following: the new Law on the General Prosecutor&#x2019;s Office based on the Concept on Prosecutorial Reform, produced by the Legal Resources Center with project co-funding; the Fair Play database produced by the Center for Analysis and Prevention of Corruption was used by the National Integrity Commission in checking the conflict of interest of public officials; the concept of paternity leave along  the gender equality gaps, identified by Center Partnership for Development, were used during the adoption of relevant legislation; Transparency International Moldova developed a new methodology on monitoring the National Integrity System in Moldova, which was extensively used by the National Anticorruption Center in developing the new Anticorruption Strategy.    EEF supported the civil society organizations in raising the awareness on European values and standards and organizing debates about the future development path of the country. These activities have been primarily conducted in Gagauzia, Balti region and rural areas in the south of Moldova. The program enabled the network of European Interactive Centers to continue their activities in promoting EU standards and information about EU-Moldova bilateral relations by engaging directly with the population groups (students, youth, women, teachers, local government officials, business groups, and other). Support was provided to develop and disseminate information about European integration and EU-Moldova relations, including the portal www.infoeuropa.md, four testimonials on benefits of EU integration in Romanian and Russian, covering Estonia,  Poland , Lithuania;  and Romania , reaching out to over 680300 viewers on TV and online.     During the reporting period, EEF focused on bringing together community-based organizations and local authorities to enhance cooperation and mobilize them around stringent local issues in the most reliable manner. Over the period 2012-2015 EEF supported 13 community development grants, bringing together 24 grass&#x2013;roots NGOs from both banks of Nistru in one common space aiming to contribute to building trust between people on both sides of the Dniester and empowering community actors in Moldova and Transnistrian region in bringing social changes and mobilize their communities around stringent issues, involving local authorities and businesses.  Grantees mobilized more than 2000 people around 18 initiatives in 52 communities. Over 450 people from the both banks benefited from training and workshops on advocacy, community mobilization and networking.   In the second phase, EEF enabled 15 community based NGOs to mobilize over 6000 people, including the most disadvantaged, around local development using human rights principles of information and participation, equality and non-discrimination and accountability. EEF partners (i) facilitated the establishment of inclusive local community groups; (ii) empowered the groups to identify community priorities (iii) engaged communities in public oversight activities (iv) mobilized local resources (v) facilitated the implementation of community development projects.   EEF made significant efforts to mobilize NGOs, national and local authorities and the communities to advance consumer rights protection in Moldova. Three regional consumer assistance centers provided counselling to around 2500 consumers, related to food safety issues. Over 25000 persons were informed about their consumer rights. Fifteen NGOs joined the Food Safety Alliance, which is a forum for consumer protection in food safety, created with EEF support.   EEF made significant strides to advance the electoral rights of persons with disabilities. Advocacy efforts of the working group on the rights of persons with disabilities contributed to the approval by the Central Electoral Commission (CEC) of the Regulation on the accessibility of polling stations in 2016. Previously, in 2015, EEF enabled NGOs to successfully advocate for the adoption by the CEC of the Declaration on the accessibility of the electoral process. As a result, accessibility of polling stations increased from 33% in 2014 Parliamentary Elections to 64% during 2016 Presidential Elections. With support from EEF, the CEC successfully piloted and applied innovative methods enabling the persons with visual impairments to vote directly, without support of other persons, using magnifying glasses and special matrix for the ballot paper. For this innovation, the partner organization, INFONET received the 2015 UN Human Rights Award.   The constant pressure of the Civic Coalition for Free and Fair Elections since 2012, determined the Moldovan MPs to adopt on 19 March 2015 the amendments on reforming the political party finance. Adopted amendments enabled the CEC to increase campaign financed oversight and instituted sanctions for failure to comply with reporting requirements.   Sustained advocacy efforts conducted by the Civil Society Platform for Gender Equality, supported by EEF since 2014, contributed to the adoption in April 2016, of the legislation that enforces the 40% gender quota along with sanctions for non-compliance, paternity leave and other measures conducive to greater gender equality in politics. In addition, most of the Gender Equality Platform&#x2019;s recommendations, developed and submitted with EEF support prior to the 2016 Universal Periodic Review of the Republic of Moldova, were covered in the OHCHR report and reflected in the recommendations submitted by various State Parties.    Women&#x2019;s political clubs in 5 regions (Briceni, Straseni, Telenesti, Cimislia, and Cahul) trained over 600 prospective women candidates and facilitated their dialogue with political parties before the 2015 local elections. After the elections, over 100 elected women were equipped with knowledge on good governance and gender equality. Gender audits of 25 localities provided pertinent recommendations to local public authorities, which are paving the road to further mainstreaming gender equality at local level. A comprehensive analysis on the resolution of electoral disputes, finalized by Promo-Lex with program support in 2016, paved the way towards identifying challenges, articulating training needs of judges, election servants, as well as the recommendations conducive to a fairer electoral process.  During the period of 2012-2016 EEF worked to support the media self-regulatory mechanisms in order to ensure a more ethical and deontological approach, to offer qualitative media products to the consumers. In this sense, the Independent Press Council staged-up its work and enhanced its reputation. Awareness raising activities empowered media consumers to submit complaints to the Independent Press Council whenever their rights as information consumers were violated. The IPC issued and widely disseminated 3 guidelines on media ethics, with specific focus on human rights and non-discrimination.  During the reporting period the IPC received 94 complaints, examined and issued 71 decisions with recommendations to the respective media outlets and to regulatory bodies, such as the Coordination Broadcasting Council. Approximately 75% of the decisions issued by the IPC have been implemented by the media outlets concerned.     In order to scrutinize media biases in Moldova, EEF closely cooperated with media monitoring NGOs, namely the Center for Independent Journalism, Association of Independent Press. NGOs monitored several dimensions of media behavior, including respect of ethical standards, coverage of diversity. Findings and recommendations were widely disseminated to various actors, including the Independent Press Council, Broadcasting Coordinating Council, media, NGOs, Central Electoral Commission, etc. Continuous support for the news portal www.stiripozitive.eu was offered in order to promote community initiatives . The portal covered over 700 subjects while the total number of visitors increased to 2,581,275.     During the years of 2014-2016 EEF supported nine NGOs that are running social enterprises aiming to assist specific vulnerable groups (people with physical and mental disabilities, children with migrating parents, single mothers etc.).  Assistance included facilitating experience sharing and strengthening the capacity of beneficiaries to run sustainable social businesses. To date, through supported social enterprises, 285 vulnerable persons improved their social and economic conditions through free meals, vocational training and other opportunities. In addition, the social enterprises managed to employ 63 vulnerable persons.      EEF supported the development of 8 YouthBanks in 8 rayons across the country. Over a period of 4 years, the developments within YouthBank Program have begun to affect young people&#x2019;s lives and improving community life. The initiative had direct impact on the lives of over 10,000 young people from more than 100 rural communities. The YouthBank model advanced the associative culture of youth in targeted communities, as the number of young people involved in civic associations increased from 36 in 2012 to 934 by the end of 2016. Equality and non-discrimination is a fundamental principle of youth banks&#x2019; activities. Thus, at least 15% of the current Youth Bank members are from vulnerable groups (ethnic and linguistic minorities, people with precarious social and economic backgrounds, deprived rural areas, children of migrant parents, young people with disabilities, ethnic minorities). YouthBanks program increased substantially the voluntary engagement of young women and men in development initiatives, which shifted from approximately 1000 youth in 2013 to more than 30000 youth by the end of 2016.  To empower youth and strengthen access to quality education, EEF worked with the Ministry of Education, to implement the eTwinning Plus Program in our country. In 2016, the number of teachers registered on the platform reached 200, out of which 71% initiated teaching projects with their peers in EU countries.  Republic of Moldova received 22 European Quality Labels awarded for the great projects examples of collaborative work and excellent demonstrated achievements.   During the reporting period EEF up-scaled support to NGO initiatives that contributed to the inclusion of vulnerable groups and the respect of their social and economic rights. The following vulnerable groups benefitted from project support: children living in residential institutions (30), victims of domestic violence (254), children with special needs (2000), people with special needs and elderly people (1500). All program interventions sought to empower individuals and work with the institutions in order to better address the needs of right holders. In this regard, during 2012-2016, EEF supported 22 CSOs to promote adequate support of local authorities and inhabitants in targeted communities for the integration in social life of vulnerable people through capacity building and advocacy campaigns. The local administration&#x2019;s involvement was considerable, providing in-kind, logistical and service provision support. This contribution is estimated to an average of 70% of the total amount of each initiative (8 projects) that was implemented at the local level.     In addition, each EEF partner applied various advocacy tools to engage central authorities in protecting the rights of vulnerable persons and ensuring sustainability of the interventions. One of the main results in terms of engaging duty bearers towards addressing vulnerable groups&#x2019; problems was the early intervention service introduced by &#x201C;Voinicel&#x201D; Center, which brought a new model of early intervention services in Moldova leading to sub-contracting its services by the National Health Insurance Company. Additionally, the problem of autism was for the first approached publicly and the National Strategy for People with Autism for the next 3 years is now being elaborated and discussed with the Government and Parliament representatives. The problems of people with hearing impairments were introduced on the National Public Agenda, while two guides on the use of sign language were elaborated to facilitate their communication at the national level. Over 20 campaigns were organized within the project to increase awareness on rights of vulnerable groups. With program support, Amnesty International produced 13 TV programs, broadcasted on Moldova 1, reflecting the human rights and the specific obligations of national authorities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="55030036" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.0" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
