<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5503002401-MDA-31120</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture Competitiveness, WB</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Konkurrensm&#xE4;ssigt jordbruk, VB</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projektet avser att ge b&#xE4;ttre f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar att nyttja Moldaviens   potential att integreras i den regionala handeln med                  jordbruksprodukter.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Agricultural Competitiveness project promotes Moldova&apos;s potential to integrate better into regional trade with horticulture products.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moldova (the Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="311" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">886406.9494304835</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1166197.7579848103</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">711802.8780563036</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">886406.9494304835</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1166197.7579848103</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">711802.8780563036</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-01">2954689.831434</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-28">886406.9494304835</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-11-28">1166197.7579848103</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">711802.8780563036</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-28">-117.8311700267</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2016Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: The decision on contribution was signed in December 2012; however the operations were delayed and started only in 2014. Despite the late coming into force of the Swedish contribution, the intervention has produced good results with high impact in both components.

The Swedish contribution is aimed at supporting the project to enhance the competitiveness of the Moldovan agro-food sector through: 
(i) supporting the modernization of the food safety management system;  
(ii) facilitating market access for farmers.  

Part A: Enhancing Food Safety Management

Activities conducted under this component aimed at facilitating implementation of National Food Safety Agency NFSA/ANSA responsibilities to ensure the safety and quality of food and feed in Moldova, in accordance with national and international regulations/EU standards, to strengthen management and operational capacity of the Agency so that it can effectively fulfil its role of official control of food quality and safety in accordance with national policy of Moldova. 

Swedish support contributed to the establishment of a new institution - the National Food Safety Agency. By the end of the operational period of the Swedish contribution (June 2016) there were considerable investments done into the reconstruction of the building where National Food Safety Agency NFSA/ANSA is located, as well as of the construction of several Border Inspection Points (PIF) in Tudora, Criva, Giurgiulesti and Leuseni. The reconstruction of the Balti and Cahul Laboratories for testing the quality and health of plants, feed and food was prepared and managed. The laboratories correspond to international standards in this field. 

The NFSA central building was equipped with necessary IT equipment and furniture and can host 400 employees. Modern IT systems were installed and functional: MMSV, LIMS, Animal Tracking Information System (SITA) was modernised. 

The contribution has provided regulatory and institutional support to Ministry of Agriculture and Food Industry /MAFI for enhancing the food safety management system. The process of legislative harmonisation of the national legislation with the relevant EU regulations has been in the focus of the project. Amendments to the existing veterinary legislation on border inspection activity were prepared, as well as drafts of several Government decisions on transposition of the EU Sanitary veterinary standards for establishing animal health and public health conditions and veterinary certification of imports of raw milk and dairy products intended for human consumption. 

The support was provided to the transposition of the several Commission Regulations on Rapid Alert System for Food and Feed; on informing consumers about foods; audits to ensure verification of compliance with feed and food law and rules of animal health and animal welfare; adoption of a general plan for crisis management in the food and feed sector; etc.

The institutional capacity of MAFI and its subordinated food safety management institutions was strengthened. More than 200 inspectors have enhanced their capacities in basic legislation on food safety; general requirements on food safety; implementation of good hygiene practices; implementation of HACCP programs; microbiological criteria of food; risks associated with food consumption as a result of three regional trainings (Balti, Cahul, Chisinau) for inspectors involved in official control of food products of animal origin as well as representatives from production units of non-animal origin. 

Capacities of the veterinary and phyto-sanitary service personnel at border inspection points were enhanced.  
Quality management has received major attention. Significant improvements have been achieved by introducing the EN ISO / IEC 17025 standard in the Animal Health Laboratory (AHL) of the RVDC. Protocols for diagnostics methods have been prepared in accordance with OIE and ISO requirements and key laboratory experts were trained and their practical skills on the methodology and implementation of quality management have been improved.

The lab equipment for &#x201C;Animal Health&quot; was installed at Animal Health Laboratory Chisinau RVDC / Republican Center for Veterinary Diagnosis. The institution was upgraded and is awaiting its formal accreditation for ISO 17025.

Part B : Enhancing Market Access Potential  
The project has provided business development support for productive partnerships for primary horticultural producers. Extensive public information and promotion campaigns were carried out (153 outreach activities that involved 1597 participants with women&#x2019;s participation of 20%).
In total, 54 initiative groups were created.  The Producer groups have received business development assistance combined with grants for post-harvest infrastructure. The structure of the initiative groups by product type is dominated by grapes, with about 37% of the total as a unique product and in combination with other fruits. At the same time the groups of fruit producers account for 91% compared with the producers of vegetables, including potatoes (9%). 39 groups were registered as Enterprise cooperative, including 38 &#x2013; newly established, and 1 &#x2013; re-registered. 3 groups were registered as limited liability companies &#x2013; newly established.

During the project operation  the project team has created  and strengthened  47 new productive partnerships in the area of horticulture that were registered at the Chamber of Commerce.  36  PG out of 40 application files were deemed eligible for the grant portion. Until now 30 PG received funding amounting to approximate. 7.5 million USD and technical assistance.  Women&#x2019;s participation reached 20%, which half of what has been planned. 

However, due to complicated political situation with Russian embargo on Moldovan agricultural production that was worsened by draught and economic- financial crisis in the country, it has been difficult to reach the planned targets in terms of increased sales and income generation during 2014-2016. According to the monitoring data for the 30PG that received funding, only 12 groups recorded sales in 2015, in the total amount of 3,774 tons of horticultural production. The value of such production was 22,139 thousand let, with the average per group of 1.845 thousand lei. When PG were launched, these figures amounted to 38,575 tons with the value 150,705 thousand lei, with an average of 5,023 thousand lei per group. Thus, the average sales amount per PG as of the time of reporting is 37 per cent of the average sales amount in the country as the time of launch of PG. The price of one kg of horticultural product after the launch in 2014  of PG increased by 151% by 2016.

The project has provided investment support for post-harvest technology development. Cumulatively since the start of the project, grant resources amounting to USD 7,491,542.40 have been disbursed to 30 producer groups out of 36 approved by the Evaluation and Selection Committee. 

Six producer Groups received financing from Swedish Government amounting to USD 1,443,874,12.   
Co-financing provided by producer groups represents approximately USD 8.6 million. The total value of approved investment projects is approximately USD 17.8 million. The average value of a grant disbursed constitutes about USD 258,000. 

The storage capacity of 29 cold storage facilities, built with Project support, exceeds 23,700 tons. 11 cold storage facilities have already been completed, another 18 are under construction with a degree of completion between 5-50%. Additional investments were made in 6 drying lines for processing of plums, 8 grading lines, 2 units of refrigerated transport and specialised equipment for processing of nuts and almonds.

The project has supported the establishment of an institutional platform to promote and defend the interests of cooperatives/producer groups in relation to public and private authorities both in the country. Thus, the Union of Entrepreneurial Cooperatives &quot;AGRI EXPO &#x201D;was created and registered with the Ministry of Justice on 02.03.2016. Thus, with the project support, the Union was registered with the regional fiscal authorities, statistical bodies, the NHIC, NSIC and opened settlement accounts in one of the commercial banks.

The union is expected to become a business support organisation and a &quot;hub&quot; (resource and intelligence centre) for cooperatives, which will concentrate and strengthen the cooperatives&#x2019; development capacity, including in order for the cooperatives&#x2019; own investments and those of MAC-P to become sustainable over time.
The Union has the following goals:
&#x2022;	promoting the culture of association and benefits of association among farmers;
&#x2022;	attracting investment and funds for the development of cooperatives/PG;
&#x2022;	creating opportunities and facilities for the export of agricultural products, including by promoting local agricultural product brands;
&#x2022;	creating the products&#x2019; quality infrastructure for domestic and export markets;
&#x2022;	participation in regional and international specialised organisations etc.

European Business Association signed a contract on consultancy services rendered under Moldova Agricultural Competitiveness Project (MAC-P), second component of the project &#x201C;Enhancing market access potential&#x201D; focused on training on export promotion and market access support and matchmaking for producer groups. 15 practical workshops have been delivered to GP by international experts &#x2013; practitioners and a match making events with Romania and Poland.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55030024" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
