<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13521A0101-MDA-15180</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Preparatory (pre-core) support Artemida 2019</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Preparatory (pre-core) support Artemida 2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Artemida is a non-governmental organization that manages a center (shelter) for victims of domestic violence. The pre-core support granted for organisation is a simplified contribution which aims at supporting the organization to develop its internal capacities and policies. 

During pre-core support phase Artemida will implement priority recommendations provided by the Nordic Consulting Group in the system-based audit report produced in 2018. Therefore, it will develop institutional capacities, internal routines, staff knowledge and skills to be able to implement core-support activities. Based on a follow-up report on pre-core activities to be conducted tentatively in December 2019, Sida may consider continuing with core-support with Artemida based on the Strategic Plan, RAF and strategic budget developed during pre-core support.

The intervention total budget is 324 000 SEK.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Artemida &#xE4;r en enskild organisation som sk&#xF6;ter ett center &#x2013; ett skyddsboende f&#xF6;r offer f&#xF6;r v&#xE5;ld i hemmet. Det f&#xF6;rberedande k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;det f&#xF6;r enskilda organisationer Artemida bereds som en f&#xF6;renklad insats. Syftet med det f&#xF6;rberedande k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;det &#xE4;r att st&#xE4;rka organisationens kapacitet och utveckla deras interna regelverk.

Artemida kommer under denna f&#xF6;rsta fas av st&#xF6;det (innan k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d) att genomf&#xF6;ra de prioriterade rekommendationerna fr&#xE5;n Nordic Consulting Group presenterade i den systembaserade revisionsrapporten som gjordes 2018. Artemida utvecklar institutionell kapacitet, interna rutiner, personalkunskaper och andra f&#xE4;rdigheter f&#xF6;r att kunna genomf&#xF6;ra k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;dsaktiviteter. Baserat p&#xE5; en kommande uppf&#xF6;ljningsrapport som avser aktiviteter under denna f&#xF6;rsta fas (rapport tas prelimin&#xE4;rt fram i december 2019) kan Sida sedan &#xF6;verv&#xE4;ga att forts&#xE4;tta med k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d till Artemida baserat p&#xE5; en strategisk plan, resultatram och den strategiska budgeten som utvecklats inf&#xF6;r k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;det. 

Insatsens totala budget uppg&#xE5;r till 324 000 SEK.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As a result of the SBA, Artemida engaged in an organisational development process to implement the recommendations. To facilitate this process the Swedish Embassy entered into a pre-core support grant agreement with Artemida in May 2019, provided trainings and individual mentoring support during the autumn 2019 through a framework contract with Swedish Development Advisers (SDA).
During the pre-core support period Artemida has worked to implement the 16 key recommendations from the SBA. The work encompassed revision of Artemida&#x2019;s Strategic plan for 2020 &#x2013; 23, development of a RAF and a three-year strategic budget, development and revision of some internal policies and regulations, development of operative templates and an Annual Results Report for 2018. 
During the autumn 2019, the Artemida team participated in three training events organised by SDA in:
 1) Strategic planning, RAF and Results Based Management (RBM), 
2) Sida&#x2019;s cross-cutting perspectives and 
3) Good governance, anti-corruption and audits. 
Artemida thereafter tried to apply the learnings gained in the process of implementing the recommendations. In addition, two rounds of mentoring were conducted during the same period, each one for 1,5 - 2 days.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A.O. Artemida</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A.O. Artemida</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moldova (the Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ending violence against women and girls</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">34264.3217462114</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">34264.3217462114</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">-3921.3003680902</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-01">34264.321746</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">34264.3217462114</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-28">-3921.3079687721</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A new organisational structure was developed during the pre-core support period after intensive discussions in the team and with the Board of Directors. The new structure is approved by the Board and is linked to the four priority areas of the Strategic Plan. Several new positions are included in the new organigram, illustrating a substantial expansion in staff if and when core support is approved. 
Artemida shows a good understanding of using the Strategic Plan and RAF for its future fundraising where projects will be developed in line with the expected outcomes, using the indicators of the RAF. By monitoring the immediate outcomes, the RAF will help Artemida to focus on the changes in society it intends to contribute to and not lose track due to the large number of outputs. The management shows an understanding of the importance of outcome monitoring. Artemida has planned to train its General Assembly members and the Board on the full package of strategic documents.
The first training in RBM, strategic planning and the RAF was experienced as difficult and Artemida needed further support to fully understand it and be able to apply it. Eventually this created a fundamental change in their perception and analysis of their role and work. Applying the skills resulted in a results based Strategic Plan and well elaborated RAF. 
The biggest change during the pre-core period is, according to the staff interviewed, the changes that have happened in the way the Artemida team thinks, shifting from activity and project planning to a focus on results. The consequence of this change was explained as fundamental, having raised the staff members&#x2019; thinking to a completely new strategic level. The team felt that it was not easy to make this mental shift, but that the process has opened their minds in how they see Artemida and its role in society. The trainings offered, combined with the mentoring support in how to understand and apply the new skills, were critical to for this change to happen, according to the team.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13521" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
