<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-14147A0102-MDA-15180</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core support Women&apos;s Law Center 2020 -2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Core support Women&apos;s Law Center 2020 -2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Sverige kommer att st&#xF6;dja Kvinnors lagcentrum (WLC), en civil organisation fr&#xE5;n Moldavien, f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;randet av k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;dsaktiviteter f&#xF6;rsedda av WLCs Strategiska plan och RAF under april 2020 &#x2013; december 2022. K&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d beviljas f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka den institutionella kapaciteten och f&#xF6;r att st&#xF6;dja genomf&#xF6;randet av WLCs medell&#xE5;ng sikt Strategisk plan 2019&#x2014;2024 i bek&#xE4;mpning av v&#xE5;ld i hem och k&#xF6;nsrelaterat v&#xE5;ld i Moldavien. Det huvudsakliga m&#xE5;let och f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade resultat av k&#xE4;rnaktiviteterna &#xE4;r att Kvinnors lagcentrum bidrar med att bygga ett samh&#xE4;lle d&#xE4;r m&#xE4;nniskor kan leva fria fr&#xE5;n v&#xE5;ld och &#xF6;vergrepp och &#xE4;r s&#xE4;kra och skyddade i deras familjer och relationer. Det h&#xE4;r &#xE4;r det andra k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;det som erbjuds till WLC fr&#xE5;n Sverige.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden will support Women&apos;s Law Centre (WLC), a civil society organisation from Moldova, to implement core support activities provided by WLC&#x2019;s Strategic Plan and RAF during April 2020 - December 2022. Core support is granted to strengthen institutional capacities and to assist the implementation of WLC&#x2019;s medium term Strategic Plan 2019-2024 in fighting domestic and gender-based violence in Moldova. The main objective and expected result of core activities is that the Women&#x2019;s Law Center contributes to building a community where people live their life free of violence and abuse and are safe and protected in their families and relationships. This is the second core support offered to WLC by Sweden.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is the second WLC&apos;s intervention supported by Sweden in Moldova.The intervention is based on the institutional Strategic Plan 2019-2024. Sweden will support WLC via core support in 2020-2022. The objectives, indicators and measures of implementation are described clearly in the RAF and the institutional budget. The main objective is to support further institutional development of WLC with the final scope for the organisation: to be financial sustainable, to enhance institutional mechanisms and routines to ensure results&apos; sustainability over time, to deliver professional services for domestic violence victims and to advocate and promote best legal and institutional standards in preventing and fighting domestic violence at the national level.&#xA0;
Given the context and the field where the organisation is active, the lessons learned and the strategic goal, WLC&apos;s activity in the next six years (2019-2024) will focus on the following areas of intervention:
1. Prevention
Strategic objective 1: Raise public awareness about violence against women
Strategic objective 2: Build the capacity of professionals in the justice, social assistance and health care sectors
Awareness-raising events and information campaigns will be arranged aimed at changing social and behavioural norms and increasing the knowledge of different population groups (women in rural areas, older women, men and young people) about causes and consequences of gender-based violence and domestic violence, available legal remedies, assistance and protection services available to victims of gender-based violence and domestic violence. Youth hubs, librarians&apos; network, media outlets, individual professionals (through small grants) and survivors of DV will be involved in these activities as strategic partners (example: 16 days campaign, national conference on fighting DV, etc). &#xA0;&#xA0;
Capacity building of professionals will be organised to help them change their attitudes, perceptions and behaviour and will promote a cross-sector approach to domestic violence, communication between professionals throughout their intervention, and referral of identified cases to specialised services. With priority to address the&#xA0;acute need to build the capacity of judges, prosecutors, lawyers, police officers, social workers, psychologists and doctors to respond effectively to cases of domestic violence, including at the local level.&#xA0;
2. Protection
Strategic objective 3: Develop and consolidate services provided to victims of violence against women
WLC&#xA0; will continue to make efforts to develop holistic services for victims based on their needs, including: free telephone line for legal counselling of victims of gender-based violence and domestic violence; primary legal aid; qualified legal aid; social assistance, including economic empowerment of survivors of domestic violence; psychological counselling.
The&#xA0;assistance to women in detention (Rusca prison) will continue through legal counselling to convicted women, individual psychological counselling, therapy through art, legal assistance to women accused of DV crimes. &#xA0;
3. Researched based policies
Strategic objective 4: Policy development through direct contribution, lobbying and advocacy on the basis of evidence from research and analysis
WLC&apos;s strategic priority in the coming years will remain the promotion at policy and legislative level of initiatives based on the respect for the rights of victims of domestic violence, ensuring their free access to justice, ensuring their access to high-quality specialised services of assistance and protection and the exercise of due diligence by authorities. One of the main objective is to continue active advocacy for Istanbul&#xA0; Convention&apos;s ratification and its proper implementation in the Republic of Moldova as well as lobbying for the alignment of the legal framework with international standards (examples: Femicide Report, Economic Abuse Report, etc.).&#xA0;
&#xA0;4. Organisational development
Strategic objective 5: Increase the efficiency and effectiveness of the organisation
From 2016 to 2019, WLC being supported by Sweden, invested enormously in the development of the organisation and each team member. The organisation developed internal operational procedures, built the capacity of team members, and set up comprehensive mechanisms for the management, monitoring and evaluation of implemented activities. In the next strategic cycle, WLC aims to continue the development of the organisation by maximizing the team&apos;s potential, increasing its efficiency and effectiveness including of the board, promoting the organisational values and culture within the team. Financial sustainability and diversification of funding sources will continue to be one of the strategic priorities. Conflict and environment perspective will be strategic priorities to be developed and integrated.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Womens Law Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Womens Law Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-02-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moldova (the Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ending violence against women and girls</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">306882.851775845</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">306882.851775845</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-01">306882.851775</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/14147_AgreementWCL.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core support Women&apos;s Law Center 2020 -2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/14147_AmendmentWCL.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core support Women&apos;s Law Center 2020 -2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/14147_DecisionAmendmentWLC.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core support Women&apos;s Law Center 2020 -2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/moldova/14147_DecisionWLC.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core support Women&apos;s Law Center 2020 -2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="14147" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
