<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-16/3481/AFG/APC/INGO/3784</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community based child protection and mine awareness  in Nangarhar province - / Isthema project 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nangarhar province has been deeply affected by conflicts &#x2013; inducing a large number of IDPs and ERWs contamination. In addition, current trends of returnees are worrying &#x2013; as the influx is putting more pressure on already overstrained resources. (I)NGOs have difficulties to access some areas, for assessment and for any kind of prevention or assistance. With winter season and influx of additional thousands returnees, needs for protection and assistance will only grow. 
Tdh has been implementing a CHF funded project in 6 districts of Nangarhar since December 2015 &#x201C;Ishtema 1&#x201D; &#x2013; with outstanding results and successes so far. Through direct assistance of NFI, CP and MRE awareness sessions, as well as PSS lifesaving activities, social cohesion between IDP and host population has been increased, hundreds of families have received assistance and thousands of adults and children have now a better understanding of mine risks and child rights. This was made possible as the project lies on very good knowledge of the region, a strong network of local volunteers (&#x201C;CBCPC members&#x201D; and PSS volunteers) as well as excellent trust and acceptance of Tdh teams within the communities and an innovative approach to reach the most isolated and unserved population..
Ishtema 2 is willing to build on these excellent results and successes, maintain the current activities and expand the scope of the activities in new districts of intervention in Nangarhar and in Kunar (in total 5 new districts covered, reaching a total of 11 districts)&#x2013; where needs are also very important. Objective will remain to  reach out to the vulnerable returnees, IDPs and conflict affected populations and their children through mobile teams and to develop community based child protection services &#x2013; including life-saving PSS - complemented by mine awareness activities.
Tdh will continue to work with the already formed CBCPC And identify new CBCPCs. It will be possible by increasing the number of mobile teams (2 additional team to reach a total of 5 team) to face the needs of returnees, IDPs and conflict affected population. Activities will continue in the villages already targeted in Ishtema 1  (48 villages), and newly identified villages (24 villages) &#x2013; based on assessment and depending on the influx of returnees, will be added to monthly workplan. Tdh teams will continue to reach out to communities receiving no other support, as well as targeting the most vulnerable among the vulnerable individuals (IDP, returnee and conflict affected population). When possible and relevant, data collected during Ishtema activities will be shared and used as a leverage to involve more actors and more funds for the emergency response in the region.
CBCPC members  in coordination with 5 mobile teams composed of 2 social workers, 1 community mobilisers and 2 animators, will thus provide awareness sessions on CP and MRE (ToT by MACCA) as well as identify/flag extremely vulnerable cases for follow-up or direct assistance support. These 5 mobile vans will continue to deliver life-saving PSS activities in coordination with identified and trained volunteers. Those volunteers will be slowly been capable to do PSS activities on their own. Life-saving PSS activities will also allow Tdh team to detect extremely vulnerable children in need of specialized services. Mine awareness sessions will complement these activities. A strong focus on women and girls&#x2019; vulnerabilities and particular needs is already in place (50% of staff and volunteers are female) &#x2013; this approach will continue in Ishtema 2.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Terre des hommes Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Terre des hommes Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sylvain Fournier</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tdh Country Representative</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93707154657</telephone>
   <email>sfo@tdh.ch</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="13">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kunar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.84658930 71.09731700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="6">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nangarhar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.17183130 70.62167940</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-26">126999.41</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-26">210735.28</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-3784">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-26">337734.69</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Terre des hommes Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302175713">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-29">270187.75</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Terre des hommes Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302818994">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-07">67546.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Terre des hommes Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
