<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-16/3481/SA1/H/NGO/509</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of effective trauma care  and mass casualty management to conflict affected people</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Nangarhar: AADA is the BPHS implementer in Nangarhar Province under SEHAT-I and provides health services to 1,557,024 people through 99 health facilities and 926 health posts. While most of the needs are covered through BPHS, still there is unmet needs to be covered through vertical project by approaching funds from donors interested to humanitarian actions. Considering insecurity and increasing incidence of conflict casualties, and owing to the data collected from NGOs &#x2013;particularly AADA, PPHD, UN organizations, and local government, and HMIS analysis, 8 districts are identified by Health Cluster/OCHA for establishment of FATPs. Further assessment was done by AADA in coordination with PPHD to identify the CHCs/BHCs where the needs are huge for establishment and support of FATPs. 
AADA will establish and support 7 FATPs in 2 CHCs of Achine and Hesarak, and 5 BHCs of Chaparhar, Nazyan, Pacheiragam, Sherzad and Surkhrod districs.  The location of the FATPs have been selected considering most vulnerable places in term of security and remoteness. Through this project trauma referral and stabilization services will be provided through FATPs. Space will be provided, staffing will be done considering the FATP pattern, and salary will be paid according to NSP. Two nurses for each FATP (BHCs) will be hired to provide 24 hours services in two shift. Considering load of work in CHCs, one nurse will be hired for the FATP in CHC. To ensure clean environment and infection prevention, there is need for 2 cleaners in two shifts the cleaner will also be trained in first aid to assist the nurse during emergencies. Equipment will be provided and required supplies, including drug, will be timely provided to the facility. To improve the trauma cases management and referral, 7 ambulances will be rented. Community awareness will be given by CHS and CHWs about the project and existence of the trauma care services. Training on trauma care and management will be conducted to the FATP staff as well as for the health facility staff. The communities are already contacted to ensure safety of the staff and equipment. AADA commits to regularly monitor and supervise the project and provide require support to the project.
2. Khost: AADA is the EPHS implementer in Khost provincial hospital total catchment area population of the Khost provincial hospital is 96,000 for OPD, but for IPD, it covers the whole province population which is 574,582 as per CSO. As there is no District Hospital in the Khost province, the provincial hospital is the only referral point for all emergency cases coming from the province. The hospital also covers the emergency cases of refugees (170,000 -UNHCR) in the province. In 2014, total trauma OPD was 7367 and IPD was 678 while in 2015 it was increased to 10863 OPD and 951 IPD. Referring to this data and context of this conflict affected province, there is need of rehabilitation and reestablishment of a mass-casualty management unit in provincial hospital. In the existing building, adequate space is allocated for the trauma center, and will be equipped with the already procured (by HNTPO through CHF) medical and non-medical equipment. Two tents will be provided for triage in the hospital. AADA will utilize the existing specialized staff and will hire 3 male and 3 female nurses for the trauma center. Total of 6 EPHS staff will contribute to this center (admin/finance officer, lab technician, X-Ray technician, laundry, toiler, and cook). 
Total 35 staff need to be trained on ICU care, basic and advanced life support, First Aid and war surgery and trauma care. The trauma center will be linked with BPHS health facilities run by OHPM. A field team will be mobilized from existing staff of PH whom will be responsible to provide the first aide at the place where mass casualties occurs and accompany them to the trauma center. The project will be regularly monitored and supervised by AADA main office and provincial hospital.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Assistance  for Development of Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Assistance  for Development of Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-09" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yasamin Yousofzai</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Development Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093700012254</telephone>
   <email>yyousofzai@aada.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="26">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khost</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.35850790 69.85974060</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="6">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nangarhar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.17183130 70.62167940</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-07-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-01">203521.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-07-09"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-01">222235.68</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-509">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-01">425756.77</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Assistance  for Development of Afghanistan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302020334">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-03">255454.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Assistance  for Development of Afghanistan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302996111">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-10">147297.26</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Assistance  for Development of Afghanistan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
