<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5503024402-REU-33150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">CEPS St&#xF6;d till de tre AA/DCFTA: Georgien, Moldavien, Ukraina</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEPS Support to the three AA/DCFTAs: Georgia, Moldova, Ukraine</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">De tre l&#xE4;nderna Georgien, Moldavien och Ukraina har undertecknat var sitt Associeringsavtal (AA) med EU. Syftet med avtalen &#xE4;r att fr&#xE4;mja politiskt n&#xE4;rmande och ekonomisk integration med EU baserat p&#xE5; gemensam v&#xE4;rdegrund, n&#xE4;ra och &#xF6;kat deltagande i samarbetet. De syftar ocks&#xE5; till att steg f&#xF6;r steg leda till en integration med EU:s inre marknad s&#xE4;rskilt genom de f&#xF6;rdjupande frihandelsavtalen DCFTA som utg&#xF6;r en del av AA. Frihandelsavtalen kommer att ge betydande tilltr&#xE4;de till den inre marknaden genom omfattande n&#xE4;rmande av lagstiftning och regelverk i &#xF6;verensst&#xE4;mmelse med r&#xE4;ttigheter och skyldigheter som f&#xF6;ljer av WTO-medlemsskapen.

Det &#xE4;r ett mycket stort och komplext &#xE5;tagande som &#xE5;vilar olika ministerier i l&#xE4;nderna och olika generaldirektorat inom EU. Insatsen syftar till att analysera konsekvenserna och hj&#xE4;lpa regeringarna att prioritera och samordna sitt reformarbete samt att i arbetet involvera civila samh&#xE4;llet och n&#xE4;ringslivet.

Insatsen genomf&#xF6;rs av Centre for European Policy Studies, CEPS, som Sida ing&#xE5;r avtal med. CEPS &#xE4;r en oberoende tankesmedja med s&#xE4;te i Bryssel och en l&#xE5;ng erfarenhet av EU-fr&#xE5;gor. CEPS samarbetar n&#xE4;ra med lokal expertis och f&#xF6;r att reglera samarbetet ing&#xE5;r underavtal i varje land med en ekonomiskt inriktad tankesmedja/civil-samh&#xE4;llesorganisation. 

Insatsen har tre m&#xE5;l:
1. att ta fram en handbok f&#xF6;r vart och ett av l&#xE4;nderna med en uttolkning av avtalstexten i DCFTA
2. att ta fram analyser &#xF6;ver k&#xE4;rnfr&#xE5;gor inom DCFTA och tillg&#xE4;ngligg&#xF6;ra dessa
3. att str&#xE4;va efter att inkludera Sidas strategiska prioriteringar s&#xE5;som milj&#xF6; och j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet samt f&#xF6;lja hur insatser relaterade till de tre Associeringsavtalen hanteras i regeringarnas reformprioriteringar

Ett antal seminarier och konferenser kommer att h&#xE5;llas.
Insatsen inleds med en inceptionsperiod vars fr&#xE4;msta m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att f&#xF6;rankra insatsen i l&#xE4;nderna.

Det finns ett merv&#xE4;rde i att insatsen genomf&#xF6;rs regionalt. Delar av avtalen har likheter varf&#xF6;r den expertis (DCFTA, handel, EU-lag, konflikt) som finns tillg&#xE4;nglig f&#xF6;r projektet kan dra nytta av synergierna i sin analys.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The three countries Georgia, Moldova and Ukraine have signed Association Agreements with the EU. The aim of the AAs is to promote political association and economic integration with the EU based on common values and close links and increasing participation in policies, programmes and structures. It is also to achieve gradual economic integration into the EU Internal Market in particular through establishing a Deep and Comprehensive Free Trade Area, DCFTA, which will provide far-reaching market access on the basis of sustained and comprehensive regulatory approximation in compliance with the rights and obligations arising from its WTO membership.

It is a huge commitment in legal and economic terms which is fragmented between different departments, even in the European Commission, as well as in the governments of the partner states. The intervention involves representatives of civil society in the three countries and aims at analysing the consequences and assisting the governments to prioritise and coordinate their reform work.

Distribution Georgia, Moldova, Ukraine:
No country allocations in advance.

The intervention has three objectives:
1. To deliver a clear and comprehensive handbook for each of the countries
2. To analyse the core DCFTA topics where the partner countries take on legally binding and operational obligations that are also of substantial economic importance.
3. To address hot topics without legally binding or operational specifications including Sida&apos;s strategic priorities

There will be a number of seminars and conferences to present and debate the findings.
The intervention will start with an inception phase with the main purpose to anchor the intervention with the respective governents, interested civil society organizations and business representatives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of Phase II the Project &#xAB;Understanding the Association Agreements &amp; Deep and Comprehensive Free Trade Agreements between the European Union and Georgia, Moldova and the Ukraine&#xBB; (Jan. 2019 &#x2013; Dec. 2021) is:
- To enhance knowledge and understanding of the Association Agreements (AA), including the Deep and Comprehensive Free Trade Areas (DCFTA), and the implications of their implementation. The AA/DCFTAs, signed on 27 June 2014 by the EU with Georgia, Moldova and the Ukraine, are very extensive and complex documents, which are not readily understood, even to decision-makers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEPS/Centre for European Policy Studies</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEPS/Centre for European Policy Studies</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="331" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Policies &amp; Regulations</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="33150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade-related adjustment</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="8.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.a - Increase Aid for Trade support for developing countries, in particular least developed countries, including through the Enhanced Integrated Framework for Trade-related Technical Assistance to Least Developed Countries.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.a - &#xD6;ka det handelsrelaterade st&#xF6;det (Aid for Trade) till utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna, i synnerhet de minst utvecklade l&#xE4;nderna, bland annat genom det f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rkta integrerade ramverket f&#xF6;r handelsrelaterat tekniskt bist&#xE5;nd till de minst utvecklade l&#xE4;nderna (Enhanced Integrated Framework for Trade-related technical Assistance to Least Developed Countries).</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">542905.84926762</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">233184.483904441</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">542905.84926762</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">233184.483904441</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">830436.691065</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">542905.84926762</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-28">233184.483904441</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/Ost/55030244_1.DraftAmendmentno.3toAgreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement Amendment no.3</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/Ost/55030244_2.CEPSREGAvtal.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">CEPS REG Avtal</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/Ost/55030244_1.CEPSREGBeslutominsats.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">CEPS REG Beslut om insats</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/Ost/55030244_0.DecisiononAmendmentno.3.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Decision on Amendment no.3</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results presented byt CEPS are more as a list of activities, implemented during 2020, than measurable goals achieved.
The CEPS project fulfils the complex task of explaining the advantages and benefits of the difficult-to-understand Association Agreements (AA), including the Deep and Comprehensive Free Trade Areas (DCFTA), to both decision-makers and the general public. The difficulty is to make theory become practice. Nevertheless, the project shows some, although limited, progress achieved within the framework of so-called work packages (WP). Assessing progress made, it is necessary to keep in mind, though, (i) that the process is lengthy and cumbersome, (ii) that the project management must be allowed a large enough time span to be able to present measurable results, and (iii) that real results may be visible only towards the end of the project in the beginning of 2022.
I. The following results achieved / activities implemented in 2020 have been presented (2nd. year of the three-year (2019-2021) Phase II of the Project):
- EU leadership continues to be silent on the future of the AA/DCFTA process (same comment was given in 2019), which gives rise to concern among the three participating project countries (GEO, MOL, UKR).
- Economic development was negative in the three countries, with an estimated GDP decline in GEO of 6.1%, in MOL of 7.5%, and in UKR of 4.0%.
- Overall comment on AA/DCFTA implementation process is widespread implementation delays in the three countries (for political, as well as Corona situation reasons), although a large number of legislative activities have been on-going
- Plenary coordination meetings: 2 coordination meetings with CEPS and its 3 partner institutes in Tbilisi Chisinau and Kiev were held on-line on 4-5 Feb. and 5 Nov. 2020
- Focus groups: continuation of focus group series had to be suspended, due to Covid-19 pandemic; in general, GEO and MOL are progressing, whereas UKR is lagging (UKR has restrictive and protectionist EU road haulage licensing system, which is now becoming a bottleneck for EU-UKR expansion of trade):
--- Trade and market access
--- Technical barriers to trade (TBT)
--- Sanitary and phytosanitary Regulations (SPS)
--- Financial services
--- Energy
--- Environment
--- Customs services
--- Transport (initiated in early 2020)
- Regional perspectives: deferred until 2021 (also none in 2019)
- Democracy: overview paper (by Richard Youngs) was produced and published at www.3dcftas.eu, to serve as analytical framework for four country studies (ARM added); the following studies were completed and published in 2020:
--- The Uncertain States of Georgian Democracy
--- Moldovas Anaemic Democracy and Distorted Europeanisation
--- Democratisation and Europeanisation in 21st Century Ukraine
--- Armenias Auspicious Democratic Advance, Hanging by a Thread
--- their overall message stresses instability and fragility of these countries democratic systems; together with other contributions on judicial reform and anti-corruption polices (and their limited progress), they form the core content on a 2nd edition to The Struggle for Good Governance in Eastern Europe, to be published early in 2021.
- Governance capacity-building: Kataryna Wolczuk has been commissioned to produce an overview of EU coordination systems in the three AA states, which will be used as framework for CEPS experts in to elaborate further on this issue, but since this will require face-to-face interviews with policy-makers, it has been deferred until 2021
- Up-dating: comprehensive study of up-dating process in the three countries was completed, with publication of Catch me if you can: Updating the Eastern Partnership Association Agreements and DCFTAs by Guillaume Van Der Loo and Tinatin Akhvlediani planned for May 2021 (it seems, however, that notwithstanding a considerable amount of up-dated annexes to Agreements, with regard to new EU laws, these have been far from always completed, likely due to a process, often done in an ad hoc way, completely dependent on EC departments and the three countries initiatives; furthermore, it seems that CEPS study is the only one available, where an overall review of the process has been published)
- Trade and macro-economic results: these were summarised in short comparative studies in 2020:
--- Evolution of Trade between the EU and its Associated States: five years after the signing of the DCFTAs (main results show a substantial shift in trade structures of the three countries in favour of EU and a decline of trade with Russia, but with the pandemic there has been a sharp decline in trade with EU and a major increase with China)
--- Overview of macro-economic trends in In Georgia, Moldova and Ukraine under the Association Agreements since 2014 (moderate, but sustained positive growth of GDP until the pandemic that pushed all countries into recession in 2020, with uncertainty over recovery in 2021)
- Eastern Partnership and EAEU: Covid-19 pandemic led to CEPS initiating formation of a club of civil society/think tank partners in all six EaP states, building on existing teams in the three AA/DCFTA countries (a series of Zoom meetings and webinars on pandemic and -related issues, incl. economic and political consequences; short papers were commissioned from each of the six key civil society participants, published on-line at www.3dcftas.eu as Covid-19 Bulletins, which reached 13 in number by year end; series will be continued in 2021; CEPS assesses participation of leading civil society experts from BEL, ARM and AZE as excellent; whereas, initially, meetings were conducted in closed Zoom meetings, the format of these were switched to an open webinar format, starting autumn 2020, which attracted around 100 external participants on each occasion)
- Wider neighbourhood concept: a study was commissioned with ARM think tank analysts to review the Comprehensive and Enhanced Partnership Agreement with EU, and prospects for building on that (ARMs defeat in the war with AZE over Nagorno Karabakh disrupted this work; study was at an early draft stage at end of 2020)
- Conflict regions: work initiated in 2019 on all unresolved separatist conflicts of post-Soviet space was completed with publication of book Beyond Frozen Conflict  Scenarios for the Separatist Disputes of Eastern Europe, co-published by CEPS and Rowan and Littlefield, by Thomas de Waal on Abkhazia, South Ossetia, Nagorno Karabakh and Transdnistria, and by Nickolaus von Twickel on Donbass in the only available comprehensive account of this distressed region so far (book was completed before the war erupted in Sep., but chapter on Nagorno-Karabakh signalled possibility of renewed war; 2nd edition of book planned for 2021 with additional chapter, analysing the war and its consequences)
- Gender policies: detailed comparative study, published ahead of schedule in 2019, incl. comparison with EU member states, provided a basis for assessing gender policies and performance in the three AA countries, completed in 2020 and to be published as chapters in Handbook 3rd edition (in terms of gender equality, performance of the three countries is not unfavourable, compared to EU member countries average, but, notwithstanding, is not up to highest standards observed)
- Communication: project improved its presence on social networks, increasing number of followers of its Facebook page by 250% (up from 318 to 800), and producing 180 posts on Facebook and Twitter (average number of web-site visits per month was 1,300, totalling 15,662 in 2020; whereas Handbooks have remained the most downloaded publications in absolute numbers, the book Beyond Frozen Conflict was the most popular publication in 2020 - over 4,000 downloads)
--- in addition to publishing short op.ed. articles (35 in 2020), a series of Bulletins were published, mainly dedicated to COVID-19 impact; 13 special EaP Bulletins were issued in 2020 in cooperation with external partners; 8 COVID-19 Bulletins were issued for Southeast Europe and MENA with 4 editions per each region; 4 public on-line webinars on ZOOM platform and 1 on-line discussion in UKR with 558 participants:
------ Economic and social impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on the EaP countries
------ Political implications of the COVID-19 pandemic for the EaP countries
------ Eastern Europe  between democracy and conflict
------ COVID-19 in Eastern Europe: economic and political consequences
------ discussions (in Ukrainian) Digital services during COVID-19
- Handbook, 3rd edition: 30 (of 33 chapters) have been completed, ready for publication, with all three country volumes having advanced in parallel, according to a common structure (compared to first 2 editions, notable innovations are inclusion of new chapters on gender, public health/Covid-19, cyber security)
- Collaboration with 3 AA Governments: Covid-19 pandemic limited direct contacts with three Governments and their ambassadors in Brussels (some physical meetings were conducted, incl. the ones with Deputy Prime Minister of UKR for Euro-Atlantic Relations, Head of GEO Parliaments European Affairs Committee, Foreign Minister of MOL)
- Future fundamentals: preliminary work progressed with studies by Michael Emerson, published in 2020:
------ Future Fundamentals for the Association Agreements between the EU and Georgia, Moldova and Ukraine, and Organisation of the Wider Europe
------ Recasting European Values for the EU and the associated neighbours
------ 100 Ideas for Upgrading the Association Agreement and DCFTAs with Georgia, Moldova and Ukraine
II. Covid-19 situation
The Covid-19 situation has affected the project as of March 2020. The project management has applied pro-active measures to mitigate the consequences, and have, likely, been able to minimise delays in project implementation during 2020, as far as this has been possible. Some activities have had to be discontinued altogether - this goes mostly for the focus groups, which has been proven difficult to conduct on-line.
III. Mid-term evaluation
- An independent mid-term evaluation was carried out mid-2020, commissioned by the project team, by Dr. Laure Delcour of Sorbonne University in Paris. Some of her comments and recommendations were:
--- project lacks robust impact and outcome indicators, which makes it particularly difficult to measure the projects impact
--- project team could more systematically seek feedback from policy-makers on their needs and the use of the projects policy-oriented activities
--- project has become a knowledge hub about the AA/DCFTA  however, the project could still enhance its role as a source of knowledge and informed debates
--- project could still gain visibility (among others in the social media) by systematically harnessing links to external publications, in particular reports and analyses from international organisations and think-tanks. This has not been done systematically thus far
--- project could also step up the visibility of follow-up activities by (i) systematically publishing targeted analyses on the basis of the extensive evaluation of environmental policies carried out for the Handbooks; (ii) increasing the links to external publications on the projects website
- In its Management Response, CEPS agreed with the main findings of the Evaluator, but stated that:
--- it remains a fragile transition to an incompletely defined destination (i.e. Europeanised states without EU membership perspectives). EU policy makers have been unable to agree on membership perspectives for these states for reasons that are well understood. At the same time, the regimes of the three countries have changed their approach to the process of transition towards the EU, where Moldova under President Dodon has already moved some way back into Russias sphere of influence. The Zelensky regime in Ukraine marks a shift from a pro-European administration to one that is floating or indeterminate strategically. Georgia, while relatively efficiently governed, has nonetheless fallen into a condition of oligarchic state capture.
- With regard to project design and performance framework, CEPS stated that:
--- it is easy to call for robust impact and outcome indicators in general terms, but the realities make this much more difficult. The project  cannot be the basic driver of the political and economic transformation  The theory of change methodology is far easier to apply to cut and dried projects  much of the content of the AA/DCFTAs relate to political norms and to many economic regulatory reforms that are not strongly trade-related. The outcome and impact indicators, beyond the strict trade field, relate to macroeconomic and political indicators that are driven more fundamentally by national politics, including the role of influential interest groups. To separate the impact of the AA/DCFTAs from these other determinants in any formal or quantified sense is hardly possible. There has to be some balanced judgemental analysis taking into account all the main causal factors. We try to do this.
- With regard to policy-oriented activities, CEPS stated that:
--- the recommendations are very much in line with what we are trying to do. We have sustained contact with the senior officials and ambassadors of the three AA/DCTA states, and feel we have their confidence for making informed policy assessments and recommendations  We try to make our recommendations as operationally specific as possible, sometimes in publications, sometimes more discretely  we have been advocating forcefully in public in favour of the EU side agreeing to upgrade their relations with the three AA/DCFTA states together. On this we work in informal collaboration with key leaders in the European Parliament as well as the three AA/DCFTA states.
- With regard to the role of the project as a knowledge hub, CEPS stated that:
--- we see our communication activities in Stage 2 as being much in line with these recommendations, with increasing publication of op-eds and links to other relevant and externally produced texts, and use of social media outputs (Facebook and Twitter)
- With regard to future policy options for the AA/DCFTA process, CEPS stated that:
--- it is now observed that the three counties have moved beyond a first stage of initial Euro-enthusiasm. The political trends in all three countries, as already reported above, see warning signs over waning commitment to European values. Alternative political tendencies of nationalist-populist character emerge, notably in Ukraine. These are warnings to the EU that the sustained European orientation of these three countries should not be taken for granted, and the case for strengthened EU commitment remains. For our part we try to assess these basic political tendencies, but this is going to be an ongoing story, beyond the present 2021 end point for our project  Thinking about the future of the EaP, due to be debated at the delayed EaP summit now due for March 2021, is bound to be affected by the current crisis in Belarus, with some parties (but not so far a majority) in the European Parliament in favour of expelling Belarus. The Belarus question, and its implications, are now on hold, pending clarification of the outcome of the uprising.
- With regard to Environment, CEPS stated that:
--- we plan to enhance our Environmental and Climate work, with particular reference to the new context posed by the EUs Green Deal that in principle applies to the European continent. We therefore set in hand work to explore how far the three AA/DCFTA states might plausibly be associated with the Green Deals proposed mechanisms. This covers all the existing environmental commitments made in the AA/DCFTAs, to be reviewed in the 3rd edition of our three Handbooks currently under preparation, but with upgraded and more ambitious commitments to come from associating with the Green Deal.
- Sida comments on CEPS Management Response: the Evaluators observations and recommendations, and CEPS response to these, show the complexity of the current approach and that this is not an ordinary project, which is easy to implement and follow up on. The project builds on a large number of political factors, both within the EU (where there are three groups of different-minded member states) and within the three AA/DCFTA states themselves (where some degree of EU membership fatigue can be noted, given that clear positive results of the transition process are still rather few). In the context of this, CEPS response to the evaluation findings are assessed to be relevant and analysing, striving to explain the reality and difficulties, in the framework of which the project continues to work.

IV.Overall assessment of project progress
- The project constitutes an active and intensive approach in striving to support the three AA countries to conform with requirements in the Association Agreements to adapt and bring national legislation up to date with relevant development in the EU legal spere, as well as carrying out explanatory work among the population of the country. The project teams in both Brussels and the three countries have been able to cope with and adapt the work to new realities, caused by the Corona situation.
- Notwithstanding that activities within the project have been presented in great detail, which witnesses of ambition and commitment, it is still difficult to draw conclusions on the impact of the project on the on-going EU integration processes in the three countries. However, the following can likely be stated:
--- regarding sustainability, the three partner institutes in Tbilisi, Chisinau and Kiev have now built up capacity for analysing European policy issues  they are well placed to secure continued (alternative) funding
--- regarding impact, it seems to be too early to be advance a definitive assessment, although is seems to be achieving considerable resonance with the governments, parliaments and civil societies of the three associated states, as with the European parliament and EU think tanks</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55030244" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
