<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5503024402-REU-33150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">CEPS St&#xF6;d till de tre AA/DCFTA: Georgien, Moldavien, Ukraina</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEPS Support to the three AA/DCFTAs: Georgia, Moldova, Ukraine</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">De tre l&#xE4;nderna Georgien, Moldavien och Ukraina har undertecknat var sitt Associeringsavtal (AA) med EU. Syftet med avtalen &#xE4;r att fr&#xE4;mja politiskt n&#xE4;rmande och ekonomisk integration med EU baserat p&#xE5; gemensam v&#xE4;rdegrund, n&#xE4;ra och &#xF6;kat deltagande i samarbetet. De syftar ocks&#xE5; till att steg f&#xF6;r steg leda till en integration med EU:s inre marknad s&#xE4;rskilt genom de f&#xF6;rdjupande frihandelsavtalen DCFTA som utg&#xF6;r en del av AA. Frihandelsavtalen kommer att ge betydande tilltr&#xE4;de till den inre marknaden genom omfattande n&#xE4;rmande av lagstiftning och regelverk i &#xF6;verensst&#xE4;mmelse med r&#xE4;ttigheter och skyldigheter som f&#xF6;ljer av WTO-medlemsskapen.

Det &#xE4;r ett mycket stort och komplext &#xE5;tagande som &#xE5;vilar olika ministerier i l&#xE4;nderna och olika generaldirektorat inom EU. Insatsen syftar till att analysera konsekvenserna och hj&#xE4;lpa regeringarna att prioritera och samordna sitt reformarbete samt att i arbetet involvera civila samh&#xE4;llet och n&#xE4;ringslivet.

Insatsen genomf&#xF6;rs av Centre for European Policy Studies, CEPS, som Sida ing&#xE5;r avtal med. CEPS &#xE4;r en oberoende tankesmedja med s&#xE4;te i Bryssel och en l&#xE5;ng erfarenhet av EU-fr&#xE5;gor. CEPS samarbetar n&#xE4;ra med lokal expertis och f&#xF6;r att reglera samarbetet ing&#xE5;r underavtal i varje land med en ekonomiskt inriktad tankesmedja/civil-samh&#xE4;llesorganisation. 

Insatsen har tre m&#xE5;l:
1. att ta fram en handbok f&#xF6;r vart och ett av l&#xE4;nderna med en uttolkning av avtalstexten i DCFTA
2. att ta fram analyser &#xF6;ver k&#xE4;rnfr&#xE5;gor inom DCFTA och tillg&#xE4;ngligg&#xF6;ra dessa
3. att str&#xE4;va efter att inkludera Sidas strategiska prioriteringar s&#xE5;som milj&#xF6; och j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet samt f&#xF6;lja hur insatser relaterade till de tre Associeringsavtalen hanteras i regeringarnas reformprioriteringar

Ett antal seminarier och konferenser kommer att h&#xE5;llas.
Insatsen inleds med en inceptionsperiod vars fr&#xE4;msta m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att f&#xF6;rankra insatsen i l&#xE4;nderna.

Det finns ett merv&#xE4;rde i att insatsen genomf&#xF6;rs regionalt. Delar av avtalen har likheter varf&#xF6;r den expertis (DCFTA, handel, EU-lag, konflikt) som finns tillg&#xE4;nglig f&#xF6;r projektet kan dra nytta av synergierna i sin analys.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The three countries Georgia, Moldova and Ukraine have signed Association Agreements with the EU. The aim of the AAs is to promote political association and economic integration with the EU based on common values and close links and increasing participation in policies, programmes and structures. It is also to achieve gradual economic integration into the EU Internal Market in particular through establishing a Deep and Comprehensive Free Trade Area, DCFTA, which will provide far-reaching market access on the basis of sustained and comprehensive regulatory approximation in compliance with the rights and obligations arising from its WTO membership.

It is a huge commitment in legal and economic terms which is fragmented between different departments, even in the European Commission, as well as in the governments of the partner states. The intervention involves representatives of civil society in the three countries and aims at analysing the consequences and assisting the governments to prioritise and coordinate their reform work.

Distribution Georgia, Moldova, Ukraine:
No country allocations in advance.

The intervention has three objectives:
1. To deliver a clear and comprehensive handbook for each of the countries
2. To analyse the core DCFTA topics where the partner countries take on legally binding and operational obligations that are also of substantial economic importance.
3. To address hot topics without legally binding or operational specifications including Sida&apos;s strategic priorities

There will be a number of seminars and conferences to present and debate the findings.
The intervention will start with an inception phase with the main purpose to anchor the intervention with the respective governents, interested civil society organizations and business representatives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEPS/Centre for European Policy Studies</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University, college or other teaching institution, research institute or think-tank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="331" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Policies &amp; Regulations</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="33150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade-related adjustment</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="8.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.a - Increase Aid for Trade support for developing countries, in particular least developed countries, including through the Enhanced Integrated Framework for Trade-related Technical Assistance to Least Developed Countries.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.a - &#xD6;ka det handelsrelaterade st&#xF6;det (Aid for Trade) till utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna, i synnerhet de minst utvecklade l&#xE4;nderna, bland annat genom det f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rkta integrerade ramverket f&#xF6;r handelsrelaterat tekniskt bist&#xE5;nd till de minst utvecklade l&#xE4;nderna (Enhanced Integrated Framework for Trade-related technical Assistance to Least Developed Countries).</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">542905.84926762</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">217162.339707048</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">542905.84926762</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">217162.339707048</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">830436.691065</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">542905.84926762</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/Ost/55030244_2.CEPSREGAvtal.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">CEPS REG Avtal</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/Ost/55030244_1.CEPSREGBeslutominsats.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">CEPS REG Beslut om insats</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results presented in the Annual Report are more as a list of activities implemented during 2019, and activities planned for 2020 (pre-Covid-19 planning), than measurable goals achieved. The CEPS project fulfils the complex task of explaining the advantages and benefits of the difficult-to-understand Association Agreements (AA), including the Deep and Comprehensive Free Trade Areas (DCFTA), to both decision-makers and the general public. The difficulty is to make theory become practice. Nevertheless, the project shows some, although limited, progress achieved within the framework of so-called &#xAB;work packages&#xBB; (WP). Assessing progress made, it is necessary to keep in mind, though, (i) that the process is lengthy and cumbersome, (ii) that the project management must be allowed a large enough time span to be able to present measurable results, and (iii) that real results may be visible only towards the end of the project in 2022. I. The following results achieved / activities implemented in 2019 have been presented: (WP 1a): Focus Groups, as a means of receiving information on AA/DCFTA implementation from government authorities, private sector, business associations, NGOs, independent experts, in order to discuss and assess measures needed to make the necessary adjustments, is a crucial factor to make the project attain its goals. The focus groups cover the following areas: - Trade policy issues, incl. market access - Technical barriers to trade - Sanitary and phyto-sanitary regulations - Financial services - Energy policy - Environment policy - Customs services, incl. trade facilitation Originally, the project addressed three countries: Georgia, Moldova and the Ukraine, but given the new political situation in the country, Armenia was added in 2020 as the fourth country. In 2019, focus groups were organised in: Georgia - 7 times, Moldova - 7 times, the Ukraine - 7 times. (WP 1b): Regional perspectives have been deferred until 2020, with a similar focus group method to be followed. (WP 2a): Democracy. An overview paper was produced and published at www.3dcftas.eu, which will serve as the analytical framework for country studies in the four countries. Expert authors have been recruited and drafts are expected by the end of March 2020. (WP 2b): Governance capacity-building. An expert was commissioned to produce an overview of the EU coordination systems in the three AA states (GEO, MOL, UKR), which will be used as framework for the CEPS experts to elaborate further on this issue in the target countries. Results expected by mid-2020, ahead of schedule. (WP 2c): Up-dating. This is work underway, and will be done alongside possibilities for up-grading the AA/DCFTAs. Results also expected by mid-2020. (WP 3): Trade and macro-economic results. This will be reviewed in the first half of 2020. (WP 4a): Eastern Partnership and EAEU. This was subject to working-papers in 2019, ahead of schedule, and will see further politically sensitive outputs in the first half of 2020. (WP 4b): Wider neighbourhood concept. Merging with WP 4a, to a large degree, a new item - on Armenia&#x2019;s Comprehensive and Enhanced Partnership Agreement with the EU, will be added in 2020 (in the format, following the method of the handbooks, but on a smaller scale). (WP 5): Conflict regions. Advancing well ahead of schedule in 2019, (i) studies were published at www.3cftas.eu on Abkhazia, South Ossetia, Nagorno Karabakh and Transdnistria, and on Donbass, to be used as the basis for (ii) developing scenarios for the future of these unresolved conflicts, which will be (iii) published as a book in the first half of 2020. (WP 6): Gender policies. This has also advanced ahead of schedule, with (i) a detailed comparative study, published at www.3dcftas.eu, by the CEPS team on gender performance in the three AA states (GEO, MOL, UKR), including comparisons with EU member states. The study will be used by CEPS three partner institutes (ii) to prepare more thorough assessments, and, subsequently, lead to their (iii) inclusion of new gender chapters in the 3rd edition of the Handbooks. (WP 7): Communications. In line with the objective of enhancing dissemination of outputs, (i) the web-site www.3dcfta.eu was improved in structure and appearance, (ii) a new series of short &#xAB;op.ed.&#xBB; articles (one new feature per week) and (iii) a quarterly newsletter feature introduced, as well as (iv) links to social media enhanced. The output of publications in 2019 was as follows: 27 working-papers, 43 &#xAB;op.ed.&#xBB; articles, 53 linked publications. (i) The total of all three Handbooks (GEO, MOL, UKR), with their 1st an 2nd editions in all languages, reached a total of 107,806 down-loads (end-2019), incl. 36,000 in the course of 2019; (ii) the volume on &#xAB;The Struggle for Good Governance in Eastern Europe&#xBB; had 13,466 down-loads (end-2019); (iii) other &#xAB;top 10&#xBB; publications reached, in most cases, over 1,000 down-loads, with some reaching the 6-8,000 level; (iv) web-site visits were on a steadily rising trend until August 2019, when a change in the web soft-ware caused discontinuity in the statistical series. (WP 8): Handbook, 3rd editions, where work is scheduled to begin in the second half of 2020, to be completed in 2021. (WP 9): Collaboration with the 3 AA governments (GEO, MOL, UKR). CEPS reports of excellent working-relations and trust with the three governments, built-up over the past three years, and that they also keep continuous contact with their ambassadors in Brussels over on-going discussions on how to enhance the AA/DCFTA process. (WP 10): Future fundamentals. The project is already now looking into various ideas that have the potential of becoming strategically significant for the future of the AA/DCFTA process, and which will feed into output at the end of 2021, drawing up the project&#x2019;s final conclusions. II. Covid-19 situation Although the Covid-19 situation have affected the project only as of March 2020, and despite the project management&#x2019;s pro-active measures to mitigate the consequences, is obvious that there will be some delays in project implementation during 2020, and likely also in the years to come. However, it must be kept in mind that this is a global problem, and, judging from the project&#x2019;s mitigation measures so far during March-April 2020, it can be assessed that the consequences will likely be minimised, to the extent possible. Some of these mitigation activities can be summarised, as follows: - re-direction of a large part of the work, so that it is carried out in Brussels (up-date of Handbooks, where contacts with partners are done via Skype and e-mail) - studying the issue, whether a chapter on public health / contagion could be added to the EU association agreements - organisation of a team of staff from the six Eastern Partnership countries and the EU, aiming at monitoring the development of Covid-19 that bi-weekly will publish a bulletin on comparative summaries of the situation in each of the Partnership countries and the EU (see https://3dcftas.eu/publications/covid-19-bulletin-no-3) - initiation of preparing a handbook-type study on Armenia, in relation to the consequences of Covid-19 III.Overall assessment of project progress (i) On the overall, project progress can be assessed to be satisfactory, based on activities implemented in 2019, in accordance to work-plan. (ii) That no major impact can yet be seen is normal, given the complexity of the project &#x2013; measurable results to be expected towards the end of the project only. (iii) Judging from the project management&#x2019;s pro-active mitigation measures, implemented so far during March-April 2020, it can be assessed that the consequences for the project will likely be minimised, to the extent possible.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="55030244" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.0" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
