<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11608A0101-VBA-16062</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Statistical Regional Cooperation Western Balkans 2019-2023</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Statistiskt regionalt samarbete V&#xE4;stra Balkan 2019-2023</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Statistics Sweden (SCB) have applied for a total of 19 122 000 SEK in order to implement &quot;Regional Cooperation Project in South Eastern Europe&quot; (Albania, Bosnien &amp; Herzegovina, Kosovo, Macedonia, Montenegro och Serbia) during 2019-2023. This is the fourth and final phase in the cooperation between SCB and the respective national statistical institutes.

The development objective of this fourth project phase are well developed stastitical systems in the region in line with the EU acquis for stastics. The project objective is that the National Statistical Institutes (NSIs) of the region actively engage each other regarding support and transfer of know-how with reference to more efficient statistical production and adaptation ot EU standards and acquis.

The component objectives are:

1) The NSIs are able to produce statistics more efficiently by using administrative date, with retained or improved quality
2) The NSIs are jointly able to supply each other with training and support, consistent with EU standards and EU acquis.
3) The Summer School institutionalised and fully owned by the NSIs in the region.

By contributing to the strengthening and institutionalisation of the cooperation between the national statistic authorities in the region the capacity building provided in previous project phases is expected to be strengthened and as such contributes to the long term sustainability of good standards for respective countries statistics.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Statistiska Centralbyr&#xE5;n (SCB) har s&#xF6;kt om medel om totalt 19 122 000 SEK f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra &quot;Regional Cooperation Project in South Eastern Europe&quot;  (Albanien, Bosnien &amp; Herzegovina, Kosovo, Macedonien, Montenegro och Serbien) under perioden 2019-2023. Denna insats omfattar en fj&#xE4;rde och sista fas i samarbetet.

Syftet med insatsen &#xE4;r  att utveckla statistiska system i regionen i linje med EUs acquis f&#xF6;r statistik. Insatsens syftar till att de nationella statistikmyndigheterna i respektive samarbetsland i regionen aktivt engagerar och st&#xF6;djer varandra samt bidrar till gemensam kapacitetsutveckling, delar med sig av varandras kunskap och erfarenheter om att utveckla statistik och anpassning till EUs standards och acquis.

I insatsens komponenter ing&#xE5;r:
1) Att de nationella statistik myndigheterna producerar statistik mer effektivt genom att anv&#xE4;nda administrativ data, med bibeh&#xE5;llen och f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad kvalite;
2) Att de nationella statistik myndigheterna gemensamt bidrar till utbildningar och st&#xF6;d till varandra, i enlighet med EUs standards och EUs acquis;
3) Att sommarskolorna institutionaliseras och fullt ut &#xE4;gs av de nationella statistik myndigheterna i regionen.

Genom att bidra till att st&#xE4;rka och institutionalisera samarbetet mellan de nationella statistik myndigheterna i regionen v&#xE4;ntas den kapacitetsutvecklingen som ing&#xE5;tt i tidigare faser st&#xE4;rkas och skapa b&#xE4;ttre f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar f&#xF6;r l&#xE5;ngsiktig h&#xE5;llbarhet vad g&#xE4;ller god standard f&#xF6;r respektive lands statistik.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project includes the following component objectives:
1. The national statistical institutes are able to produce statistics more efficiently by using administrative data, with retained or improved quality.
2. The national statistical institutes are jointly able to supply each other with training and support, consistent with EU standards and EU acquis.
3. The Summer School institutionalised and fully owned by the national statistical institutes in the region.
The project will include administrative data and registers; survery methodology; and summer schools.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SCB/Statistiska centralbyr&#xE5;n</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="11001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SCB/Statistiska centralbyr&#xE5;n</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16062" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Statistical capacity building</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="17.18" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">17.18 - By 2020, enhance capacity-building support to developing countries, including for least developed countries and small island developing States, to increase significantly the availability of high-quality, timely and reliable data disaggregated by income, gender, age, race, ethnicity, migratory status, disability, geographic location and other characteristics relevant in national contexts</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">17.18 - By 2020, enhance capacity-building support to developing countries, including for least developed countries and small island developing States, to increase significantly the availability of high-quality, timely and reliable data disaggregated by income, gender, age, race, ethnicity, migratory status, disability, geographic location and other characteristics relevant in national contexts.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">381445.3410040293</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">381445.3410040293</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-01">381445.341004</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-28">139752.0066836578</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">241693.3343203714</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/vbtla/11608_012636-19ServicePurchaseArrangementbetweenSidaandStaticticsSwedenregardingRegion2451564_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Service Purchase Arrangement between Sida and Statictics Sweden regarding Regional Cooperation Project South Eastern Europe 2019-2023</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/vbtla/11608_010543-19Beslutominsats,StatistisktregionaltsamarbeteVastraBalkan2019-20232439777_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Cooperation Project South Eastern Europe 2019-2023</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project &quot;Regional Cooperation Project in South Eastern Europe - 2019-2023&quot; is the fourth and final phase of a cooperation between Statistics Sweden (SCB) and the national statistics institutes in the EU canidate&#xA0;and potential candidate countries of Western Balkans namely Albania; Macedonia; Montenegro; Serbia; Kosovo; and Bosnia and Herzegovina. This final phase continues to aim for well-developed statistical systems in the region in line with the EU acquis for statistics.&#xA0;Additionally, to contribute to long term sustainability by enhancing the national statistical institutes of the region to actively engage each other regarding support and transfer of know-how regarding a&#xA0;more efficient statistical production and adaptation to EU standards and acquis. The current budget is 13&#xA0;517&#xA0;000 SEK.&#xA0;&#xA0;
Some results reported per component&#xA0;
Administrative Registers Component Three activities within the component were conducted during the reporting period: a planning meeting in May 2019, a seminar on the register-based censuses in November 2019 and a regional conference on the use of administrative data in December 2019. The conference had participants from statistical authorities and authorities with administrative data. Experiences of using various administrative data sources in different statistical areas were shared and new potential registers data were discussed.&#xA0;
Survey Methodology ComponentA three-week course on Survey Methodology took place in the period June &#x2013; October 2019 engaging two local expert and one Swedish expert.
Twenty-five inexperienced statisticians trained in survey methodology and encouraged to share the knowledge with their counterparts at home and in the region. After the course, 79 per cent of the participants expressed that they would be able to use the acquired knowledge in their everyday work. All participants expressed that they would be able to improve the quality in any survey they work with. This contributes to one of the component objectives.
Having local experts participating as lecturers on the courses,&#xA0;together with expert from SCB,&#xA0;represents a contribution towards the component objective &quot;The NSIs are jointly able to supply each other with training and support, in accordance with EU standards and the EU acquis&quot;.&#xA0;
Summer School Component The late project start (the project officially&#xA0;started in March 2019, but the first activity took place in May 2019) primarily&#xA0;affected the results under this component. Due to the short period from project outset until September, when the School usually takes place, the Summer School 2019 had to be cancelled. Instead the Regional Statistics Committee (RSC)&#xA0;decided to arrange a workshop on Farm Structure Survey to be conducted in early March 2020. It was however canceled based on Eurostat&apos;s decision to cancel all meetings due to the Covid-19 pandemic. SCB are now thinking about conducting the workshop&#xA0;online instead.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11608" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
