<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-6107012501-REU-15111</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTOSAI Development Initiative Core Support 2019-2023</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">INTOSAI Development Initiative k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d 2019-2023</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDI&apos;s vision, and hence the contribution&apos;s overall objective, is: Effective public external audit by Supreme Audit Institutions (SAIs) promotes transparency and accountability, effective public financial management, good governance, improved service delivery, fights corruption and contributes to poverty reduction and sustainable development.
The vision is followed by a mission-statement, core-principles and four objectives with three intermediate objectives each. These objectives are all clearly linked to performance-indicators, outputs, outcomes and impact as well as to baselines and targets. The four objectives constitute &quot;work streams&quot;, meaning that IDI works with these areas continuously and not only as program objectives to be achieved over a short period of time.&#xA0;
The four objectives are: Independent SAIs, Well governed SAIs, Professional SAIs and Relevant SAIs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTOSAI Development Initiative (IDI) hereby applies for a continued core support for its new Strategic Plan 2019-2023, for the period 1 January 2019- 31 December 2019. The applied total amount is 75 000 000 SEK, amounting to 12-14 % of IDI&#x2019;s total budget for the entire Strategic Plan. 

The International Organisation for Supreme Audit Institutions (INTOSAI) is a non-profit umbrella organization of Supreme Audit Institutions (SAI) across the world with 194-member countries. INTOSAI Development Initiative (IDI) is a non-profit, autonomous INTOSAI body, mandated to support SAI&apos;s in developing countries to sustainably enhance their performance and capacity. The IDI also serves as secretariat to the INTOSAI-Donor Cooperation. IDI was established in 1986 as an INTOSAI training body, and is currently located in Oslo, Norway. IDI receives a significant portion of its core funding based on an Act of the Norwegian Parliament, passed when IDI was transferred to Norway in 2001, where it is established under Norwegian Foundation Law. Except Norway, other core support donors are (Sweden), Austria, Estonia, DFID, European Commission and INTOSAI. A number of donors with earmarked-support are i.e. France, Canada, Saudi Arabia, Iceland. 

IDI has presented a more ambitious Strategic Plan for 2019-2023. The increased ambition lies in a new working method, so-called work streams with a new results matrix, increased focus on quality in the capacity development and increased focus on support and a full integration of gender mainstreaming throughout the Strategic Plan; from gender analysis of specific projects to gender mainstreamed activities and gender-mainstreamed selection of participants, trainers and workplans. 

IDIs Strategic Plan aims at capacity strengthening of the Supreme Audit Institutions (SAI&#x2019;s) in developing countries and in fragile countries through need-based and locally anchored programmes involving trainings, technical support and organisational development. Sida assesses IDI to have the mandate, expertise, systems, networks and long-term experience of conducting capacity development programmes of SAI&#x2019;s in developing countries, and can therefor contribute to rule of law through its contribution to increased transparency, accountability, and improved service delivery, benefiting all citizens, and mostly the most poor.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen avser ett k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d till den internationella organisationen f&#xF6;r riksrevisioner, the International Organisation for Supreme Audit Institutions, INTOSAI Development Initiative (IDI), om totalt 75 000 000 SEK under en fem &#xE5;rs-period med startdatum 1 januari 2019 till och med 31 december 2023. Insatsen syftar till att kapacitetst&#xE4;rka riksrevisioner i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nder genom ett behovs- och efterfr&#xE5;gansbaserat arbete best&#xE5;ende av utbildningar, informationsspridning och tekniskt st&#xF6;d. 

INTOSAI &#xE4;r en icke-vinstdrivande paraplyorganisation f&#xF6;r riksrevisioner &#xF6;ver hela v&#xE4;rlden. INTOSAI har 194 medlemsl&#xE4;nder och ar en regional organisationsstruktur med underorganisationer och diverse kommitt&#xE9;r och arbetsgrupper. INTOSAI har ett kapacitetsutvecklingsorgan; INTOSAI Development Initiative (IDI) som &#xE4;r registrerad som en separat enhet och &#xE4;r icke-vinstdrivande organisation. IDI har haft k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d fr&#xE5;n Sida de senaste 15 &#xE5;ren och de har h&#xE4;rmed inkommit med en ny ans&#xF6;kan om f&#xF6;rnyat k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d om 75 000 000 SEK som t&#xE4;cker perioden f&#xF6;r IDI&apos;s nya strategiska plan, 2019-2023. Den totala budgeten f&#xF6;r IDI 2019-2023 &#xE4;r ca 579 228 196 SEK, det f&#xF6;reslagna Sida st&#xF6;det om 75 000 000 uppg&#xE5;r till ca 12-14 % av den totala budgeten. Det inneb&#xE4;r en procentuell minskning fr&#xE5;n f&#xF6;reg&#xE5;ende k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;dperiod - 2014-2018, d&#xE5; den totala IDI budgeten uppgick till ca 220 000 000 SEK - d&#xE5; Sida st&#xF6;det uppgick till ca 18%. Den procentuella minskningen, trots den stora totala budget&#xF6;kningen, h&#xE4;rleds till ut&#xF6;kat st&#xF6;d fr&#xE5;n traditionella givare samt nyf&#xF6;rv&#xE4;rv av nya givare. K&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;dsgivarna &#xE4;r i f&#xF6;ljande storleksordning; Norge, Sverige/Sida, &#xD6;sterrike, Estland, DFID, Europeiska Kommissionen samt INTOSAI. Bland givare med &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkt st&#xF6;d finns t ex; Frankrike, Canada, Saudi Arabien, Island m.fl.  

IDI bed&#xF6;ms av Sida ha mandat, kompetens i form av expertis, system, n&#xE4;tverk och erfarenhet att bedriva ett kapacitetsutvecklande program av riksrevisioner i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nder i syfte att bidra till de svenska prioriteringarna och till att r&#xE4;ttsstatens principer i h&#xF6;gre grad kan r&#xE5;da i de kontexter programmen verkar i.

IDI har en ny och mer ambiti&#xF6;s strategisk plan f&#xF6;r 2019-2023. Den &#xF6;kade ambitionen best&#xE5;r av en ny arbetsmodell med mer fokus p&#xE5; kvalit&#xE9; och st&#xF6;d, anpassade efter lokala behov och rekommendationer fr&#xE5;n en halvtids&#xF6;versyn genomf&#xF6;rd av Sida. Den &#xF6;kande ambitionen best&#xE5;r &#xE4;ven av en genderintegration av hela den strategiska planen, fr&#xE5;n genderanalys av samtliga insatser och aktiviteter till genomf&#xF6;rande och urval av aktiviteter, deltagare, f&#xF6;rel&#xE4;sare och arbetsplaner.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDI/Intosai Development Initiative</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDI/Intosai Development Initiative</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-23" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15111" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public finance management (PFM)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">951.7867151725</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">488.6152643409</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">804.4864694703</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">1049.33017757</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">1818.8389744546</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">951.7867151725</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">488.6152643409</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">804.4864694703</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">454.7097436137</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">1818.8389744546</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-23">4758.933575</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-28">475.8933575863</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-28">475.8933575863</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-28">488.6152643409</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-28">524.665088785</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-28">279.8213806853</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-07">454.7097436137</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61070125_61070125_GrantAgreementbetweenSidaandINTOSAIDEVELOPMENTINITIATIVE.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/61070125_61070125_Beslutominsats,INTOSAIDEVELOPMENTINITIATIVEKARNSTOD2019-2023.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDI has submitted an extensive report with an even longer appendix. The appendix is a detailed account for all activities during 2019 whereas the main report is an attempt to highlight the main achievements in terms of results for 2019. It is Sida&apos;s overall assessment that the report is still a very output oriented product but there are attempts to show results on a higher level. 

Given that this is the first year of the program period, IDI is not expected to reach concrete and sustainable results based on the new strategic plan already at this point; however, given that IDI has worked for a long time with SAIs and is an appreciated partner and resource, it is likely that some results and positive impact can be reached based on the foundation and development built over the years. 

IDI has recently reported its first year of activities 2019 and have a lengthy report with an even longer appendix specifying all activities. It is sometimes not easy to get an overview of progress made with such a detailed reporting. Nevertheless, IDI highlights a number of achievements in the last report. It is Sida&apos;s view that IDI has a tendency to report on activities and outputs rather than results in the sense we would prefer. This is understandable but it needs to be repeatedly raised in the dialogue with IDI that Sida appreciates efforts to report achievements on outcome level. 

IDI has reached many of the world&apos;s SAIs during 2019, confirming the global caracther of the organisation. IDI reports that 166 SAIs were supported by IDI activities, of which 120 developing countries SAIs. Approximately 1900 SAI staff individuals were reached. 

One of the most important features of an SAI is the independence from the executive (and other undue influence). In the dedicated work stream for SAI independence, IDI has assisted a number of SAIs to advocate for independence, as well as supporting one individual SAI in strengthening its practical independence. IDI has developed a knowledge centre and an online platform to provide support on independence issues and tried to set up a &apos;rapid advocacy mechanism&apos; for SAIs whose independence is threatened. In the INTOSAI-donor cooperation (where Sida is a part) IDI tried to mobilise support for a joint donor statement for two countries where the SAIs were threatened by measures from the executive to limit their independence. When Sida discussed the issue with foreign representations in the countries concerned it was decided that Sweden would prefer a response from the country representatives regarding all public institutions at risk, in certain cases also including the threats to CSOs and free media. Some donor colleagues in the INTOSAI-donor cooperation will likely face similar challenges, which is a limitation to the effectiveness of such a rapid advocacy mechanism. The audit office is often not the only institution that is under attack during unrestful times; and partner countries with country representation are often eager to coordinate its response from there. 

A big piece for IDI when it comes to well-governed SAIs is the SAI Performance Measurement Framework that is developed based on other assessment tools such as the PEFA tool for PFM systems. PMF is a measurement tool for SAIs to use as an indication of its own development. It is not thought to be a benchmark to other peer institutions but it may unavoidably be used in that way, which of course has both pro&apos;s and con&apos;s. 11 SAI PMF were finalised in 2019 and so far 57 countries have undergone the assessment to identify performance in a number of areas such as audit quality and quality assurance systems. 

Regarding the professionalisation of SAIs, IDI has developed handbooks for both financial and compliance audit. It is too soon to note any impact of these handbooks even if they have been published in multiple languages. It is also not very clear how these products relate to the handbooks already in place in individual countries as well as the connection to other development initiatives by other actors or provider of support. Given that the quality is good, it is of course very positive that the handbooks are available to any SAI who needs them. It will be interesting to hear how the handbooks have been received by the SAI community. 

In an effort to make SAIs relevant to their national stakeholders, IDI has supported more than 50 SAIs in their audit of the respective government&apos;s implementation of the SDGs. Also this effort needs to be followed up at a later stage to see t owhat extent it has had any effect on a ational level. 

IDI is also a bilateral partner to the audit offices of Somalia and South Sudan. It is the board&apos;s ambition to keep IDI&apos;s bilateral engagements to a minimum and on a basis of &apos;provider of last resort&apos;. This is something that also the Swedish National Audit Office has promoted through its board presence (Auditor General Helena Lindberg is a board member). This goes well in line with Sida&apos;s basis for support to IDI as an international organisation with a global added value.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="61070125" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1070103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Human rights, democracy and the rule of law 2018-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>M&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter, demokrati och r&#xE4;ttsstatens principer 2018-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
