<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12715A0101-VBA-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Civil Society Development Hub (BCSDN)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Regional Civil Society Development Hub (BCSDN)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project aim: Through the establishment of a Regional Civil Society Development Hub to enhance the cooperation and resilience of civil society organisations, by connecting and empowering them in innovative uptakes of the enabling environment and their practises of accountability.
Specific objective 1: To contribute to a conducive environment for civil society that enables CSOs to be influential actors in the society.
Specific objective 2: To support effective, transparent and accountable CSOs that contribute in protecting civic space.
Specific objective 3: To strengthen regional cooperation for promoting civic space through the Civil Society Development Fund.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Civilsamh&#xE4;llesn&#xE4;tverket BCSDN utarbetar och testar en regional mekanism f&#xF6;r kapacitetsuppbyggnad och bidragsf&#xF6;rmedling, som skapas och f&#xF6;rvaltas av n&#xE4;tverkets medlemmar, som &#xE4;r v&#xE4;letablerade civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer med expertkunskap och vidaref&#xF6;rmedlingserfarenhet i sex l&#xE4;nder p&#xE5; Balkan. Fokusomr&#xE5;den f&#xF6;r n&#xE4;tverkets arbete &#xE4;r i) en gynnsam milj&#xF6; f&#xF6;r det civila samh&#xE4;llet, ii) CSO:s egna system f&#xF6;r ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande och &#xF6;ppenhet. Insatsen &#xE4;r en pilotfas p&#xE5; tv&#xE5; &#xE5;r.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Balkan Civil Society Development Network (BCSDN) is elaborating and testing a regional capacity-building and grant-making facility, created and managed by their members, ie well established CS organisations with CS expertise and grant-making experience in the six Balkan countries. The overall aim is, through the establishment of a Regional Civil Society Development Hub to enhance the cooperation and resilience of civil society organisations, by connecting and empowering them in innovative uptakes of the enabling environment and their practises of accountability. The two focus areas are i) the enabling environment for civil society, ii) CSOs&apos; own systems for accountability and transparency.
This is a piloting phase of 2 years during which a participatory elaboration and co-creation process as well as the launch of two rounds of calls for proposal will be carried out.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="32000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Balkan Civil Society Development Network/Fondacija BCSDN Skopje</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="32000" role="4" type="30">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Balkan Civil Society Development Network/Fondacija BCSDN Skopje</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.8" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.8 - Broaden and strengthen the participation of developing countries in the institutions of global governance.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.8 - Utvidga och st&#xE4;rka utvecklingsl&#xE4;ndernas deltagande i institutionerna f&#xF6;r global styrning.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">740278.5562453072</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">740278.5562453072</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">-1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-28">740278.5562453072</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-01">740278.556245</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/vbtla/12715_022657-19GrantAgreementbetweenSidaandBalkanCivilSocietyDevelopmentNetwork(BCSDN2504594_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement between Sida and Balkan Civil Society Development Network (BCSDN), Protecting Civic Space - Regional Civil Society Development Hub</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/vbtla/12715_023043-19BeslutominsatsRegionalCivilSocietyDevelopmentHub(SEE)2502829_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution Regional Civil Society Development Hub</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BCSDN is a regional network of 14 local civil society organisations from the Balkan region. With many years of previous informal cooperation, the network was formally established as a non-profit civil society organisation under North Macedonian law in 2009, with its hub (the Executive Office) registered in Skopje. Members pay annual membership fees to the Network. Their mission is to empower civil society and influence policies towards more enabling environment for civil society development in order to ensure sustainable and functioning democracies in the Balkans.
The project includes a sub-granting mechanism to be elaborated, set up and managed by the involved parties. The process of designing the Hub and the Fund and its functioning is at the core of the project. During the first project year BCSDN has been focusingng on&#xA0;finalizing the institutional set up, developing the procedures and mechanisms of its functioning and implementing the strategic research on the enabling environment for civil society in the region.&#xA0;
Some results during the period;
During the first months of implementation Partnership Agreements were signed with the five members from Albania, BiH, Macedonia, Montenegro and Serbia that would be involved in the implementation of the project as implementing partners (In the case of Kosovo &#x2013; a Memorandum of Understanding(MoU) for implementing the same tasks was signed, but without allocation of funding, as the Kosovo Civil Society Development Foundation is already receiving core funding from Sida).
Following the launch of the partnership agreements, work on the strategicresearch involving monitoring of the enabling environment for civil society in the region has been done.&#xA0;The Task Force Group was established in November 2019, where each of the implementing partners assigned one person &#x2013; usually the grants manager and/or other representative with grants experience.&#xA0;The Task Force Group had intensive work on the development of the Internal Manual of Procedures, which&#xA0;provides information on the formation on the roles and responsibilities of all entities involved in functioning of the HUB, procedures for the selection of projects and contracting, monitoring and evaluation, payments, prevention and detection of irregularities, audits and records keeping. The Manual was developed by the Grants Manager as a participatory process involving the input of the Task Force Group comprised from grants managers from the implementing partners/ members of BCSDN.
The Steering Group were established during the second quarter of the project. Based on clearly stated criteria and well designed process, the members of the Steering Group were selected by the Board in mid April 2020. All of the five members are experts with strong background in civil society development, including enabling environment, civic space and accountability of CSOs, good knowledge of the region and sound experience as managers or evaluators of grantmaking in these areas. Except the representative of the Board, the rest of the members are independent from the network, though they have good knowledge of its work due to cooperation with it in the past.
The strategic research on the enabling environment tendencies and challenges has been completed at the national level and on the regional level, whichprovides a good basis for defining the priorities of the Fund&#x2019;s implementation strategy and respectively of the calls for proposals.
Call for proposals for ad-hoc support grants as well as&#xA0; for the regional grants have been launched. However, due to Covid-19 the calls were launched a bit later than first forseen.&#xA0;
Sida notes that BCSDN during the first project year have come a long way with the institutional set up of the new Fund. This was also confirmed in the mid-term evaluation that was conducted during spring 2020.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12715" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
