<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5503013403-COE-41010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">E5P Eastern Europe Energy Efficiency and Environment Partnership - Regional</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">E5P Eastern Europe Energy Efficiency and Environment Partnership - Regional</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">E5P syftar till att minska koldioxidutsl&#xE4;pp, &#xF6;ka                      energieffektivisering och minska milj&#xF6;p&#xE5;verkan fr&#xE5;n t ex avfall,      vatten och avloppsvatten. Insatsen avser bidrag till E5P (Eastern     Europe Energy Efficiency and Environment Partnership)att f&#xF6;rutom      Ukraina (p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende) inkludera &#xE4;ven Moldavien, Georgien och Armenien.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The E5P&#xB4;s objectives are to improve energy efficiency, reduce CO2 and Green House Gas Emissions and reduce impact on environment from i.a.  waste, wastewater. The contribution concerns the extention of the E5P (Eastern Europe Energy Efficiency and Environment Partnershipto)to    include beside Ukraine (on-going) also Moldova, Georgia och Armenia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are Fund objectives at three levels: outcome, bridging, and output. The intended outcome of the E5P Fund is described in the Rules of the Fund. There are two outcome objectives 1) significant energy savings; 2) a reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) and other greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. There are no baseline or target values set at the outcome level.
The output objectives&#xA0;for the Fund is actual projects being implemented in accordance to the requirements of the Fund as described in the Annex 2 of the Rules of the Fund. The actual projects will have to describe clear outputs related to the two main outcomes of the Fund in the form of estimated energy and environmental benefits. Reform&#xA0;results (&quot;soft issues&quot;) are also&#xA0;measured within the framework of each project.
There are bridging objectives for the intervention logic between the actual projects and the intended outcome of the Fund. These are the actual Fund Management activities, described in the Rules of the Fund and also in the Work Program for the Fund. Among these are 1) handling administrative issues, such as to prepare contribution agreements and to administer funding agreements; 2) establishing, maintaining and developing an E5Prelated policy dialogue with the counterparts in cooperation with the IFIs, and 3) paying attention to marketing, awareness and visibility to increase the awareness and competence regarding energy efficiency in the municipal utility sector in general, and E5P as a tool to solve bottlenecks in the sector in particular.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="46015" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EBRD/European Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="46015" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2029-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="410" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Environment Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="17.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">17.3 - Mobilisera additionella finansiella resurser till utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna fr&#xE5;n m&#xE5;nga olika k&#xE4;llor.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">17.3 - Mobilize additional financial resources for developing countries from multiple sources.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="7.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">7.b - By 2030, expand infrastructure and upgrade technology for supplying modern and sustainable energy services for all in developing countries, in particular least developed countries, small island developing States and landlocked developing countries, in accordance with their respective programmes of support.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">7.b - Till 2030 bygga ut infrastrukturen och uppgradera tekniken f&#xF6;r att leverera moderna och h&#xE5;llbara energitj&#xE4;nster till alla i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna, i synnerhet de minst utvecklade l&#xE4;nderna och sm&#xE5; &#xF6;nationer under utveckling.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="9.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">9.4 - By 2030, upgrade infrastructure and retrofit industries to make them sustainable, with increased resource-use efficiency and greater adoption of clean and environmentally sound technologies and industrial processes, with all countries taking action in accordance with their respective capabilities.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">9.4 - Till 2030 rusta upp infrastrukturen och anpassa industrin f&#xF6;r att g&#xF6;ra dessa h&#xE5;llbara, med effektivare resursanv&#xE4;ndning och fler rena och milj&#xF6;v&#xE4;nliga tekniker och industriprocesser. Alla l&#xE4;nder vidtar &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder i enlighet med sina respektive f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">2931691.5860451483</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">2931691.5860451474</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">5429058.4926762</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">4145427.746729</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">2931691.5860451483</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/vbtla/55030134_013013-21signedversion5thDec2013-201312051420599172905307_1_1.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contribution agreement 2013</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The cooperation with the E5P Secretariat, managed by the EBRD, has worked satisfactorily. During 2017, the Fund Manager has had frequent contacts with both Sida and the Ministry of Foreign Affairs in Sweden, on strategic and operational issues. Assembly meetings have been held as per the E5P Rules. Steering Group meetings likewise. Steering Group meetings for Ukraine have continued with a frequency of twice per year. The EBRD /E5P Secretariat has improved narrative reporting from the fund, an issue which has been brought up by Sida several times, latest in May 2017 during the EBRD Annual meeting. There are now separate country reports for each of the recipient countries. What is still&#xA0;missing is a global aggregation of results from all five recipient countries. 1. Ukraine At the&#xA0;end of 2017,&#xA0;the amounts pledged by donors to the E5P Fund for Ukraine were approximately EUR 112 million of which&#xA0; all were paid in to the Fund. After the E5P Assembly meeting in December 2017, all funds were committed to projects. Disbursement levels from the fund are still very low due to the problems in project implementation. Despite that both the macroeconomic and&#xA0;conflict&#xA0;situation in Ukraine has improved somewhat, the environment for project implementation in the municipalities remains very difficult and it will take more time and effort than previously envisaged to resolve issues related to implementation and fund disbursement. There is also a risk that new and larger initiatives like the proposed Energy Efficiency Fund, although welcomed and needed, are given more attention by the Government, leading to less possibility for E5P to remain as the major platform for dialogue on energy efficiency between the Government of Ukraine, the EU and other key donors and partners. The overall rate of disbursements in Ukraine remains slow, mainly due to the current legal and regulatory obstacles in Ukraine, the most serious on being the right for Naftagas to block DH utilities accounts and divert part of revenues for payments of debts and penalties. Major efforts by the IFIs, mainly the EBRD, in cooperation with the Ukraine Government has improved the situation somewhat by unlocking some of the key barriers, but severe hurdles to effective project implementation and disbursement remain. There is a great deal of concern about the current rate of disbursements of the E5P grants in Ukraine and&#xA0;E5P has urged Ukraine to continue efforts to resolve the outstanding legal, regulatory and tariff issues in cooperation with the IFIs, the EU and other donors to ensure effective implementation of E5P projects.&#xA0;In February 2017, a special meeting was held in Kiev to address issues on slow project progress and related disbursements from the fund for the Ukraine project.&#xA0;As a result, a&#xA0;list of actions to try to&#xA0;accelerate the Ukraine projects was agreed on. 2. Other participating countries For Moldova, about 30 MEUR has been pledged for Moldova and&#xA0;12 MEUR paid in so far by donors.&#xA0;After the 2017 Assembly,&#xA0;3 projects have been approved with a total grant contribution of&#xA0;13 MEUR. For Armenia, 20 MEUR has been pledged and&#xA0;12 MEUR paid in. Up to now,&#xA0;four projects for Armenia with an overall grant allocation of EUR&#xA0;11 million have been approved for financing from E5P. For Georgia, 20 MEUR has been pledged and&#xA0;15,7&#xA0;MEUR paid in. Up to now,&#xA0; 4 projects for Georgia with an overall grant allocation of EUR 16,3 million has been approved for financing from E5P. During 2017, Belarus announced its intentions to join the E5P. Donors pledged a total amount of about&#xA0;16 MEUR for the Belarus window of E5P. Sweden pledged an amount of 50 MSEK, with 10 MSEK to be paid in directly, the remaining 40 MSEK to be be paid in conditional to administrative and regulatory reforms by Belarus to i.a. create a more enabling environment for implementation of projects under the NDEP as well as the E5P. The first project in Belarus, a solid waste project in Puhovichi, was also approved with E5P financing of 2 MEUR. The Energy supply and consumption context for the new countries of operation differs substantially from Ukraine, meaning that other types of project will be put forward by the countries and implementing agencies. The projects in Armenia, Georgia and Moldova, are generally in earlier stages and it remain to be seen of they can be implemented at a faster pace than in Ukraine.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
   <other-flags code="3" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="55030134" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.0" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
