<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>ZA-NPO-048-364-SSN_VCA</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="ZA-NPO-048-364" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SouthSouthNorth</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voices for Just Climate Action SSN</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme will be implemented in Bolivia &amp; Paraguay, Brazil, Indonesia, Kenya, Tunisia and Zambia, and will be supported by a global programme and a Dutch society engagement component. We will build broad societal support for locally-shaped, often nature-based, climate solutions using an inclusive and rights-based approach. The Alliance will facilitate new coalitions in ways that
protect and expand civic space, and engage in inclusive dialogue that builds mutual trust. We aim to influence (climate) finance and investments in support of locally shaped solutions for climate
adaptation and mitigation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme will start by creating an environment in which organisational development and new collaborations can take place through mutual capacity strengthening for co-creating alternative
solutions. This will be done by connecting civil society organisations
representing a wide range of constituencies (women, youth, indigenous people, local communities, urban poor, digital activists, citizen journalists, etc.) that have valuable experience, skills, perspectives and aspirations relating to climate action. We believe different civil society groups can collaborate on a shared climate agenda because they face shared risks, challenges and opportunities around climate and development. Strong civil society organisations and actors that unite behind a common agenda, with improved strategic lobbying and advocacy capacities and a supportive public debate, can no longer be ignored by decision-makers. At the same time, the Alliance and its partners will
strengthen their mutual capacity around scalable locally-shaped, climate solutions, promote them and connect scalable solutions to external private and public funding sources. Our strategic focus on
locally-shaped solutions therefore refers to climate solutions that are locally (co-)developed, shaped or supported by citizens and civil society in a way that effectively and appropriately addresses
their fundamental rights and needs. They are also often nature-based: ecosystem conservation, management and/or restoration interventions intentionally planned to deliver measurable positive
climate adaptation and/or mitigation benefits that have human development and biodiversity co-benefits, managing anticipated climate risks to nature that can undermine their long-term
effectiveness. Locally-shaped solutions can also be urban actions or inclusive digital innovations, such as decentralised renewable energy or urban planning that meets the needs of slum-dwellers.
Second, Alliance partners will seek to set the agenda and create movement on climate action through amplifying alternative storytelling. Through online and offline multimedia strategies, information on climate will become more easily accessible and more engaging through innovative communication and storytelling. Where information gaps exist, we will connect civil society groups to knowledge networks and promote citizen-led data collection premised on intersectionality to inform lobbying and advocacy. Through smart use of traditional and (secure) digital media, new partnerships and innovative storytelling, this information and narrative can shape public debate on climate action. This will help to amplify voices in a way that ensures civil society cannot be ignored. An outspoken civil society with increased capacity, a shared agenda, supportive public debate, informed by access to information and with powerful allies, will be well positioned to provide strong joint lobbying &amp; advocacy to make climate policy, practice and finance more responsive to locally shaped climate solutions, and will be heard by governments and the private sector.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="ZA-NPO-048-364-SSN_VCA" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="ZA-NPO-048-364" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SouthSouthNorth</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="ZA-NPO-048-364-SSN_VCA" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="ZA-NPO-048-364" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SouthSouthNorth</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41177588-201964" ref="NL-KVK-41177588" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WNF Wereld Natuur Fonds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Amplifying Voices for Just Climate Actions (VCA) programme start date is 1 January 2021.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The end date for the Amplifying Voices For Just Climate Actions (VCA) programme is 31 December 2025</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SouthSouthNorth</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate and Development Implementation</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate and Development Implementation</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+27214470211</telephone>
   <email>info@voicesforclimateaction.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">55 Salt River Rd, Salt River, Cape Town, South Africa</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-23">4005000</value>
  </budget>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41177588-201975" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
