<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>ZA-NPO-048-364-VCA_SSN_Tunisia</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="ZA-NPO-048-364" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SouthSouthNorth</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voices for Just Climate Action SSN Tunisia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As a VCA Alliance member, SSN brings extensive experience and expertise on knowledge and partnership brokering for climate-compatible development, and on building unique relationships with decision-makers in various contexts. Through the Alliance, SSN aims to support the generation, dissemination, and brokering of information, building the capability of partners to enable them to respond innovatively to the challenges and opportunities that climate change presents. Knowledge intermediaries and knowledge translators are roles that we often refer to as part of &#x2018;Knowledge Management&#x2019; and are key roles that SSN provides in the VCA programme. Knowledge brokering, on the other hand, includes activities by knowledge/process brokers and innovation brokers, focusing on networks, relationship-building, and systemic change through knowledge co-production.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Voices for Just Climate Action (VCA) Programme is being implemented in 7 countries, including Tunisia. In VCA Tunisia the programme focuses on strategically involving and prioritising three main groups. The first group consists of stakeholders that have high influence, but low interest in climate justice. Such stakeholders include government entities and officials. In order to advocate and lobby at such a level, the programme will strongly focus on involving stakeholders that have high influence and high interest in climate justice, such as CSOs, social entrepreneurs, journalists, knowledge institutions, climate justice activists, youth and women movements. In order to further unite and amplify voices, the programme will also include stakeholders that have high interest, but low influence such as citizens and CSOs, national and regional networks, and national knowledge institutions.This programme aligns with several other programmes and projects in Tunisia and will closely monitor their work by utilising VCA Tunisia Alliance members&#x2019; vast local, regional and international network. It will also build upon its wide network of investigative journalists, artists, and activists in Tunisia to amplify voices on climate justice. .</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="ZA-NPO-048-364-SSN_VCA" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="ZA-NPO-048-364" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SouthSouthNorth</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="ZA-NPO-048-364-SSN_VCA" ref="ZA-NPO-048-364" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SouthSouthNorth</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Voices for Just Climate Action (VCA) programme start date is 1 January 2021.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The end date for the VCA programme is 31 December 2025. However, the Tunisia programme is a shorter component.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SouthSouthNorth</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate and Development Implementation</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate and Development Implementation</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+27214470211</telephone>
   <email>info@voicesforclimateaction.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">55 Salt River Rd, Salt River, Cape Town, South Africa</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-23">572239</value>
  </budget>
  <related-activity ref="ZA-NPO-048-364-SSN_VCA" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
