<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="KES" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ-NIG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S" secondary-reporter="0" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development and Communication Network (FEMNET)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AACJ-Nigeria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FEMNET will work with Education as a Vaccine (EVA), a youth advocacy organization with six local offices in Nigeria which strengthens the capacities of young people to facilitate and sustain social change. We will work with women, youth and local communities &#x2013; as well as other traditionally sidelined groups, such as people with disabilities</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STRATEGIC COUNTRY OBJECTIVE: A grassroots driven movement &#x2013; bringing together local organizations and broad constituencies &#x2013; drives the implementation of climate policies that enable all Nigerians to thrive and live in a healthy environment.The programme will contribute to the following impact areas Impact Outcome 1: IMPACT Outcome 1: A strong, inclusive and effective civil society movement is connected and empowered to amplify communities&#x2019; voices in the fight for climate justice. The AACJ consortium in Nigeria will work with local organizations on outreach and build alliances between organizations of women, youth and (climate/oil)- affected rural communities to jointly run campaigns and advocate for community-driven solutions (Pathway 1). 
Climate-just narratives will raise awareness on climate change and bring in more constituencies such as youth, journalists, local policy makers (Pathway 2). A network of nano-influencers in communities, media content creators, journalists, artists and social media influencers will mobilize support for a just energy transition and realization of NDC commitments. Plans include a #ClimateJusticeTour and an art-based campaign to showcase local narratives around climate justice, highlighting the leadership of women and young people. To increase support for community-driven climate action, the consortium will initiate national-level forums (inviting legislators at national and subnational levels, state, civil society and private sector actors), events and media engagements to showcase workable innovations that boost climate resilience and information sharing in communities (Pathway 4).

Impact Outcome 2: Systems of accountability at national and subnational levels are strengthened 
to help ensure the protection of communities and resilience of livelihoods against the worst of climate change impact and environmental degradation.
To increase public accountability the consortium will establish formal platforms that enable government officials to listen to and engage with citizens on policy issues. For example, Climate Governance Dialogues will involve local, national and state executives, legislature, local communities and excluded groups in knowledge transfer with government agencies on e.g. access to cleaner, decentralized and community-controlled energy, improved climate finance and budgeting, environmental impact assessments, climate finance, adaptation plans and reporting (Pathway 5). 
The consortium will support working groups of journalists, community leaders and CSOs to access climate negotiations147 and co-create policy positions. The programme will develop an NDC implementation index and compliance scorecard. 
The consortium will also invest in working with oil-affected communities to increase their knowledge and understanding of their rights and how to claim them, for example through FPIC. The consortium will directly support environmental defenders, strengthening their security and protection capabilities (Pathway 3). 
The programme focuses on women and youth due to their challenges in accessing resources and decision-making, and on the northern part of the country as it is especially affected by climate change and poverty.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The AACJ programme will be implemented in eight African countries: Burkina Faso, Ethiopia, Kenya, Nigeria, Mozambique, Senegal, Somalia and South Africa. The AACJ consortium believes that building strong and inclusive movements for climate justice in these countries can be the engine for a powerful pan-African movement for climate justice. For the AACJ consortium, climate justice means all people have the right to live a decent and dignified life in a healthy environment. We believe that curbing climate change and enabling all people to build resilience and recover from climate-related shocks is key to break the vicious cycle of inequality and vulnerability. The impacts of climate change are not being borne equally or fairly, between rich and poor, women and men, and older and younger generations. The voices of frontline communities who both offer solutions to protect our climate and face the harshest consequences of the immediate impacts of climate change, are excluded from the policy debates shaping their futures. Their voices are often also isolated as opposed to aligned and lack the capacity to come together in unified front calling for action. The goal of our programme is to amplify and unite the voices in Africa demanding that women, youth and local and indigenous communities in the 8 target countries can defend and realize their human rights and live a decent and dignified life in a healthy and sustainable environment, within the context of the climate emergency. We will not only respond to power asymmetries within countries, but also challenge asymmetries of power between countries. 

We will connect with movements outside Africa, such as Climate Action Network Europe, jointly challenging unaccountable governments and unsustainable production and consumption patterns. Making these connections will help increase solidarity across communities and make the global climate movement more inclusive and legitimate. We will work from local to regional to global level, and vice versa. We will amplify local voices &#x2013; communicating both struggles and positive experiences &#x2013; to advocate for strong climate policies and national laws, and demand and monitor their implementation. We will use progressive frameworks, such as the Paris Agreement, the Africa 2063 Agenda and the SDGs to influence national governments and companies for positive changes in people&#x2019;s lives The AACJ consortium believes that clear and compelling narratives play a crucial to increase the engagement of youth, women and local and indigenous communities in the debate and policy processes on climate justice. Taking people&#x2019;s lived experience as a starting point, these narratives will play a key role in raising awareness, unveiling prejudices and stereotypes, debunking lies and rebalancing relations of power. 

The AACJ consortium will amplify African voices, encouraging environmental activists, indigenous leaders, women, youth, religious leaders, artists and opinion makers to share their personal experiences and contribution to addressing climate change. We will create safe spaces for traditionally sidelined groups to develop their own narratives which demonstrate their strength, resilience, innovative capacities and contributions to the climate crisis. We will ensure that these new narratives are shared and spread through climate debates and policy processes, connecting policy makers with people on the frontline of the climate crisis. With will connect activists, movements and communities with popular media (TV talk shows, radio call-ins and other interactive platforms) to enable exchange of ideas and information, foster understanding and increase public awareness on how women, youth and local and indigenous communities are experiencing and coping with climate change. The role of FEMNET will be indispensable to implementing Pathway 2 by creating counter narratives to help shift the discourse on changing the discourse on climate change</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ" ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S" role="1" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development and Communication Network (FEMNET)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ-NIG" role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education as a Vaccine (EVA),</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education as a Vaccine (EVA),</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="50">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1030" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">74490</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">125800</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">106855</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">100983</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2025-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">91650</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-02">74489</value>
   <provider-org ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S"></provider-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-02">54007</value>
   <provider-org ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">35940</value>
   <provider-org ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
