<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="KES" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ-BF</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S" secondary-reporter="0" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development and Communication Network (FEMNET)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AACJ Burkina Faso</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FEMNET will work with Voix des Femmes -a local partner and will particularly advance Pathways 1 and 3. We will work with women, youth and local communities &#x2013; as well as other traditionally sidelined groups, such as people with disabilities</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The AACJ programme will be implemented in eight African countries: Burkina Faso, Ethiopia, Kenya, Nigeria, Mozambique, Senegal, Somalia and South Africa. The AACJ consortium believes that building strong and inclusive movements for climate justice in these countries can be the engine for a powerful pan-African movement for climate justice. For the AACJ consortium, climate justice means all people have the right to live a decent and dignified life in a healthy environment. We believe that curbing climate change and enabling all people to build resilience and recover from climate-related shocks is key to break the vicious cycle of inequality and vulnerability. The impacts of climate change are not being borne equally or fairly, between rich and poor, women and men, and older and younger generations. The voices of frontline communities who both offer solutions to protect our climate and face the harshest consequences of the immediate impacts of climate change, are excluded from the policy debates shaping their futures. Their voices are often also isolated as opposed to aligned and lack the capacity to come together in unified front calling for action. The goal of our programme is to amplify and unite the voices in Africa demanding that women, youth and local and indigenous communities in the 8 target countries can defend and realize their human rights and live a decent and dignified life in a healthy and sustainable environment, within the context of the climate emergency. We will not only respond to power asymmetries within countries, but also challenge asymmetries of power between countries. 

We will connect with movements outside Africa, such as Climate Action Network Europe, jointly challenging unaccountable governments and unsustainable production and consumption patterns. Making these connections will help increase solidarity across communities and make the global climate movement more inclusive and legitimate. We will work from local to regional to global level, and vice versa. We will amplify local voices &#x2013; communicating both struggles and positive experiences &#x2013; to advocate for strong climate policies and national laws, and demand and monitor their implementation. We will use progressive frameworks, such as the Paris Agreement, the Africa 2063 Agenda and the SDGs to influence national governments and companies for positive changes in people&#x2019;s lives The AACJ consortium believes that clear and compelling narratives play a crucial to increase the engagement of youth, women and local and indigenous communities in the debate and policy processes on climate justice. Taking people&#x2019;s lived experience as a starting point, these narratives will play a key role in raising awareness, unveiling prejudices and stereotypes, debunking lies and rebalancing relations of power. 

The AACJ consortium will amplify African voices, encouraging environmental activists, indigenous leaders, women, youth, religious leaders, artists and opinion makers to share their personal experiences and contribution to addressing climate change. We will create safe spaces for traditionally sidelined groups to develop their own narratives which demonstrate their strength, resilience, innovative capacities and contributions to the climate crisis. We will ensure that these new narratives are shared and spread through climate debates and policy processes, connecting policy makers with people on the frontline of the climate crisis. With will connect activists, movements and communities with popular media (TV talk shows, radio call-ins and other interactive platforms) to enable exchange of ideas and information, foster understanding and increase public awareness on how women, youth and local and indigenous communities are experiencing and coping with climate change. The role of FEMNET will be indispensable to implementing Pathway 2 by creating counter narratives to help shift the discourse on changing the discourse on climate change</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will contribute to the following impact areas: Impact outcome 1: Organizations of young and female farmers, pastoralists, people with disabilities and IDPs in the Centre, Nord, Sahel, Sud-Ouest and Centre-Nord regions of Burkina Faso rally together to promote climate justice: The AACJ consortium in Burkina Faso will promote and facilitate a broad movement of impacted communities, IDPs and minorities (including women and youth) from multiple regions (Pathway 1). The programme will allow for existing groups, organizations and movements to join forces, to develop a shared narrative and to rally together on climate justice topics (Pathway 2). Varied civil society actors will be connected with the appropriate communication channels, delivering an inclusive and effective platform. 
The consortium will also address the reduction in civic space and limits to freedom of expression faced by climate movements, including women and youth groups, supporting official recognition of civil society structures and building capacity on mobilization.
Impact Outcome 2: Public policies and frameworks have been developed that advance climate justice for the groups that are most vulnerable to the effects of climate change, through the inclusion of young and female farmers, pastoralists, people with disability and refugees in policy-making process. The programme will raise awareness of vulnerable and impacted groups &#x2013; including indigenous people, women, youth, and IDPs &#x2013; on environmental laws and climate policies and work with local communities to claim and defend their rights to a decent livelihood and healthy environment (Pathway 3). It will support local and indigenous communities to document, share and spread traditional knowledge and best practice. regarding climate adaptation and resilience (Pathway 4) while ensuring this knowledge is acknowledged as a major resource for climate adaptation by policy makers. 
The AACJ consortium in Burkina Faso will advocate for public policies and practices for protecting the livelihoods of vulnerable groups, improving their resilience and promoting inclusive climate financing, and strengthen capacities of CSOs to participate in political processes (pathway 5).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ" ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S" role="1" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development and Communication Network (FEMNET)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voix des Femmes</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voix des Femmes</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">35656</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">40376</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">40921</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">40665</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2025-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">39411</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-09">35656</value>
   <provider-org ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S" type="23"></provider-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-09">16472</value>
   <provider-org ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">22153</value>
   <provider-org ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
