<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="KES" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S" secondary-reporter="0" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development and Communication Network (FEMNET)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AACJ-African Activists for Climate Justice</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STRATEGIC REGIONAL/ GLOBAL OBJECTIVE: National AACJ movements have been connected across countries and rally together and with other (national, regional and global) climate movements, advancing the rights and interests of groups that have been affected disproportionately by climate change.

The programme will contribute to the following impact Impact areas Impact Outcome: Impact Outcome 1: Regionally Coordinated Globally Connected, Inclusive And Effective Movements Promote climate justice, while linking local issues and experiences to regional and global discussions, and keeping global and regional bodies accountable. The AACJ consortium&#x2019;s regional and global activities will aim to bring together regional movements, including those that have not traditionally engaged on climate justice, and connect national climate justice movements to regional and global levels to form broad alliances. The consortium will focus on mutual capacity development of local, national and regional organizations to self-organize, connect their struggles to regional and global challenges, and engage with regional and global debates and processes. We will reach out to (networks of) local communities and other traditionally sidelined groups to ensure they get leadership positions in regional and global movements (Pathway 1). 
AACJ will create a broad platform to allow movements to find each other, connect and rally around influencing opportunities, and build common agendas and a unified voice to influence narratives, attitudes, beliefs, policies and practices. AACJ will initiate and coordinate regional and global campaigns, and work with journalists, academics and artists to develop and promote new narratives expressing African perspectives on climate justice-related issues (Pathway 2).
IMPACT OUTCOME 2: Regional and global level policies, practices and frameworks which advance climate justice are adopted, funded, and implemented.
Through its influencing strategies (Pathway 5), AACJ will aim to: Strengthen the African voice in international agreements by proposing and promoting new alternative narratives on justice and sustainable development, and directly engaging with and technically supporting negotiators and policy makers, Engage with regional and global policy processes to secure ambitious global climate mitigation commitments and financial commitments to allow African countries and communities to take adequate adaptation action and address climate change-related loss and damage, Promote peer-to-peer learning and peer pressure (a &#x2018;race to the top&#x2019;) among African governments, to strengthen their translating of regional and global climate justice commitments into national legislation and implementation. PACJA has started comparing African countries&#x2019; progress in implementing NDCs through an NDC Index, aiming to organize competition among peers.205 AACJ can build on this, Engage with AfDB and other development banks (and potentially also private banks and investors) to leverage their influence over financial flows to promote investment in renewable energy rather than fossil energy sources, Strengthen the role of human rights frameworks through strategic litigation (aiming to create precedents and jurisprudence) and engagement with (AU and UN) Human Rights Commissions and Special Rapporteurs to influence their reports and resolutions (Pathway 3). The consortium will also support and train representatives of women, youth, indigenous peoples and local communities, to increase their climate-related knowledge and understanding of and participation in regional and global level policy procedures (Pathway 1, 4, 5).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The AACJ programme will be implemented in eight African countries: Burkina Faso, Ethiopia, Kenya, Nigeria, Mozambique, Senegal, Somalia and South Africa. The AACJ consortium believes that building strong and inclusive movements for climate justice in these countries can be the engine for a powerful pan-African movement for climate justice. For the AACJ consortium, climate justice means all people have the right to live a decent and dignified life in a healthy environment. We believe that curbing climate change and enabling all people to build resilience and recover from climate-related shocks is key to break the vicious cycle of inequality and vulnerability.

The impacts of climate change are not being borne equally or fairly, between rich and poor, women and men, and older and younger generations. The voices of frontline communities who both offer solutions to protect our climate and face the harshest consequences of the immediate impacts of climate change, are excluded from the policy debates shaping their futures. Their voices are often also isolated as opposed to aligned and lack the capacity to come together in unified front calling for action. The goal of our programme is to amplify and unite the voices in Africa demanding that women, youth and local and indigenous communities in the 8 target countries can defend and realize their human rights and live a decent and dignified life in a healthy and sustainable environment, within the context of the climate emergency.

We will not only respond to power asymmetries within countries, but also challenge asymmetries of power between countries. We will connect with movements outside Africa, such as Climate Action Network Europe, jointly challenging unaccountable governments and unsustainable production and consumption patterns. Making these connections will help increase solidarity across communities and make the global climate movement more inclusive and legitimate. We will work from local to regional to global level, and vice versa. We will amplify local voices &#x2013; communicating both struggles and positive experiences &#x2013; to advocate for strong climate policies and national laws, and demand and monitor their implementation. We will use progressive frameworks, such as the Paris Agreement, the Africa 2063 Agenda and the SDGs to influence national governments and companies for positive changes in people&#x2019;s lives

The AACJ consortium believes that clear and compelling narratives play a crucial to increase the engagement of youth, women and local and indigenous communities in the debate and policy processes on climate justice. Taking people&#x2019;s lived experience as a starting point, these narratives will play a key role in raising awareness, unveiling prejudices and stereotypes, debunking lies and rebalancing relations of power. The AACJ consortium will amplify African voices, encouraging environmental activists, indigenous leaders, women, youth, religious leaders, artists and opinion makers to share their personal experiences and contribution to addressing climate change. We will create safe spaces for traditionally sidelined groups to develop their own narratives which demonstrate their strength, resilience, innovative capacities and contributions to the climate crisis. 
We will ensure that these new narratives are shared and spread through climate debates and policy processes, connecting policy makers with people on the frontline of the climate crisis. With will connect activists, movements and communities with popular media (TV talk shows, radio call-ins and other interactive platforms) to enable exchange of ideas and information, foster understanding and increase public awareness on how women, youth and local and indigenous communities are experiencing and coping with climate change. 

The role of FEMNET will be indispensable to implementing Pathway 2 by creating counter narratives to help shift the discourse on changing the discourse on climate change.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ" ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S" role="2" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development and Communication Network (FEMNET)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ" ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development and Communication Network (FEMNET)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="KE-NCB-OP218051200904966065" ref="KE-NCB-OP218051200904966065" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pan African Climate Justice Alliance</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="57">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="7">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="7">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="SN" percentage="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="12">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="PT"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">1159857</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">1534229</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="KES" value-date="2021-05-01">1528067</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">1543857</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2025-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">1511767</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">1159587</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="KE-NCB-OP218051200904966065-PACJA-AACJ2021" ref="KE-NCB-OP218051200904966065" type="23"></provider-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <related-activity ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ-BF" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ-ETH" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ-KEN" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ-MOZ" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ-NIG" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ-REG" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ-SA" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ-SN" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="KE-KRA-P000634725S-AACJ-SOM" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
