<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://data.mcc.gov/" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:mcc="https://data.mcc.gov/ns#" xmlns:usg="http://foreignassistance.gov/iati#">
  <iati-identifier>US-18-SL2-2750BXCOMD-BUS DEVEL</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-18" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Development Services</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">El Salvador II - Business Development Services project: MCC will support the Government of El Salvador in its effort to eliminate and streamline regulations targeted towards improving the investment climate for the private sector. By supporting the implementation of El Salvador&apos;s public private partnership law, the compact will catalyze large-scale investments in key public services required for private sector-led growth. MCC and the Government will also co-sponsor the El Salvador Investment Challenge, an innovative grant facility designed to efficiently and transparently allocate scarce public resources and encourage private investment in the trade sector. With matching investments from the private sector and the Government of El Salvador, the challenge facility will leverage at least five dollars for every dollar of MCC&apos;s investment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-8" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Account - El Salvador</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States of America</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-09" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-09" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SV" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">El Salvador</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://data.mcc.gov/evaluations/index.php/catalog/233">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Investment Climate</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SL2-2750BXCOMD" type="1"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SL2-2750BXCOMD-BUS DEVEL-0389" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SL2-2750BXCOMD-BUS DEVEL-0401" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SL2-2750BXCOMD-HUMAN CAP" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SL2-2750BXCOMD-INFRSTRE" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SL2-2750BXCOMD-MON &amp; EVAL" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SL2-2750BXCOMD-NA" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-SL2-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN" type="3"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to the Disbursement of MCC Funding for any PPP transaction advisor under the Public-Private Partnerships Sub-Activity, the Government will have adopted regulations mutually satisfactory to the Parties in furtherance of the PPP Law.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to the Disbursement of MCC Funding for the transaction advisor for a particular public-private partnership (?PPP?) project under the Public-Private Partnerships Sub-Activity, the Government will have provided adequate funding and staff for that PPP project at PROESA, Hacienda, and the relevant line government entity, regulator, or sectorial oversight institution, satisfactory to MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to the Disbursement of Program Funding for ESIC investments, the Board of Directors of MCA-El Salvador will have approved the ESIC Operations Manual, satisfactory to MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to the Disbursement of Program Funding for the El Salvador Investment Challenge (?ESIC?), a proportionate amount of the Government Contribution, up to the amount available for that time period or thereafter under the Government Contribution budget at Annex 3 to this PIA, will have been disbursed under the El Salvador Investment Challenge Sub-Activity under Section B.1(a)(ii) of Annex I of the Compact, as a ratio of the Government Contribution versus the amount of the Program Funding budgeted for ESIC.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
