<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>47135-XSREAM035A</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="47135" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementing</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Utility Scale Solar Power Support Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project development objective is to increase privately owned and operated solar electricity generation in Armenia. The proposed $26 million of SREP funding will be combined with $4 million of IBRD resources to provide loan guarantees for up to 6 green-field solar power plants. These sub-projects are expected to be financed, built, owned and operated by private developers selected following a two-phase international competitive bidding process. This is the first solar power auction program ever taking place in Armenia. Not only SREP support will contribute to the diversification of Armenia&#x2019;s energy mix, currently dominated by gas and nuclear energy, it will also reduce investment barriers by piloting the deployment of the country&#x2019;s first utility-scale solar PV plants and stimulating the mobilization of commercial financing. Ultimately, the project is expected to mobilize up to $124 million of additional resources and improve access to electricity services to 3 million people, including 1.62 million of women.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-24" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementing</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+1-202-458-1801</telephone>
   <email>cifadminunit@worldbank.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Bank, 1818 H Street, NW, Washington, DC 20433 USA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AM" percentage="100" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ARMENIA</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
