<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=ETH/15/02/SID" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-105361-1207-2019-ETH176</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving industrial relations for decent work and sustainable development of textile and garment industry in Ethiopia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to contribute to national development by supporting the development of socially sustainable textile and garment industry through improved labour relations, productivity, wages and working conditions. For this purpose, the project will take multi-pronged approach of assisting the government, social partners, major stakeholders of the industry at various levels in their efforts to improve productivity, to promote social dialogue within and between the parties, and to improve wages and working conditions through nurturing sound labour relations practices and promoting collective bargaining. At national level, the project will focus on facilitating social dialogue among multiple stakeholders, under the leadership of the tripartite partners, including other major stakeholders of the industry such as major multinational brands with social and labour commitment to the country, in developing a common vision and strategies to make Ethiopia an African hub of socially responsible production of garments for both global and domestic markets. At regional and sectoral level, the project will assist labour administration at regional level, employers, workers and their organizations at sectoral and enterprise levels, in strengthening their organizational capacity and in developing sound industrial relations and social dialogue practices to improve wages and working conditions in tandem with improved productivity. At enterprise level, the project will focus on capacity building support for employers and workers and their representatives at the participating enterprises, which explicitly make commitment to the principles of the ILO on labour relations and socially responsible garment and textile industry in Ethiopia. At international level, the project will work with national tripartite partners, multinational buyers, global unions and other stakeholders to create conducive environment for socially responsible garment industry in Ethiopia. Combined together, the project will contribute to improved labour relations, social and labour compliance of Ethiopia&#x2019;s garment products in both foreign and domestic markets, through improved labour market governance, which will help to expand the industry in socially sustainable manner and therefore create decent jobs in the sector. The project is fully aligned with the country&#x2019;s development plan, the GTP. It contributes to achieving three of the seven GTP pillars namely: sustaining rapid and equitable economic growth; creating conditions for the industry sector to play key role in the economy; and promote gender and youth empowerment and equity. The project has direct deliverables to achieve sound industrial relations and occupational safety and health which are cross cutting issues to achieve seven pillars of the plan. The project also responds to tripartite priorities and concerns identified in the DWCP which is aligned to GTP and UNDAF. At the same time, the project will benefit fully from the support of the SIDA and also commitment and support of H&amp;M as a stakeholder as well as donor, as defined in the ILO- H&amp;M global partnership agreement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden, Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Departement of Partnerships and Field Support (PARDEV)</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="ET" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="ET" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="7.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ILO Results Framework 2020-2021: Output 7.1. Increased capacity of the member States to ensure respect for, promote and realize fundamental principles and rights at work</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16070" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">25082.15</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="ETH/15/02/SID-2019-ETH176 - Increased capacity of ILO&apos;s constituents to improve workplace compliance">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-30">25082.15</value>
   <provider-org ref="SE-0">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden, Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ETH/15/02/SID-2019-ETH176 - Increased capacity of ILO&apos;s constituents to improve workplace compliance">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-30">25082.15</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=ETH/15/02/SID">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Improving industrial relations for decent work and sustainable development of textile and garment industry in Ethiopia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A06"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2021-03-15"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
