<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=GLO/19/53/EUR" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-107202-823571-2019-GLO371</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving synergies between social protection and Public Finance Management</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving synergies between social protection and PFM The action supports governments&#x2019; efforts to expand or refine life-course risk protection measures including their financing basis and redistributive effects and considering the broader demographic, strategic, economic and fiscal context within which they are to be realised. Consequent improvements are to be expected to legal, policy, fiscal and macroeconomic frameworks through complementary stages of coverage, alignment and better coordination of sectoral social protection instruments, their implementation and assertion of entitlements for the beneficiaries. Integration of the social protection system with other development interventions will broaden coverage further, at the same time as increasing the longer-term resilience of beneficiaries. For a country-owned social protection system to achieve its full potential, it must be developed and regularly revised in concert with national fiscal, health, education, employment, and economic policies. Incorporating social protection policies and programmes into a policy framework that ensures the sustainability and efficiency of social protection systems requires the support of partner countries&apos; policymakers as well as the commitment of development partners to mainstream social protection at both political and technical levels. The Action&#x2019;s intervention logic refers to the following results chain: 1) Further enhancements to the policy coherence in the design and financing of social protection (specific objective 1) will not only generate improvements in the effectiveness and impact of current and future EU budget support programmes but will also foster collaboration and mutual learning across policy sectors on the social needs, best practices and operational synergies of social protection interventions and their financing to ultimately achieve stable economic growth in a sustainable, equitable and inclusive manner. 2) The increased political recognition of the potential and value of social protection will benefit in turn from the Action&#x2019;s support to better coordination, implementation and monitoring of different social protection programmes, and to capacity building at all levels (specific objective 2) thereby creating a more coherent and comprehensive overall social protection system. 3) Finally, through demonstrating the potential of social protection systems to meet basic needs and protect households and specifically respond to the differing demands in contexts of emergencies, forced displacement, structural fragility, crises or displacement, and to help creating income generating activities (specific objective 3), the Action will reinforce the importance of integrating social support into broader development and humanitarian policies, including through the participation of forcibly displaced persons in public social protection programmes, in order to achieve greater resilience of poor and vulnerable populations to family level and widespread shocks. The Action is based upon the underlying assumption that low-income economies and fragile countries generally already have co-existing social insurance schemes, covering only a minority of the working population, and a disconnected myriad of fragmented and uncoordinated poverty-targeted safety nets. To develop a comprehensive and inclusive social protection system, the intervention logic also highlights important cross cutting issues, namely the importance of strengthening national capacities, the adoption of a rights-based approach and national, participatory processes including social and national dialogue, gender responsiveness, disability inclusiveness and non-discrimination, paying attention to the environmental dimension, addressing the needs of informal economy and migrant workers and fostering knowledge creation, sharing and partnerships in order to enhance the project&#x2019;s impact. Finally, the intervention logic mentions potential risks that might arise during the projec</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-EC_DEVCO" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Commission, DG for International Cooperation, Development Cooperation Instrument</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Departement of Partnerships and Field Support (PARDEV)</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-region code="GLO" percentage="100" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="8.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ILO Results Framework 2020-2021: Output 8.1. Increased capacity of member States to develop new or reformed sustainable national social protection strategies, policies or legal frameworks to extend coverage and enhance benefit adequacy</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">45988.81</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="GLO/19/53/EUR-2019-GLO371 - Increased capacity of member States to develop new or reformed sustainable national social protection strategies, policies or legal frameworks to extend coverage and enhance benefit adequacy">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">45988.81</value>
   <provider-org ref="XI-IATI-EC_DEVCO">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Commission, DG for International Cooperation, Development Cooperation Instrument</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="GLO/19/53/EUR-2019-GLO371 - Increased capacity of member States to develop new or reformed sustainable national social protection strategies, policies or legal frameworks to extend coverage and enhance benefit adequacy">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">45988.81</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=GLO/19/53/EUR">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Improving synergies between social protection and Public Finance Management</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A06"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2021-03-15"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
