<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=RER/19/03/EUR" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-107248-1356-2019-SBU105</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Employment and Social Affairs Platform 2 (ESAP2)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This three year project is the Phase II of the Employment and Social Affairs Platform project (ESAP). This new phase (ESAP2) will consolidate the results achieved under phase I and expand the platform to cover additional employment and social policy topics of high relevance for Western Balkans. The ESAP2 consists of three thematic components: 1. Informal Employment and Undeclared Work The Informal Employment and Undeclared Work Component aims to generate quantitative evidence on what works and what does not work with regard to transition to formality in the region and improve availability and quality of data on the different dimensions of informality. The results will be the basis for evidence based policy-making supporting improved policy design and implementation to reduce informal employment and undeclared work. 2. Labour Inspection In relation to the Labour Inspection Component, informal employment and undeclared work is the main policy areas for peer learning within the Network of Labour Inspectorates in the Western Balkans mirroring the EU&#x2019;s Senior Labour Inspectors&#x2019; Committee (SLIC). The Network was established under ESAP1. A peer-review will be undertaken to increase the regional knowledge and the understanding of the different labour inspection systems and practices for preventing and combating undeclared work. Based on the results of the peer review, tailored Inspection Guidelines for detecting undeclared work will be designed and pilot tested. The results will lead to an increased outreach of the Labour Inspectorates in preventing and combatting undeclared work. 3. Social Dialogue To foster increased effectiveness of tripartite and bipartite social dialogue, the Social Dialogue Component includes three strands of action: 1. Establishment of online national and regional performance-monitoring tools in Economic and Social Councils (ESCs) for improving their impact on policy-making, 2. Development of regional guidelines for the promotion of collective bargaining in selected economic sectors, and 3. Development of online regional policy and performance tools in the area of labour dispute resolution and industrial relations. Through regular updating of the Database on Industrial relations and Working Conditions, more accurate data on number of collective agreements and collective bargaining coverage in the Western Balkans will be generated.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Commission, DG Employment and Social Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Departement of Partnerships and Field Support (PARDEV)</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="3"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-region code="SBU" percentage="100" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central and Eastern Europe - subregional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="3.5" percentage="100" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ILO Results Framework 2020-2021: Output 3.5. Increased capacity of member States to formulate and implement labour market programmes and employment services for transitions to decent work over the life course, with particular focus on young and older workers</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16070" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">3321.56</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="RER/19/03/EUR-2019-SBU105 - Improved functioning of social dialogue institutions and labour inspection">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">3321.56</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Commission, DG Employment and Social Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="RER/19/03/EUR-2019-SBU105 - Improved functioning of social dialogue institutions and labour inspection">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">3321.56</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=RER/19/03/EUR">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Employment and Social Affairs Platform 2 (ESAP2)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A06"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2021-03-15"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
