<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12851A0101-BOL-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDEA: Democracy, gender and youth</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">IDEA: Demokrati, j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och ungdomar</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Det projekt som f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;s av IDEA International syftar till att bidra till att st&#xE4;rka den bolivianska demokratin och ut&#xF6;vandet av medborgarnas r&#xE4;ttigheter genom att fr&#xE4;mja deltagandet av ungdoms- och kvinnorganisationer, samt samordningen med de politiska partierna, de autonoma regionala regeringerna (GAD) och den nationella valmyndigheten. Insatsen genomf&#xF6;rs utifr&#xE5;n fyra huvudlinjer med syfte att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra:  i) offentlig f&#xF6;rvaltning, ii) kvinnornas politiska deltagande, iii) ungdomspolitiska deltagande, och iv) valmyndighetens institutionella kapacitet. Det anses vara en forts&#xE4;ttning p&#xE5; bidraget 55180029 (Kvinnors ledarskap och medborgarnas deltagande p&#xE5; lokal niv&#xE5; - IDEA)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project proposed by IDEA International seeks to contribute to the strengthening of the  Bolivian democracy and to the full exercise of citizen rights, by promoting a coordinated participation between youth and women&apos;s organizations, the political parties, the autonomous departmental governments (GAD) and the National Electoral Body. The four strategic lines of action that will guide IDEA&apos;s initiative to achieve its objectives are aimed to enhance: i)public management, ii) the women&apos;s political participation, iii) the youth&apos;s political participation, and iv) the institutional capacity of the electoral body. It is considered to be a continuation of contribution 55180029 (Women Leadership and Citizen Participation at the local level - IDEA)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the intervention was to contribute to the strengthening of the Bolivian democracy by promoting an integral participation of the youth and women in political parties while also providing technical assistance to the National Electoral Body. The five target regions under this initiative were La Paz, Santa Cruz, Cochabamba, Tarija and Beni.
The four components of the contribution, as developed and implemented by IDEA International, in the 5 mentioned Bolivian regions, were: i) the strengthening of some municipal/regional management issues, ii) the consolidation of a deeper gender equality participation, iii) the promotion of a more&#xA0;active and deep political participation of the youth, and iv) the improvement of the quality of electoral services delivered by the Bolivian Electoral Body.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="47058" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International IDEA/International Institute for Democracy and Electoral Assistance</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47058" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International IDEA/International Institute for Democracy and Electoral Assistance</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bolivia (Plurinational State of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">460278.0079167817</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">651487.0191211441</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">460278.0079167817</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">651487.0191211441</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-15">2301390.039583</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">460278.0079167817</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-28">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-28">651487.0191211441</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main results achieved in each one of the four components under the present contribution can be summarized as&#xA0; follows:
First component: public finance management at regional levels.&#xA0;Depending on the regional context of the five chosen regions, different degrees of results were achieved:&#xA0;
- In La Paz, Santa Cruz and Cochabamba regional development agendas based on metropolitan areas were initiated in the three main cities of the country.
- in all cases, important technical assistance was provided to different regions. For example, i) how to improve and manage public investment resources (Santa Cruz), ii)how to strengthen regional planning including electronic government at local level and institutional strengthening to protect national parks (Beni), iii) the formulation of a new development plan for the Tarija region and iv) the formulation of an environmental agenda for Cochabamba.&#xA0;&#xA0;
While, the technical assistance provided was well received by local governments even during the 2020 transition government, it should be said that after the 2021 sub-national elections, it is quite likely that many of these initiatives may be delayed in its implementation -if not&#xA0;discontinued at all-&#xA0;by the new elected regional authorities. It is a shame that the contribution ended precisely when such change of authorities was in place.&#xA0;
Second component: Improving gender equality participation.&#xA0;The so called proposal &quot;parity is now&quot;&#xA0;was&#xA0;launched by IDEA to promote women&apos;s political participation at all levels, in order to comply and preserve the characteristics of political parity and&#xA0;alternation&#xA0;among elected women and men, while also&#xA0;preventing political violence against women. Under this component, several women&apos;s organizations from the nine Bolivian regions were involved and received technical assistance in order to learn and to&#xA0;exert an&#xA0;effective&#xA0;exercise of their political rights.&#xA0;
As a sound result of this component, within the electoral lists of&#xA0;candidates to the 2019 and 2020&#xA0;national elections, all political parties running in those elections complied with what it is prescribed in the electoral law in terms of parity. After the 2020 national elections, there are 20 female members in the senate (55,5% of the total) and 61 female members in the lower chamber (46,9% of the total).&#xA0;&#xA0;
As to the female presence leading the recently elected municipal governments, it is important to mention that two capital cities will be led by female leaders during the 5 coming years: the cities of Cobija (Pando) and El Alto in La Paz.&#xA0;
As to regional assemblies, the women&apos;s participation after the march 2021 sub-national elections has determined that&#xA0;48 percent of women (out of 247 positions), were elected as &quot;asambleistas&quot; in the nine regional governments of the country. In previous years female participation was very reduced at this level. However, the country does not have any female governor yet but it has a female sub-governor in Pando.
Third component: Deeper political participation of the youth. Under this component, youngsters from the five chosen regions were given enough space to deliberate, interact and propose a called agenda of public policies (Agenda from the Youth) to be prioritized by regional governments. Also a&#xA0;virtual platform from and for the Youth has been designed and launched to strengthen their political participation and social control, especially after the irruption of the pandemic in&#xA0;the country. Also the active technical assistance provided by IDEA determined that during the two national elections 200 young participants under this initiative,&#xA0;representing to the most representative political parties,&#xA0;decided to run as candidates for different positions. As a result, 27 of them were elected and they are now members of the Bolivian Parliament for the 2021-2025 legislation. &#xA0;
Fourth component: Contributing to improve the institutional capacity of the National Electoral Body. In the beginning&#xA0;of the contribution in 2018, it was agreed that the achievement of an electoral ISO&#xA0;(International Organization for Standarization) provided by the Organization of American States (OAS), as the only institution authorized to certify electoral processes around the world, was to be executed in Bolivia. Sweden, Spain and the European Union agreed to finance such certification.&#xA0;Unfortunately, the process to deliver the final results&#xA0;by OAS took more time than originally planned and it would have been used as a political tool, especially to&#xA0;benefit the Government,&#xA0;in the 2019 national elections that took place in October 2019. In the end, the final ISO&#xA0;certification was suspended. Some weeks later, such decision was&#xA0;proven to be an adequate one&#xA0;in view of the fraudulent results provided by the Bolivian Electoral Body which were confirmed after a quick electoral audit conducted by the&#xA0;same&#xA0;OAS&#xA0;itself.&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;
In the end, while the official ISO&#xA0;was not given to the Bolivian Electoral Body, technical assistance was provided to&#xA0;the sampled regional electoral offices for this purpose but, in the end, the official certification from OAS was not delivered.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12851" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1050303" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="990000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Bolivia 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Bolivia 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
