<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11197A0101-BOL-43030</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Urban  Policy Bolivia 2017-2023</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Nationell stadspolitik Bolivia 2017-2023</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Bolivias regering har bett om st&#xF6;d fr&#xE5;n UN Habitat i att genomf&#xF6;ra den nya Regionala Handlingsplanen f&#xF6;r implementering av den Nya Urbana Agendan (the New Urban Agenda). Som svar p&#xE5; detta har UN Habitat utarbetat ett projektf&#xF6;rslag omfattande s&#xE5;v&#xE4;l tekniskt st&#xF6;d till regeringen g&#xE4;llande den Nya Urbana Agendan och utveckling av en Nationell Urban Policy som implementering av lokala urbana projekt samt samordning med andra FN-organisationer i Bolivia med urban verksamhet.

F&#xF6;ljande resultat ska uppn&#xE5;s:
- En Nationell Urban Policy i linje med den Nya Urbana Agendan finns framtagen.
- Bolivias regering har kapacitet att implementera integrerade urbana projekt som bidrar till &#xF6;kat v&#xE4;lbefinnande och minskad fattigdom, d&#xE4;r faktorer s&#xE5;som bost&#xE4;der, transporter och integrerade f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttringar i bostadsomr&#xE5;den inkluderas.
- Minst tre lokala integrerade processer baserade p&#xE5; den Nya Urbana Agendan som bidrar till att st&#xE4;rka kvinnors och ungdomars st&#xE4;llning samt skapar arbetstillf&#xE4;llen &#xE4;r p&#xE5; plats.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the contribution is to advise and accompany the Government of Bolivia in the formulation and implementation of a National Urban Policy based on the Bolivian context and the Swedish priorities established in its strategy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of this program is to advise and support the Government of Bolivia in the formulation and the start up of a National Policy for the Integrated Development of Cities (NPIDC), within the framework of an urban agenda that contributes to the sustainable development of human settlements in Bolivia, incorporating the methodologies and expertise developed by UN-HABITAT and the UN System, aiming at contributing to the achievement of the great purposes of Living Well of the Patriotic Agenda of the Government of Bolivia, including the fight against poverty.
Three main expected results have been established:
ER1 &#x2013; The Government of Bolivia has a National Urban Policy that supports the integrated development of cities, aligned to the Patriotic Agenda and the New Urban Agenda criteria and based on four pillars: financial management; planning and urban design system; appropriate legal framework and institutional governance; and capacity building and training for the implementation of the urban policy.
ER2 &#x2013; The Government of Bolivia has the mechanisms, tools and the operational capacity for the implementation of the National Policy for the Integrated Development of Cities&#xA0;including an instrument for its monitoring and evaluation.
RE3 &#x2013; The Government of Bolivia has strengthened its capacity to develop urban mechanisms, tools and actions for the formulation and implementation of social components of the National Policy for the Integrated Development of Cities, linking the multidimensional approach to poverty reduction and human rights</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41120" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat/United Nations Human Settlements Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41120" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat/United Nations Human Settlements Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bolivia (Plurinational State of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="11.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.3 - By 2030, enhance inclusive and sustainable urbanization and capacity for participatory, integrated and sustainable human settlement planning and management in all countries.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.3 - Till 2030 verka f&#xF6;r en inkluderande och h&#xE5;llbar urbanisering samt f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra kapaciteten f&#xF6;r deltagandebaserad, integrerad och h&#xE5;llbar planering och f&#xF6;rvaltning av bos&#xE4;ttningar i alla l&#xE4;nder.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.7 - By 2030, provide universal access to safe, inclusive and accessible, green and public spaces, in particular for women and children, older persons and persons with disabilities.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.7 - Senast 2030 tillhandah&#xE5;lla universell tillg&#xE5;ng till s&#xE4;kra, inkluderande och tillg&#xE4;ngliga gr&#xF6;nomr&#xE5;den och offentliga platser, i synnerhet f&#xF6;r kvinnor och barn, &#xE4;ldre personer och personer med funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.a - Fr&#xE4;mja positiva ekonomiska, sociala och milj&#xF6;m&#xE4;ssiga kopplingar mellan stadsomr&#xE5;den, stadsn&#xE4;ra omr&#xE5;den och landsbygdsomr&#xE5;den genom att st&#xE4;rka den nationella och regionala utvecklingsplaneringen.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.a - Support positive economic, social and environmental links between urban, peri-urban and rural areas by strengthening national and regional development planning.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.b - By 2020, substantially increase the number of cities and human settlements adopting and implementing integrated policies and plans towards inclusion, resource efficiency, mitigation and adaptation to climate change, resilience to disasters, and develop and implement, in line with the Sendai Framework for Disaster Risk Reduction 2015&#x2013;2030, holistic disaster risk management at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.b - Till 2020 v&#xE4;sentligen &#xF6;ka det antal st&#xE4;der och samh&#xE4;llen som antar och genomf&#xF6;r integrerade strategier och planer f&#xF6;r inkludering, resurseffektivitet, begr&#xE4;nsning av och anpassning till klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringarna och motst&#xE5;ndskraft mot katastrofer samt utveckla och genomf&#xF6;ra, i linje med Sendai-ramverket f&#xF6;r katastrofriskreducering 2015&#x2013;2030, en samlad katastrofriskhantering p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1170001.17000117</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2589063.794531897</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">2379466.7879313445</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">868649.358828192</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1170001.1700011697</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2589063.794531897</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">2379466.7879313445</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">868649.358828192</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-01">7371007.371007</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">1170001.17000117</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-28">2589063.794531897</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-28">2379466.7879313445</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">434324.679414096</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-28">434324.679414096</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bolivia/2019-04-05-amendment-signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreeement amendment</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bolivia/signed-un-habitat_nup.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bolivia/11197_11197_DecisiononAmendmentofContribution_UNHabitat.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Amendment UN Habitat</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bolivia/11197_decision-on-contribution_un-habitat.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bolivia/decision-on-amendment_2nd-amendment-un-habitat_signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Decision on amendment (2nd major amendment)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During 2019 (before the 2019 National elections crisis) and in order to try to adjust the programme to fit the perspectives of the national counterpart, namely the Vice-Ministry for Housing and Urban Planning, as well as the UN system, a change in the Programme implementation was needed to ensure it was&#xA0;adapted to the new circumstances.
&#xA0;
Although no financial changes were foreseen; and the expected results, objectives and the logical framework remained the same, the following adjustments had to be done:
- Establish a more efficient and timely administrative mechanism within the UN System that will allow to speed up the process of the development and implementation of the policy. It was agreed that the whole focus area 3 and some activities from focus area 1 and 2 would be&#xA0;executed through UNDP
- Strengthen the ownership of the Viceministry of Housing and Urban Development, adding an institutional strengthening component that will allow to generate stronger institutional capacities within the organization (especially for the design and implementation of the urban policy). The Viceministry wanted to be a central actor in the construction of the Urban Policy, so it was agreed that UN Habitat will hire a team under the supervision of the Vice-Minister. In turn, the Vice-Ministry had agreed to keep the new team with government funds after the end of the programme.
- To strengthen the Viceministry human capacities to develop integrated urban interventions. This activity was central considering that the national government at that time had leveraged 200 million dollars for urban infrastructure projects. As the government had allocated a substantial amount of funds to develop integrated urban interventions, it was agreed that no pilot interventions will take place. The Vice-ministry requested to eliminate those provisions in the Programme budget but to extend the duration and enlarge the technical team in charge of supporting the development of the projects to be funded by the national budget.
&#xA0;
&#xA0;
Based on these changes, the main results per results are as follows:
&#xA0;
Expected Result 1: National Urban Policy that supports the integrated development of cities
&#xA0;
From a general perspective, the process of building the Urban National Policy has progressed significantly and, after a participatory multilevel process that culminated with the Second National Urban Forum (held in August), a draft proposal is already available and during this period and while the transitory government remains in office will be socialized in order to generate a final version that can be approved once the new government is elected and in office.
&#xA0;
Output 1.1. The different coordination and participation bodies and means for the formulation, monitoring and evaluation of the NPIDC are stablished and functioning.
&#xA0;
The activities under this output have been severely affected by the events following the 2019 National elections and the subsequent change of government, as well as, more recently, by the emergence of the coronavirus in the country and the measures taken to prevent its spread.
&#xA0;
The important progress made during the first semester of 2019 in terms of the generation of partnerships around the formulation of the Urban Policy (at the national and local level) has been slowed and even&#xA0;stagared by the failure of the election process. A process of reconstructing the relationship, as of&#xA0;December, has been necessary, often with new partners (specially at the government level).
&#xA0;
Activity. 1.1.1. Establishment of governance mechanisms for the development and implementation of the PNDIC.
&#xA0;
As we mentioned above, actions related to this activity have been strongly affected by the change in the direction of the Programme in mid-2019 and the events that occurred after the October elections.
&#xA0;
Between the months of June and November, the renewal of the Program team, and the difficulties in making effective the recruitment of staff to promote institutional relations, prevented this work from being carried out with all the necessary attention. Even so, substantial progress was made in the involvement and engagement of different sectors, particularly in the construction of National Urban Policy and the New Urban Agenda in Bolivia. Municipalities from all over the country and with different political ideologies have been part of the process (but it still needs to be reinforced in the future).
&#xA0;
At a national level, in the first half of 2019, the Viceministry of Urban Development and Housing &#x201C;VMVU&#x201D; re-assumed the leadership of the Cabinet of Deputy Ministers for Urban Affairs. Two meetings were held, on 20th March and 11th June, with a strong representation of several viceministries and the Director of the National State Autonomy Service. The main agreement was to work more in a cross-sectorial way under the urban umbrella scope. However, the Political Committee for the development of the National Urban Policy remains a task to be completed once the policy is formally approved it with a new government.
&#xA0;
On the other hand, the expert advisory group (conformed in 2018) has been very active, participating in two main activities: the review of the diagnostic document and the review of the preliminary proposal of the Urban Policy.
&#xA0;
Activity 1.1.2. Development of a comprehensive and representative participatory process, throughout the different stages of development of the Urban Policy
&#xA0;
The participation process for the development of the Urban Policy progressed significantly during 2019 both in its diagnostic phase and in the formulation phase until the conclusion of the Second National Urban Forum on 25 and 26 September 2019, mainly at the national level.
&#xA0;
Many workshops around the country were held to disseminate the results of the diagnostics and the strategic guidelines of the urban policy (the detail of the workshops have been explained with more detail in the annual report).
&#xA0;
However, strong work at a local level and with civil society must be reinforced in the future.&#xA0;Due to the October events it will be needed to start over (strengthening the communication activities) in this process to really get the ownership of the different actors at the local and national level around the urban policy and its process of elaboration.
&#xA0;
Activity 1.1.3. Realization of two National Urban Forums as culminating events of the diagnostic and formulation stages of the Urban Policy
&#xA0;
Following the celebration of the first National Urban Forum on October 30th and 31st , 2018 in La Paz (as an initial event to start up the process of elaboration of the first National urban policy), on 25th and 26th September 2019 its second edition was held in Cochabamba with the main objective of agreeing on the guidelines of its formulation. The event attracted around 200 participants from all areas related to the urban, who discussed the Policy&apos;s proposals on eight strategic areas: 1) Inclusion in public spaces and citizen security; 2) Opportunities, productivity and employment; 3) Resilience, climate change and risk management; 4) Housing; Environmental management, health and sustainability; 5) Territorial urban planning and access to land; 7) Services and urban mobility; 8) Governance.
&#xA0;
&#xA0;
Activity 1.1.4. Organization and deployment of a communication campaign of the Urban Policy development process
&#xA0;
The communication campaign was designed under the&#xA0;tag line&#xA0;&#x201C;urbano, sue&#xF1;a tu ciudad&#x201D;, with the aim to communicate the urban policy process to the general public.
&#xA0;
The strategy used different social networks to disseminate the urban policy contents and its proposals using an accessible language. Among of some of their publication it can be mentioned:
- Urban themes related to the policy guidelines and their articulation with global agendas,
- Socialization and participation activities for the formulation of the Urban Policy,
- Good practices of Bolivian urban actors
- References to opinion columns of specialists linked to urban problems.
&#xA0;
&#xA0;
Output 1.2. Diagnostic of the urbanization process in the country
&#xA0;
The diagnostic was completed and submitted to the Viceministry of Urban Development and Housing on July together with a series of complementary studies.
&#xA0;
Activity 1.2.1. Development of an induction process between central, regional and local government institutions, civil society, private sector, academia
&#xA0;
The activities of the induction phase have been carried out during the 2018 period. However, and due to the government changes, it has been necessary to resume the work that has been done to the new authorities at the Central State Level and in some municipalities following the events of October and November.
&#xA0;
Activity 1.2.2. Development of a diagnostic of the urbanization process in the country and its challenges and opportunities
&#xA0;
The diagnostic document was developed in collaboration with the Viceministry until its delivery the 23th July 2019. The delivered version was completed from a first preview version presented internally at the end of February 2019, and subsequently publicly distributed. It incorporates the comments and recommendations received after the various events held within the framework of the participatory process described under activity 1.1.2. It is important to mention that the first version received some critics, especially from the civil society organizations. During the final version a close work with them has been carried out (such as Sociedad de Ingenieros, Colegio de Arquitectos, Comit&#xE9; Popular Habitat among some).
&#xA0;
Activity 1.2.3. Conducting studies on specific aspects of the diagnostic
&#xA0;
In order to deepen the analysis on some specific aspect of the diagnostic, some additional studies have been carried out to reinforce its results. Among the most important we can mention: 1) Analysis of the Urban Legislation Assessment Framework; 2) Analysis of municipal finances, 3) Sustainable urban mobility study; 4) Report of food safety guidelines for the Urban Policy; 5) Urban Productivity Study
&#xA0;
Output 1.3. National Policy for the Integrated Development of Cities
&#xA0;
The formulation of the Urban Policy has continued its development despite the changes within the Viceministry and UN-Habitat technical teams and the events of October and November. During the first nine months of 2019, UN-Habitat along with the Viceministry technical team have been working elaborating the draft guidelines of the National Policy. They have been presented the initial results (initial guidelines) in the 2nd National Urban Forum holding in September. During 2020, a socialization process specially at the local level is expected.
&#xA0;
Expert Result 2: Development of the national operational capacity for the implementation of the NPIDC and the means for its monitoring and evaluation
&#xA0;
Output 2.1. The capacities of urban stakeholders and citizen awareness for the implementation of the Urban Policy are reinforced
&#xA0;
Although the program has developed specific capacity-building activities, as well as the improvement of citizen culture, particularly through its communication networks; little progress has been achieved in the development of the capacity-building programme. The awareness-raising strategy for the improvement of a citizen culture has not yet been implemented, the challenges remain for the next period.
&#xA0;
Activity 2.1.1. Design of a capacity building program
&#xA0;
As we mention above, many specific capacity building activities have been developed during the 2019 period. Experts have come to give lectures on urban issues and some staff members from the Viceministry and municipalities have participated in training courses (details of those activities are specified in the annual report).
&#xA0;
However, one of the main observations is that these activities have not been designed or developed under a capacity building program. UN-Habitat is aware about this situation and, this target will be addressed in the next period as a key and strategic area.
&#xA0;
&#xA0;
Activity 2.1.2. Design of a communication campaign and implementation of awareness-raising actions for the improvement of a civic and inclusive citizen culture committed to urban action.
&#xA0;
An initial discussion during the last quarter of 2019 has been initiated with the Municipality of La Paz (specifically with the Secretary of Education and Culture) for the systematization and replica of its &quot;Citizen Culture&quot; and &quot;Culture of Peace&quot; programme. A letter of intent has been sent to formalize collaboration. This still in process.
&#xA0;
As in previous periods, messages of awareness of topics related to citizen culture have continued to spread continuously through the &quot;Urbano, Sue&#xF1;a tu ciudad&quot; platform. It has also been agreed that this area should be reinforced during the next period.
&#xA0;
Output 2.2. The technical, legal, financial and methodological mechanisms and tools for the initial implementation of the NPIDC are developed.
&#xA0;
The development of some of the mechanisms and instruments already identified in the project document has been delayed by the events that occurred after the October elections, and particularly by the change of government, due to its reliance on agreements with different public institutions.
&#xA0;
Activity 2.2.1. Development of legislative, technical, financial and/or methodological instruments for the implementation of the PNDIC.
&#xA0;
Many of the planned instruments had a delay due to events mentioned above. In particular, one key product was the support envisaged by the Vice-Ministry of Planning and Coordination for the definition of urban guidelines in the municipal territorial plans. This work could not be incorporated into the next versions of the Territorial Plans for Integral Development (PTDI) and in new approach of the Economic and Social Development Plan (PDES). It is expected to re-establish the contact with the new authorities and technical team of the Ministry of Planning next period to be included.
&#xA0;
The same has happened with the planned collaboration with the Vice-Ministry of Autonomy to develop a legal instrument to promote the formation and development of metropolitan areas in the country. However, it has been possible to launch the procurement for the study for the development of the Policy&apos;s financing strategy.
&#xA0;
On the other hand, progress has been made with the preparation of the proposal for the formulation of specific legislation on urban planning and land use in articulation to the proposed guidelines of the National Urban Policy. This work will continue during 2020.
&#xA0;
Activity 2.2.2. Development of the Action Plan for the implementation of the Urban Policy
&#xA0;
This activity will be done once the Urban Policy will be formally approved.
&#xA0;
Activity 2.2.3. Preparation of the monitoring plan and evaluation of the implementation of the Urban Policy.
&#xA0;
A proposal is already under the table. The proposal for the Urban Policy indicator system has already been developed remaining pending the socialization and validation processes. The verification of indicators, and their sources of information, is being carried out with the institutions responsible for each of the related sectors in order to ensure their alignment and availability of sources of information.
&#xA0;
Activity 2.2.4. Elaboration of the Prosperous Cities Index (ICP) for measuring the impact of the Urban Policy and the development of cities.
&#xA0;
The calculation of the Prosperous Cities Index for 26 cities in Bolivia, covering 83% of the country&apos;s urban population, has been completed. A preliminary analysis document of its results has been made and is under review. An agreement has already been reached in this regard with the relevant institutions on statistical and geographical information under the head of the Vice-Ministry of Planning and Coordination during 2019. For the next period, it will be important to re-initiate the dialogue to reach an official agreement with the new authorities on their validation as a measuring instrument of the Urban Policy implementation.
&#xA0;
Output 2.3. Design, structuring and development of urban projects for the implementation of the Urban Policy.
&#xA0;
Activity 2.3.1. Set up of the Urban Technical Unit within the Viceministry of Urban Development and Housing
&#xA0;
The Programme has supported the set-up of the Urban Technical Unit between December 2018 and March 2020. The main objective was to support final design projects for urban intervention programmes funded by other ministries at the Central Level, particularly the Ministry of Development Planning.
&#xA0;
Activity 2.3.2. Technical support and implementation of integrated urban interventions.
&#xA0;
The Urban Technical Unit has supported the development of the following projects: i) Renovation of &quot;La Coronilla&quot; park in the city of Cochabamba (project funded by the Urban Interventions programme for Social Innovation of the Ministry of Development Planning) ii) Rehabilitation of the former Central Station of Cochabamba; iii) Recovery and rehabilitation of the municipal protected area and urban ecological preservation park &quot;Curichi la Madre&quot; in Santa Cruz de la Sierra. iv) Final Design of El Alto Fairgrounds.
&#xA0;
In addition, the technical unit has developed 11 projects in La Paz, Viacha, Cochabamba, Sacaba and Quillacollo under &quot;Mi Barrio Mi Hogar&quot; program funded by the Productive and Social Investment Fund (FPS), of which 8 were approved for its implementation.
&#xA0;
Activity 2.3.3. Articulation of the different projects/programmes/initiatives in the urban area at different levels with the Urban Policy formulation process
&#xA0;
Synergies have been generated with the main urban intervention initiatives in the country in order to strengthen its alignment with the Urban Policy process.
&#xA0;
As we mention above, the Urban Technical Unit has generated a good articulation with the main urban intervention programs promoted from the Central Level of the State (mainly those of Urban Interventions of Social Innovation and Mi Barrio-Mi Hogar programmes&quot; driven by the Ministry of Development Planning).
&#xA0;
Also, a close dialogue has been made with the World Bank&apos;s Resilient Cities Programme (recently approved). In addition to the finally agreed interventions for La Paz and Santa Cruz (which are aligned with the urban policy proposals), the WB has agreed to channel the support received from Swiss cooperation, through SECO, to support the resilience component of the Policy.
&#xA0;
A good collaboration with Helvetas has also been generated in the development of its resilient city project in the city of Sucre, which has allowed the alignment of his actions with the Urban policy guidelines.
&#xA0;
Activity 2.3.4. Development of strategic urban intervention guidelines for the 3 main metropolitan areas based on the results of the ICP analysis and the study of the city system.
Activity planned for 2020
&#xA0;
Activity 2.3.5. Design and structuring of 3 of the large-scale integral urban operations identified in 2.3.4.
&#xA0;
Activity planned for 2020
&#xA0;
&#xA0;
Expected Result 3: Articulation of the UN support to the National Policy for the Integrated Development of Cities formulation and early implementation processes
&#xA0;
Coordination with the UN system and among the UN agencies has not been an easy target to achieve. However, and after a long process of discussion, agreements have been reached. UNS&apos; contribution actions to the construction of the PNDIC initiated at the end of 2018 with the signing of a first cooperation agreement, which has been extended with the signing of a second agreement on July 2019. These agreements have allowed the implementation of a series of complementary activities to support not only the policy formulation process but projects prioritizes by the Viceministry within the urban program.
&#xA0;
Output 3.1. Developed interagency actions to support the formulation of the New Urban Policy through the UNDAF 2018-2022 Results Groups
&#xA0;
The support of the UN agencies has been materialized in the following actions:
&#xA0;
1. Inclusion of a children, adolescents and youth scope in the process of design and formulation of the Urban Policy in order to ensure the observance, enforcement, exercise and fulfilment of their rights. This action is carried out by the Interagency Group for Adolescents and Youth (GIAJ), led by UNFPA and formed by UNDP, FAO, UNODC, UNICEF and UNV.
2. Contribution to the development of the Urban Policy from a gender and human rights approach. This action is led by UN-Women and supported by the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights (OHCHR)
3. Analysis of multidimensional well-being in cities involving the contribution on urban poverty to the diagnostic document, the measurement of urban multidimensional poverty and its incorporation into the UNDP-associated indicator system. This action is under UNDP leadership.
&#xA0;
A specific diagnostic on the status of the situation of children, adolescents and young people (NNAJ) in cities to be incorporated into the urban diagnostic for the formulation of the Policy has also been carried out. 13 workshops have been developed with adolescents and young people in 10 cities (with a participation of 360 young people), as well as consultation workshops with Departmental Committees of Children and Adolescents in the main three cities. These workshops have made it possible to identify future needs and proposals for Children and young people to be incorporated into the Urban Policy.
&#xA0;
A virtual platform has been developed (www.ciudadesjovenes.org.bo) to publicize key information around the policy, develop some virtual courses and to collect proposals and recommendations from young people. More than 600 people have been involved, around 200 of whom completed the course and developed proposals. Finally, on September 12th, the National Urban Forum of Children, Adolescents and Youth was organized in the city of La Paz with the central objective of generating a specific proposal regarding the Urban Policy.
&#xA0;
On the other hand, a close collaboration has been established with UN-Women who has deployed an expert consultant to work on a daily basis with the team in charge of the formulation of the Policy.
&#xA0;
Output 3.2 Designed and implemented social projects on the integrated urban interventions
&#xA0;
To accompany the urban project of &#x201C;La Coronilla&#x2019;s Renovation&quot; in the city of Cochabamba (oriented to support an adequate attention to the drug dependent population currently occupied by that space), the project &quot;Re-appropriation of public space by youth in the municipality&quot; has been developed under the leadership of UNODC. However, the follow up has been conditioned by the change of the government and the delay in the execution of the planned works. It is expected that this work will be reinitiated during the second semester of 2020.
&#xA0;
&#xA0;
Output 3.3. Designed and implemented an interagency agenda to support the State in the implementation of the NUP and the New Urban Agenda in Bolivia
In order to support the Resident Coordinator Office with the facilitation and collaboration of the UN Agencies in the development of the Urban Policy and, more particularly, with an interagency agenda in the topic, an International Volunteer has been recruited to begin to carry out functions to promote such coordination. In the same way, the procurement for an International Urban Advisor has been planned for the next period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11197" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1050303" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="990000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Bolivia 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Bolivia 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
