<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10187A0101-BOL-14030</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Bolivia Sanitation Models</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bolivia Sustainable Sanitation Models</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Long term effect: Increased climate resilience among the population in Bolivia through access to sustainable sanitation that improve living conditions in poor and marginalized peri-urban areas.  Short term effect: Increased access to sustainable sanitation solutions among the target population.  Immediate effects: (i) Scalable sustainable sanitation models developed and adopted to the various climate and sociocultural conditions in Bolivia (The models should be scalabe, i.e. with the potential to be implemened on wider nation wide scale in the country); (ii) Apropriate technical solutions that contribute to mitigate the effects of climate change are adopted in participating municipalities; (iii) The national policies and norms for sanitation are applied in participating municipalities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen syftar till att utveckla modeller f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbara och klimatanpassade sanitetsl&#xF6;sningar i fattiga f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;der i utvalda kommuner i Bolivia: Dels l&#xF6;sningar med ekologiska torrtoaletter och &#xE5;tervinning av restprodukter som g&#xF6;dningsmedel i jordbruket, dels alternativa system f&#xF6;r avloppsvattenrening med &#xE5;tervinning av renat avloppsvatten f&#xF6;r bevattnings&#xE4;ndam&#xE5;l. I Bolivia saknar fortfarande 50 % av befolkningen eller 5 miljoner m&#xE4;nniskor tillg&#xE5;ng till toaletter.

Insatsen &#xE4;r baserad p&#xE5; tidigare v&#xE4;l genomf&#xF6;rda pilotprojekt i landet, s&#xE5;som en tidigare finansiering av programmet &quot;Knowledge Node for Sustainable Sanitation (id: 55180013) som koordinerades av den holl&#xE4;ndska enskilda organisationen SNV och d&#xE4;r bland annat de bolivianska enskilda organisationerna AguaTuya och SumajHuasi med framg&#xE5;ng genomf&#xF6;rde pilotprojekt i att utveckla kretsloppssystem baserade p&#xE5; ekologiska torrtoaletter samt alternativa l&#xF6;sningar f&#xF6;r avloppsvattenrening. 

Ambassadens avtalspartner &#xE4;r Diakonia, som i sin tur kommer att samarbeta med AguaTuya och Sumaj Huasi i allians med utvalda kommuner i landet som representerar de olika klimat- och sociokulturella f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningarna i Bolivias tre viktigaste ekoregioner: det Andinska h&#xF6;glandet, de subhumida Andinska dalg&#xE5;ngarna och det tropiska l&#xE5;glandet i Amazonasregionen.  

&#xC4;ven om syftet med programmet i f&#xF6;rsta hand &#xE4;r att fokusera p&#xE5; utveckling av h&#xE5;llbara och klimatanpassade sanitetsl&#xF6;sningar, kommer &#xE4;ven 25 000 personer att f&#xE5; tillg&#xE5;ng till sanitet genom programmet. F&#xF6;rhoppningen &#xE4;r att de av programmet utvecklade sanitetsmodellerna sedan ska kunna skalas upp p&#xE5; nationell niv&#xE5; och bidra till Bolivias regerings utvecklingsplan att ge hela befolkningen tillg&#xE5;ng till toaletter senast &#xE5;r 2025. Insatsen f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntas bidra till att uppn&#xE5; SDG 6.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme will develop models for sustainable sanitation in selected municipalities in Bolivia: (i) Systems with ecological dry toilets and closing of the nutrient cycle through re-use of waste as fertilizers in agriculture; (ii) Alternative systems for waste water treatment with the potential for re-use of treated waste water for irrigation. The Programme is based on previous successfully implemented pilot projects in the country. Cooperation partners are the Swedish NGO Diakonia and two Bolivian NGOs: the AguaTuya and Sumaj Huasi foundations. In total 25 000 people will gain access to sanitation through the Programme. The models developed are expected to have the potential to be implemented nationwide at a later stage and contribute to the Bolivian governments plan to provide universal access to sanitation by 2025. In Bolivia today, 50% of the population or 5 million people lack access to safe sanitation. The Programme is expected to contribute to the SDG 6.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bolivia (Plurinational State of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic drinking water supply and basic sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">818091.5093788349</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">818091.5093788349</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-01">818091.509378</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">818091.5093788349</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-28">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Embassy of Sweden in Bolivia and Diakonia accorded by agreement to implement the Sustainable Sanitation Models programme initially for the period from 1st October 2016 to 30 June 2019 with an initial budget of SEK 48 million and together with the participation of the foundations AguaTuya and Sumaj Huasi as implementing organisations in the programme.
During the programme&#x2019;s first months, certain problems were identified in the budget, mainly concerning overhead costs of Diakonia. Their budgeting was prepared considering only resources directly managed by Diakonia and not including the risk that third-party transfers imply.
This situation was solved with an important commitment of the Embassy to conduct an internal control and management assessment of AguaTuya and Sumaj Huasi during the first year of the implementation of the programme. The main objective was to determine if both local organisations had adequate fund management capacities (especially since both Bolivian organisations managed around 40 million SEK of the agreed budget).
In September 2017,&#xA0;the internal control and management assessment&#xA0;for Sumaj Huasi determined that they&#xA0;presented institutional and administrative weaknesses. Immediate actions needed to be taken to mitigate future risks.
In broad consensus with all the involved stakeholders it was decided to refocus the programme by reducing the scale of implementation and change the programme period to 1 October 2016 to 31 December 2018, including a responsible phase out period from 1 January to 30 September 2018. The purpose of the phase out period was&#xA0;to assure the provision of decentralised sanitation services to vulnerable peri-urban populations (mainly in some districts in&#xA0;El Alto), which was one of the main commitments of Sumaj Huasi. The financial contribution of the Swedish Embassy due to this adjustment was reduced to SEK 19,777,751.
As part of their programme commitment, AguaTuya concluded on 31 December 2017 the pre-investment stage for the construction of Wastewater Treatment Plants and Fecal Sludge Treatment Plants in the country. Since January 2018 and based on the satisfactory results of their capacity analysis, AguaTuya is implementing another programme under a new agreement with the Swedish Embassy that makes the construction stage of those treatment plants viable.
Diakonia reimbursed SEK 8,848,829 to Sida in Sweden and remained responsible for a budget of SEK 10,928,922 for the period October 2016 to 30 September 2018, including the responsible phase out stage. At the end of the whole intervention an additional amount of SEK 225,738 was reimbursed to the&#xA0;embassy according to the planned phase out budget.&#xA0;
Based on these changes, the programme has achieved some results but the overall objectives have not been reached. Work in many areas will still be needed in the future. Below is a presentation of some of the partially achieved results (per intermediate and immediate effects):
- &#x201C;Intermediate effect: The coverage of sustainable sanitation services among the target population has increased&#x201D;: inhabitants in El Alto (3,250), Sucre (300), Montero (300), Cliza (10,000) and Tolata (5,000) have benefited from the coverage of non-traditional or decentralised sanitation services implemented in peri-urban contexts with service models that allow for the treatment of liquid and solid waste with three main purposes: (i) reuse of water for irrigation of perennial species; (ii) production of liquid bio-fertilizers and (iii) production of solid bio-fertilizers.&#x2019;
- &#x201C;Immediate effect: Replicable models of sustainable sanitation in different ecological levels have been implemented&#x201D;:
* Eco-Sanitation Model: Initially implemented in El Alto city (altiplano), replications were achieved in the cities of Sucre (valley) and Montero (flatlands) benefiting 50 families in each site. However, sustainability of this eco sanitation model in El Alto and Montero has not been reached. Currently, and through a new WASH programme with UNICEF, the Embassy will work in this area to achieve the sustainability of the model with local stakeholders (the municipalities of El Alto and Montero and the WASH utilities EPSAS and COSMOL).
* Wastewater Treatment (PTAR) Model: Initially implemented in the municipalities of Cliza and Tolata (valley&#x2019;s) with a tertiary level of treatment, an effort to replicate the treatment model design was programmed for the city of Tarija in close coordination with the Tarija municipality.
* Fecal Sludge Treatment Model for nutrient recovery: a feasibility study has been executed for the implementation of what would be the first sludge treatment plant in the country, located in the municipality of Cliza. It is expected that this plant would process 1,560 m3 of fecal sludge per year in 300 m2 with SaniC technology which bases its treatment on sludge aeration and addition of urea.
The construction of both plants will be done with the new decentralised sanitation models programme carried out by AguaTuya.
- Products: Financial sustainability via social marketing: In order to establish potential markets for the products that result from the sanitation processes, Diakonia&#xB4;s Economic and Social Justice Platform conducted trials regarding the use and applicability of liquid and solid bio-fertilisers that derives from ECOSAN and Water Treatment Plants models in the valley and lowland areas, as well as commercial studies regarding possible markets in which these sanitation derivatives could be marketed. Some of the main studies are: Validation of a systems protocol considering four sorts of fruit for production in Agroforestry Systems in the municipalities of Ascensi&#xF3;n de Guarayos and San Ignacio de Velasco (lowland). A current demand for liquid bio-fertilizer at national level has been identified through a market study.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10187" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1050303" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="990000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Bolivia 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Bolivia 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
