<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-14216A0102-BOL-15151</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Culture of Peace and  Strengthening of the Plurinational Electoral Body</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Fredskultur och st&#xE4;rkt kapacitet hos den Plurinationella valorganisationen</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Bidraget syftar till att st&#xE4;rka en mycket komplex politisk och social milj&#xF6;, valmyndigheten i Bolivia, genom att ge institutionell f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rkning till h&#xF6;gsta valdomstolen (Tribunal Supremo electoral &quot;TSE&quot;) och decentraliserade Valdomstolar - Departmental Electoral Courts (Tribunal Electoral Departemental &quot; TED &quot;) i olika aspekter av valprocessen f&#xF6;re valet 2020.
Fyra f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade resultat har definierats:

- Resultat 1: Att &#xF6;ka effektiviteten, kapaciteten och insynen i valstyrning och administration genom r&#xE5;dgivning.

- Resultat 2: Utarbeta och implementera en kommunikationsstrategi f&#xF6;r att n&#xE5; ut, skapa medvetenhet och fr&#xE4;mja insyn i hela valprocessen och minska potentiellt v&#xE5;ld i valet.

- Resultat 3: S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ut&#xF6;vandet av kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter i valprocessen.

- Resultat 4: &#xC5;terst&#xE4;lla valutrustning och material f&#xF6;r TED som har f&#xF6;rst&#xF6;rs under konflikten i oktober-november 2019 f&#xF6;r att kunna genomf&#xF6;ra valet 2020.

I slutet av interventionen &#xE4;r det f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade resultatet att st&#xE4;rka trov&#xE4;rdigheten av 2020-valprocess samt att st&#xE4;rka valorganets institutionella kapacitet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The contribution aims to strengthen within a  very complex political and social environment, the Plurinational Electoral Body in Bolivia as a whole by providing institutional strengthening to the Supreme Electoral Court (Tribunal Supremo Electoral &quot;TSE&quot;) and the Departmental Electoral Courts (Tribunal Electoral Departamental &quot;TED&quot;)  on different aspects of the electoral process before elections in 2020.


Four expected outcomes have been defined:

- Outcome 1: To increase efficiency, capacity and transparency of electoral management and administration, through technical assistance and advice.

- Outcome 2: Design and implementation of a communication strategy to outreach, create awareness and promote transparency of the whole election process and mitiage potential electoral violence

- Outcome 3: To ensure in an effectively and efficiently  way the exercise of women&apos;s rights in the electoral process.

- Outcome 4: Acquisition of election equipment and materials for the TEDs that have been burnt down during the conflict in October-November 2019.


At the end of the intervention, the expected result is to strengthen the credibility, plurality and inclusion of the 2020 electoral process as well as to strengthen the institutionality of the Electoral Body.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objectives of the intervention have been complemented, adding a bigger scope that includes the subnational electoral process, including new components such as the support of Canada to the effective exercise of women&apos;s rights in the electoral process and the post electoral institutional strengthening process support by Sweden, this latter with supplementary funds.
&#xA0;
The aim of the contribution continues to be the strengthening of the Plurinational Electoral Body in Bolivia as a whole by providing institutional strengthening to the Supreme Electoral Court (Tribunal Supremo Electoral &quot;TSE&quot;) and the Departmental Electoral Courts (Tribunal Electoral Departamental &quot;TED&quot;). However, as we mentioned, the scope of the work has increased, going beyond the 2020 national electoral process to include the 2021 subnational election process and a post electoral 2021-2022 support process.
&#xA0;
Regarding the national and subnational elections, a specific component to support the effective exercise of women&apos;s rights in the electoral process has been included. This component will be exclusively financed by Canada.
&#xA0;
At the end of the two electoral processes it is expected:
- Output 1: Greater efficiency, capacity and transparency in electoral management and administration of the Supreme Electoral Court and the Departmental Electoral Courts.
- Output 2: Create awareness and reinforce transparency to increase the credibility of the electoral process and mitigate the potential for electoral violence.
- Output 3: Effective exercise of women&apos;s rights in the electoral process.
- Output 4: Acquisition of new electoral equipment and materials for the national and subnational election processes.
&#xA0;
It is important to mention that the contribution of Sweden with the current amendment will have a direct impact in output 1, output 2 and output 4 (in the original agreement Sida&#xB4;s funds were only allocated to output 1 and 2. See the budget section for more detail).
&#xA0;
The 2021-2022 post electoral process will be included as a fifth component with the aim:
- to strengthen OEP technical and institutional capacities, giving priority to the development of management and leadership capacities of the TEDs in electoral processes of intercultural and parity democracy&#xA0;
- to promote deliberation and democratic coexistence, strengthening citizen participation.
&#xA0;
At the end of the post electoral support it is expected:
- Result 1: To institutionalize an ongoing training mechanism for officials and technicians in the OEP
- Result 2:&#xA0;To develop institutional capacities of TEDs in areas of planning, management, normative production and communication
- Result 3: To promote deliberation and democratic coexistence and strengthen citizen participation in the construction of public policies
&#xA0;
Among the specific outputs for the post electoral intervention we can mention:
For Result 1:
- 30 TSE and TED officials trained with the BRIDGE methodology
- 100% of OEP officials have taken electoral management modules
- &#xA0;50 authorities (Vocals) participate in two coaching processes and two exchanges of international experiences
- &#xA0;A document of electoral jurisprudence of indigenous peoples (community democracy election formats) and 3 studies on political organizations
&#xA0;
For Result 2:
- 9 institutional development plans of the TEDs designed and implemented
- 9 protocols for supervision and follow up of the community election processes adapted to the particularities of each TED&#xB4;s - 9 communication strategies designed and implemented by TEDs
- 54 courses / seminars developed by TEDs together with universities (5 per department)
&#xA0;
For Result 3:
- A dialogue facilitation guideline developed
- 30 TSE and TED officials handle political dialogue methodologies
- 90 territorial dialogues of the TEDs (10 per department) developed and systematized&#xA0;
- A culture and art contest on the rights and political participation of youth and indigenous peoples developed</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bolivia (Plurinational State of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15151" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elections</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">524665.0887849922</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">466368.967808882</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">524665.0887849922</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">466368.967808882</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">922939.943754</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-28">524665.0887849922</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bolivia/agreement_oep.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement UNDP_Elector Body Support</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bolivia/decision-on-contribution_oep.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">With respect to objective 1 (The OEP has achieved a strengthened institutional framework and strategic and operational capacities), the following results have been achieved:

1. 60 TSE officials and the nine TEDs participated in 5 training workshops on the BRIDGE methodology. Each of the five-day workshop had twelve participants from all the TEDs and from almost all the areas/units of the TSE.

The 2021 goal was of 30 TSE officials trained.

 2. An international exchange on electoral experiences with other countries in the region has been promoted. Four officials (1 from TSE and the other 3 from different TEDs) monitored the Legislative Elections of Argentina and other 2 officials (1 TSE and one another from TDE) learned from the General (presidential) Elections held in Honduras.

The 2021 goal was to have 3 international exchange experiences.


As to objective 2 (The parity intercultural democracy is institutionalized in the political system and assumed as a form of democratic coexistence in Bolivian society), the 2021 results were:

1. Nine dialogue processes were held with elected women (titular and alternate) of the Departmental Legislative Assemblies, on women&apos;s political rights and prevention of harassment and political violence, in order to move towards an effective political participation with a gender approach. Officials from the TSE and TEDs participated in all the events. 

2. To promote/incentive political participation of young people, the first &quot;Olympics of Democratic Knowledge 2021&quot; were organized to promote civic and democratic culture among secondary school students from all over the country. 

3. Support actions were implemented to carry out the election of new  authorities in the autonomous indigenous governments of Charagua (Santa Cruz) and Uru Chipaya (Oruro). Also, support was provided for the election of the first authorities in the indigenous government of the Jatun Ayllu Yura (Potos&#xED;).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="14216" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1050304" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="930000000" strategy-end-date="2025-12-31" strategy-start-date="2021-01-01">
    <sida:title>Bolivia 2021-2025</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Bolivia 2021-2025</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
