<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>ZW-ROD-MA988-87-US-EIN-132890727-001</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="ZW-ROD-MA988-87" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&apos;s Action Group</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dissemination of Results on Abortion Incidence Study</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Influential people: Policy makers (Parliamentarians), Government ministries, women&apos;s coalition, Health workers, NGOs, Activists, community leadership and media</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Zimbabwe-University of California San Francisco Collaborative Research Program (UZ-UCSF; now called the University of Zimbabwe College of Health Sciences Clinical Trials Unit or UZCHS-CTU) partnered with the Guttmacher Institute to carry out an abortion incidence and morbidity study in Zimbabwe. The research was aimed at filling a major gap in the evidence base by producing and widely disseminating the first-ever national estimates of unsafe abortion, and abortion-related complications in Zimbabwe. Women&#x2019;s Action Group (WAG) has now partnered Guttmacher Institute in the dissemination of the study results. There are a number of activities that have to be implemented under this initiative. The first activity is a Women&#x2019;s Health Conference which is aimed at; raising awareness on maternal mortality and morbidity in Zimbabwe and its causes, initiating dialogue on maternal health issues including unsafe abortion. WAG will also facilitate a high level dissemination workshop for the study results which will be attended by obstetricians and gynaecologists, members of parliament, government ministries, civil society, media and academia. WAG will ensure publicity of research findings through media, this will include a press conference and other forms of print media. Results of the study will also be disseminated at community level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022;	To disseminate findings of the Zimbabwe Abortion Incidence and Morbidity Study
&#x2022;	To develop strategies for addressing unsafe abortions and abortion complications in Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guttmacher Institute US-EIN-132890727</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&apos;s Action Group</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ruwa, Goromnzi, Mashonaland East, Zimbabwe</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-17.895114303749143 31.272583007812496</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ruwa, Goromnzi, Mashonaland East, Zimbabwe</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-17.916022703877665 31.272583007812496</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="15164" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-10-02"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-04-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-30">8947.9</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="IT172832W0100247">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-12">8947.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">First disbursement for Women&apos;s Health Indaba</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&apos;s Action Group</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
