<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Donne e persone con disabilit&#xE0; in azione per un sistema  agropastorale ecosostenibile</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Il progetto si pone come finalit&#xE0; il rafforzamento della sicurezza alimentare e nutrizionale della regione di 
Zinder, in Niger: in linea con gli Obiettivi di Sviluppo Sostenibile nr. 2 e 6 (Target nr. 2.1, 2.3, 2.4 e nr. 6.1), si 
intende promuovere l&#x2019;accesso inclusivo a cibo, acqua potabile e sistemi di produzione agroalimentare
resilienti e sostenibili nei dipartimenti di Magaria, Kantch&#xE9; e Mirriah.
La proposta progettuale si rivolge in modo particolare alle categorie pi&#xF9; vulnerabili della popolazione, quali 
persone con disabilit&#xE0; e donne. L&#x2019;azione nasce grazie alla pluriennale presenza dei partner internazionali CBM 
Italia, CISP e ACRA nel territorio di Zinder (dove nell&#x2019;agosto 2020 si &#xE8; concluso il progetto AID 10963, finanziato 
da AICS), e si arricchisce della partnership di organizzazioni locali con esperienza ventennale nei settori della 
sicurezza alimentare, dell&#x2019;agricoltura, dell&#x2019;acqua potabile e dell&#x2019;inclusione delle persone con disabilit&#xE0;, quali 
KARKARA, DEMI-E e la Federazione Nigerina delle Persone con Disabilit&#xE0; &#x2013; FNPH (ente che raccoglie 25 
associazioni di persone con disabilit&#xE0; in Niger). 
L&#x2019;impianto progettuale &#xE8; disegnato in maniera da essere pienamente rispondente ai bisogni evidenziati nei 
Piani di Sviluppo Locale (Plan de D&#xE9;veloppement Communal) emanati dalle autorit&#xE0; municipali dei comuni 
rurali di Hamdara, Kwaya e Ichrinawa, ed &#xE8; in linea con le priorit&#xE0; del &#x201C;Plan de D&#xE9;veloppement Economique et 
Social 2017-2021 (PDES)&#x201D; del Governo del Niger.
Il Niger occupa l&#x2019;ultimo posto al mondo nell&#x2019;indice di Sviluppo Umano stilato da UNDP nel 2020, ed &#xE8; 
caratterizzato dagli indicatori socio-economici pi&#xF9; bassi al mondo, con il 90,5% della popolazione che vive una 
condizione di Povert&#xE0; Multidimensionale. Le ricerche di assessment dei bisogni e gli studi di fattibilit&#xE0; di 
progetto, condotti direttamente sul campo dai partner da luglio 2020 a marzo 2021, hanno evidenziato i 
seguenti gap e bisogni principali nei 3 comuni target: a) la produzione agricola locale non &#xE8; sufficiente a coprire 
neanche la met&#xE0; del fabbisogno alimentare delle famiglie e gran parte della popolazione &#xE8; persistentemente 
esposta a ricorrenti rischi di malnutrizione; b) l&#x2019;accesso a fonti di acqua sicura, sia per il consumo umano che 
per l&#x2019;impiego nei sistemi di produzione agricoli e pastorali, non &#xE8; attualmente garantito a gran parte della 
popolazione; c) esiste un circolo vizioso tra disabilit&#xE0; e povert&#xE0;: le persone con disabilit&#xE0; (5,3% - tra le 
percentuali pi&#xF9; alte del Paese) soffrono ulteriormente di discriminazione ed esclusione sociale
(particolarmente grave nei casi di donne con disabilit&#xE0;).
Nei 3 anni di implementazione previsti dalla proposta progettuale, il Soggetto Proponente CBM Italia ed i 
partner intendono rafforzare la resilienza delle comunit&#xE0; locali, focalizzandosi sulle persone con disabilit&#xE0;, 
sull&#x2019;empowerment femminile e sui gruppi pi&#xF9; vulnerabili della popolazione. Il lavoro sinergico con i Servizi 
Tecnici comunali e con le strutture tecniche dello Stato e degli enti territoriali costituir&#xE0; una dinamica strategica 
appropriata per garantire la sostenibilit&#xE0;, l&#x2019;ownership comunitaria e l&#x2019;endorsement locale dell&#x2019;iniziativa. I 
partner intendono lavorare su 3 pilastri strategici, raggiungendo un totale di 7.780 persone:
- Il potenziamento del settore agricolo locale, attraverso: la realizzazione di orti familiari per 
l&#x2019;incremento di produzione di cibo, dotati di sistemi efficienti di irrigazione; l&#x2019;avviamento di pratiche aggiornate di certificazione delle sementi; il supporto di attivit&#xE0; generatrici di reddito che vertono 
sulla conservazione e il processamento del cibo; il miglioramento di tecniche e pratiche delle piccole 
produttrici agricole del territorio.
 
- L&#x2019;aumento della produttivit&#xE0; dell&#x2019;allevamento locale, con focus sulle filiere del latte e della carne, 
tramite: il rafforzamento delle tecniche di gestione degli animali delle allevatrici locali; la dotazione di 
capi di bestiame di razza migliorata</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to strengthen food and nutrition security of Zinder region in Niger: in line with the Sustainable 
Development Goals no. 2 and no. 6 (Targets 2.1, 2.3, 2.4 and 6.1), it will promote inclusive access to food and 
water in the departments of Magaria, Kantch&#xE9; and Mirriah, together with the promotion of resilient and 
sustainable agricultural and food production systems in the area.
The project proposal aims to target the most vulnerable population groups, such as people with disabilities 
and women. The action has been formulated thanks to the long-standing presence of the international partners 
CBM Italia, CISP and ACRA in the territory of Zinder (where the AID 10963 project, funded by AICS, was 
concluded in August 2020), and it is enriched by the partnership of local organizations with 20 years&#x2019; experience 
in the sectors of food security, agriculture, water and the inclusion of people with disabilities, such as KARKARA, 
DEMI-E and the Niger Federation of People with Disabilities - FNPH (the umbrella federation of 25 associations 
of people with disabilities in Niger). 
The project is designed to be fully in response to the needs enumerated in the Local Development Plans (Plan 
de D&#xE9;veloppement Communal) issued by the municipal authorities of the rural municipalities of Hamdara, 
Kwaya and Ichrinawa, and it is in line with the thematic priorities set in the &quot;Plan de D&#xE9;veloppement Economique 
et Social 2017-2021 (PDES)&quot; issued by the Government of Niger.
According to UNDP, Niger occupies the last position of the Human Development Index 2020, and it is 
characterized by the lowest socio-economic indicators in the world, with 90.5% of the population living in a 
situation of Multidimensional Poverty. The needs assessment research and project feasibility studies conducted 
directly in the field by the partners, in the period July 2020 - March 2021, highlighted the following main gaps 
and needs in the 3 target municipalities: (a) local agricultural production is not sufficient to cover even half of 
household food needs and a large part of the population is persistently exposed to recurrent risks of 
malnutrition; (b) access to safe water sources, both for human consumption and for use in agricultural and 
pastoral production systems, is currently not guaranteed to a large part of the population; (c) there is a vicious 
circle between disability and poverty: people with disabilities (5.3% - among the highest percentages in the 
country) further suffer from discrimination and social exclusion (particularly aggravated by gender 
discriminations, in cases of women with disabilities). In the 3 years of implementation of the project, the Proponent CBM Italy and the partners intend to strengthen 
the resilience of local communities, focusing on people with disabilities, on women&#x2019;s empowerment and on 
the most vulnerable groups of the population. The synergic work with the Municipal Technical Services and 
with the technical structures of the State and territorial authorities will constitute an appropriate strategic 
dynamic to guarantee the sustainability, community ownership and local endorsement of the initiative. 
The partners intend to work on 3 strategic pillars: 
- The enhancement of the local agricultural sector, through the establishment of family gardens for 
increased food production, equipped with efficient irrigation systems; the initiation of up-to-date seed 
certification practices; the support of income generating activitiesthat focus on food conservation and 
processing; improvement of techniques and practices of smallholder farmers in the area.
 
- Increasing the productivity of local livestock production, with a focus on the milk and meat sectors, 
through: strengthening the animal management techniques of local breeders; providing improved 
breed of cattle and specific equipment; enhancing the production capacities of milk derivatives, fodder 
and feed</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CBM ITALIA ONLUS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/01/7" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="14031" percentage="40" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic drinking water supply</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31161" percentage="38" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food crop production</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31163" percentage="22" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Livestock</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="6.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, achieve universal and equitable access to safe and affordable drinking water for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, double the agricultural productivity and incomes of small-scale food producers, in particular women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers, including through secure and equal access to land, other productive resources and inputs, knowledge, financial services, markets and opportunities for value addition and non-farm employment</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end hunger and ensure access by all people, in particular the poor and people in vulnerable situations, including infants, to safe, nutritious and sufficient food all year round</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure sustainable food production systems and implement resilient agricultural practices that increase productivity and production, that help maintain ecosystems, that strengthen capacity for adaptation to climate change, extreme weather, drought, flooding and other disasters and that progressively improve land and soil quality</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-08">2689708.27</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CBM ITALIA ONLUS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-17">1613824.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CBM ITALIA ONLUS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
