<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/13899" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-MZ-14-13899</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique Niassa SLH &amp; VIDA Community Health Program 2015</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Volunteer,Community Health Worker,Individuals,Family members,People with Disabilities,Pregnant women,Men,People living with HIV/AIDS (PLWHA),Staff,Children &amp;lt; 5,Youth 13-24 yrs</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Cobue archdeaconry, there are two projects, Sal Luz Saude-SLS (Salt Light Health) and Equipas de Vida (Life Teams), which as a result of Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development&#x2019;s encouragement and 2013 project support have been working together more and more closely over the last two years. As a result, there currently exists a large network of volunteers (including SLS community health volunteers and Equipas de Vida HIV education volunteers) that are providing health and community development education as well as a wide range of preventive health services, in collaboration with the District Health Department. The overarching goal of the SLS project is to promote and facilitate sustainable community-led improvements in public health. In 2015, both the SLS and Vida projects will continue to work together to contribute to this long-term goal by jointly mobilizing and building capacity of local communities to address their own health and development needs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Visit Community Health Committees to strengthen local management and oversight of community health activities.,Coordinate quarterly advocacy meetings between Community Health Committees and district Government health officials. ,Facilitate exchange experiences between communities (committees),Conduct KAP survey data collection on HIV, maternal-child health and malaria.,Encourage work of 400 Community Health Advisors to conduct education and consultative home visits.,Support work of 30 First-Aid/Health Post Workers (APEs) via training and equipment for government authorized administration of first-line anti-malarias, antibiotics and other forms of consultation/care.,Encourage community-wide health education sessions (palestras).,Provide monthly consultations, medication disbursement, and family education sessions for an estimated 146 individuals with Epilepsy. ,Train and equip 69 Traditional Birth Attendants along with 48 Activist Fathers.,Equip, train and monitor laboratory testing services for individuals, including HIV testing.,Train and monitor record system for accurate guarding of test results.,Equip 40 Chronic Disease Activists for their promotion of treatment protocols for patients and PLWHAs.,Support and strengthen the SLS Technical Health Team and the Equipas de Vida in their leadership and management of project administration, planning, training, monitoring, and results-oriented evaluations and reporting activities. ,Train 576 Nutrition Animators to promote healthy eating, improved agriculture techniques and improved cook-stove construction.,Facilitate Equipas de Vida (Life Teams) in their community education activities. ,2) SLS&#x2019;s end-of-year team visit to all 13 project areas and Community Health Committees to hold listening dialogues with the population that captured both the impacts of 2014 project activities and ideas for 2015 planning. ,1) Annual collection of KAP (knowledge, attitudes and practices) data on HIV, Malaria and Maternal-Child Health.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Niassa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="B60E174A-DECD-4C77-896F-E9F20A2E486A" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-MZ-14-13899" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-10-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_1030006">
   <location-id code="1030006" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niassa</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niassa, Mozambique (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="1030006" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-13.0 36.7</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="8" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-10-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-05-01"></period-end>
     <target value="18141"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
