<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/19030" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-MZ-15-19030</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique Community Health Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Cobue archdeaconry, there are two projects, Sal Luz Saude-SLS (Salt Light Health) and Equipas de Vida (Life Teams), which as a result of Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development&#x2019;s encouragement and 2013 project support have been working together more and more closely over the last two years. As a result, there currently exists a large network of volunteers (including SLS community health volunteers and Equipas de Vida HIV education volunteers) that are providing health and community development education as well as a wide range of preventive health services, in collaboration with the District Health Department. The overarching goal of the SLS project is to promote and facilitate sustainable community-led improvements in public health. In 2015, both the SLS and Vida projects continued to work together to contribute to this long-term goal by jointly mobilizing and building capacity of local communities to address their own health and development needs. In 2016, the program intends to put in place an exit strategy for some of the old project sites and expand to new areas. In exiting communities, the program will support this process through occasional meetings with health committees and key volunteers, and through the creation of community-based savings and loans groups for community volunteers in these communities. This will serve to encourage the volunteers to continue their work in the communities and also create an opportunity for ongoing formal interaction amongst them. In new communities, the program will facilitate community creation of communities and volunteer nomination and train and equip these committees and volunteers to provide services and advocacy for the improvement of the overall/total community health</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individuals, Staff</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Train and mentor 1,431 volunteers (principally counselors) through at least 1120 days of facilitation or mentoring by project staff, Develop a new set of 20 teaching modules on key health themes, and their corresponding pamphlets., Implement annual Knowledge, Attitude and Practice (KAP) survey in all new project communities, Train 16 new Traditional Birth Attendants and support them, Sensitize community members on key health topics, Training and mentoring of 5 health committees and 6 co-management committees; Visitation of them to strengthen local management and oversight of community health activities, Ensure representation/participate in all government health meetings, Build capacity on basic health principles of at least 36 diocesan leaders (staff, clergy and key activists) who are not an active part of this project&#x2019;s implementation in Lake District, Community network building, particularly in Tete, Nampula, and Zambezia, with at least 16 communities organized and ready to mobilize action around community health in the future (using funding from other funding sources), Mentor 30 apprentices and &#x201C;dinamizadores&#x201D; / &#x201C;promoters,&#x201D; preparing them to be field facilitators in new areas in future years, Support and strengthen the SLS Technical Health Team in their leadership and management of project administration, planning, training, monitoring, and results-oriented evaluations and reporting activities. At least 15 days of support to health team by diocesan technical team; at least 40 days of support by senior members of health team to junior members of health team., Encourage and support 10 health committees, Provide HIV laboratory and treatment services to 650 patients living with HIV, Facilitate occasional coordination and evaluation meetings with existing community health workers (volunteers) in the &#x201C;original area,&#x201D; (total of 200 days) and provide limited targeted training based on identified gaps (estimated 40 days),Implement annual Knowledge, Attitude and Practice (KAP) survey in all original project communities, Provide epilepsy treatment to 175 patients, and education to them and their families, Provide transport to more equipped health facilities, in exceptional cases, to 48 patients, Maintain system for accurate records of HIV lab and clinical results for all HIV patients in the original project area, Occasional support to 64 previously trained Traditional Birth Attendants (TBAs),Be present during the 22 days of meetings of the Coordinating Committee (the committee made up of representatives of all health committees), and provide technical support if or when solicited, Train and support 45 saving and loan groups, comprised primarily of health volunteers, with a total of 945 members, of whom at least 630 are women</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Niassa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="16D75C71-B6C1-40BE-889A-F39A0137A828" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-MZ-15-19030" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_1030006">
   <location-id code="1030006" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niassa</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niassa, Mozambique (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="1030006" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-13.0 36.7</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="64640"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
