<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/13919" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-SV-14-13919</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction through Community Capacity Building and Community Infrastructure</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concurrent with the Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development strategic planning process, the Asociacion Mangle underwent a similar strategic planning process culminating in a new organizational strategic plan starting in 2010 until 2015. Therefore, integrating aspects of Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development&apos;s new strategy combined with Mangle&apos;s new strategy resulted in the development of a new project focused primarily on disaster risk reduction in 86 communities in southeastern El Salvador. The project will respond to the lack of disaster preparedness and risk management at the community level, address the high social and environmental vulnerability of the communities&apos; inhabitants--especially to flooding, and address a lack of adequate community infrastructure in the area of WASH and lack of resilience of communities. As a result, in partnership with Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development, the project intends to: * build the capacity of 86 communities in the Bajo Lempa region to mitigate risks of natural disasters by training and facilitating the formation of local community civil protection commissions. * capacitate and equip community civil protection commissions with rescue equipment and supplies. * capacitate and equip an early alert system that will benefit at least 86 communities. * facilitate a participatory, community-based infrastructure plan focused on shelter and sanitation to benefit at least 23 communities. * utilizing asset-based methodologies, analyze and research appropriate technologies to facilitate community construction using as much local materials as possible to facilitate pilot construction of water system that will benefit up to 63 communities. 2015 will see the completion of an 18 month exit strategy to turn over operations to the local committees.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Develop a process of management of the water resource to ensure its conservation and protection in quality and quantity for human consumption through the 3 local water committtees,Facilitate a 2-year strategic planning process for Central Civil Protection Commission, that provides oversight to 65 communities, to improve institutional capacity and sustainable coordination at the local, municipal, departmental and national levels,Strengthen the Civil Protection Committees in the 8 areas of the Baja Lempa district, in order to prepare, mitigate and respond to disasters effectively,Create and broadcast media materials, particularly on Mangle&apos;s radio frequency, for the dissemination of advocacy messaging related to emergency preparedness and water quality, as well as early warning communications,Mobilize communities, through the disaster committees, in the risk reduction activities including the construction of hillside ditches, mamanagement of waste and garbag, and maintenance of plant nurseries to strengthen soil and protect the coastline,Train staff to plan, implement and monitor the final year plan of the exit strategy of the disaster risk reduction programme</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individuals</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anglican Episcopal Diocese of El Salvador</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asociacion Mangle</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="220119EA-6A70-4F1D-8DEB-A183F0B8487C" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-SV-14-13919" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SV" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_3582882">
   <location-id code="3582882" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Usulutan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Usulutan, El Salvador (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="3582882" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.43333 -88.53333</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Prevention and Preparedness</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation and Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-05-01"></period-end>
     <target value="49124"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
