<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/19015" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-BI-15-19015</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burundi Sexual &amp; Gender-Based Violence Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clergy/Lay Leaders, Youth 13-24 yrs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establish safe center for psychological, health and legal counsel or referral to survivors of SGBV in Bujumbura, Initiate referral network between key insitutions (ie. churches, local administration, police, health centers, NGOs, associations, etc.) in 3 new dioceses, Organize 3-day refresher course for 63 faith leaders trained on SGBV in 3 existing dioceses (from 2015), Monitor counseling and other support provided at parish and diocesan level in 3 original dioceses, Train 45 Clergy, 3 diocesan staff members and 15 M.U representatives on trauma counseling for SGBV survivors, Train 45 Clergy, 3 diocesan staff members and 15 M.U representatives on including SGBV prevention in marital / couple counseling, Train 45 clergy, 15 M.U representatives and 3 diocesan staff members on Gender Roles and Gender Inequalities and the promotion of balanced power between men and women, Train 45 clergy, 15 M.U representatives and 3 diocesan staff members on challenging SGBV through Biblical messages and relevant sermons, Hold forums with key actors in SGBV prevention and response on creating, improving or enforcing SGBV laws and policies in 3 dioceses and at national level, Integrate SGBV and new masculinities curricula into 12 school health clubs in 3 dioceses, Mobilize community participation for annual 16 Days of Activism campaign through faith leaders and school health clubs reaching approximately 3000 people in 6 dioceses, Broadcast messages on SGBV prevention and response in 6 dioceses</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Burundi, political and ethnic conflict has not resulted in civil war or government upheaval the past few years; yet is has contributed to ineffective or non-existent government policies, economic stagnation and poor social development indicators. This instability and poverty increases women and girls&apos; risk to violence, in all of its forms. The social and cultural norms underlying the attitudes and behaviors that lead to gender inequalities and violence are quite entrenched. A culture of impunity and lack of government social services mean that most survivors of violence suffer in silence with little or no recourse to justice or support. The Anglican Church of Burundi is expanding its faith community-driven SGBV prevention and response project into 3 new dioceses in 2016 - Gitega, Muyinga and Buye, and monitoring and providing technical support to the original pilot dioceses of Makamba, Rumonge and Bururi. The project&apos;s objectives are threefold: (1) Increase active leadership, knowledge and support skills related to SGBV prevention and response for 126 faith leaders in 3 existing and 3 new dioceses by the end of 2016; (2) Organize and strengthen SGBV referral service network in 3 existing and 4 new dioceses; and (3) Increase SGBV advocacy and awareness efforts of faith leaders and 24 youth school health clubs in 3 existing dioceses, 3 new dioceses and at the national level by the end of 2016. The project envisions diocesan development staff, pastors, Mother&apos;s Union representatives and youth group leaders as agents of change and key community mobilizers and as such they will participate in intensive and participatory workshops and discussions that will help prepare them to speak out against violence; promote positive masculinities and gender equality; and advocate for and support survivors of violence. The Anglican Church of Burundi&apos;s strong presence in national-level advocacy forums on SGBV, HIV/AIDS and other social and health development issues, provides the foundation needed for the program to newly establish a women&apos;s safe center in Bujumbura. The center is in its planning stages and will be created by the end of 2016. It will provide psychological, health and legal counsel or referral to survivors of SGBV.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anglican Church of Burundi</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="ED2006BD-997B-44D9-8C4E-EFEAE7115AD4" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-BI-15-19015" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BI" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_426271">
   <location-id code="426271" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gitega</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gitega, Burundi (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="426271" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-3.5 29.95</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_430567">
   <location-id code="430567" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ngozi</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ngozi, Burundi (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="430567" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-2.875 29.925</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_431747">
   <location-id code="431747" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muyinga</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muyinga, Burundi (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="431747" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-2.83333 30.33333</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="26" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="11141"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
