<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/17867" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-MM-14-17867</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men&apos;s Association Demonstration Farm</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As Myanmar is an agricultural country where most residents depend on agriculture production as a livelihood, the Men&apos;s Association identified the need to introduce appropriate, cost effective methods to increase productivity in the agricultural sector. Introduced by a Japanese agronomist in the 1990s, Effective Microorganism (EM) technology is an environmentally friendly low-cost method of farming that allows for the production of crops without damage to the ecosystem, including effects on soil, water supplies, biodiversity or other surrounding natural resources. The technology uses low cost and locally appropriate inputs to produce a microorganism based process for the producing organic fertilizers. With findings of an agricultural survey, the Men&apos;s Association identified the need to provide the EM technology and innovative agricultural techniques to farmers who struggle to sustain their own farms due to increasing costs and unpredictable weather patterns. The Association established a 6-acre demonstration farm in 2008 on rented land from one of the Association&apos;s members. The demonstration farm uses soil from under the bamboo trees to produce EM by mixing it with molasses and rice husk. At each training, farmers will learn the improved techniques and apply them in the demonstration farm over a three-week training period in order to prepare them to use these technologies in their home farms. In 2015, the Men&apos;s Association will evaluate the previous 6 years of training to measure the impact of the application of the training. This evaluation would include an a review of the curriculum, participant selection process, post-training extension services and develop a consistent monitoring mechanism. The farm also intends develop a sustainability plan to support the continued service to small-holder farmers in Myanmar. The plan would include income generating agricultural ventures, sale of farm produce, animal husbandry and the renting of the facility and the As part of this strategy, the farm operational expenses will be fully sustainable by 2018. To assist the Men&apos;s Association enhance their monitoring and financial management capacity, the Episcopal Church in the Philippines will provide technically support as part of Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development&apos;s South-to-South learning exchange initiative. The south-to-south accompaniment process will included 3-4 visits to Myanmar per year, including the facilitation of exchange visits and shared learnings with the the Philippine&apos;s Tadian Demonstration FArm.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farmers</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monitor application of current training in all 6 dioceses and evaluate the impact of the training course on past participants, with a report due in December 2015,Develop and test a monitoring mechanism to determine farmer application of training in all 6 dioceses, with a report due in December 2015,Review and monitor progress of existing sustainability strategy in order to be 100% self-funded in 2018, with quarterly reports of progress on meeting the income diversification benchmarks in the sustainability plan. Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development will retire the partnership in 2018.,Participate in south-to-south learning exchange with the Episcopal Church in the Philippines to enhance monitoring and management capacity, including consultancy support from the Filipino church, and staff capacity building training at the Tadian Center in the Philippines</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mens&apos; Association, Church of the Province of Myanmar</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="89EC7844-DC68-4360-8AA1-463753D118B8" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-MM-14-17867" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-05-01"></period-end>
     <target value="7020"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
