<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/5499" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-SB-13-5499</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate Change Project &#x2013; Ontong Java</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farmers</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maintenance of plant nurseries, strengthening of 200 existing permaculture plots in Luaniua, distribution of seedlings for 4 new permaculture plots in Pelau, and installation of 25 rainwater harvesting tanks in Ontong Java to serve 1,604 individuals ,Provision of training on environmental awareness and agricultural techniques for 1,604 farmers in the islands of Pelau and Luaniua by June 2014,Completion of the technical atoll permaculture manual for replication of methodology by May 2014,Facilitation of the process of creating an ACOM Disaster Preparedness Plan by Dec 2014,Development of the ACOM Climate Change policy following a Consultation by June 2014,Facilitation of an external evaluation to measure the final outcomes of the agricultural stations in Luaniua. ACOM will also update the Results Table on a quarterly basis</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ontong Java, also known as Lord Howe Atoll, is a 50 km boot-shaped atoll made up of 122 islands lying just south of the equator and north of Santa Isabel. The impacts of climate change experienced to date on the low lying islands include damage to food crops, coastal erosion, contamination of water sources, and the reduction in the general health of the people, for example increased incidences of water-related illnesses. 

The overall aim of the project is to build an experimental agriculture station on Ontong Java to test salt-resistant crops and identify means of protecting crops from salinity from both rising water levels and increased sea-spray in inclement weather. 2014 activities will continue to build on the initial assessment to determine the sustainability of agriculture in Ontong Java completed in 2010 and the potential for integrating salt resistant crops. This process involved a study of the soil and vegetation types of the islands, paying particular attention to existing crop varieties. Any introduction of alternative crops would satisfy food production &amp;amp; availability needs. 

With the results of the assessment, staff designed an appropriate gardening system that should be systemically viable and culturally feasible Finally, staff negotiated with individual land owners for an initial four sites in 2011 where the experimental agriculture station were piloted to serve as a demonstration farm for local villages. 

In 2012, the pilots were expanded to a further 150 home gardens using the same technology. During 2013, staff continued to monitor closely the 200 sites to strengthen farmer use of the technology, and expand into the Pelau island community with an initial 4 sites using the same methodology. Provision of 20 rain water tanks is expected to be implemented in 2014 for mainly agricultural use. An outcome evaluation is also expected in June 2014 to determine best-practices for further replication. A training booklet will also be produced to provide details on the methodology use in this pilot project for expansion of the program to other areas with similar circumstances.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anglican Church of Melanesia (ACoM)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private donations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="245ECA63-A2E7-4974-8E87-A2BF4F937EB3" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-SB-13-5499" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org/where-we-work/country/solomon-islands</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environment</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="33.33333333333333" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation and Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.episcopalrelief.org/where-we-work/country/solomon-islands">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4561"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
