<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/5497" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-SB-13-5497</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Melanesia Mothers Union Literacy Programme 2014 Church of the Province of Melanesia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individuals,Family members,Community Volunteer</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Per program criteria, provide lump-sum support to 9 dioceses and 5 Religious Organizations for the running of at least 59 Literacy Schools, which includes the launching of at least 8 new schools.,Encourage good teaching practices contributing to an increase in reading, writing and arithmetic skills for at least 1,037 literacy learners, which includes at least 110 new learners, and an estimated total of 907 women and 130 men.,3.1 Encourage the inclusion of educational dialogues within existing literacy schools through the creation, reproduction and distribution of creative dialogue tools.,Equip at least 100 volunteer literacy teachers with skills and tools (TVET teaching and grading books) necessary to improve the quality of literacy education and learner achievement; this includes the identification of an estimated 15 new teachers, as well as training (or refresher training) for at least 72 teachers.,Conduct at least 1 site visit per literacy program (i.e., 9 Dioceses and 5 Religious Institutions) to encourage local coordinators and teachers, as well as collect/confirm program statistics.,Facilitate the growth of program management, reporting and leadership skills of 9 Diocesan Literacy Coordinators.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Mothers&#x2019; Union includes 16,000 members throughout eight dioceses of the Church of Melanesia. The Mothers&#x2019; Union initiated literacy programs in the province in 1989, and since has been one of the main providers of literacy training throughout the two countries. Literacy schools are supported and facilitated by Mothers&#x2019; Union members in each diocese. Schools take place within parishes, where there are 20 to 40 students in a class. Classes range from beginner to advanced in both Pidgin and English. All of the Mothers&#x2019; Union teachers, trained by program leadership and government services, lead these classes voluntarily. 

Since 2009, Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development has helped Mothers&#x2019; Union to support over 60 schools where over 1,500 individuals have learned to read and write. 

In 2014, the Mothers&#x2019; Union intends to strengthen its literacy program in each diocese by enhancing the teaching methods, and reproducing and distributing standardized class record books and learner testing tools. Additionally, working with the national literacy network and Ministry of Education, Mothers&#x2019; Union leadership intends to produce new teaching materials that will encourage learner-driven reflection and action on important community topics like preventive health, small enterprise management, and life skills. 

The specific 2014 program targets include: 9 Diocesan Literacy Coordinators, 59 Literacy Schools (including 8 new schools), 100 Literacy Teachers (including 15 new teachers), and 1,037 Literacy Students (including at least 110 new learners, and an estimated total of 907 women and 130 men), and an indirect beneficiary target of 4,048 family members of literacy learners.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anglican Church of Melanesia (ACoM)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private donations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="2195C6BF-4D6E-44C3-820B-3418C8C1F295" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-SB-13-5497" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org/where-we-work/country/solomon-islands</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="5" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.episcopalrelief.org/where-we-work/country/solomon-islands">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5185"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
