<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/13912" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-TZ-14-13912</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Central Tanganyika (DCT) - Development Services Company (DSC) Food Security &amp; VSLA Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individuals,Farmers</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mobilize and introduce community groups about village savings and loan benefits and methodology ,Organize and train village agents (i.e. trainers) on village savings and loan methodology ,Train VSLA management committee members (each committee with 5 members, each community) on VSL methodology,Train farmers on village savings and loan methodology through education and entrepreneurship skills,Educate farmers about challenges of the current farming system in terms of food security and environmental sustainability,Conduct public meetings to create awareness on climate change, trends and conservation agriculture as a potential mitigation strategy ,Identify and create workable by-laws and regulations to control free ranging livestock and fires with village governments,Mobilize and train farmers on conservation agriculture principles and benefits,Mobilize and train farmers on use of conservation agriculture technology (i.e. rippers),Purchase and distribute conservation agriculture equipment to farmer groups ,Train of farmers on cover crops and green manures as source of food, mulch, cash, soil moisture and fertility improvement,Purchase and distribute green manure and cover crop seeds to farmers ,Train farmers on on-farm seed selection, storage and use</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The majority of the people in Central Tanganyika are engaged in smallholder, subsistence agriculture. Many households also have some degree of livestock production. The transition from subsistence to market economy is very slow due to various factors, such as: natural and man-made disasters (i.e. drought); inadequate social and economic infrastructures; poor access to agricultural technology, inputs and equipment; and very low education base. The rapid degradation of the environment is due to poor soil management, uncontrolled livestock grazing, deforestation, overpopulation and water shortages. By promoting Conservation Agriculture and the formation of Village Savings &amp;amp; Loans Associations (VSLAs), the long term goal of DCT-DSC is to help the people living within the Diocese to achieve food security in an economically and environmentally sustainable manner. Objectives are generally related to achieving self sufficiency in food grain production through use of minimum tillage, improved seeds, retention of crop residue, crop rotation and proper storage techniques. Both men and women will directly or indirectly benefit from the project in 6-8 villages within 4 parishes. Indirect beneficiaries are expected to be more numerous as most of the technologies are transferable by just copying or purchasing the inputs required. Government agricultural extension agents play a key role in reinforcing CA skills and knowledge relayed through program supported field trainings. DCT-DSC has recently initiated VSLA interventions in several of the Diocese project sites. Discussions and initial results from the pilot VSLA&apos;s show that members, mostly women, desire funds for small business activities. Small commerce allows women to set aside much-needed money for children&apos;s school supplies and food.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Central Tanganyika</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="70BC916A-10D5-4330-8324-D0B7C155F023" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-TZ-14-13912" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_160192">
   <location-id code="160192" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dodoma</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dodoma, Tanzania (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="160192" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-5.91667 35.91667</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-05-01"></period-end>
     <target value="4680"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
