<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/5489" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-IN-13-5489</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yavatmal 2014 Comprehensive Food Security Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conduct exchange field trips to farms which have adopted low cost and organic farming methods for farmers to observe, learn, and be motivated how these methods are benefiting those who are already using them. ,Conduct training for farmers on techniques such as vermiculture manure, watershed management and organic farming methods.,Support for vermiculture pit construction and organic manure production for 20 selected beneficiaries from 3 villages.,Support for land management, including farm bunding at Belore Van on 17 acres of land, at Sudhakar Nagar on 20 acres of land and at Naik Nagar in 15 acres of land, land clearance and stone bunding at Belore Van on 8 acres of land, at Sudhakar Nagar on 10 acres of land and at Naik Nagar on 20 acres of land, construction of compartment bunds at Naiknagar on 10 acres of land, and construction of water outlets at Sudhakarnagar.,Support for purchase of indigenous seeds for 80 farmers and saving of seeds for next cultivation where possible, and for agricultural tools for 13 targeted farmers. ,Support for backyard goat rearing for 5 beneficiaries each from 3 villages, with each family giving one goat kid to another family the following year.,Support for business tools including purchase of sewing machines for 5 women, carpenter tools and shamiana decoration supplies for targeted families. ,Provide financial literacy, bookkeeping and account management training to participating community members. ,Support to kitchen gardens at Belore Van and Naik Nagar.,Provide training on local-level district management and government schemes for farmers and women&apos;s groups.,To provide support systems for families of suicide victims on immediate livelihood requirements and assist them in acquiring relief packages from the Government.,Hold planning meetings with mandal groups of 3 villages and network meeting with different stakeholders and NGOs. ,Support village and zonal level review and planning meetings, including hazard mapping and incorporate interventions for disaster risk reduction.,Provide support for crop insurance for 120 farmers from 3 villages.,Support health check up camps to look into the overall well being of families and identify those which should be referred for further medical attention.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farmers,Individuals</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the second year of this new program we will continue to address the challenges faced by farmers, and particularly women, the landless, sharecroppers and other vulnerable people in the Yavatmal area of Maraharastra, in India. Many of these farmers are faced with high debt burdens, due to the high rates charged by local lenders, and the need to use sufficient amounts of fertilizers and pesticides on the hybrid seeds they buy. The farmers are also primarily engaged in cash-crop farming, and are therefore susceptible to local and international market price swings. Many do not have diversified sources of income, or food grown for household consumption that they can fall back on. In addition, some of the practices promoted by the government in past years, such as the promotion of cash crops for export, subsidy support for industries other than agriculture, and the artificial support for wheat grown for export, are harming the environment through excessive use of irrigation and fertilizers, and efforts need to be taken to reverse this trend. 

The program will work to introduce low-cost sustainable agricultural practices, to build capacity of households in financing, production, and marketing of both agricultural and non-agricultural enterprise, and to increase financial literacy and savings. In addition, they will assist farmers in advocating the government for the services that they are entitled to, such as support for families who have experienced a death, and access to fairly priced inputs, credit and markets. CASA has a strong history of working on similar programming and hopes to bring their skills and experience to this region of India.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Church&apos;s Auxiliary for Social Action (CASA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private donations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="67DADD88-D8B0-4430-87A4-B4A79D8F5310" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-IN-13-5489" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org/where-we-work/country/india</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_1264418">
   <location-id code="1264418" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maharashtra</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maharashtra, India (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="1264418" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.5 76.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="33.33333333333333" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.episcopalrelief.org/where-we-work/country/india">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
