<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/17860" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-VU-15-17860</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addressing Climate Change in Vanuatu</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individuals</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of disaster risk reduction training for community members, Provision of disaster risk reduction training for clergy, Establish Disaster Risk Reduction Committees in 9 communities, including risk mapping and creating a work plan, Establish community committees to identify appropriate plots for home-gardening demonstration farms, Train farmers in enhanced farming techniques and improved varieties of seeds and crops, Facilitate mass coastal reforestation through the local disaster risk reduction committees, Networking with local government and civil society organizations, develop a coastal reforestation action plan for both communities</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vanautu&apos;s relatively small population of 257,000 is spread across 83 islands, with nearly all at great risk of the effects of climate change. These effects include the salinization of agricultural soil from sea sprays and tropical storms, the erosion of coastal belts due to rising sea levels, and frequent population displacement due to weather-related events such as cyclones and land slides. Much of the country is now affected by a severe El Nino-induced drought, which is having an adverse effect on community food security. Outside of the main cities, many people in rural areas still rely heavily on subsistence farming. ACOM-Vanuatu&#x2019;s Climate Change Program is a gesture of serious commitment to combatting the adverse impacts of climate change that is wide spread with varying degree of threats. The scope of the program is two fold, first is a Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR) strategy that aims to address visible coastal erosion in two specific areas, Port Patterson on Vanua-lava in the Diocese of Banks &amp;amp; Torres (DOBT) and Saratamata on Ambae, Diocese of Vanuatu and New Caledonia (DOVNC). These two locations have been earmarked as pilot locations due to the extreme rate at which physical processes are occurring. Coastal reforestation will be a key activity in cooperation with the government&#x2019;s Forestry Department and the Public Works Units in each province as key partners. Secondly, the program includes food security activities that aim to promote back yard gardening to the most vulnerable group in the societies, especially widows. To enhance food security, the program will focus on different varieties of root crops and vegetables that can be cultivated in the back yard farm, crop rotation to maintain soil fertility as well introduction of agro forestry or alley farming, improve nutrition and a minimal income source. To meet the  two key objectives by engaging communities on disaster risk reduction, the program will be using Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development&#x2019;s Pastors and Disasters Toolkit. The Toolkit allows for communities with the opportunity to learn new methods and techniques to build their own disaster resilience to protect their lives and properties. The hands on implementation approach will build community confidence and capacity in their own ability to address disaster risk</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anglican Church of Melanesia (ACoM)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="643935F6-B4D4-4B08-86AA-E4B80ACBC1FF" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-VU-15-17860" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-30" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VU" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_2134898">
   <location-id code="2134898" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sanma</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sanma, Vanuatu (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="2134898" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-15.33333 166.75</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="3" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Prevention and Preparedness</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="33.33333333333333" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environment</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-11-30"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="6582"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
