<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/19031" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-CD-15-19031</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provincial Development Office Programming Institutional Strengthening &quot;Ensemble Nous Pouvons&quot;</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1 Support Bukavu, Kinshasa, Kisangani, Kasai and Katanga ENP Teams with a lump-sum grant to purchase a motorcycle to be used for the promotion and follow up of ENP groups throughout the Diocese. 2.2 Support Kinshasa, Kisangani, Kasai and Katanga ENP Teams with a lump-sum grant to purchase computer equipment to be used for the monitoring and reporting of ENP groups throughout the Dioceses. 2.3 Upon ISTAS&#x2019;s reimbursement of borrowed ENP funds, support Kindu ENP Team with a lump-sum grant to purchase equipment to be used for the promotion, monitoring and reporting of ENP groups throughout the Diocese. 1.1 Support Aru &amp;amp; Nord Kivu ENP Teams with a lump-sum grant to initiate an income generating activity that will provide financial self-sufficiency for the continuation of their ENP program. 1.2 Upon ISTAS&#x2019;s reimbursement of borrowed ENP funds, support for the Anglican University of Congo (UAC) ENP Team with a lump-sum grant to initiate an income generating activity that will provide financial self-sufficiency for the continuation of their ENP program. 3.2 Support administrative training for 15 PEAC staff, conduced by Christophe Nzalamingi, ENP Auditor. Participants included: 3 ENP Facilitators, 3 Diocese of Boga staff, 3 Teachers, 1 representative of Agape, 1 representative from ISTAS, 1 representative from MU, and 2 representatives of finance at UAC. 3.1 Support ENP Provincial Team with stipends and admin costs (bank fees) during their collaboration with the project auditor during the 2013-2014 ENP project audit. 3.3 Support PEAC&#x2019;s representation at the 2015 CAPA-sponsored training of trainers (TOT) event in Nairobi, Kenya. PEAC represented by Provincial Coordinator Fidele Hamisi Mushamuka and N.Kivu ENP Facilitator Charlote Kavira.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Staff, Clergy/Lay Leaders, Individuals</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Together We Can - Ensemble Nous Pouvons (ENP) is a provincial program of the Anglican Church of Congo (PEAC) that employs an asset-based church and community mobilization methodology to facilitate churches and community members to identify and effectively use their existing resources in community-led development initiatives. Through a process of contextual Bible studies and experiential exercises, church and community members map their individual and collective resources, dream dreams, and initiate group projects that improve physical, economic, social and spiritual life in their communities. It has been nearly 9 years that the ENP philosophy has been promoted by PEAC. The initial pilot phase under the leadership and guidance of Mosaic Creative (Bill Crooks&#x2019; UK-based consulting agency) began in 2008 in the three dioceses of Aru, Boga and North Kivu with the envisioning of provincial leaders and the subsequent 2009 formation of an initial 17 ENP facilitators. In 2011, PEAC&#x2019;s provincial staff Fid&#xE8;le Hamisi Mushamuka, Provincial Coordinator, and Reverend Martin Nguba, ENP Program Assistant, assumed leadership of the program&#x2019;s promotion and expansion throughout the province. Since 2011, with the financial and technical support of Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development, the ENP program has seen both quantitative and qualitative improvements in results, including: - Formation of 10 national Trainers of ENP Facilitators for the self-promotion of ENP within the province. - Progressive provincial-led expansion of the program from 3 to all 9 dioceses in DRCongo. - Envisioning of over 335 leaders across the province. - Training of 293 active ENP facilitators, who in turn have encouraged the parish- and/or community-led initiation of 610+ development projects by 374 different ENP groups that include over 19,376 participating group members. - Development of an empowering and sustainable ENP program expansion plan that provides PEAC diocesan development teams with provincial accompaniment through three phases: Phase I: Envisioning and launch, i.e., initial religious leaders sensitization and training of a pilot group of ENP facilitators. Phase II: Equipping and expansion, i.e., strengthening diocesan ENP coordination teams through coaching, peer exchanges and networking, and administrative and logistical equipment. Phase III: Maturing and self-promotion, i.e., supporting diocesan ENP coordination teams to transition from provincial financial support to diocesan self-financing of future ENP promotion. - Development of tools for the reinforcement of both Provincial and Diocesan technical expertise in program monitoring, results tracking and the application of generally approved standards of accounting. The plan for 2016 seeks to complete outstanding Phase II activities to equip ENP teams in Bukavu, Kinshasa, Kisangani, Kasai and Katanga with one moto and computer each, as well as Phase III activities to graduate ENP teams in Aru and Nord Kivu to sufficiency via support for their individual ENP project-supporting income-generating activity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Province of the Anglican Church of Congo</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="50E1BACC-23C0-4379-8E58-2F4F7B57EC08" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-CD-15-19031" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_205413">
   <location-id code="205413" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sud-Kivu</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sud-Kivu, Democratic Republic of the Congo (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="205413" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-3.16667 28.25</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_205703">
   <location-id code="205703" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Katanga</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Katanga, Democratic Republic of the Congo (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="205703" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-9.0 26.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_209610">
   <location-id code="209610" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maniema</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maniema, Democratic Republic of the Congo (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="209610" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-3.0 26.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_214138">
   <location-id code="214138" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kasai-Oriental</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kasai-Oriental, Democratic Republic of the Congo (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="214138" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-4.5 24.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_214139">
   <location-id code="214139" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kasai-Occidental</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kasai-Occidental, Democratic Republic of the Congo (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="214139" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-5.33333 21.58333</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_216139">
   <location-id code="216139" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Orientale</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Orientale, Democratic Republic of the Congo (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="216139" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.5 27.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_2314300">
   <location-id code="2314300" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kinshasa</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of the Congo (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="2314300" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-4.375 15.97</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="24" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Strengthening for CSOs (general)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="19376"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
