<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/19019" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-GH-15-19019</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security and Livelihoods Program in Ghana</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Provide training on harvesting, handling and disinfecting of targeted crops. (200 new farmers and about 740 continuing), 1. Support women farmers in the processing of groundnuts, soya, shea and rice, using the equipment previously purchased, through training and monitoring (70 new women and 440 continuing women), 5. Support six women to establish independent pig farms as income generation projects., 6. Train Community Extension Volunteers to support technology transfer in their communities and provide incentives. (20 volunteers), 3. Provide training on correct use of agro-chemicals (200 farmers), 1. Demonstrate improved farming practices including the construction of contour bunds, crop rotation, integrated pest management, crop spacing and compost production using participatory workshops, demonstration plots and training sessions. (with up to 200 new farmers and 740 continuing), 2. Support targeted farmers with improved seed varieties (maize, soybeans) and chemical fertilizer on a credit basis (up to 200 new and 740 continuing), 4. Assist targeted farmers with the management of sheep and goats by providing improved breeding stock, training on animal health and management and facilitating access to needed inputs. (240 goats and sheep for 120 farmers, plus up to 120 animals to be distributed from offspring of previous recipients), 9. Follow-up and reflect on mid-term results from 2015 and incorporate learning into project planning. 8. Provide building the capacity of ADDRO staff on good Agricultural practices (example selection of seeds, planting distance, seedling rate, fertilizer application, and weed control, Disease and pest management etc.) This will enable the staff to serve as trainers for agricultural workshop., 2. Monitor mango tree seedlings supplied to individual farmers in 2015., 1. Conduct sensitization on land preservation and bushfire prevention (200 new farmers. Plus follow-up with 878 current), 1. Provide credit to interested entrepreneurs (women, men, youth, PLWHA, PWDs) (60 new, plus 220 current),Form Saving with Education groups. ADDRO Staff and Volunteers will be trained and equipped to form, train and coach community-based savings groups. 2. Train entrepreneurs in credit and business management (60 new, plus 410 current), 3. Support women donkey set owners to use their donkey set effectively, facilitate their continued repayment of their loans and continue to monitor their use of the donkey, plough and cart through field diaries. (100 women)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Northern Ghana, most of the population are small landowners relying on subsistence farming. While the country has made great progress over the last decade, in the north, poverty, food insecurity and malnutrition rates remain high. ADDRO uses an integrated approach to tackle issues of poverty and hunger, improve health and combat gender and disability discrimination. ADDRO continues to build on its long experience working on food security in the region. This year they will implement the fourth year of a five-year comprehensive program aimed at increasing productivity, reducing postharvest losses, conserving natural resources, and improving incomes. Activities include improving agricultural input supply with the latest seed varieties and appropriate fertilizers, assisting farmers with new crop techniques through demonstration and training, training in vegetable and fruit-tree production, and small animal rearing, as well as food processing activities like peanut and shea butter production. ADDRO is also working to improve women&apos;s ability to till land, reduce their labor and increase independence through the provision of an innovative technical and financial package for women to own a donkey, plough and cart. The program also includes a micro-credit facility, managed by ADDRO, which allows farmers and other entrepreneurs in the communities to access credit for their operations. They also continue their long-standing work in disability rehabilitation, assisting the blind, mentally or physically handicapped through their integration in their broader program support. Finally, in 2016, the Savings with Education methodology will be used by ADDRO, managed by both Food Security and Health program staff, in communities where ADDRO activities are already taking place.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women, Farmers, Individuals</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anglican Diocesan Development and Relief Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="0905B698-7197-40CB-8762-38CA05C0C300" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-GH-15-19019" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_2297169">
   <location-id code="2297169" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern, Ghana (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="2297169" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.5 -1.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="24" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Strengthening for CSOs (general)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environment</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3848"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
