<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/19023" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-ZM-15-19023</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Childhood Development Program for Children Affected by HIV/AIDS</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individuals, Community Volunteer, Family members, Children &amp;lt; 5, Community Health Worker, Women, Children Affected by HIV, Staff</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 3 year grant would support an expanded program to reach a total of 12, 446 children under six and 7, 070 families through 53 ECD Centers. During our current 2012-2013 grant implementation period, Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development and our partner the Zambia Anglican Council (ZAC) established a community-based, volunteer-driven Early Childhood Development Program in three provinces, involving 8, 000 children under five and their caregivers (CGs) affected by HIV/AIDS. The holistic program built on the assets and programs of our faith-based organization at the national, regional and local levels. There is now a thriving network of ECD Centers housed in schools and churches in rural Zambia &#x2013; with ECD volunteers working with caregiver support &amp;amp; learning groups and children&#x2019;s playgroups, combined with home visits and coordinated services. The Essential Package&#x2019;s Visual Guides and other tools form the basis of the program, integrated with child health, nutrition, and livelihoods strengthening. The ECD Program is also serving as a catalyst for community organizing and development in these marginalized areas. With its holistic design, volunteer structure, referrals and linkages, the ECD Program has shown signs of success in helping caregivers and communities so that young children can thrive in very challenging rural areas. Based on this strong foundation, over the next three years we propose to expand the program by serving additional families at the current centers and by integrating the ECD program into our community development work in other high HIV prevalence areas in other provinces. With lessons learned from the first twenty months&#x2019; implementation, we will improve the project design and its impact (see section v, page 8 for specific quality improvements) The current program is managed by two ZAC field offices in six project sites in 3 provinces. In one of these project sites, Chibombo district, we leveraged unused ECD Centers constructed by Plan International that had been left with the communities when Plan International&#x2019;s funding for its ECD program ended. However, as Plan International has just received funding through UNICEF, the plan is now for Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development/ZAC to transfer the 8 ECD Centers and their activities to Plan who will take over the management and reporting via UNICEF. As Chibombo is close to the capital there are many NGOs working in the district, so by transferring the sites to Plan, Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development &amp;amp; ZAC will be able to start ECD programs in more neglected areas such as Luapula and Southern provinces. Therefore, we will continue and expand services in four current sites and integrate ECD into programs managed by the other three of ZAC&#x2019;s five field offices, setting up 15 new ECD-Center based programs in 12 rural project sites</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;CHWs provide quarterly training sessions during caregiver group meetings in nutrition and specific age-appropriate feeding &quot;, Monthly cooking demonstrations to 212 caregiver groups, Provide training 212 caregiver group members in cultivating kitchen (vegetable) gardens and maize, Provision of seeds (maize and vegetables) to caregiver support group members for distribution to start family gardens, Training of Savings Facilitators on SWE (77 Volunteers and 3 PMs), Formation, training and facilitation of 176 Savings Groups for caregivers (12 month process), Empower Volunteers with Agriculture Cooperative membership and registration fee support, Establishment of Volunteer SWE groups, Replenishment of Volunteer work tools (boots, back packs, wraps), Establishment of Joint Local Caregiver/Stakeholder project steering committee(Coordination and Planning meetings), Formation of 53 Granny-Toddler Stimulation Groups, Quarterly Documentation of Story Telling Sessions by Grannies, Drama performance sessions, Improving 13 ECD Structures using Community Matching Inputs (Nails, Iron sheets, Cement, brickforce wire, 212 Caregiver Support &amp;amp; Learning Groups and toddler playgroups meet Once per month using EP, Toddler Playgroup Stimulation Sessions (87 toddler groups meet once a week), Quarterly Caregiver Creative Arts and Toy making sessions, Production of Indigenous Story Book from Granny Sessions and Video Library (in Local Languages), Caregiver support groups sessions conduct discussions on selected parental skills themes( self esteem, parenting styles, positive parenting etc.), Translation of Parental Skills Visual aids and key messages in 4 languages (Bemba, Tonga, Chewa and Kaonde)- 425 Copies (1 for 2 ECD Promoters), Preschool Playgroups meet weekly, using preschool curriculum and additional learning tools purchased for each Center, Monthly home visits for 6228 families on EP, Monthly home visits for 7070 families on Parental skills, ECD Volunteer In-Service &amp;amp; Reflection Meetings with 1166 volunteers - every other month, Parental skills training for volunteers, Formation of 7 Drama Groups (2 in Northern, 2 in Central, 1 in Eastern and 2 in Lusaka), Training of Drama Groups in Behavioral Change Theatre Skills, Audio visual learning sessions( 10 sessions each) for 212 caregiver support groups, CHWs provide monthly health education session for 212 caregiver groups (malaria, diarrhea, pneumonia, nutrition, water and sanitation, eye and ear infections, PMTCT, Family Planning, HV/AIDS, TB), Group Health Counseling Sessions (feeding, health and psychosocial), Health referrals made for children and caregivers as needed, Bi- annual Child Health Week ( MCH, WATSAN and Treatment), Household Counseling (HIV/AIDS, TB, Family Planning, RDT, HIV Testing, ACT, Social, Diagnosis and management of common childhood illnesses), Monthly Growth Monitoring conducted for U5 children by CHWs (New and old centers), Rehabilitation of 13 ECD Center Water Points, SBCC TOT for 212 Lead ECD Promoters (4 per ECD Center), SBCC Cascade Training for 954 ECD Promoters, Monitoring of Financial Systems, operations, compliance &amp;amp; accountability (Diocesan Level - Quarterly trips), 1.1 Development of TOR for Financial Management Systems Strengthening, 1.4 Financial Systems Management Assessment (National and Diocesan Levels) Consulting Assignment Phase I, Production of ZACOP Financial Manual (Consulting Assignment Phase II), Roll out workshop - Financial Manual and Management Systems - Consulting Assignment Phase Iii, Staff Contracts &amp;amp; Setting up of Salary Scales Systems, Development of TOR for HR Manual Review, Board HR Manual Review and Approval, Development of Staff Performance Assessment Tool, Quarterly Board Meetings (ZACOP Policy review, Programmes updates and strategy plan review, Training of Diocesan Managers in EXCEL Data Base Management and Micro-Links, Annual Technical Support Meetings with National and Diocesan Accountants and Administrators, Institutional Audit</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia Anglican Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="59E84A4E-35D1-41D5-8E8A-5A476A1A5269" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-ZM-15-19023" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="24" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Strengthening for CSOs (general)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="5" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation and Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-30"></period-end>
     <target value="31124"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
