<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/19027" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-LR-15-19027</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberia Integrated Food Security Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farmers, Clergy/Lay Leaders, Individuals, Women</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Procurement of demo sites Inputs (fertilizers, seeds, Knap-sack sprayer &amp;amp; tools). Expansion of 2 demo sites plots. Establishing of Seed multiplication site. Organize farmers visit to demo sites. Procurement of fish processing and preservation Inputs (dryers&amp;amp; accessories). Establishment of women&apos;s fish processing and preservation groups. Tosor Fishing Group support (Boat &amp;amp; Machine maintenance). Tosor Fishing group leadership training, Conduct Sensitization and Educational Events at Sunday Sermon and Retreat at Districts and Village Communities. Channel of Hope Training (Bassa Region)- 20 Priests and Lay Leaders. Inclusion of affected communities in savings groups. Identification and selection of communities. Provision of seeds and agri. Implements to Ebola affected community. Post-Ebola Skills Training (in tie dying, soap making, Sewing etc.). Establishment of (11) New Savings Groups, Bi-annual training &amp;amp; experience sharing for savings and loan facilitators and groups Leadership, Provision of printed materials (ledgers and pass books). Participatory Planning and Mobilization Meetings, Carry out Participatory Learning and Action Exercises with Farm Group Members. Establishment of 11 Community farm groups (Agro, Vegetable, Rice &amp;amp; Cassava). Training in improved farming methods. Provision of improved high yielding seeds (Rice, Cassava Cuttings, Plantain &amp;amp; Eddoes Suckers, Vegetables). Linking Farms group with Ministry of Agriculture extension services, Provision of new and Replacement of lost and/or old tools to communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Episcopal Church of Liberia Relief and Development will continue implementing its Food Security, Livelihood and Ebola Projects in the four Archdeaconries: South Eastern, Northern, South Western and Bassa. The Program will continue to strengthen the churches farms as a means of sustaining the churches, as well as the community-based farm groups, thereby enabling them to generate income for their families and support their community development initiatives. Two Demonstration sites have been established and contain one oil palm nursery each and other mixed crops. The oil palm seedlings will be distributed to four local churches and the Diocese for their agro farms. Each local church after harvesting will set aside 30% of their sales to the Diocese to support the development initiatives of the Diocese. One of the Demonstration sites will be expanded for the purpose of establishing a seed multiplication site. The improved seeds and other crops will be distributed to the farming groups. Overall the two Demonstration sites will also be used to train farmers in new farming methods and techniques. In 2015 three churches and one farm community planted a total of 7,100 oil palm seedlings on 60.5 acres of land. It is expected that within the next 3-4 years when the oil palm is matured and harvested, proceeds would be used to support these churches and community in their development initiatives. Improved vegetable seeds and other crops were distributed to four farming groups, while two local churches and five farming groups received tools and other agricultural implements. The farms groups have been engaged in various agricultural activities ranging from cassava, rice and other vegetables production. The Program will continue to engage the communities to provide the land and labor to grow food crops that will be sold on the local market. In some cases the crops will be processed to add value, as a means of increasing the income of the farming groups. With an increase in their incomes, the various groups would be in the position to support their faming efforts by purchasing additional farming implements and other supplies needed to continue their farming activities. The Program will continue to provide technical support to these farming groups through the provision of farming implements and training to enable an increase in their yield, thereby supporting their community development initiatives and providing income to the groups and addressing their nutritional needs. The program will continue to support the Savings and Loan Project to build and strengthen savings and income for women, men, and their families, thereby contributing to the economic empowerment of their families. This program which started in February 2014 has economically changed the lives and living conditions of more than 4,149 women and their families. The Program intends to increase the number of Savings and Loan Groups from 31 to 42 with a membership of 1,010 persons. The Savings Groups will be encouraged to register with the County Savings and Loan Association as well as the National Village and Savings Loan Association. The Groups association with these bodies, will enable them have access to available micro loan and other economic empowerment services. Also, the Groups will be linked to the Agriculture activities as a means of increasing their incomes to enable them contribute to the development initiatives of their communities. In addition members of the various Savings and Loan Groups will receive training in basic GBV concepts and will be supported to form GBV Networks to prevent and respond to GBV related issues in their communities. The Ebola outbreak in Liberia adversely affected the program activities. The Program responded to the outbreak by providing the much needed Ebola prevention materials and supplies to affected Ebola communities, Ebola survivors, ETUs, as well as health centers and hospitals. In support of the Ebola Recovery Process, the Program will continue to focus on livelihood training and linking one Ebola affected community to agricultural activities. In addition, Religious leaders from both the Muslim and Christian faiths will be trained to work with their communities to prevent and respond to Ebola, avoid stigmatizing Ebola survivors and ensure their reintegration in their communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Liberia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="81B528BB-7007-4807-80B1-01D970E0F19C" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-LR-15-19027" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="3" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Prevention and Preparedness</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="18" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="40541"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
