<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/17862" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-SB-14-17862</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building ACOM Rural Training Centre Sustainability 2015</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1 Allocate SBD 21,297.85 to MBM/MU Literacy program to cover their 2014 end-of-year negative balance. ,4.1 Ensure the accredtation of ACOM-V RTCs through the purchase of tools required for tool package completion. This involves the re-allocation and transfer of US$10,000 to ACOM-V.,3.1 Re-allocate SBD 23,774 to ACOM MBM HQ as Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development&apos;s 2015 contribution to the Financial Officer position. ,1) Respond to the demands for learning at all six centers, targeting an estimated 1,150 youth (890 male, 260 female). This includes supporting all six RTCs in their: increasing of school enrollment, offering of short courses to communities, and enhancing of course curricula to be in line with national standards and to include new subjects.,3) Improve female enrollment at each center by 50%. This includes supporting all six RTCs in their: a) Development of curriculum to attract female students, b) Building of infrastructure appropriate for female students, and c) Establishment of policies and student counselor to support female students.,4) Improve centers&apos; sustainability and economic self-reliance. This includes supporting all six RTCs in their: a) Monitoring of progress towards strategic objectives, b) Development of financial independence strategies, and c) Development of existing land and resources to sustainably support centers.,2) Improve the quality of training and education offered at all centers. This includes supporting all six RTCs in their: a) Establishment and monitoring of Quality Management System, b) Staff development for trainers, c) Addressing of infrastructure needs, and d) Improvement in level of literacy and numeracy among students.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Staff,Youth 13-24 yrs</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Church of Melanesia operates eleven Rural Training Centers (RTC), five in Vanuatu and six in the Solomon Islands. The RTCs were established against the backdrop of many school dropouts from the primary &amp;amp; secondary education systems in Solomon Islands and Vanuatu. These school dropouts do not have the necessary education or self-esteem to be functioning members in society. The RTCs provide an avenue for some of the school dropouts to be empowered with useful knowledge, values and skills. The RTCs receive some limited financial assistance from the Governments of Solomon Island and Vanuatu. Based on the results of a comprehensive review and study of the RTCs conducted in 2009 by Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development and ACOM, five policy goals have been identified: 1) to increase the number of female students and lower the ratio differential between men and women in all 9 schools; 2) to increase and/or improve the number of business and management courses; 3) To initiate or expand short community courses as a means of increasing impact and non-formal education access to the wider community; 4) to develop the local business and management plans for at least 4 RTCs (possibly all ten) which result in increasing the income and self sustainability of the individual RTCs; and 5) introducing solar power as both a course and a source of revenue for the school. The program will be overseen by a Business Development Committee which will function for at least 2 years. 2015 Represents the final year that Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development will be supporting ACOM Solomon Islands RTC program. A balance of 2014 funds on hand with ACOM Solomon Islands will support the 2015 RTC work, as well as lessen the gap in funding as Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development phases out in 2016.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anglican Church of Melanesia (ACoM)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="727725E2-F80C-4844-8CA5-2942F123981E" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-SB-14-17862" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="5" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-05-01"></period-end>
     <target value="10353"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
