<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/20402" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-LR-16-20402</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Church of Liberia Church Income Rehabilitation and Strengthening Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clergy/Lay Leaders, Community volunteers</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establishment of Farm Management Committees, Transportation and transplantation of 15,000 seedlings to 9 Church managed farms, Identification and Preparation of Church Land for palm oil cultivation, Train farm management teams in farm management and leadership, Train Farm management teams and selected Priests in Basic Agriculture and Improved Agriculture practices, Provide Incentives to the ECL Farm Management Team and Clergy, Provided Technical Support to Farm Management Teams (ECLRD)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Episcopal Church of Liberia has been a development partner of the Episcopal Relief and Development, New York for more than 10 years. Through this collaboration, Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development has provided both technical and financial support to the Episcopal Church of Liberia (ECL) to enable it address some of its challenges. Notwithstanding, the ECL has been struggling to cope as its meager resources are inadequate to support its development initiatives, especially in the rural areas. Furthermore, the Ebola crisis also had its toll on the Church, which has contributed to a shortfall in the Church&#x2019;s income. The ECL has a total of 76 churches spread out in four Archdeaconries (South-Eastern, Northern, South-Western and Bassa), with a total of sixty (60) Priests responsible for the spiritual growth of these churches. The Church, like other Institutions has to grow and needs to be self-sufficient and self-sustainable. Over the years, the Episcopal Church of Liberia Relief and Development with support from Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development has partnered with few of the churches in the Laboni Archdeaconry to establish oil palm farms in the areas where the churches are located. The oil palm farms are being operated by the Churches and members of their various congregations, while being supervised by the assigned Priests. During the just ended Convention, it was agreed that the ECL establishes an oil palm farm, to support its development initiatives as well as for sustainability. The Farm when established will be managed by a Management Team to be set up by the Diocese. The oil palm farm will be situated in the South-Western Archdeaconry. Furthermore, the establishment of the oil palm farms is intended to support the ECL Diocese&#x2019;s development and sustainability efforts, thereby reducing dependency on external support, which may come to an end when funds can no longer be mobilized. It is to this end that the ECL is seeking support from Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development for the establishment of the Diocese oil palm farm to be operated and managed by the Diocese through a Farm Management Team. Also those rural churches that have oil palm farms and those desirous of establishing oil palm farms will benefit as well. The ECL revenue stream are limited with much of it s assets ruined during the civil war. The recent Ebola outbreak has also exacerbated the situation, as meager resources were being shared and distributed to cover salary backlogs of priests and those running basic Church services. This continues to impact on the Church evangelic reach to its congregants. Some priest have not waited for the Church and have began establishing farms through training provided by ECLRD. Results obtained from this experience have led the Church to identify training of priests in farm management as a means of diversifying personal income and more importantly the establishment of farm management teams for larger scale palm oil farms. Proceeds from individual priest managed farm plots can cover basic family needs while in the longer term, income from the sale of palm oil will put the Church to develop a sustainable revenue stream.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Liberia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DBE62212-B790-4D87-86F5-57572124CB5E" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-LR-16-20402" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-30" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_2276630">
   <location-id code="2276630" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grand Bassa</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grand Bassa, Liberia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="2276630" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.23333 -9.83333</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="31544"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
