<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/17872" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-MM-14-17872</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocesan Development Partnership</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development&apos;s partnership with the Church of the Province of Myanmar involves activities in each of the six dioceses and the Provincial Development Office. Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development is working with the provincial and diocesan development staff to strengthen and expand community development program planning and implementation, and to build professional capacity of development staff. Each diocesan office conducts assessments to determine community priorities and plan program activities, with community participation and leadership, to meet development needs as defined by their constituencies. Provincial Office The Provincial Development Desk will closely monitor all programs and incorporate capacity building training activities for development staff, including coordinating the 2015 Partner Steering Committee. The staff will facilitate the learning exchange of 6 development workers with the Episcopal Church in the Philippines. The Provincial Desk will also oversee the launch and implementation of the new staffing and organizational structure. Diocese of Hpa&apos;an The Diocese will provide a seed nursery for a teak plantation for 40 households serving 504 people in Ee Hae township as part of a two-year plan for community and parish economic self-sufficiency. Diocese of Mandalay The Diocese will establish a model animal husbandry farm in Pa Thein Gyi, to serve as an extension of the Mingalardon Men&apos;s Association farm to provide monitoring support and extension services to 30 farmers per quarter. Diocese of Myitkyina The Diocese will establish a youth training center in the diocesan office and provide training on improved cultivation techniques to 295 persons in Mohnyin village. Diocese of Sittwe The Diocese will establish a paddy terrace farming demonstration farm for 34 farmers. The farm will include a sustainability plan and monitoring mechanism. Diocese of Toungoo The Diocese will establish 7 microfinance groups in 4 villages clusters of Htee-Day parish (Aung Nan Cho, Taei Su, Chailk Ein Su and Lau Ein Su). Diocese of Yangon The Diocese will facilitate the financial resiliences training and accompaniment through inputs in farming, fishing, livestock and small business to 496 perons in Ahlamagn-Tuchaung village.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individuals</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Provincial Development Department will facilitate the Partners Steering with CPM leadership in November 2015 to further the new organizational structure,The Provincial Development Department will facilitate a peer exchange initiative with the Episcopal Church of the Philippines for upto 8 development workers on leadership training program,The Provincial Development Department will provide monitoring and evaluation support to all diocesan projects, including reviewing and enhancing the provincial mapping tool to track the overall reach and impact of the Church&#x2019;s programs,The Diocese of Hpaan provide an income generational teak plantation with cash crops to Ea Hae township to serve 504 persons,The Diocese of Mandalay will initiate a model animal husbandry farm in Pa Thein Gyi to provide extension services for at least 30 farmers per quarter,The Diocese of Myitkyina will provide training for vocational training for 34 youth and improved cultivation techniques for 295 farmers,The Diocese of Yangon to build household financial self-sufficiency through training and inputs in farming, fishing, livestock and small business to 496 persons in Ahlamagn-Tuchaung village,The Diocese of Yangon with the Provincial Development Department to administer a disaster risk reduction capacity building programme using the Pastors and Disasters toolkit in Irrawaddy deanery,The Diocese of Sittwe will build a terrace paddy farming demonstration farm to serve 34 farmers every 6 months,The Diocese of Toungoo to form 7 microfinance groups in 4 village clusters in Htee-Day parish</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Church of the Province of Myanmar</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Hpa-an</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Mandalay</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Myitkyina</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Sittwe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Toungoo</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Yangon</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="BEA9ABA5-2574-476F-844C-5D5AAAF63650" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-MM-14-17872" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="3" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Prevention and Preparedness</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="23" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fishing</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-05-01"></period-end>
     <target value="6480"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
