<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/13917" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-LK-14-13917</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Livelihood Microcredit Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development began a partnership with ECLOF Lanka two years after the tsunami as those affected were better able to restart livelihoods. Since the people affected directly or indirectly living in the tsunami areas have no access to finance from formal financial sources due to the lack of collateral, the ECLOF Lanka program is one of the only avenues for beneficiaries to start up new activities that would generate income for sustainability. In 2015, ECLOF Lanka will continue to replicate their same methodology in new target areas. ECLOF Lanka identifies clients in the marginalized areas by weighing heavily on the support and information from respective local government offices. At these local government offices are personnel identified for development of income- generating livelihood programs. These persons assist in the formation of groups / societies of women&#x2019;s along with the grass root Village Level Officer. These government agents conduct awareness programs in the training of income generation projects with the assistance of social organizations and volunteer technical consultants. As the traditional wage earner in the family is the male, ECLOF Lanka&apos;s efforts will have a direct impact on women as over 95% of loan recipients are women. This will give opportunities for the development of talents and empower women, as well as enhance the quality of food and educational facilities available to the children in the family.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Utilize Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development&apos;s monitoring framework, and report on the social indicators to measure the success of the interventions,Facilitate training on financial management concepts to 26 loan solidarity groups in Mannar division,Provide training on Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development Savings Methodology to 10 ECLOF-Lanka staff,Conduct a baseline assessment by April 2015 to assist with monitoring the programme and evaluating the social impact of the programme on female entrepreneurs and their families,Pilot Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development Savings Methodology to at least 4 groups in Nannattan division in Mannar district to serve at least 60 women,Provide micro-credit loan services to at least 1070 women with an interest rate of 13%. Monitor group performance and repayment on a monthly basis,Work with the local government offices to form and support upto 100 women&#x2019;s societies to facilitate loan delivery, 50 in Mannar and 50 in Avisavella/Paduka, for 1080 persons</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ECLOF Sri Lanka</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="2DA2F75F-7437-4DED-8690-D1C0DCF733B5" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-LK-14-13917" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-30" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-11-30"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-05-01"></period-end>
     <target value="19430"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
