<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/13920" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-ZM-14-13920</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Childhood Development Program for Children Affected by HIV/AIDS</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children Affected by HIV,Family members,People living with HIV/AIDS (PLWHA),Community Volunteer,Staff,Community Health Worker</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 3 year grant would support an expanded program to reach a total of 12,446 children under six and 7,070 families through 53 ECD Centers. During our current 2012-2013 grant implementation period, Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development and our partner the Zambia Anglican Council (ZAC) established a community-based, volunteer-driven Early Childhood Development Program in three provinces, involving 8,000 children under five and their caregivers (CGs) affected by HIV/AIDS. The holistic program built on the assets and programs of our faith-based organization at the national, regional and local levels. There is now a thriving network of ECD Centers housed in schools and churches in rural Zambia &#x2013; with ECD volunteers working with caregiver support &amp;amp; learning groups and children&#x2019;s playgroups, combined with home visits and coordinated services. The Essential Package&#x2019;s Visual Guides and other tools form the basis of the program, integrated with child health, nutrition, and livelihoods strengthening. The ECD Program is also serving as a catalyst for community organizing and development in these marginalized areas. With its holistic design, volunteer structure, referrals and linkages, the ECD Program has shown signs of success in helping caregivers and communities so that young children can thrive in very challenging rural areas. Based on this strong foundation, over the next three years we propose to expand the program by serving additional families at the current centers and by integrating the ECD program into our community development work in other high HIV prevalence areas in other provinces. With lessons learned from the first twenty months&#x2019; implementation, we will improve the project design and its impact (see section v, page 8 for specific quality improvements) The current program is managed by two ZAC field offices in six project sites in 3 provinces. In one of these project sites, Chibombo district, we leveraged unused ECD Centers constructed by Plan International that had been left with the communities when Plan International&#x2019;s funding for its ECD program ended. However, as Plan International has just received funding through UNICEF, the plan is now for Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development/ZAC to transfer the 8 ECD Centers and their activities to Plan who will take over the management and reporting via UNICEF. As Chibombo is close to the capital there are many NGOs working in the district, so by transferring the sites to Plan, Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development &amp;amp; ZAC will be able to start ECD programs in more neglected areas such as Luapula and Southern provinces. Therefore, we will continue and expand services in four current sites and integrate ECD into programs managed by the other three of ZAC&#x2019;s five field offices, setting up 15 new ECD-Center based programs in 12 rural project sites</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training of 43 Volunteer Savings Group Facilitators ,Formation, training and facilitation of 212 Savings Groups for caregivers (12 month process),Water, Sanitation, Hygiene Education sessions at Caregiver group meetings (4 sessions),Equip 53 Centers with durable hand washing stations appropriate for children,Refresher Training on SBCC for volunteers,Health referrals made for children and caregivers as needed,CHWs provide quarterly health education session for 212 caregiver groups ,Monthly Growth Monitoring conducted for U5 children by CHWs (New and old centers),Conduct 8 Quarterly cooking demonstrations to 212 caregiver groups,Provide training to 212 of caregivers in cultivating kitchen (vegetable) gardens and maize,Provision of seeds (maize and vegetables) to 212 caregiver support groups for distribution to start family gardens ,&quot;CHWs provide quarterly training sessions during caregiver group meetings in nutrition and specific age-appropriate feeding &quot;,Establishment of Youth caregiver drama groups(2*10 members each),EP training of 30 Psychosocial Volunteers,Zambia National and District ECD Quarterly Meetings,212 Caregiver Support &amp;amp; Learning Groups and toddler playgroups meet twice per month using EP curriculum,Monthly home visits for 7070 families ,ECD Volunteer In-Service &amp;amp; Reflection Meetings with 1166 volunteers - every other month,Mentoring of caregivers to take lead in center child play activities,Training of 1389 volunteers in parental skills,424 Preschool Playgroups meet twice per month, using preschool curriculum and additional learning tools purchased for each Center. ,Psychosocial Counseling for caregivers as needed,Monthly home visits for 7070 families on Parental skills, 76 toddler playgroups meeting twice per month, using EP curriculum. TBD,Parental skills training for 17 ZAC staff,Strengthening of youth parental skills (Chibondo and Senama),212 caregiver support groups conduct discussions on selected parental skills themes( self esteem, parenting styles, positive parenting etc)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia Anglican Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="B0D01392-BE87-4111-8373-AB0338B22F16" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-ZM-14-13920" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_896972">
   <location-id code="896972" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southern</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southern, Zambia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="896972" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-16.5 27.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_909845">
   <location-id code="909845" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Luapula</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Luapula, Zambia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="909845" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-11.0 29.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_921064">
   <location-id code="921064" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central, Zambia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="921064" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-14.0 29.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="5" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation and Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-05-01"></period-end>
     <target value="48448"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
