<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/13885" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-CU-13-13885</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Church of Cuba Integrated Development Program 2014 Diocese of Cuba</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development has partnered with the Episcopal Church of Cuba and the Primate&apos;s World Relief and Development Fund to support the Episcopal Church of Cuba&apos;s with improving and strengthening the development office&apos;s institutional capacity to conceptualize, develop, and implement development projects. As a result, the ECC&apos;s Integrated Development Program has identified four key objectives: 1. Increase institutional knowledge and skills to carry out outreach work 2. Increase community empowerment through training of community leaders 3. Implement food security projects that improve family nutrition and increase income 4. Improve community gender awareness Special emphasis will be given to vulnerable populations (physically unpaired, elderly, women, children, and HIV and AIDS carriers). The beneficiaries are from 14 communities located in two geographic regions: 1) Guantanamo to Camaguey; 2) Ciego de Avila to Pinar del Rio. In terms of results, the project will increase the knowledge, skills, and capacity of 2,000 community members to establish community vegetable gardens, which will improve and increase the food production, thus addressing the food security issue. It will also provide work, income, and improve the nutrition status of the beneficiaries. The program is also expected to increase community awareness about gender-based violence assist the community with finding solutions on how to confront and eliminate it. The program will also enhance ECC institutional capacity, expertise and skills to respond in a timely way to natural disasters and reconstruction of affected communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individuals</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Train 25 community leaders to carry out community needs assessments project design, implementation, monitoring and evaluation. ,To train and build Episcopal Church of Cuba institutional knowledge of development programming and skills to carry out outreach work. ,Utilize a microcredit fund for the support of 8 community projects designed by trained program community leaders. ,Training and implementation of family vegetable gardens to improve nutrition and increase income through the sale of surplus products from gardens. ,Train and build the capacity of community leaders to increase awareness on gender-based-violence and solutions to confront and control it.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Cuba</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Primate&apos;s World Relief and Development Fund (PWRDF)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="D408E0E7-9E4F-471C-800D-595AEC11AD35" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-CU-13-13885" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-29" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CU" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.episcopalrelief.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
