<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/5507" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-CD-14-5507</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PEAC Provincial Development Office Programming 2014 ENP &quot;Ensemble Nous Pouvons&quot;</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individuals,Clergy/Lay Leaders,Family members,Community Volunteer,Staff</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Together We Can - Ensemble Nous Pouvons (ENP) is a provincial program of the Anglican Church of Congo (PEAC) that employs an asset-based church and community mobilization methodology to facilitate churches and community members to identify and effectively use their existing resources in community-led development initiatives. Through a process of contextual Bible studies and experiential exercises, church and community members map their individual and collective resources, dream dreams, and initiate group projects that improve physical, economic, social and spiritual life in their communities. It has been nearly 7 years that the ENP philosophy has been promoted by PEAC. 

The initial pilot phase under the leadership and guidance of Mosaic Creative (Bill Crooks&#x2019; UK-based consulting agency) began in 2008 in the three dioceses of Aru, Boga and North Kivu with the formation of 17 facilitators and 10 trainers of facilitators. 

In 2011, PEAC&#x2019;s provincial staff Fidele Mushamuka, BDC Coordinator, and Reverend Martin Nguba, Finance &amp;amp; Program Assistant, assumed leadership of the program&#x2019;s promotion and expansion throughout the province. Over the last three years, with the financial and technical support of Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development, the ENP program has seen both quantitative and qualitative improvements in results, including: 

1) Expansion of the program from 3 to 6 of the 9 dioceses across DRCongo, i.e., Aru, Boga, N.Kivu, Bukavu, Kindu and Kinshasa. 

2) The training of 210 active ENP facilitators, who in turn have contributed to the community-led initiation of 370+ development projects by 218 different ENP groups (church and/or community-based) that include over 10,933 participating group members. 

3) Development of a motivation and reinforcement plan for the equipping of diocesan ENP coordination teams 

4) Reinforcement of the provincial ENP coordination team that includes the production of tools for the support of diocesan activities as well as the collection and analysis of data (narrative, interpretive and financial). 

The plan for 2014 includes final expansion of this work to the remaining 3 dioceses of Katanga, Kasai and Kisangani, and thus the anticipated increase of 75 Facilitators, 60 ENP Groups and 60+ community-led projects throughout these areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transmit the ENP vision to 90 clergy and lay leaders in the 3 new dioceses.,Mobilize three new Diocesan ENP Coordination Teams made up of ENP Trainers and BDC staff.,Accompany new Diocesan ENP Coordination Teams and Facilitators in their mobilization of at least 60 new ENP Groups (est. 20/diocese) that include over 900 participants (ets. 15+/ENP group).,Train at least 75 new ENP Facilitators (est. 25/diocese).,Organize three exchange visit for new Diocesan Coordination Teams to existing ENP program sites in Bukavu, Kinshasa and Kindu to learn from ENP Coordination Teams and ENP Groups.,Document activities and anticipated 60 ENP project initiated by parish and community groups.,Accompany Diocesan ENP Coordination Teams and Facilitators in their strengthening of 157+ ENP Groups that include over 8,606 participants.,Document activities and progress of over 289 projects initiated by ENP Groups.,Evaluate and support at least 4 income generating self-financing activities of Diocesan ENP Coordination Teams (1/diocese) and the UAC.,Accompany Diocesan ENP Coordination Teams and Facilitators in their strengthening of 62 existing ENP Groups and mobilization of 60+ new ENP groups (est. 20/diocese) that include over 3,227 participants.,Reinforce and equip 3 Diocesan ENP Coordination Teams in terms of transportation, office equipment and communication support.,Train Coordination Teams to be ENP Trainers at the diocesan level, who in turn will strengthen the existing 72 Facilitators as well as train an additional 60+ Facilitators.,Organize one exchange visit of Kindu Facilitators to N.Kivu ENP Coordination and community groups.,Document activities and anticipated 130 ENP project initiated by parish and community groups.,Compile statistical and narrative report based on accompaniment of Diocesan ENP Coordination Teams in activity and progress tracking.,Train accountants and Diocesan ENP Coordination Teams in financial record keeping, system controls and reporting.,Conduct site visits to each Diocesan ENP program to affirm progress and facilitate learning and growth of each Diocesan ENP Coordination Team.,Disseminate PEAC 2014 ENP plans, budgets and progress reports to all Dioceses and partners throughout the province.,Compile testimonies and interpretive reports based on accompaniment of Diocesan ENP Coordination Teams in impact tracking.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private donations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Province of the Anglican Church of Congo</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="CD75DC57-92D8-4451-8521-918401725DE2" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-CD-14-5507" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-02-27" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-02-28" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org/where-we-work/country/the-democratic-republic-of-congo</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_205703">
   <location-id code="205703" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Katanga</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Katanga, Democratic Republic of the Congo (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="205703" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-9.0 26.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_214138">
   <location-id code="214138" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kasai-Oriental</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kasai-Oriental, Democratic Republic of the Congo (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="214138" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-4.5 24.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_214139">
   <location-id code="214139" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kasai-Occidental</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kasai-Occidental, Democratic Republic of the Congo (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="214139" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-5.33333 21.58333</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.episcopalrelief.org/where-we-work/country/the-democratic-republic-of-congo">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-02-28"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-02-27"></period-end>
     <target value="39648"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
