<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/19016" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-BI-16-19016</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Livelihoods Program (Food Security and Environment) in Burundi</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establish anti-erosion trenches with grasses alongside (244km of trenches, with grasses and agro-forestry trees planted alongside), Procure seedlings, establish nurseries and conduct tree planting and maintenance (forestry and agroforestry) (750,000 trees targeted for planting, 6 types of seedlings, 37 nurseries established), Support composting and introduce green manure cover crops (at least 2 cover crops introduced, and 500 composting sites established),Conduct community mobilization activities in 37 communities, Build tanks for collection of rainwater in schools and churches (9 tanks),Construct water points, establish management committees for water points, and protect water sources by reforestation (51 water points with committees),Build latrines at the community level (100 latrines), Improve disease control for cassava and banana, including establishing Mother Gardens for banana crops (30 new banana mother gardens),Acquire and distribute goats through solidarity chain approach (120 goats), Community mobilization, training and learning on agriculture and support for farmer group legalization (87 activities with 1300 farmers),Conduct training for target women for kitchen gardens and nutrition, including seed saving and trading with continuing women (500 new women trained, provide follow-up support for current women gardeners), Acquire improved seeds, cuttings and tubers (from ISABU, IITA, agro-biotech, etc.), and continue seed multiplication centers (4,000 farmers receive new varieties disseminated, 12 established seed centers continue), Do ongoing monitoring, data collection, and analysis of data. Get ready for End term Evaluation in 2017., Collaborate with ISABU, IITA and agrobiotech to contribute to best practices on plant disease control in Burundi., Invest in staff capacity through targeted trainings and international, regional and local workshops, including training for 5 coordinators and 2 accountants., Increase visibility of program through improvement of PEAB website, and use of TV, radio, and networking., Keep office and field equipment updated (1 laptop, continue high-speed internet connection)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farmers, Staff</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Anglican Church of Burundi&#x2019;s Transformative Sustainable Livelihoods Program seeks to assist poor and vulnerable people in all seven dioceses. The Province is working to strengthen the capacity of the poorest in targeted communities in order to provide them with sustainable solutions to food insecurity. This includes increasing access to improved seeds (grain seeds, cassava cuttings, banana tubers, vegetable seeds, fruit tree seedlings) and training on agricultural skills and crop disease control with over 20,000 farmers. They are also working with farmers to adapt to the changing climate which is bringing more erratic rains and droughts in some areas. The program is engaging communities in large-scale efforts to decrease soil erosion on Burundi&apos;s steep hills, through the digging of trenches, and planting of trees and grasses. In 2014 the Program began a partnership with Cornell University, and has been able to introduce work on the creation of home vegetable gardens with women in order to improve and diversify family nutrition. The Program also works to improve community sanitation by protecting natural water aquifers and channeling water to community water points, installing rainwater harvesting tanks, and the building of household and community latrines.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anglican Church of Burundi</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cornell University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="6022AF98-14EC-49B8-892C-5491CD04D34D" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-BI-16-19016" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-29" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BI" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environment</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="26" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation and Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-29"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="103940"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
