<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/13930" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-BI-15-13930</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PEAB Sustainable Livelihoods Program - Health</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clergy/Lay Leaders,Individuals,People living with HIV/AIDS (PLWHA),In school youth,Out of school youth,Women of Reproductive Age,Orphans &amp;amp; Vulnerable Children (OVC)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Anglican Church of Burundi&#x2019;s Transformative Sustainable Livelihoods and Health Program seeks to assist poor and vulnerable people in the areas of the six dioceses in their efforts to recover from the depletion of livelihoods and health that has affected the country for over 19 years. Using a comprehensive approach to address HIV/AIDS called &quot; SAVE&quot; (Safer practices, Available medication, Voluntary counseling and testing, Empowerment), the program focuses on raising acceptance and awareness and working against the stigma and discrimination associated with HIV and AIDS. The program also aims to increase attendance at clinics which work to prevent mother-to-child transmission of HIV, as well as work with youth in schools through STOP AIDS clubs. This year the program will use the same participatory training and advocacy strategies as the HIV/AIDS activities to engage religious leaders on Ebola prevention and response. In addition the program includes family planning and female hygiene objectives, so as to promote a more holistic approach to improved community health.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Train pastors on family planning and SRH as part of pre and post marital counseling ,Support religious leaders to develop and validate action plans for family planning in their respective congregations,Advocate for improved access to family planning education and services among women of reproductive age and their husbands or partners,Organize consultation meetings at congregational level to present Family Planning issues&#xA0;,Sensitize community members on family planning (255 farmers and spouses in 4 groups participating in FSE program),Sensitize HIV+ pregnant women on PMTCT program ,Train and support interfaith religious leaders on HIV/AIDS and stigma using the SAVE approach (in new locations),Carry out a mass education campaign during the week leading up to World AIDS Day (testing clinics and advocacy throughout week, service in each Diocese on Sunday, official celebration December 1st),Train religious leaders and CHWs on homed-based care (HBC) of PLWHIV ,Conduct program management and M&amp;amp;E capacity builiding meetings for diocesan coordinators,Train HIV+ women on how to plan and manage a kitchen garden,Facilitate VCT mobile clinics with school STOP AIDS clubs ,Advocate for improved PLWHIV rights and care ,Train PLWHIV and OVC head of households on kitchen gardens,Support orphans and vulnerable children (OVCs) with school materials and fees ,Teach girls in school how to make and/or properly use sanitary pads ,Sensitize local leaders (i.e. religious, community, government) about Ebola prevention</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anglican Church of Burundi</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="3433F5E1-853F-490E-896E-717145EC91CA" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-BI-15-13930" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-30" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BI" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="8" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-30"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-05-01"></period-end>
     <target value="43394"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
