<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/13911" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-LR-14-13911</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Engaging Faith-Based Organizations to Prevent Violence Against Women &amp; Girls and Increase Survivors&apos; Access to Services</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Compile, assess, adapt available faith-based tools for prevention and response to VAW/G, Develop or secure additional materials needed, incorporting specific messages drawing on religious texts.,Implement SBC C process and adapt messages and materials to local contexts, produce and distribute materials and tools.,Train clergy and key staff in Ending VAW/G toolkit, curriculum and how to use SBC C including participatory tools for each specific type of interaction- e.g. sermons, retreats/workshops, marriage preparation, marriage counseling, revivals.,Clergy promote participation at county and national level in the &quot;We Will Speak Out&quot; platform and organize annual awareness/education events on ending VAW/G, culminating in &#x201C;Speak Out Day&quot; every November.,Clergy share project lessons and promote replication of project activities in other counties through engaging other Chris&#x10000B;an and Muslim clergy at bi-annual meetings of the National Interfaith Council; using the project&#x2019;s Faith-Based Toolkit and the We Will Speak Out Platform.,Clergy and program staff participate in Ministry of Gender&apos;s monthly county-level and GBV Task Force meetings with key stakeholders, to maintain up-to-date information about available services and to advocate for services that are still needed in project areas.,Program staff together with County and National level Task Forces develop and/or disseminate simple referral network reference guides in local language throughout project districts (i.e. emergency hotline, phone numbers and locations of referral health centers, etc.),Clergy, lay leaders, and traditional leaders are trained in making referrals and the services available,Trained Clergy, lay leaders and traditional leaders make referrals for women and girl survivors,Clergy are trained in psychosocial counseling, including addressing violence-related stigma, provide counseling and encourage overcoming stigma to access appropriate services,Faith networks trained and provide accompaniment and other support when needed for women and girls to safely access services.,Set up a hotline to provide referrals to survivors in project areas and train community volunteers to staff it.,Train group leaders of faith based social organizations as trainers in Ending VAW/G curriculum and SBC C strategies and tools, including the FAMA learning-ac&#x10000B;on dialogue approach and how to develop and use creative SBCC activities including drama and video.,Youth faith groups and school health clubs develop creative SBCC vehicles (drama, video, radio) and organize youth awareness events in communities.,Facilitate dialogue forums with traditional leaders through County GBV Task Forces.,Train traditional leaders to use SBCc communication at regular community events to prevent VAW/G and improve response to survivors,Traditional leaders use community-wide events in target districts to share key VAW/G messages on zero-tolerance for violence and support for survivors.,Implement Ending VAW/G workshops with local savings groups and farming groups and facilitate members&apos; identifica&#x10000B;on of ways to engage in prevention and response.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The root causes of violence against women and girls are embedded in family and community dynamics. In post-conflict countries like Liberia the challenges of tackling and changing attitudes, behaviors and cultural norms are exacerbated by the previous experiences of widespread violence. While government efforts are understandably focused on providing services to and justice for survivors; it is often civil society organizations, particularly faith-based ones that tackle attitudes and behaviors that can contribute to violence. Faith institutions, clergy and lay leaders, are uniquely positioned to promote attitudes and behaviors that prevent violence and create an enabling environment for survivors. Clergy engage with couples, families, youth, men and women leaders in a variety of ways during their lives and guide knowledge, attitude and behavior change quite closely. Through sermons, religious teachings, marriage preparation, marriage counseling, family counseling, retreats, and revivals, clergy will influence the cultural and behavioral norms prevalent in a community. Lay leaders will also be trained as agents of change and then facilitate learning-action dialogues with members. Training and equipping youth leaders and engaging particularly male teens is a critical key to the project&apos;s success &#x2013; as engaging adolescents is a prime period for shaping attitudes about gender roles, interpersonal conflict resolution and other drivers for prevention of VAW/G. The Christian and Muslim youth movements in Liberia are strong and active and will serve as a vital asset in the project. Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development and our long-term Liberian partner, the Episcopal Church of Liberia Relief and Development have a proven track record in social behavior change communication and programs that address malaria prevention and control, agricultural development and rehabilitation, and education. The church will link these experiences and networks to more traditional faith based counseling and teaching formats and knowledge of other faith based institutions to address the root behavior and cultural norms underlying VAW/G and impunity for perpetrators. Faith-based organizations will engage all at the local level to map and network with available services for violence survivors and serve as referral sources to connect them. They will also organize assistance to help survivors overcome obstacles to receiving needed services. In this way, they expect to mitigate the challenges of providing integrated services particularly in rural areas where disperse populations, poor transportation, and lack of coordinated information is the norm. ERD and ECL-RD&#x2019;s close collaboration with the government and other key stakeholders on GBV will also increase the project&#x2019;s reach and effectiveness. In areas where there are inadequate services, and as a member of the Ministry of Gender and Development&#x2019;s GBV Task Force, ECL-RD will advocate for additional government and other stakeholder support to fill gaps in needed services across the continuum. The project has four key areas of intervention: 1. Developing capacities of community groups and leaders &#x2013; the project engages leaders and members of faith groups, each church and mosque has a men&#x2019;s group, a women&#x2019;s group, a youth group, and some also have a girls&#x2019; faith group. 2. Engaging new partners &#x2013; men and boys through faith groups, and traditional leaders. 3. Changing individual knowledge and attitudes &#x2013; the starting point is clergy, lay leaders, faith group members, congregants, and traditional leaders. The positive influence will also target cultural norms and behaviors related to prevention of violence and support to survivors. 4. Enhancing multi sectorial referral systems &#x2013; the local faith-based organizations and project staff will disseminate information about available services and provide referrals at the community level, connecting to district, county, and national levels. The project will implement evidenced-based strategies for social &amp;amp; behavior change. An adaptation of the BEHAVE Framework (from the Academy of Educational Development) includes barrier analysis so that specific drivers and motivations can be targeted in the messaging developed. Clergy and lay leaders will be trained in the Facts, Association, Meaning and Action Learning-Dialogue approach (FAMA), which they will then facilitate with their group members.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women,Clergy/Lay Leaders,Men</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Liberia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="AE1CCA9A-F76F-4CE3-8A9A-4B64AF57B1A5" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-LR-14-13911" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-05-01"></period-end>
     <target value="16886"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
