<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/13924" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-IN-14-13924</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yavatmal 2015 Comprehensive Food Security Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farmers,Individuals</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the third year of this program we will continue to address the challenges faced by farmers, and particularly women, the landless, sharecroppers and other vulnerable people in the Yavatmal area of Maraharastra, in India. In 2015, we will work with the original 500 farmers, and also expand the approach to add an additional approximately 3,000 new farmers in surrounding communities. CASA will continue to work with this full group through at least 2017 in order to achieve sustainable change at a significant scale. Many of these farmers are faced with debt burdens, due to the high rates charged by local lenders, and the need to use sufficient amounts of fertilizers and pesticides on the hybrid cotton seeds they buy. The farmers are also primarily engaged in cash-crop farming, and are therefore susceptible to local and international market price swings. Many do not have diversified sources of income, or food grown for household consumption that they can fall back on. In addition, some of the practices promoted by the government in past years, such as the promotion of cash crops for export and subsidy support for industries other than agriculture are harming the environment through excessive use of irrigation and fertilizers, and efforts need to be taken to reverse this trend. The program will work to improve land management over the regional watershed, introduce low-cost sustainable agricultural practices, build capacity of households in financing and marketing of agricultural and non-agricultural products, and to increase financial literacy and savings. In addition, they will assist farmers in advocating the government for the services that they are entitled to, such as support for families who have experienced a death, or services for those living below the national poverty line. CASA has a strong history of working on similar programming and hopes to bring their skills and experience to this region of India.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support farmer participants with indigenous seed for mixed cropping on up to 2 acres each. ,Planning 9 such activities will be undertaken by involving village, youth, farmers, women and panchayat members for identifying and planning natural resource management activities. 9 documents on watershed planning for 9 villages will be available.,Begin construction of stone bunds, nala bunds, farm bunds, check dams, rain water harvesting structures, and common wells according to the formulated community watershed management plans. Plans to be completed around April 2015.,Construct compost pits and vermi-compost production units in all 12 villages. ,Form Self-Help Groups for farmers to support themselves and each other through savings and credit, in 9 new villages.,Programs will be undertaken in 6 villages by involving village youth, farmers, women, and panchayati members. 6 documents on community planning of the 6 villages will be available.,Form farmers groups for farmers to support and share information with each other, in 9 villages.,Conduct training programs on gender with 100 men and women to understand the importance of gender equality for development, in up to 4 villages.,Conduct trainings on the local governance system, with up to 180 participants each, in 9 villages. Assist community members to understand how the panchayat functions, their roles and responsibilities, and the benefits they can receive if they can work effectively. ,Support participants in the marketing of their agro-based products, in 12 villages with up to 10 activities.,Conduct programs in up to 6 villages, with 120 participants each, on crop insurance and risk cover options. Provide subsidized crop insurance for up to 100 most vulnerable participants.,Conduct training on disaster risk reduction and climate change to bring awareness on the changing climate scenario and its impact on the environment and the action/adaptation that needs to be taken. 1 program for participants from all villages.,Support planting of up to 6000 fruit tree saplings for environmental regeneration and income generation. Trees will be planted and taken care of by individual families. ,Provide psycho-social support to families which have experience a suicide, with up to 30 families. Follow up with families to enable them to access government relief options. ,5 training programs on watershed activities will be conducted with 100 participants. They will learn about how to conserve water and harvest water.,3 progs will be conducted for 60 participants to build their skills in cultivation of indigenous and organic seed cultivation.,At least 2 trainings conducted and 50 participants each taught how to take up dry land farming and crop diversification.,3 trainings on government schemes with around 90 men and women to train them on various schemes related to agriculture and other general schemes applicable to the poor communities.,2 trainings on preparing organic pesticide and manure would be conducted for around 50 participants.,1 entrepreneurship program conducted for 40 youth participants to run collective income generation programs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Church&apos;s Auxiliary for Social Action (CASA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="13370939-4D13-4AE3-8573-6C4F3E9E06A5" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-IN-14-13924" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_1264418">
   <location-id code="1264418" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maharashtra</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maharashtra, India (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="1264418" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.5 76.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environment</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter and Housing</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-05-01"></period-end>
     <target value="8951"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
