<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/13893" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-GH-14-13893</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADDRO Food Security and Livelihoods Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Provide credit to interested entrepreneurs (women, men, youth, PLWHA, PWDs) (60 new, plus current),2. Train entrepreneurs in credit and business management (60 new, plus current),3. Assist in access to market and weather information for farmers, food processors and entrepreneurs,7. Provide Capacity Building for ADDRO staff ,1. Demonstrate improved farming practices including the construction of contour bunds, crop rotation, integrated pest management, crop spacing and compost production using participatory workshops, demonstration plots and training sessions. (with up to 250 new farmers),2. Support targeted farmers with improved seed varieties (maize, soybeans and possibly millet) and chemical fertilizer on a credit basis (up to 250 new and 690 continuing),3. Provide training on correct use of agro-chemicals (250 farmers),4. Assist targeted farmers with the management of sheep and goats by providing improved breeding stock, training on animal health and management and facilitating access to needed inputs. (120 farmers, 2 animals each, plus up to 240 animals to be distributed from offspring of 2013 recipients),5. Support six women to establish independent pig farms as income generation projects.,6. Train Community Extension Volunteers to support technology transfer in their communities and provide incentives. (20 volunteers),7. Engage chiefs, community leaders and religious leaders in dialogue that will facilitate women&#x2019;s rights and access to land (25 meetings),9. Support mid-term evaluation activities to gather information on the outcomes of the Food Security and Livelihoods program from 2013 - 2015.,1. Continue to monitor participants to test feasibility of credit and support package.,3. Support end-of-grant evaluation and report (deadline June 2015),2. Provide any needed refresher training on donkey management, business management, and agricultural production techniques.,1. Support farmers in the processing of groundnuts, soya, shea and rice through training and monitoring (90 women),2. Provide training on harvesting, handling and disinfecting of targeted crops. (250 new farmers),2. Support payment for labor for ADDRO&apos;s mango plantation, working towards the plantation&apos;s financial self-sustainability in 2016, and monitor mango seedlings supplied to individual farmers.,1. Conduct sensitization on land preservation and bushfire prevention (250 new farmers)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Northern Ghana, most of the population are small landowners relying on subsistence farming. While the country has made great progress over the last decade, in the north poverty, food insecurity and malnutrition rates remain high. ADDRO uses an integrated approach to tackle issues of poverty and hunger, improve health and combat gender and disability discrimination. ADDRO continues to build on its long experience working on food security in the region. This year they will implement the third year of a five-year comprehensive program aimed at increasing productivity, reducing postharvest losses, conserving natural resources, and improving incomes. Activities include improving agricultural input supply with the latest seed varieties and appropriate fertilizers, assisting farmers with new crop techniques through demonstration and training, training in vegetable and fruit-tree production, and small animal rearing, as well as food processing activities like peanut and shea butter production. ADDRO is also working to improve women&apos;s ability to till land, reduce their labor and increase independence through the provision of an innovative technical and financial package for women to own a donkey, plough and cart. The program also includes a micro-credit facility, managed by ADDRO, which allows farmers and other entrepreneurs in the communities to access credit for their operations. They also continue their long-standing work in disability rehabilitation, assisting the blind, mentally or physically handicapped through their integration in their broader program support.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individuals,Farmers,Women</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anglican Diocesan Development and Relief Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="11EDA33E-9721-40C9-8B1C-1E87B79BABF8" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-GH-14-13893" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_2294291">
   <location-id code="2294291" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upper East</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upper East, Ghana (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="2294291" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.75 -0.75</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="33.33333333333333" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environment</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-end>
     <target value="5460"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
