<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/13932" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-CD-15-13932</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Aru SGBV Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.3 Support clergy, lay leaders and actors with the dissemination of teaching tools (legal rights documents, policy documents, protection documents, etc.).,2.4 Accompany an estimated 100 survivors of SGBV in the judicial process of police reporting, court hearings, and advocacy services. ,2.2 Identify and reinforce local actors implicated in SGBV prevention and response, and promote the formation of a referral network of service providers (i.e., counseling, medical care, shelter, legal help, law enforcement, livelihood support, and pastoral care).,2.1 Reinforce actions of 139 clergy and lay leaders in offering trauma counseling sessions for women affected by SGBV.,3.1 Identify and train 12 new actors (health care workers) at four Service Medical structures (Adranga, Ekanga, Kumuru and Kpandoma) in medical and psychological care for survivors of SGBV.,3.2 Support the provision of health and psychological services to survivors of SGBV through the equipping of the four health structures with 48 testing and 48 treatment kits.,3.3 Organize 4 exchange visits and refresher trainings for personnel at various Service Medical structures.,4.1 Participate in regional and multi-sectoral working groups aimed at SGBV prevention and response to develop at least 11 new network partnerships.,4.2 Organize 2 exchange workshops for at least 22 local actors and organizations engaged in SGBV prevention and response.,4.3 Cultivate a Network for information exchange and professional development of at least 22 local actors/organizations engaged in SGBV prevention and response.,1.5 Conduct mass population education via the creation and transmission of 2 SMS mobile phone messages, 100 t-shirts and other banners and signs.,1.6 Organize 8 exchange visits and refresher trainings between an estimated 310 clergy, lay leaders and community advocates.,1.1 Identify and train at least 139 clergy and lay leaders of the church in the different aspects of SGBV, as well as actions for prevention and response (i.e., health and psychosocial healing).,1.4 Create 10 &quot;flash&quot; messages for transmission on four local radio stations.,1.2 Identify and train at least 85 community leaders, school teachers, health workers, and community group representatives) in the different aspects of SGBV, as well as actions for prevention and response. ,1.3 Create and record radio spots (30-minutes each) on the different aspects of SGBV for 192 sequential transmissions on four local radio stations (RTK-Aru, RTK-Rethy, Radio Ryno de Faradje, and Radio Savane Energie).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clergy/Lay Leaders,Women,Community Volunteer,Staff</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Violence against women and girls, in all of its forms (i.e. sexual, physical, emotional and economic abuse), is a global epidemic that destroys not only individual lives, but impedes the well being and growth of communities. As part of its integrated approach to fighting poverty and disease through empowerment, Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development prioritizes supporting grassroots efforts to prevent and respond to sexual and gender based violence (SGBV). By using its social, spiritual, human and physical capital, the Church has the power and obligation to act as agents of change and champions of peace and equality. As such, Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development in-conjunction with the Provincial Departments of Development and Social Transformation and Service Medical of the Anglican Church of Congo (PEAC) are supporting a one-year pilot SGBV program with the Diocese of Aru. The overall goal of this pilot project is to increase church and community participation in SGBV prevention and response in the Diocese of Aru, and to establish a model SGBV prevention and response program approach that can be replicated in other PEAC dioceses in future years.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Aru</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Province of the Anglican Church of Congo</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="59E3FD54-EAA9-41C2-8358-A779805FE5B9" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-CD-15-13932" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-02-28" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="8" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-02-28"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-05-01"></period-end>
     <target value="6467988"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
