<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/19021" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-VU-15-19021</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building Vanuatu Rural Training Centers Sustainability</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Out of school youth, Individuals, Staff</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of new courses in literacy and agroforestry, Conduct awareness programmes in 5 communities, Develop a new course to target female students, Establish minimum trainer requirements, Sponsor staff for government-organized refresher courses, Develop a business plan, Provide quality vocational education in electronics, carpentry and mechanics to 30 students (3 females &amp;amp; 27 males), Establish minimum training requirements, Sponsor staff for government-organized refresher course, Improve financial sustainability by developing sawmill business, Provide quality vocational education in hospitality, automotive and building construction to 80 students (40 females and 40 males), Establish minimum training requirements, Develop a short community course in small engine maintenance, Develop a business plan to build on the vegetable production, Provide quality vocational education in electronics, carpentry, hospitality and agriculture to 38 students (18 females &amp;amp; 20 males), Develop a survey to gauge needs for female students in order to develop or expand existing courses, Improve financial self-sustainability by enhancing carpentry workshop and agro-forestry business, Provide quality vocational education in mechanics, carpentry, hospitality and agriculture to 72 students (32 females &amp;amp; 40 males).,Complete skills assessments for each individual staff, Provide Staff refresher course, Implement recognized standards and Quality Management System, Develop and Implement annual staff appraisals, Develop the bakery as an income generating venture, Develop curriculum to meet required National Standards, Provide quality vocational education in electronics, carpentry, mechanics, plumbing, literacy, hospitality and agriculture to 145 students (45 females &amp;amp; 100 males)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Church of Melanesia operates eleven Rural Training Centers (RTC), five in Vanuatu and six in the Solomon Islands. The RTCs were established against the backdrop of many school dropouts from the primary &amp;amp; secondary education systems in Solomon Islands and Vanuatu. These school dropouts do not have the necessary education or self-esteem to be functioning members in society. The RTCs provide an avenue for some of the school dropouts to be empowered with useful knowledge, values and skills. The RTCs receive some limited financial assistance from the Governments of Solomon Island and Vanuatu. The aim of ACOM&#x2019;s Rural Training Centers is to empower men and women with appropriate life skills that would enhance their own well-being and that of their respective communities. In 2009, ACOM with Episcopal Relief &amp;amp; Development&#x2019;s support conduced a comprehensive review and study of all ACOM RTCs. This 2016 plan is based on the guiding principles that emerged from the 2009 study as documented in the Master ACOM Rural Training Center Policy document that are: 1) Increase access and gender equity in enrollment, 2) Create better quality standards in education and training, 3) Improve infrastructures, 4) Strengthen teacher training and recruitment, 5) Introduce new and relevant curriculum including short-courses, 6) Equip centers with tools and inventory controls, and 7) develop business plans to work toward sustainability. Building on the 2015 results of serving 387 students and 32 staff amongst the five rural training centers, the Anglican Church of Melanesia-Vanuatu will, in 2016, seek to attain each RTC&apos;s strategic priorities. These priorities range from enhancing the quality of teachers (with activities related to skills assessment, teacher appraisals and refresher courses), developing curriculum (with activities related to meeting national standards, introducing community-level short-courses, and designing courses for female students) and the sustainability of the center (with activities related to developing business plans and expanding income-generating ventures). 2016 will also prioritize the need for ACOM-Vanuatu to participate and comply with the Ministry of Education&#x2019;s Transitional Plan to move the all national Rural Training Centers into the oversight of the Ministry of Education under the Tertiary Sector. Previously, the Rural Training Centers were an independent department, and not recognized by the Ministry as under its purview.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anglican Church of Melanesia (ACoM)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="A87534BC-4CBA-440B-804C-5483ABA91E33" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-VU-15-19021" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SB" percentage="50"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="VU" percentage="50"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="5" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15105"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
