<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-1067406-DFID-GOAL-DEERF-2016</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-1067406" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Doctors of the World UK</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening Isolation Capacity and Potential Epidemic Preparedness</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) To ensure Isolation area in Moyamba Hospital is fully functional in case there is a new EVD case in the District and no cross-contamination occurs in the Hospital. 2) To ensure that permanent isolation units are established in the district and EVD cases are quarantined and treated according to national protocols 3) The DHMT will be fully operative in case of a confirmed EVD cases. (Reinforce referral system and improve interaction between actors, protocol) MdM/DOTW will Contribute to set up an effective and efficient epidemiological preparedness and response management system in Moyamba district 4) &#x2013; To ensure that CHC Staff are fully train in the management of a Isolation Unit and proper Triage of patients at the 4 CHC&#x2019;s (Moyamba Junction (Fakunya) , Gbangbatoke (lower banta), Shenge (Kargboro) &amp;Taiama (Kori). These 4 CHC have been selected as they were the ones who have received the most of the EVD positive cases in the Dsitrict. This action was especially requested by DMO as that was not covered by any other partner..Guarantee as well material needed for management of Isolation Unit</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moyamba district population: total 260.910- 138.544 female/ 122.366 male</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End date of activities</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Start date of activities</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Doctors of the World UK</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Programmes Department</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gareth Walker</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Programmes Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>02035357721</telephone>
   <email>gwalker@doctorsoftheworld.org.uk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">29th Floor One Canada Square, London E14 5AA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sierra Leone</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="SL-S" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southern Province</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moyamba district in Southern Province</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1) Introduce clear Flow charts / panels and plan of action of the entire system within the isolation. 1.2) Do an assessment and identification of plan of action if one positive case comes from the exiting wards in the hospital. Later, communicate it and inform the workers. 1.3) Through Simulation activities test and teach the functioning of the isolation flow. 1.4) To ensure that all the CHC&#x2019;s (BEMONCS centres) and PHUs in Lower Banta have fences to fully comply with IPC Guidelines. 2.1) Training for nurses and doctors in Case definition, triage, early identification of suspected cases, isolation and prompt referral of patients when necessary- according to national protocol 2.2) On job (mentoring) of health staff on IPC and minimum hygiene medical standards 3.1) Give technical support to the DHMT, Training of the different specialist needed within the group. 3.2) Support the District set up a proper plan, according with the National guidelines, to manage suspect cases of EVD. 3.3). Training and spread the information of the District Plan for EVD. 3.4) Support the DHMT to establish the DOEC (District emergency Operative Committee) 3.5) provide technical support to the DEOC, Training of the different specialist needed within the group. 3.6) Support the DHMT to establish the PHEMC (District Public Health Emergency Management Committee) (Reinforce referral system and improve interaction between actors, protocol) 3.7) Provide logistic support to establish and run activities supporting the PHEMC 3.8) Training of the staff and simulated exercises on EOC management 3.9) Support the DHMT to establish the RRT Rapid Response Team and active participation 4.1. ) Training in Case definition for CHCs Staff (triage), isolation and prompt referral of patients when necessary- according to national protocol. 4.2) On job (mentoring) monitoring of health staff checking and briefing on IPC and minimum hygiene medical standards. 4.3) Supply a minimum stock of IPC material to run Isolation Units accordingly in case of gaps</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="SL.SO.MO" level="2" vocabulary="A3"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.0629 -12.44401</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMD"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="12191" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-01">112560</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-04">112560</value>
   <provider-org ref="CHY6271" type="FUND MANAGER">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="DFID-GOAL-DEERF-2016" ref="GB-CHC-1067406" type="INGO">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Doctors of the World Uk</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="4"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
