<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5213003202-GGG-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Action and Team of Experts 2015 - 2020</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UN Action och Team of Experts 2015 - 2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to UN Action Against Sexual Violence in Conflict, which       unites efforts across the UN system with the goal of ending violence  during and in the aftermath of armed conflict.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UN Action against Sexual Violence in Conflict och Team of Experts Rule of Law har genom UN Action Multi Partner Trust Fund (MPTF) inkommit till Sida med en samlad projektans&#xF6;kan. P.g.a olika tidsintervaller i deras respektive planeringscykler &#xE4;r UN Action:s programdokument f&#xF6;r perioden 2015-17 och Team of Experts programdokument f&#xF6;r perioden 2015-19. 

UN Action och Team of Expert har olika men kompletterande mandat. UN Action against Sexual Violence in Conflict &#xE4;r unikt p&#xE5; s&#xE5; s&#xE4;tt att det samlar tretton FN-organisationer till gemensamma anstr&#xE4;ngningar i syfte att f&#xF6;rebygga och p&#xE5; ett ansvarsfullt s&#xE4;tt lindra effekterna av konflikt relaterat sexuellt v&#xE5;ld. Team of Experts m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att bidra med kapacitetsuppbyggnad f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka nationella lagar och deras implementering f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rebygga konfliktrelaterat sexuellt v&#xE5;ld och bidra till att minska den r&#xE5;dande straffriheten f&#xF6;r denna typ av brott. B&#xE5;de UN Action och Team of Experts &#xE4;r tillsammans med FN:s generalsekreterarens  s&#xE4;rskilda representant i fr&#xE5;gan, nyckelakt&#xF6;rer i anstr&#xE4;ngningar att motverka konfliktrelaterat sexuellt v&#xE5;ld som ett hot mot fred och s&#xE4;kerhet, inom ramen f&#xF6;r FN-systemet.

F&#xF6;r tre&#xE5;rsperioden &#xE4;r UN Actions och Team of Experts totala budget ca. 130 MSEK (16 MUSD) . Sida&apos;s bidrag g&#xE5;r till UN Action Multi-Partner Trust Fund som administreras av UNDP. Sidas totala bidrag f&#xF6;r tre&#xE5;rsperioden &#xE4;r 45 MSEK. H&#xE4;lften av Sidas medel g&#xE5;r till UN Action och h&#xE4;lften av Sidas medel g&#xE5;r till Team of Experts genom ett f&#xF6;nster inom fonden. Sida &#xE4;r en viktig givare. Under 2015 utgj&#xF6;r Sidas st&#xF6;d till UN Action MPTF ca. 37 % av den totala budgeten.  

Sida har samarbetat med UN Action sedan 2009 och med Team of Experts sedan 2011. B&#xE5;de UN Action och Team of Experts spelar en central roll vad g&#xE4;ller att samordna FN att arbeta mer strategiskt kring fr&#xE5;gan om konflikt-relaterat sexuellt v&#xE5;ld, som ocks&#xE5; &#xE4;r en prioriterad fr&#xE5;ga f&#xF6;r Sverige och svenskt utrikespolitik. Sida har tillsammans med andra givare och med st&#xF6;d i den externa utv&#xE4;rderingen som gjordes av UN Action 2012/13 drivit ett &#xF6;kat fokus p&#xE5; landniv&#xE5; och minskat fokus p&#xE5; globala kampanjer. Ingen extern utv&#xE4;rdering har hittills gjorts av Team of Experts. 

UN Actions och Team of Experts finansiella situation samt behovet av f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad resultatredovising &#xE4;r fortsatt centrala fr&#xE5;gor som behandlas i beredningen men som kr&#xE4;ver fortsatt kontinuerlig uppf&#xF6;ljning av Sida.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Action against sexual violence in conflicts: Improved coordination and accountability across the UN-system, amplified advocacy and support to country efforts to prevent conflict-related sexual violence and respond more effectively to the needs of the survivors. UN Team of Experts on rule of law/Sexual violence in conflicts: Countries facing conflict-related sexual violence are better able to address impunity related to this crime through improved legal, regulatory and policy-frameworks; strengthened institutions and enhanced capacities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.1 - Avsev&#xE4;rt minska alla former av v&#xE5;ld och d&#xF6;dligt v&#xE5;ld &#xF6;verallt.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.1 - Significantly reduce all forms of violence and related death rates everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.C" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.c - Adopt and strengthen sound policies and enforceable legislation for the promotion of gender equality and the empowerment of all women and girls at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.c - Anta och st&#xE4;rka v&#xE4;lgrundad politik och genomf&#xF6;rbar lagstiftning f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och &#xF6;ka alla kvinnors och flickors egenmakt p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1035625.5178127589</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1035625.5178127589</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-01">1067704.317084</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-28">1035625.5178127589</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Some of the more important long-term achievements of the UN Action trust fund is found in the increased visibility of conflict related sexual violence in terms of advocacy for normative/policy frame works. This contributed for example to the formation of a Special Representative, the Team of Experts and Women Protection Advisers and also for some basic operationalization of these functions.
The early days actions of the network, including the world wide Stop Rape Now campaign, have increased international and national awareness and recognition that CRSV is an international peace and security, human rights and development issue, as well as part of ware fare. The &quot;get cross&quot; symbol (crossed arm gesture) has been used by groups and individuals in 128 countries. This awareness has been important when advancing the agenda and creating an institutional architecture for the issues within UN (Women Protection Advisers, SRSG-SVC function, ToE etc). The idea with UN Action has been to create collaboration and synergies on CRSV between existing work streams of several different mandates across the UN system (humanitarian, human rights, development, political and peacekeeping).
The knowledge building and analytical framing tools which were produced by UN Action spearheaded key Security Council instruments, like the MARA system (Monitoring, Analysis and Reporting Arrangements), but also guided policy making, operations and programmatic intervention (for example standardized survey tools to collect data on CRSV, guidance note on implementations of SCR 1960 and Gender Based Violence Management and Information System).
The MPTF has funded projects in 16 countries - 18 in Africa, 2 in Europe and Central Asia, 9 in the Middle East and 3 in Asian and the Pacific, besides that 13 project were global and 6 regional or multi-country - with the intention of being catalytic, collaborative and coordinating between various UN mandates. A short summary of the most prominent results are presented in the report as follow: &quot;The network developed projects aimed to support children born of CRSV, (for example in Iraq), economic empowerment of refugees and displaced persons at risk of trafficking, (as in Myanmar), and services for LGBTI refugees (Lebanon).&quot; Other results at country level happened as one project in the beginning of the fund&apos;s existence, like in Angola, Chad, Liberia and Libya or with multiple projects over time, like in CAR, Cote d&#xCD;vore, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Iraq and DRC. Other are more recent, like CRSV support service and mitigation for refugees in Cox&#xB4;s Bazaar in Bangladesh.
Hurdles like stigma of CRSV has also been part of the interventions of the fund. &quot;In several settings, the critical needs of CRSV survivors contrasted with an overall reluctance to deal with CRSV or the legacy of crimes. Catalytic funding by UN Action helped overcome this barrier in Bosnia and Herzegovina where a series of projects spotlighted challenges related to CRSV and opportunities to meet the needs of survivors, for example access to justice, services, economic empowerment and reparations. In South Sudan, and in a number of other settings, essential life-saving support services were provided through integrated &#x201C;one-stop&#x201D; centres offering legal, medical and psychosocial support to survivors of CRSV, as well referrals to other essential services.&quot;
The deployment of the SC mandated Women Protection Advisers (WPAs) into Peacekeeping operations over the years, like in CAR, DRC, Cote d&#xB4;Ivoire and Iraq, have been spearheaded by UN Action interventions which have led to WPAs increasingly being included in regular budgets, thus being somewhat catalytic. In some other countries (Mali, Cote d&#xCD;vore and CAR) governments have shown commitment and ownership by adoption action plans to address gender based violence, including CRSV. In the example of CAR, the UN Action supported Guidance for Mediators on addressing CRSV from 2012 was put into action and the following peace agreement contained strong language on CRSV and is assessed the most comprehensive in this regard to date.
In some countries over the past few years (South Sudan, Iraq and Myanmar) UN Action has developed projects to enable operationalisation of commitments made in Joint Communiqu&#xE9;s thus being closer connected to high level political commitments.
The UN entities which have participated in projects financed UN Action fundning are UNFPA (21); UNICEF (14); UN Women (13); UNDP (12); DPO (9); UNHCR (8); IOM, OCHA, WHO and OSRSG-SVC (6); OHCHR (5); UNODC (3); and UNAIDS (1).
Another set of achievements entails the fund&#xB4;s ability to fill budget gaps for knowledge products and coordination of CRSV work. The fund is said to have reduced competition between agencies and thus contributed to more coherence and multi-sectoral projects. In some cases, the fund has contributed to better coordination and collaboration between UN entities and of leveraging of each agencies expertise and to work innovative.&#xA0;
The UN Team of Experts&#xA0;has managed to work consistently and effectively towards its stated goals. There is plenty of anecdotal evidence that suggests the 2015-2019 Joint Programme was indeed successful and the ToE has strong added value. Innovative approaches to sustaining investments through embedding experts and providing sustained support to justice processes over time are some of the success factors.&#xA0;
Since 2011 ToE has been working in 14 country contexts. In some countries there have been very instrumental results and in others the nature of interventions has been more of monitoring of the situation and to &quot;pave the way&quot; (advocacy, technical support, assessments missions etc) for future broader engagements. ToE also for example provide technical advise on various countries to the Special Criminal Court (SCC) to ensure inclusion of CRSV related crimes and take part of missions conducted by the SRSG SVC to push for gender justice considerations in peace processes and agreements.
After preparations in CAR since 2012, a breakthrough in 2015 was the establishment and operationalisation of the Joint Rapid Response and Prevention Unit for Sexual Violence against Women and Children (UMIRR), a specialized unit composed of police officers and gendarmes mandated to investigate sexual violence crimes. A total of 946 complaints was registered as of March 2019. ToE has since worked with UNMIRR to strengthen its technical capacity and made field visits outside the capital.
Cote D&#xB4;Ivoire was one of the first countries of engagement for ToE and focus has been on the process of prosecutions of CRSV perpetrators after post-election violence in 2010-11. ToE has worked throughout the years to capacitate, review legislation and facilitate experience sharing with neighbouring countries, national strategies on GBV, evidence gathering for CRSV, support presidential decrees to combat CRSV, provided national experts to increase CRSV prevention in the national armed forces which have reduced cases considerably.
In DRC, the ToE has also been working since inception up until today. The point of departure has been the areas identified in the Joint Communiques between the government and the UN - from 2013 and 2019. ToE experts has been deployed in various shapes over the years to work directly with justice actors and to for example develop action plans on CRSV and create a new special police unit to respond to sexual violence in Rutshuru, Goma and Bukavu and special prosecution support cells in all civil jurisdictions in Eastern DRC. Some of the measures have been to support military investigations in North and South Kivu, to work with military justice authorities in preparations and investigations of problematic CRSV cases, like mass rape (example Kavumu and Walikale cases). The Kavumu case recently led to lifetime imprisonment of a provincial parliamentarian and militia leader and ten other persons, found guilty of the rape of 40 girls between the age of 18 months and 10 years. Another high profile case is the Walikale case is still ongoing and involves UN-sanctioned militia leader and members of a dozen attacks against civilians in North Kivu and hundreds of acts of CRSV. Also, supported DRC in drafting reparations legislation.
Guinea is also one of the long-term commitments for ToE with a focus of assisting the government to hold trials for sexual violence committed at the Conacry Stadium in September 2009. Via deployments, technical assistance to the Panel of Judges who investigated the case (resulting in over 45o hearings, testimonies of 200 victims and witnesses and the indictment of 15 government officials, including a former president Camara). The support also included dialogue on the process between various parties and medical and psychosocial support from experts from the Panzi hospital in DRC (led by Dr Denis Mukwege) leading to a collaboration between Panzi and the government inGuinea. ToE has been part of the Steering Committee that organises the trials for which now a date has been announced.
Since 2013 the ToE has been working in Somalia with technical assessments and assistance, a national action plan for CRSV, improved legislation, work with the army to enhance investigations, supported legal aid service in five legal aid center in the country and helped to train police in sexual violence, including investigation tool kits. In South Sudan the TOE has been engaged since 2011 to develop nationally owned strategic frameworks which are now in place.
Other countries of more recent engagement is the engagement in Iraq - to support the governments of Iraq and the Kurdistan region in investigating and prosecuting CRSV - and in Sudan, Mali, Nigeria and Myanmar to conduct assessments, prepare work in line with joint communiques or advocating for accountability for CRSV.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52130032" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1120103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2017-01-01">
    <sida:title>Sustainable peace 2017-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>H&#xE5;llbar fred 2017-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
