<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5213003501-GGG-15250</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GICHD Mine Action 2015-2018</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">GICHD Mine Action 2015-2018</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GICHD:s &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att st&#xE4;rka efterlevnad och spridning av internationella konventioner ang&#xE5;ende min- och klustervapen; st&#xE4;rka nationella akt&#xF6;rer och processer f&#xF6;r minhantering samt integrering av minhantering i den bredare m&#xE4;nsklig s&#xE4;kerhetsagendan. GICHD arbetar &#xF6;vergripande med konventionerna p&#xE5; omr&#xE5;det, p&#xE5; inbjudan av enskilda l&#xE4;nder, samt i relation till civilsamh&#xE4;llesakt&#xF6;rer och myndigheter. GICHD rymmer sekretariatet f&#xF6;r International Mine Action Standards (IMAS) och hanterar IMAS p&#xE5; UN Mine Action Service&amp;apos;s v&#xE4;gnar.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Geneva International Center for Humanitarian Demining works to eliminate mines and other explosive remmants of war by research,      disseminating knowledge and capacity development with local, national and international actors in mine-affected countries.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">K&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d till Geneva International Centre for Humanitarian Demining (GICHD) f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;rande av strategiska planen 2015-2018. GICHD &#xE4;r en expertorganisation inriktad p&#xE5; minhantering och explosiva l&#xE4;mningar av krig. GICHD arbetar i relation till nationella och lokala myndigheter, civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer och internationella akt&#xF6;rer genom forskning, kunskapsspridning, utvecklande av standarder och kapacitetsst&#xF6;d. GICHD har d&#xE4;rtill en specifik roll och mandat att utg&#xF6;ra sekretariat f&#xF6;r och f&#xF6;lja upp IMAS - International Mine Action Standards.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="47123" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GICHD/Geneva International Centre for Humanitarian Demining/Centre International de Deminage Humanitaire</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Geneva International Centre for Humanitarian Demining</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15250" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Removal of land mines and explosive remnants of war</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">296584.5325234599</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">292175.5390638696</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">292500.2925002925</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">296584.5325234599</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">292175.5390638696</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">292500.2925002925</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">889753.59757</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">296584.5325234599</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-28">292175.5390638696</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-28">292500.2925002925</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the GICHD, mine action has seen significant progress over the last two decades since the Anti-personnel Mine Ban Treaty was agreed. In 1998, half of the countries in the world were contaminated by landmines and other explosives. Since then the number of new victims per year has been on a downward trend, 31 countries have declared themselves mine free and more than 53 million stockpiled mines have been destroyed. However, during the last four years this positive trend has been challenged and there has been a surge in the number of mine victims. This mostly related to the new conflicts in Syria, Yemen, Libya, Ukraine and elsewhere. Despite the negative overall global trend in mine action, the GICHD has achieved noteworthy results during the 2015-2018 period. During this period Algeria, Mauritania and Mozambique were declared free of mines. The GICHD, supported Mozambique during several years in various ways and the other two countries through the Arab regional cooperation programme. Hence, the GICHD supported these achievements to some extent. The GICHD has support national mine action strategies in the following 8 countries during 2015-2018: Bosnia and Herzegovina, Kosovo, South Sudan, Afghanistan, DRC, Zimbabwe, Sri Lanka and a donors strategy for the German Federal Foreign Office. The Zimbabwe national mine action strategy was the first national mine action strategy for the country and it has defined the mine action problem in a better way and facilitated work for the mine action operators which are now expanding operations, including with Sida funding through the Mines Advisory Group. (MAG).&#xA0; Information Management is another core area for the GICHD. The Information Management System for Mine Action (IMSMA) -a data collection, storage, validation and analysis tool - was adapted in 2017. The latest version of IMSMA, named IMSMA Core, fully benefits from advanced technologies, such as unmanned aerial imaging and three-dimensional mapping for spatial data analysis and data sharing.&#xA0;From 2015 to 2018, the GICHD assisted 32 mine action programmes in developing and implementing their capacity in information management. A capacity development framework was used in 8 of those countries to assess progress in data, processes, organisation and resources, using 37 indicators. The overall score has increased in 7 countries. The GICHD contributes to the development, review and promotion of the International Mine Action Standards (IMAS) within the mine action community, as a member of the IMAS review board and as the secretariat for the same board. In addition, the GICHD provides expert advice and training on the application of IMAS at country level. Between 2015 and 2018, 14 standards and technical notes were developed or revised to reflect the reality on the ground as much as possible. The GICHD contributed significantly to that work. Given the challenges posed by IEDs in recent conflicts, a heavy focus was out on revising standards to enhance existing guidance related to the survey and clearance of IEDs in a humanitarian context. Furthermore, a new IMAS on Environmental Management in Mine Action was adopted.&#xA0; The GICHD has supported several countries to develop and review their national standards (NMAS) in line with the IMAS. For example, Lebanon has adopted NMAS chapters for land release, information management and quality management. NMAS were established for the first time in Ukraine, following workshops and consultations regarding good practices. The improvement and implementation of the land release approach has made it possible to deploy costly clearance assets more effectively, resulting in considerable time and cost savings. In Sri Lanka for example, the civil war had left 64 km2 of suspected contaminated areas behind. The Sri Lanka Mine Action Centre was trained by GICHD experts on the implementation of non-technical surveys. In 2015 alone, 18.7 km2 of land previously considered potentially contaminated were cancelled &#x2013; this represents almost 90% of all suspected hazardous areas in 4 provinces. The experience and knowledge that the country obtained from the GICHD significantly contributed to implement this successful process, and Sri Lanka has now a much clearer picture of the level and location of mine and ERW contamination on its territory. This work together with an increased national ownership in Sri Lanka and increased efforts by operators makes Sri Lanka to be on track to be declared free of mines in the next few years.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="52130035" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
