<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13905A0101-GGG-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert core support 2022-2025</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">International Alert k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d 2022-2025</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert is an independent peacebuilding non-governmental organisation. It has a global mission to work with people in conflict-affected and -threatened areas to make a positive difference for peace; to improve the substance and implementation of international policies relevant to peacebuilding; and to strengthen the peacebuilding sector, with a key focus on gender, climate change and natural resuorce management linked to conflict, and economic development for peace. Its main methods of engagement include bringing people together through dialogue; capacity building through trainings, accompaniment (which involves guidance  to people, organisations and companies that operate in high-risk environments) and undertaking policy research and advocacy. With Headquarters in London, Alert is active and collaborates with around 160 organisations in 21 countries and territories.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">International Alert &#xE4;r en oberoende och icke-statlig organisation med globalt fredsbyggande uppdrag att arbeta med m&#xE4;nniskor i konfliktdrabbade omr&#xE5;den. Syftet med International Alerts arbete &#xE4;r att st&#xE4;rka f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar f&#xF6;r fredlig utveckling, st&#xE4;rka implementeringen av internationella policies som &#xE4;r relevanta f&#xF6;r fredsbyggande, och att st&#xE4;rka fredsbyggande sektorn, med ett tydligt fokus p&#xE5; j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet, klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar och naturresurshantering kopplat till konflikt och ekonomisk utveckling f&#xF6;r fred. Organisationens huvudsakliga arbetss&#xE4;tt &#xE4;r att f&#xF6;ra m&#xE4;nniskor samman via dialog, kapacitetsutveckling via utbildningar, medf&#xF6;ljande (vilket omfattar v&#xE4;gledning och r&#xE5;d till m&#xE4;nniskor, organisationer och f&#xF6;retag som verkar i h&#xF6;griskomr&#xE5;den) och att genomf&#xF6;ra policyforskning och p&#xE5;verkansarbete. Med huvudkontor i London bedriver organisationen verksamhet i 21 l&#xE4;nder och regioner v&#xE4;rlden &#xF6;ver, i samarbete med runt 160 organisationer.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objectives of the Core Activities shall support International Alert to deliver against its objectives as set out in their Strategic Plan (012939/19). The mission statements, as shown under Introduction and Agreement structure above, will inform informs the Strategic Plan 2019 - 2023 and the forthcoming strategy (2024  2028). The proposed support will continue to contribute to the five goals of Alert&apos;s strategic plan, namely:

1. Strengthen communities voices and their capacity to reduce violence, in particular by working with disadvantaged women and young people.
2. Harness the private sector to support inclusive peace.
3. Promote fairness, inclusion and justice in local and national governance systems, including security, to support peace and address the root causes of conflict, including structural inequalities
4. Support inclusive peace processes and wider peacebuilding initiatives 
5. Champion gender- and conflict-sensitivity in ways that contribute to peace, including in International Alerts own work.

The proposed grant includes an earmarked component to strengthen Alerts programming, knowledge base and policy work on climate, environment and conflict during 2022-2023. This workstream spans across all five objectives of the Strategic Plan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21038" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21038" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2026-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="10.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10.2 - By 2030, empower and promote the social, economic and political inclusion of all, irrespective of age, sex, disability, race, ethnicity, origin, religion or economic or other status.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">10.2 - Till 2030 m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra och verka f&#xF6;r att alla m&#xE4;nniskors, oavsett &#xE5;lder, k&#xF6;n, funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning, ras, etnicitet, ursprung, religion eller ekonomisk eller annan st&#xE4;llning, blir inkluderade i det sociala, ekonomiska och politiska livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.1 - Avsev&#xE4;rt minska alla former av v&#xE5;ld och d&#xF6;dligt v&#xE5;ld &#xF6;verallt.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.1 - Significantly reduce all forms of violence and related death rates everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">2565029.322948851</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">2565029.322948851</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2024-01-01">1982068.1131877485</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2025-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2025-01-01">1982068.1131877485</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">2565029.3229488516</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">2565029.322948851</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2024-01-01">1982068.1131877485</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2025-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2025-01-01">1982068.1131877485</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">9094194.872273</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-28">1282514.6614744256</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/fred/13905_007902-22AvtalmellanSidaochInternationalAlertgallandekarnstod,(13905)3091022_1_1.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Avtal mellan Sida och International Alert g&#xE4;llande k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d 2022-2025</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2019, International Alert reports that the organisation ran projects in 21 countries and territories, with training, research or one-off consultancies and business partnerships in a further 18. In total, Alert implemented 114 projects, 21 of which took place across multiple regions. Throughout the year, together with its partners, the organisation engaged and supported 276,301 people through dialogue, training, advocacy, accompaniment, research and outreach activities. Of these, 52% were women and 47% were men, with just under 1% of people identifying as other
or preferring not to reveal their gender identity.

International Alert records the ways in which their work effects change by tracking project data and using outcome harvesting techniques. These results reflect the changes that take place in individuals, institutions and societies following engagement  whether directly or indirectly. Alert reports the following (where the intervention achieved multiple changes  for example, changing a persons attitude and behaviour  Alert categorises it by the most relevant):
- Changes in knowledge and attitudes: 41% of results
- Changes in behaviour and processes: 41% of results
- Changes in conditions (e.g. policies, structures, etc.): 18% of results


In the 2019 reporting, International Alert illustrates its work with a number of results examples. For this year, Sida wishes to highlight how Alert has influenced policy in the area of global peace and security. Over 2019, Alert developed a strategic framework to guide the expansion of its policy influence, including setting out tangible steps for strengthening the capacity of the global team in this area. Two key cross-organisational themes were identified around which to leverage the influence over the coming two years: Gender Peace and Security (GPS); and making the case for peacebuilding. Alert used preparations for the 20th anniversary of UNSC Resolution 1325 on women, peace and security as a rallying point for the GPS agenda and set out a policy engagement plan underpinned by newly commissioned research on the impact of 1325. 

Throughout 2019 International Alert also continued to advocate that environment and climate change considerations to be factored into peacebuilding policies and practices. This included raising awareness of the rising conflict risks related to access and control over water resources and protection of water ecosystems globally, as well as specifically in Mali, through our membership in the Water, Peace and Security Partnership. Alert represented the partnership at the Paris Peace Forum, where the partnerships early warning tool on water-conflicts was presented.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13905" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1120103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2017-01-01">
    <sida:title>Sustainable peace 2017-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>H&#xE5;llbar fred 2017-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
