<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5204041201-GGG-74020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Huairou Comission 2012-2014</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Globalt Huairou Commission 2012 - 2014</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Investing in community innovation and leadership to catalyze local    implementation of the Hyogo Framework for Action.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d till Huariou Commission f&#xF6;r arbete med att st&#xE4;rka kapacitet,     innovation och ledarskap att implementera Hyogo Framework for Action  ramverket p&#xE5; lokal niv&#xE5;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Misc</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="740" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Prevention &amp; Preparedness</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multi-hazard response preparedness</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">738672.4578587363</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">767671.8049499477</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">728873.5987405065</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">738672.4578587363</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">767671.8049499477</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">728873.5987405065</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-08-01">2216017.373576</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-08-28">738672.4578587363</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-11-28">767671.8049499477</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-28">728873.5987405065</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2015Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: The Huairou Commission (HC) was granted SEK 15 000 000 from Sida to implement a three-year program between 2012-2015, called &#x201C;Investing in Community Innovation and Leadership to Catalyze Local Implementation of the Hyogo Framework for Action.&#x201D; The overall objectives of the project were:
1. To expand the Community Resilience Fund (CRF) to resource a network of community led, collaborative, pro-poor demonstrations that address local DRR priorities;
2. Building the Community Practitioners Platform (CPP) for Resilience to facilitate communities to drive the demand for redirecting development investments in response to community priorities;
3. Facilitating community practitioners to build global institutional support for community driven approaches to disaster risk reduction. 

The third and final implementation year continued to build upon the gains from the previous years and to position grassroots women as agents of change of climate resilient development by investing in a multi-country, grassroots women-led network of practitioners. The year was based in their developed &#x201C;Resilience Diamond&#x201D; which is a framework comprised of core elements anchored in the Resilience Campaign&#x2019;s member groups, focusing on Strengthening Grassroots Women&#x2019;s Organizing and Leadership; Promoting Resilient Development through Awareness and Locally-Led Initiatives; Building Constituencies and Networks and; Influencing and Changing Public Policy and Processes (local, national, regional and global). Furthermore, grassroots women&#x2019;s organizations moved from the solely focused approach of DRR towards a holistic and integrated community resilience approach, to institutionalize and mainstream successful practices within the communities as well as integrate these practices into poverty eradication programming through targeted advocacy within their local political contexts. 


Grassroots women&#x2019;s groups worked with the core strategies of the Huairou Commission Community Resilience Campaign, including the CRF and CPP as key mechanisms. In the third implementation year, there were a total of 14 women&#x2019;s organizations from countries across Asia, Africa and Latin America, leading the implementation of the program. Through the CRF, nine organizations through 91 communities and villages, focused on strengthening women&#x2019;s organising, leadership and promoting DRR and resilient development through awareness and locally-led initiatives; subsequently advanced grassroots women leaders&#x2019; skills and capacities. Over the past year, the groups focused on identifying risks, leading community plans development, leadership training, and scaling up local resilient practices. Focus was also on mentoring, training, and advising less experienced and newer grassroots groups on strategies for building community resilience. 

Asia (Bangladesh, India, Indonesia, Philippines and Vietnam)

Bangladesh. The Participatory Development Action Program (PDAP) focused its CRF efforts in the urban slums of Dhaka. 100 women were organized into five savings groups and received training and awareness on resilience building, leadership, risk mapping and advocacy. 

Indonesia. Leadership training was provided as well as resilience building to catalyse new public leadership roles for women. The trainings clustered around the areas of health and first aid, organising network building, documentation, advocacy training and enterprise training:
&#x2022; 60 women trained to enhance leadership roles;
&#x2022; 11 groups completed first aid training;
&#x2022; 35 women completed Organization Management Training;
&#x2022; 204 women completed a workshop on policy support in disaster;
&#x2022; 60 women completed the Village owned Enterprises Workshops.
Furthermore, Yakkum Emergency Unit (YEU) mainly focused on helping women diversity agricultural practices that improve food security and public health in regards to:
&#x2022; Rice Banks in three communities for storing surplus rice for emergencies; 
&#x2022; Groceries Program in two communities where groups organized to sell groceries locally at lower prices in areas affected by disaster;
&#x2022; Waste Bank/Management in five communities where women are paid to bring waste to a central location for recycling. 

Vietnam. 32 grassroots women set up a Women&#x2019;s Resilience Network (WRN) and were trained as trainers on climate change impacts, adaptive livelihoods and community-based responses to these issues. The WRN trainers conducted 12 village-based meetings with 360 women to share climate change adaptive case studies and four half-day talks on health for 200 women. 

Asian Regional Platform:

Post-Haiyan Response and Recovery Workshops, Philippines.
An advocacy workshop of grassroots groups from the three typhoon Haiyan affected regions was arranged by Lihok Filipina in partnership with Damanyan ng Maralitang Piipinong Api (DAMPA). It took place from May 14th to 17th to assess the post-Haiyan recovery process. A total of 264 women participated in the focus groups discussions on the response and recovery process after the typhoons. 

Bihar Workshop on Localizing the Sendai Framework for DRR
In July 2015, Swayam Shikshan Prayog (SSP) organized a meeting with a series of NGO partners, grassroots women and high level officials from the State Government of Bihar. The government of Bihar was developing a roadmap to implement the Sendai Framework and agreed to share this more widely and get input from other stakeholders including grassroots women. Women had the opportunity to share innovations such as: 
&#x2022; Experiences of working with local governments and mobilizing the community in accessing government schemes;
&#x2022; Initiatives in addressing water scarcity/drought;
&#x2022; Positive experiences with risk mapping;  
&#x2022; Experiences with land distribution and women&#x2019;s landless plight in Bihar;
&#x2022; How to access loans from local banks. 

Africa (Ghana, Uganda, Zambia and Zimbabwe)

Ghana. Grassroots Sisterhood Foundation (GSF) worked to increase grassroots women&#x2019;s understanding of resilience building at the national and regional level. GSF carried out two large workshops with the participations of 100 women and 12 groups, to identify and map the key stakeholders and set an action plan for the regional and national level. The outcome of this process made GSF able to federate its own local grassroots groups with the teams of volunteers trained by Ghana&#x2019;s National Disaster Management Organization (NADMO) to improve transparency and accountability of dispersed aid to communities affected by disaster.

Uganda. Kawempe Home Based Care Alliance (KHBCA) built the capacity of women as community members and leaders to ensure community resilience to disasters and environmental hazards through improved knowledge and understanding of risks and risk prevention. 75 community members were trained under the Training of Trainers methodology. After the trainings, the communities could improve 55 small drainages and five pit latrines that were causing health problems and risk in case of flooding. Furthermore:
&#x2022; Two new hand dug wells were established;
&#x2022; 100 new pit latrines built;
&#x2022; 200 dust bins for families provided;
&#x2022; Two organizations sort out garbage and recycling. 

Zambia. Two leadership trainings had 165 women and 15 youths participating. Regarding resilience practices, 45 community members undertook trainings in biogas and clean energy stoves. More than 25 women registered to purchase the stoves through credits which have reduced time burden of fetching firewood, and the ecological impact in the nearby forests. 

Zimbabwe. 33 Self-Help Groups (SHG), a total of 528 women, had ongoing weekly meetings where they received training in socio-economic activities such as weekly savings. In March 2015, Ntengwe held a three-day workshop on the Zimbabwe National Climate Change Response Strategy and Hyogo Framework of Action, where 48 grassroots women could present their work, discuss the state of the localization of the policies and give recommendations to the Ministry of Environment, which acted as co-facilitators with the Ntengwe Programs Coordinator. 

Africa Regional Platform.
The key emphasis was building and organizing infrastructure to make communities visible to larger actors and to be better informed about policy priorities, programs and budgets that are available to build community resilience. The most successful examples were Grassroots Sisterhood Foundation (Ghana), Ntengwe for Community Development (Zimbabwe) and Kawempe Home Based Care (Uganda) all expanding their base of organizations and partnering with government agencies at both local and national level. 

Latin America (Brazil, Ecuador, Guatemala, Nicaragua and Peru)

Brazil. Espa&#xE7;o Feminista (EF) focused on strengthening the CPP using global policies that promote sustainable development, support grassroots women&#x2019;s agendas in resilient development, and open opportunities to consolidate their leadership and public role in decision-making for policies and programs. 

Ecuador. In total, 2080 new grassroots women were trained in sensitization workshops on DRM and Climate Change Adaptation. They also undertook training on leadership and community organising, risk mapping and policy advocacy. 30 women members of Uni&#xF3;n de Organizaciones Campesinas de los Pueblos Cayambe (UNOPAC) became experts in sustainable agriculture as a climate adaptation practice. This entailed making organic fertilizers, using indigenous seeds and implementing diversified plots. 

Guatemala. The focus was on strengthening the CRF activities related to food security, sustainable agriculture, protection of water sources and the promotion of women&#x2019;s resilient livelihoods through the revolving fund scheme. In the department of Chimaltenango, 28 table gardens were implemented to ensure food security for women and their families. In the municipality of Patz&#xFA;n, the communities of El Sitio, Chiquel and Chuinimachicaj built 25 table gardens and protected the main water source of the communities, planting 400 trees to create natural barriers to prevent erosion and flooding, benefiting 500 families. 

Latin American Regional Platform
Learning Exchange in Tecoluca: Integrating El Salvador to the Regional CPP.
A four-day Capacity Building Workshop was implemented from August 10th to 15th in Tecoluca. In total 15 women of the Organization of Women of Tecoula attended the workshop, which was a practical exercise to learn how to implement the most successful practices of community resilience. The practices of Water and soil conservation; Production of organic fertilizers; Community Risk Mapping; Basic concepts and global policy framework of climate change and its consequences, DRR and sustainable development; Partnerships and advocacy, were transferred.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52040412" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
