<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13291A0101-GGG-14010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Integrity Network WIN 2022-2025</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Water Integrity Network WIN 2022-2025</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WINs overall goal as defined in the strategy 2017  2022 is to reach measurable outcomes in terms of increasing integrity and reducing corruption in the water sector, so as to contribute to more efficient and effective processes to attain the SDGs and fulfill the human rights to water and sanitation. In particular, WIN will contribute and connect to the efforts towards achieving SDG 6 on water and sanitation, and relevant targets under SDG 16 on governance, specifically 16.5 and 16.6 on reducing corruption and bribery as well as promoting effective, accountable and transparent institutions, taking due account SDG 5 to achieve gender equality and empower women and girls.

WIN will also contribute to the drive to meet the human rights to water and sanitation, and will strive to ensure that its work benefits poor, marginalised and vulnerable groups.

WIN are currently working on their Theory of Change for the upcoming strategy (2023-2028), and are not envisioning any radical shifts from current ToC. WIN are also still deep into the discussion on impact indicators link to SDGs which has also been identified as a continued dialogue topic between WIN and Sida. 

To reach its overall goal, WIN aims to stimulate change processes and measure change. As WIN intends to remain a relatively small entity, its main role is to mobilize change agents and to facilitate the support they need, including capacity development, knowledge transfer, and the development and testing of appropriate tools. WIN recognises that in dealing with issues of integrity, a multi-stakeholder approach is often the best route to take.

WIN works at various levels: given the global role of WIN, it works at the international or regional level engaging with strategic partners, and it works at the country level, executing programmes with implementing partners in focus countries.

In pursuing the overall goal, WIN is guided by the following four objectives:

Objective 1: Actors in the international water and sanitation sector take action to increase integrity and reduce corruption

Objective 2: Capability to improve integrity and reduce corruption in the water and sanitation sector has been measurably increased in focus countries

Objective 3: Necessary evidence, knowledge and expertise to advance and measure water integrity action are available and used

Objective 4: WIN Association is managed in a transparent and sustainable manner

Objective 1 aims to advance water and sanitation integrity across many countries and themes by triggering increased engagement of organizations that are internationally or regionally active in the water sector. WIN will provide leadership to initiate the broad efforts needed to reduce corruption risks and increase integrity in the global water and sanitation sector, and work with people and organizations who can take this challenge on through their own actions and within their organisational programmes. The focus of WIN is therefore to stimulate action by encouraging and supporting international water and sanitation sector organizations to become change agents, show leadership and contribute, in their respective roles, to governance reform processes.

Objective 2 aims to achieve change in selected countries through direct engagement together with implementing partners. This includes working with government, media and civil society organisations, including womens organizations, as these represent key stakeholders which can affect change. In addition to having direct impact in countries, objective 2 contributes to objectives 1 and 3 by showcasing/testing what can be achieved and enabling practical learning for WIN and partners.

Engagement under objectives 1 and 2 comprise measures to strengthen transparency, accountability, participation and anti-corruption (TAPA) in the water and sanitation (sub-)sector at international, regional, country, local and organizational level.

Objective 3 is aimed at supporting and leveraging the work of WIN and its partners on objectives 1 and 2 through the generation of knowledge and evidence, and the promotion of knowledge exchange and capacity development on integrity in water and sanitation.

Objective 4 is focused on ensuring that the WIN Association is stable and sustainable, and thereby able to drive the strategy that has been set out.

Sida assesses that WINs objectives are well laid out for work WIN intends to do. The scope of the objectives also fall well into WINs abilities as an organization 


In order to make its approach more systematic and evidence based, and to provide a framework for adaptive programming, WIN developed a Theory of Change (ToC) for enhancing water integrity. This ToC provides a model of the main avenues along which change towards integrity based sustainable water management happens at country level, and how this is supported from and informs the regional and international level.

The ToC is based on the concept that for sustainable change towards greater integrity and reduced corruption, institutionalized changes in individual country contexts are needed. This includes changes in rules, processes, organization, responsibilities, programmes, ways of working and behaviour. Such change processes are complex and take time, and to support this, strong change agents are needed who can push national or local policy and/or organizations. Agents and pressure for change may come top-down from political leaders and policymakers, from within administrations and sector organizations or from private sector stakeholders, or bottom-up from CSOs and direct citizen engagement, often representing marginalized groups. Development partners, investors, and international sector associations also play an important role in stimulating change.

The ToC recognises that WIN, as a small NGO, can best contribute to this change by mobilizing and supporting appropriate change agents. This requires WIN to work with network partners to take up integrity issues and for them to provide support in a specific country or region, for specific actors, or within their own organisations and mandate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">WIN:s &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;l enligt definitionen i strategin 2017&#x2013;2022 &#xE4;r &quot;att n&#xE5; m&#xE4;tbara resultat n&#xE4;r det g&#xE4;ller att &#xF6;ka integriteten och minska korruptionen inom vattensektorn, f&#xF6;r att bidra till effektivare och mer &#xE4;ndam&#xE5;lsenliga processer f&#xF6;r att uppn&#xE5; m&#xE5;len f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar utveckling och uppfylla de m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheterna till vatten och sanitet&quot;. WIN kommer s&#xE4;rskilt att bidra till och ansluta sig till insatserna f&#xF6;r att uppn&#xE5; m&#xE5;l 6 f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar utveckling om vatten och sanitet och relevanta m&#xE5;l enligt m&#xE5;l 16 om styrning, s&#xE4;rskilt 16.5 och 16.6 om att minska korruption och mutor samt fr&#xE4;mja effektiva, ansvarstagande och transparenta institutioner, med vederb&#xF6;rlig h&#xE4;nsyn till m&#xE5;l 5 f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar utveckling f&#xF6;r att uppn&#xE5; j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och ge kvinnor och flickor egenmakt.

WIN kommer ocks&#xE5; att bidra till str&#xE4;van att uppfylla de m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheterna till vatten och sanitet och kommer att str&#xE4;va efter att se till att dess arbete gynnar fattiga, marginaliserade och utsatta grupper.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WIN&#x2019;s overall goal as defined in the strategy 2017 &#x2013; 2022 is &#x2018;to reach measurable outcomes in terms of increasing integrity and reducing corruption in the water sector, so as to contribute to more efficient and effective processes to attain the SDGs and fulfil the human rights to water and sanitation.&#x2019; In particular, WIN will contribute and connect to the efforts towards achieving SDG 6 on water and sanitation, and relevant targets under SDG 16 on governance, specifically 16.5 and 16.6 on reducing corruption and bribery as well as promoting effective, accountable and transparent institutions, taking due account SDG 5 to achieve gender equality and empower women and girls.

WIN will also contribute to the drive to meet the human rights to water and sanitation, and will strive to ensure that its work benefits poor, marginalised and vulnerable groups.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="32000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WIN/Water Integrity Network Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="32000" role="4" type="30">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WIN/Water Integrity Network Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2026-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.5 - Substantially reduce corruption and bribery in all their forms.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.5 - V&#xE4;sentligt minska alla former av korruption och mutor.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">6.1 - By 2030, achieve universal and equitable access to safe and affordable drinking water for all.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">6.1 - Senast 2030 uppn&#xE5; allm&#xE4;n och r&#xE4;ttvis tillg&#xE5;ng till s&#xE4;kert och ekonomiskt &#xF6;verkomligt dricksvatten f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">6.b - St&#xF6;dja och st&#xE4;rka lokalsamh&#xE4;llenas deltagande i arbetet med att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra vatten- och sanitetshanteringen.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">6.b - Support and strengthen the participation of local communities in improving water and sanitation management.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">699553.451713323</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">699553.451713323</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2024-01-01">699553.451713323</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2025-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2025-01-01">699553.451713323</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">699553.451713323</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">699553.451713323</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2024-01-01">699553.451713323</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2025-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2025-01-01">699553.451713323</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">2798213.806853</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/social/13291_018771-22Bilaga1,GrantAgreementbetweenTheSwedishInternationalDevelopmentCooperat3137427_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant agreement SIDA - Water integrity network 2022-2025</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/social/13291_016240-22Beslutominsats,WaterIntegrityNetworkWIN2022-2025(13291)3127397_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution Water integrity Network 2022-2025</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13291" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
