<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13071A0103-GGG-24010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global investors for sustainable development GISD</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Globalt investerarn&#xE4;tverk f&#xF6;r Agenda 2030 GISD</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Det &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let med denna insats &#xE4;r att &#xF6;ka volymen av l&#xE5;ngsiktiga investeringar f&#xF6;r SDGarna.

Insatsen som helhet best&#xE5;r av tv&#xE5; huvuddelar: F&#xF6;r det f&#xF6;rsta, ett finansiellt bidrag till UN DESA f&#xF6;r projektet &quot;Launching the &#x201C;Global Investors for Sustainable Development&#x201D; (GISD) Alliance and developing a framework to map investments with the SDGs&quot;, och f&#xF6;r det andra, metodologiska st&#xF6;d och metodutveckling fr&#xE5;n Sida relaterat till att skapa och leda ett investerarn&#xE4;tverk.

UN DESAs projekt best&#xE5;r av tv&#xE5; delar:

Den f&#xF6;rsta komponenten kommer att inr&#xE4;tta den nya &quot;Global Investors for Sustainable Development&quot; (GISD) alliansen, som kommer att inledas av FN: s generalsekreterare.

Den andra komponenten syftar till att utforska och skapa konsensus kring principer och normer som informerar utvecklingen av en ram f&#xF6;r att m&#xE4;ta och rapportera om effekter av investeringar p&#xE5; SDGarna. Det skulle g&#xF6;ras genom en omfattande &#xF6;versyn av befintliga ramar som kartl&#xE4;gger SDG investeringar (&quot;SDG Impact Investments Measurement&quot;).

De tv&#xE5; projektkomponenterna f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rker varandra p&#xE5; grund av deras komplementaritet och eventuella synergier.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention as a whole comprises two main parts: firstly, a financial contribution to UN DESA for the project &quot;Launching the &quot;Global Investors for Sustainable Development&quot; (GISD) Alliance and developing a framework to map investments with the SDGs&quot;, and secondly methodological support from Sida (metodutveckling) related to the creation and facilitation of an investor network.

The intervention by UN DESA comprises two components:

The first component will establish the new &#x201C;Global Investors for Sustainable Development&#x201D; (GISD) Alliance, which will be launched by the UN Secretary-General. 

The second component aims to research and build consensus around principles and norms that would guide the development of a framework to measure and report on SDG impact of investments by conducting a comprehensive review of existing frameworks that map companies, securities and portfolio to the SDGs (&#x201C;SDG Impact Investments Measurement&#x201D;). 

The two project components will reinforce other given their complementarity and possible synergies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of this intervention is to increase the volume of long-term investments for the SDGs.&#xA0;
The intervention as a whole comprises two main parts: firstly, a financial contribution to UN DESA for the project &quot;Launching the &quot;Global Investors for Sustainable Development&quot; (GISD) Alliance and&#xA0;developing a framework to map investments with the SDGs&quot;, and secondly methodological development from Sida (metodutveckling) related to the creation and facilitation of an investor network.
The intervention by UN DESA comprises two components:
The first component will establish the new &#x201C;Global Investors for Sustainable Development&#x201D; (GISD) Alliance, which will be launched by the UN Secretary-General.&#xA0;
The second component aims to research and build consensus around principles and norms that would guide the development of a framework to measure and report on SDG impact of investments by conducting a comprehensive review of existing frameworks that map companies, securities and portfolio to the SDGs (&#x201C;SDG Impact Investments Measurement&#x201D;). 
The two project components will reinforce other given their complementarity and possible synergies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDESA/United Nations Department of Economic and Social Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41000" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDESA/United Nations Department of Economic and Social Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-29" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-29" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="240" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banking &amp; Financial Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="24010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Financial policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="17.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">17.3 - Mobilisera additionella finansiella resurser till utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna fr&#xE5;n m&#xE5;nga olika k&#xE4;llor.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">17.3 - Mobilize additional financial resources for developing countries from multiple sources.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">618912.6681650868</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">618912.6681650869</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">-571301.9855658805</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-29">602798.252942</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">618912.6681650868</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/garanti/13071_13071AgreementbetweenDESAandSweden2019.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement between DESA and Sweden 2019 on GISD</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/garanti/13071_13071beslutominsats2019.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution Global Investors for Sustainable Development</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In January 2020 GISD working groups started off with enthusism and engagement, following the positive spirit from the launch of GISD in October 2019 at the UN in New York with the Secretary General convening the meeting. A first stategy group meeting was held in Johannesburg on Feb 25-26th, resulting in new ambitions and plans.
The very following week, the first week of March, the Corona-virus hit on a global scale and was upgrated to a pandemia, with lock-downs and severe effects on lives and health. For aprox. three weeks work of GISD was on hold as actors focused on internal issues. Then UNDESA managed to, among other things&#xA0; encouragement from Sida, re-engaging actors through
1, transforming the planned in person conference in Stockholm into a digital conference and meeting
2, invinting to an extraordinary meeting convened by the Secretary General
3, initiating a report on GISD-actors activities to step up and take responsability in the crisis and
4,&#xA0;intiating work on framework for Covid-19 bonds
This re-engaged the actors. Planned work could continue through digital meetings and engagement even increased as the importance of finance in the crisis was acknowledged. However advancements on real investments where dealyed.
The accomplishments during 2020 (please also refer to gisdalliance.org:
Definition of Sustainable Development Investing
A definition that actors in GISD have agreed on. Has been communicated to rating institutes, index providers, member states etc.&#xA0;
Call for action on Covid-19 bonds and definition of use of proceeds around
A framework for parties issuing Covid-19 bonds. Has been communicated to and through ICMA, Institutional Capital Market Association.
Digital conference Buidling Back Better - development and finance leaders in joint action&#xA0;
A three-hour event with broad participation and an audience of 9 000 viewers some two weeks after the event. Organized by Sida and UNDESA.&#xA0;
Extraordinary meeting with the Secretary General and CEOs in June 2020
The SG gathered the CEOs to reinforce their importance in the Corona-crisis as them being part of the solution. CEOs encouraged for more blended finance in the crisis.
Examples of how the GISD participants work in Covid-19 environment
A report on the GISD members engagement and taken on actions in the crisis to support sustaianble developmetn was put together.
Renewed, Recharged and Reinforced: Urgent actions to harmonize and scale sustainable finance. (64 recommendations on how to scale upp sustainable investing in a report to the European Commission in their stakeholder dialogue on EU taxonomy.) A substantial report on how GISD members recommends sustainable development to be advanced on a policy level, through transparency and corporate governance, among other things.
Suggested Task team with World bank/GISD
Sida has been introducing the idea of a special task team to encourage World Bank to better catalyse private investments. Has been discussed and elaborated with World Bank and the GISD group. Will be developped further in 2021 together with Canada.
Typology of eligable SDG investments for professional investors
One working group engaged in putting togheter a typology of the alternatives for investetments that are eligible for institutional investors, in order to kick off work to find the new architecture for sustainable investing.&#xA0;
UNDP platform for investment needs in pilot countries
GISD discovered possibilities to connect to UNDP&apos;s early work on pilots of investment opportunities and needs in developing countires. Dissusions on a digital platform to upload the mappings are continuing 2021.
Investment opportunites related to GIF, Global Infrastucture Facility
Early work on investment opportunity related to Global Infrastructure Facility, GIF - a platform connected to development bank portfolios convened by World bank.
A new digital platform on the work was set up: www.gisdalliance.org
In the end of the year a GISD platform was released. However there are still many dimensions to discover of how to communicate, upload initiatives etc on this.
Investment actions have however not been realized due to Covid-19 crisis, but good momentum towards achieving them.
&#xA0;
From the Sida perspective&#xA0;
The following activities have been taken during 2020:
Weekly calls with UNDESA on coaching, nudgeing, follow up, suggesting new dimensions, meetings etc.
One internal strategy group meeting at Sida for GISD - taking advice from INTEM, Director General&apos;s staff and representative from Africa departent (early Feb 2020).
Three formalized calls including with UNDESA Director for FSDO and Sida&apos;s head of Department and Unit on next steps, coaching in&#xA0;
Convened meetings with SISD&apos;s GISD group and SISD&apos;s GISD reference group to make the connection between SISD&apos;s and GISD&apos;s work and engagement and to support the SISD representatives within GISD.
Organized conference Building back better - finance and development leaders in joint action with high level representation from the World Bank, UN, IFC, GISD members, Swedish Ministers, Swedish Crown Princess. SISD etc.
Discussions with World Bank on task force with GISD to catalyze private investments in line with the bank.
Developed methods on how to work with financial actors from a development perspective.
Internal exploratory work of possible guarantees connected to GISD initiatives.
Participating actively in all working groups and strategy group.
Reporting back to GS and supporting with speaking points, suggestions ahead of decisions on the way forward etc.
Sida co-chair with PIMCO in one work steram - on new investment vehicles.
Planning ahead and suggesting survey with Convergence on preferred investment alternatives with GISD. This survey will also discover also the over all sentiment on investing in low and middle income countries and preferred incentives to invest more in these countries.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13071" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1130103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Capacity development, partnership and methods that support Agenda 2030 for sustainable development 2018-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kapacitetsutveckling, partnerskap och metoder som st&#xF6;der Agenda 2030 f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar utveckling 2018-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
