<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-14405A0102-GGG-72010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam GB - HUM 2021-2025</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Oxfam GB - HUM 2021-2025</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Oxfam har ans&#xF6;kt om 75 miljoner SEK under 2021, varav 36 miljoner SEK tilldelas f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra humanit&#xE4;ra projekt i Algeriet, Centralafrikanska Republiken, Colombia och Tchad; 30 miljoner SEK f&#xF6;r den humanit&#xE4;ra snabbmekanismen; och 9 miljoner SEK f&#xF6;r metod- och kapacitetsst&#xF6;d samt programhanteringsst&#xF6;d. Insatsen utg&#xF6;r f&#xF6;rsta &#xE5;ret av ett strategiskt partnerskap som str&#xE4;cker sig mellan 2021 och 2025 mellan Oxfam och Sidas humanit&#xE4;ra enhet.

M&#xE5;let med insatsen &#xE4;r att skyndsamt kunna n&#xE5; m&#xE4;nniskor med humanit&#xE4;rt st&#xF6;d i akuta kriser samt att bidra till att st&#xE4;rka kapaciteten i det humanit&#xE4;ra systemet. Samtliga f&#xF6;reslagna insatser v&#xE4;gleds av Oxfams k&#xE4;rnmandat, vilket &#xE4;r att arbeta med samh&#xE4;llen innan, under och efter kriser f&#xF6;r att bygga upp deras motst&#xE5;ndskraft, r&#xE4;dda liv och tillsammans angripa orsakerna till konflikt och andra katastrofer.

Oxfam &#xE4;r en global hj&#xE4;lporganisation som arbetar med m&#xE4;nniskor mot fattigdom &#xF6;ver hela v&#xE4;rlden. Oxfam:s vision &#xE4;r en r&#xE4;ttvis v&#xE4;rld utan fattigdom, d&#xE4;r alla v&#xE4;rderas och behandlas lika, har samma r&#xE4;ttigheter och kan p&#xE5;verka sin egen framtid. Oxfam arbetar p&#xE5; flera niv&#xE5;er, genom livr&#xE4;ddande katastrofinsatser, l&#xE5;ngsiktiga projekt som ger m&#xE4;nniskor m&#xF6;jlighet att lyfta sig ur fattigdom och politisk p&#xE5;verkan lindrar vi de akuta symptomen.  Oxfam GB &#xE4;r ett av 20 medlemmar som utg&#xF6;r konfederationen Oxfam International.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam has submitted a proposal for financing to Sida for humanitarian response in the following contexts in 2021: Algeria, Central African Republic (CAR), Chad, and Colombia. The proposal includes a request for Oxfam&#x2019;s rapid response mechanism (RRM) and for method and capacity support. 

The contribution will be the first year of a strategic partnership that extends between 2021 and 2025 between Oxfam and Sida&apos;s Humanitarian Unit. The aim of the contribution is to reach people affected by crisis with humanitarian assistance and protection and to contribute to strengthening the capacity of the humanitarian system. All proposed efforts are guided by Oxfam&apos;s core mandate, which is to work with communities before, during and after crises to build their resilience, save lives and tackle the causes of conflict and other disasters.

Oxfam is a global movement of people who are fighting inequality to end poverty and injustice.  Oxfam works in about 70 countries, with partners, and allies. Oxfam GB is one of 20 affiliates that make up the confederation Oxfam International.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This contribution is aimed at supporting Oxfam in selected humanitarian crisis where Oxfam will implement specific projects and where the organisation has a clear added value to provide humanitarian assistance and protection to crisis affected populations.
In 2020 Oxfam launched its new Global Strategic Framework 2020-2030. The framework was developed over a one-year process that involved Oxfam staff and partners across its global confederation. It sets out the overall direction that Oxfam will take in the years to 2030. According to Oxfam, implementation of the framework will be supported by global horizon plans that will set out specific objectives, systemic interventions, and actions. These plans will serve as a roadmaps for measuring progress towards Oxfam&#x2019;s collective ambition. A combination of six approaches is presented in the framework and will constitute Oxfam&#x2019;s overarching theory of change. These include:
A feminist approach- To end all forms of discrimination, injustices and violations of rights suffered by women and gender non-conforming people
People power &#x2013; Amplify the voices and actions of people that experience poverty and injustice and work with those who fight for their causes
Thinking globally and acting locally- Build a coalition within and between regions and from the local to the global
Enhanced humanitarian action- remain committed to delivering life-saving assistance and protection in times of conflict and disaster
Digital rights and space- to engage with and leverage the power and influence of digital technology
Systematic change &#x2013; Mobilize to transform the systems that perpetuate poverty and injustice.
The strategy also outlines Oxfam&#x2019;s approach to enhance its humanitarian actions which involves 1) deliveing life-saving support and assistance to communities affected by conflict and disaster, including people on the move; 2) transforming the systems that contribute to fragility and humanitarian crises;3) helping people and communities develop core competencies to strengthen their resilience; 4) continue to reorient the humanitarian system towards local leadership, and; 5) expanding opportunities for those impacted by protracted conflict and recurring crises to lead on sustainable solutions.
At the operational level the global strategic framework reaffirms Oxfam&#x2019;s commitment to humanitarian assistance in the technical areas of WASH, Economic Inclusion, Cash and social protection based approaches, Gender, Community based protection and safe programming, and finally advocacy work to complement programmes in particular on women in conflict.
In&#xA0;all the technical areas there are four pillars that will inform the humanitarian approach including 1) Community Engagement; 2) Safe Programming; 3) Partnership and Leadership, 4) Feminist approach. Oxfam is currently working on its Horizon Plan for humanitarian action, which will give practical and pragmatic guidance on expectations for Oxfam countries on its humanitarian ambition, how it is changing in approach and alignment of appropriate support.&#xA0;&#xA0;
In 2021/2022 Sida will support Oxfam&#x2019;s humanitarian interventions in 4 different crises as well as its immediate response to new onset crises or rapidly deteriorating situations through the rapid response mechanisms (RRM). The specific objective of each project might differ, but Oxfam&#x2019;s core objective within its humanitarian mandate is to work with communities before, during and after crisis to build their resilience, save lives, and together address the root causes of conflict and disaster. 
Sida will also support a project implemented by Oxfam to improve the use of the Integrated Food Security Phase Classification (IPC) analysis as a tool for ascertaining food insecurity, as well as support to CaLP in order to strengthen the system wide use of CVA as a modality in humanitarian interventions.&#xA0;&#xA0;
The following provides a brief description of the projects objectives and intended results:
Algeria&#xA0;(10 MSEK) &#x2013;&#xA0;Refugees from Western Sahara have been living in 5 refugee camps in Tindouf region, southwestern Algeria since 1975 due to an on-going dispute over the control of the Western Sahara Territory. With no imminent political solution to this protracted crisis in sight, the refugee population is largely dependent on external humanitarian aid for its survival. 94% of refugees remain dependent on humanitarian aid as their primary source of support, including for the provision of food, water and other basic needs.
The intervention aims to&#xA0;strengthen the resilience amongst 133 672 Sahrawi refugees to meet their basic needs, with a focus on food security and water and sanitation. Food security will be improved through the promotion of local agricultural production and distribution of fresh food during challenging summer months. In line with the official UN 5-year WaSH Strategy and Plan, the piped water network in Boujdour camp (which has relied completely on water trucking to date) will be extended, serving as a model which can later be adapted and scaled up in other camps.
Colombia (9 MSEK) -&#xA0; During 2020, refugees and migrants from Venezuela continued arriving in Colombia, with an estimated 1,7 million remaining in the country and half a million in transit to other countries. This situation was further exacerbated by the impact of natural disasters, generalized violence in certain areas, and since March, by the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic.
This intervention is part of Oxfam&#xB4;s broad protection strategy to Venezuelan mixed migration flux. It is based on two main components: 1) a strategy to promote sexual and reproductive rights through access to short and medium-term contraceptive methods, accompanied by legal, medical and psychological counselling to manage cases of gender-based violence, and 2) a focused women migrant walkers&apos; program that provides information to tackle risks, reduce vulnerability and strengthen capacities of migrants to avoid risks and mitigate their effects. The project targets approximately 5&#xA0;000 migrants with protection and NFI assistance.
Central African Republic (CAR) (10 MSEK) -&#xA0;Clashes between rebels and government forces in various cities has caused further deterioration of the security situation in CAR since late December 2020, resulting in 105&#xA0;000 new refugees and 100&#xA0;000 new IDPs in the beginning of February 2021. The situation affects the sectors of food security; water, hygiene and sanitation; protection and gender, and particularly affects the prefectures of Ouham, Ouham-Pend&#xE9; and Mbomou in which the project will be implemented.
The intervention aims to improve the protection and living conditions of displaced, returnee and host communities in the target areas by strengthening access to food security and livelihoods, improving access to WASH services and building the capacity of affected populations to prevent and respond to protection risks.&#xA0;The project will target approximately 67 000 people across these three areas. In line with Oxfam&#x2019;s localisation of aid commitments under the Grand Bargain and the Charter for Change, Oxfam will implement this intervention jointly with local humanitarian agencies.
Chad (7 MSEK)&#xA0;&#x2013; Chad is facing three interconnected crises: food insecurity and malnutrition, population movements (481 645 refugees, 336 124 IDPs, and 109 019 new returnees) and health emergencies. The already alarming humanitarian situation in Chad has been further weakened by the suspension of certain humanitarian activities following the implementation of restrictive measures due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
The intervention will contribute to the community resilience and self-protection of the displaced populations in the Bagasola and Daboua areas in the Lake region of Chad. It will strengthen IDPs abilities to identify, respond to and mitigate risks and threats to protection. Approximately 40&#xA0;000 people will be targeted. The project also aims to increase people access to water and sanitation facilities through construction and rehabilitation of waterpoints and improvement of people knowledge and practice of public health and hygiene based on community perceptions. Through cash distribution to highly vulnerable IDPs, returnees and host communities their essential food needs will be met and their livelihoods strengthened.
IPC Project in CAR and Zimbabwe (3 MSEK)
Specific gaps in country IPC processes have been identified by Oxfam and other stakeholders in Zimbabwe and CAR. Each country has had difficulties with data collection and data quality. In CAR, there are problems with both the quantity and the quality of data available to perform the analyses including a lack of surveys data in some geographic areas and information gaps in the available data (e.g., core food security indicators). In Zimbabwe, the government leads the data collection process and NGOs are invited to participate, but sometimes at short notice and at times with resource contributions to the data collection processes as a prerequisite for participation of agencies in IPC analyses. Large surveys organized by government or UN agencies also tend to crowd out viable sources of information produced by smaller organizations that would otherwise add value and diversity to datasets used in analyses.
This interventions is expected to increase the engagement of NGOs (with a goal of at least 4-6 NGOs participating per country) and support expanded plurality in the consensus-building part of the IPC analysis workshop. Greater transparency will be seen through participation of at least two NGO representatives in the full IPC process:&#xA0; pre-analysis (includes primary data collection and preparation), analysis (e.g., workshops), and post-analysis (communication etc.). The project will consolidate one country-based community of practice of agencies involved in IPC per country (CAR and Zimbabwe).
CaLP (4 MSEK)
The Cash and Voucher Assitance (CVA) landscape is characterized by rapid change and evolving opportunities, both at global and national levels. Technological developments and the changing role of governments, private sector and local actors carry major implications for the role of international humanitarian actors. The amount spent on CVA in humanitarian response has doubled in the past three years. At the same time, overall humanitarian funding has plateaued, meaning that CVA is becoming an increasingly critical part of humanitarian response. The use of CVA has also grown in the COVID-19 response, with the Global Humanitarian Response Plan calling for a scale-up of CVA as an effective way to protect the most vulnerable, as well as reduce the deterioration of assets, livelihoods and social cohesion.
The contribution to CaLP will be in support of CaLPs annual plan (2021-2022). The plan&apos;s strategic focus includes fostering collaboration for more effective and sustainable humanitarian CVA, strengthening evidence-based policy and action in order to transform humanitarian CVA and expanding the skills and knowledge required to deliver quality, sustainable humanitarian CVA, at scale.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21501" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21501" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2026-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="720" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">3257435.0956057203</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">3257435.0956057203</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-01">3257435.095605</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-28">3257435.0956057203</value>
  </transaction>
  <contribution contributionid="14405" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1010104" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0.0" strategy-end-date="2025-12-31" strategy-start-date="2021-01-01">
    <title>Humanitarian aid 2021-2025</title>
    <titleSV>Humanit&#xE4;rt bist&#xE5;nd 2021-2025</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
