<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5403028601-GGG-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consortium ICNL 2012-2014</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Consortium ICNL 2012-2014</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">International Center for Not for Profit Law f&#xF6;r st&#xF6;d fr&#xE5;n Sida till   det tre-&#xE5;riga &quot;Civic Space Initiative&quot;. M&#xE5;let f&#xF6;r insatsen &#xE4;r att     f&#xF6;rsvara och ut&#xF6;ka utrymmet f&#xF6;r det civila samh&#xE4;llet att verka, genom verksamhet som fr&#xE4;mjar en gynnsam r&#xE4;ttslig milj&#xF6; f&#xF6;r                  civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Center for Not for profit Law receives support from     Sida to the &quot;Civic Space Initiative&quot;, with the overall objective to:  &quot;protect and expand civic space by fostering an enabling legal        environment for civil society organizations&quot;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICNL/International Center for Not-for-Profit Law Inc</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">2105216.5048973984</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">7070257.323589019</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">4591903.672065191</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">2105216.504897398</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">7070257.3235890195</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">4591903.672065191</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">-753518.0272307603</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-09-01">13562026.326286</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-10-28">2105216.5048973984</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-04-28">2187864.644107351</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">4882392.6794816675</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-10-28">4591903.672065191</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-02-28">-753518.002688015</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2015Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: The Civic Space Initiative (CSI) is a global program led by the International Center for Not-for-Profit Law (ICNL) in partnership with ARTICLE 19, CIVICUS, and the World Movement for Democracy. The program has been funded by Sida with a budget of 91.8m SEK over three years (2012-2015). CSI addresses shrinking civic space on global, regional and national level aiming to: 
&#x2022; Advance a legal environment that enables all people to exercise the freedoms of peaceful assembly, association, and expression; and
&#x2022; Create spaces for citizens, communities, and civil society organizations to meaningfully engage with government and other power holders on freedoms of assembly, association, and expression. 

Some results: 
&#x2022; The CSI has strengthened the mandate of the UN Special Rapporteur (UNSR) on the rights to peaceful assembly and association. The CSI expanded the UNSR&#x2019;s consultative process and open dialogue approach on civic space and other human rights issues. With CSI support, the UNSR has convened more than 45 consultative meetings with more than 2,800 diverse civil society actors, even activists from severely restrictive environments like Laos and Vietnam. 
&#x2022; The CSI supported UNSR visits to Malaysia, Rwanda, Burundi, Oman, Cambodia, and Kazakhstan. Through these visits, the UNSR shared concerns with the host governments and offered solutions, drawing on content gathered in large part from consultations. For example, during his academic visit to Cambodia, the UNSR raised concerns over a recent ban on public protests; two weeks after the visit, the government lifted the ban.
&#x2022;The CSI influenced discussions on the post-2015 sustainable development goals, so that civic space freedoms can be recognized as critical to development, and resources for the next fifteen years can be channeled accordingly. CSI partners were the only group advocating for the inclusion of an enabling legal environment for civil society in a submission to the High Level Panel on Development Agenda. CSI engagement in this process, including joint advocacy with partners, resulted in our recommendations on access to information (ATI) and the need for a strong enabling environment for civil society.
&#x2022;By providing technical assistance to empower local law reformers, the CSI sought to ensure that national legislation is in accordance with international norms governing the freedoms of assembly, association and expression. More specifically, the CSI consortium has written over 60 legal analyses on legislation related to civic space freedoms; participated in 22 litigations seeking positive interpretations of law affecting fundamental freedoms; and provided more than 130 supportive interventions to empower local law reformers. Furthermore, over 300 human rights defenders have participated in protection trainings.

To provide a few examples of results from national level: 
&#x2022; Enabling legal reform. In Myanmar, the CSI empowered local CSOs and key allies within the parliament to transform a restrictive draft law into a more enabling law. The drafting of the Association Registration Law was marked by unprecedented levels of participation and dialogue, with CSOs feeling empowered to influence the process. Enacted in July 2014, the Association Registration Law was substantially improved over the original draft law, including by removal of provisions that would criminalize unregistered groups. 
&#x2022; Enhancing dialogue on legal reform. In Tanzania, the CSI enabled the Tanzanian Association of NGOs (TANGO) to produce a report on challenges facing Tanzanian NGOs with regard to the current regulatory framework. The completed report is based on a district-level survey of NGOs &#x2013; the first of its kind, reportedly &#x2013; and several rounds of consultation and validation with government officials and other stakeholders. The report will be made available in Kiswahili and will likely serve as the basis for amendments to the NGO Act of 2005. 
&#x2022; Empowering CSOs to advocate against restrictive legal measures. In Bolivia, the CSI supported broad-based civil society efforts to advocate against restrictive laws that impede CSO registration and operations. A coalition of local CSOs pushed for improvements in the draft Law on Transparency and Access to Public Information; persuaded Bolivia&#x2019;s independent Public Defender to challenge the constitutionality of certain aspects of the Law on Awarding Legal Personalities; secured support from the UN Special Rapporteur on the rights to freedom of peaceful assembly and of association; and published a comprehensive book on Freedom of Association in Bolivia that compiles all relevant research into one key resource for understanding and defending that right.

More about the Civic Space Initiative here: http://www.icnl.org/csi/index.html</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="54030286" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
