<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12936A0104-GGG-32110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity development programme sustainable public procurement</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Program f&#xF6;r kapacitetsutveckling inom h&#xE5;llbar upphandling</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Det huvudsakliga och &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let med insatsen &#xE4;r att fr&#xE4;mja ett &#xF6;kat genomslag och anv&#xE4;ndande av h&#xE5;llbar offentlig upphandling och d&#xE4;rmed bidra till ett b&#xE4;ttre hush&#xE5;llande av offentliga resurser samt fr&#xE4;mja investeringar och upphandlingar som &#xE4;r mer socialt, ekonomiskt och milj&#xF6;m&#xE4;ssigt h&#xE5;llbara. Detta sker genom ett kapacitetsutvecklingsprogram med fokus p&#xE5; statliga organisationer i Sidas partnerl&#xE4;nder som &#xE4;r direkt involverade i upphandlingar eller policyarbete kring h&#xE5;llbara upphandlingar. Genom det upphandlade ramavtalet erbjuds partnerorganisationerna olika former av st&#xF6;d att genomf&#xF6;ra  interna f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringsprocesser kopplade till h&#xE5;llbar offentlig upphandling.  Programmet kommer att involvera flera regionala omg&#xE5;ngar, bl.a. i &#xD6;stafrika och Latinamerika.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The key objective of the contribution is to promote an increased use of Sustainable Public Procurement (SPP) and thereby contribute to a more efficient use of public resources and foster investments and procurement processes which are more social, economic and environmental sustainable. This will be conducted through  a capacity development programme with focus on governmental organisationsations in Sida&apos;s partner organisations directly involved in procurement processes or policy work linked to SPP.  Through the procured framework agreement the partner organisations will be offered support through different workning methods to internal change processes linked to SPP.  The programme will include different regional programmes, for example in East Africa and Latin America.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the intervention is that Sustainable Public Procurement is used as a strategic tool for sustainable development and the achievement of Agenda 2030.
The specific objective of the intervention for the short and medium term is that public organisations and other actors initiate, support, strengthen and develop policies, methods and tools that strengthen the conditions and incentives for SPP and efficient public procurement while considering the rights, needs and demand of people living in poverty.
The specific objective implies that participating organisations actively apply the theoretical and practical knowledge gained through the programme to bring about organisational and institutional change, to contribute to the deployment of SPP and in the long-term to the overall development objective of the programme.
The programme&#xA0; applies an adaptive management which means that the specific outputs for different partner organisations are not pre-determined. However, in line with the suggested working methods the programme as a whole is expected to generate outputs along the following lines; &#xA0;
- Enhanced knowledge and practical experience of fundamental principles for public procurement and policies, legal frameworks and methods and tools for implementing SPP.- Support to a change processes linked to a SPP process through mentorship and technical support&#xA0;- Enhanced knowledge of methods, as well as strengthened leadership skills, to conduct organisational and institutional change.- Increased access to national stakeholder platforms and regional/international networks for peer-to-peer learning in support of effective work on SPP and efficient procurement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FCG Swedish Development AB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FCG Swedish Development AB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2026-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="32110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Industrial policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Industry</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="12.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">12.7 - Fr&#xE4;mja h&#xE5;llbara offentliga upphandlingsmetoder, i enlighet med nationell politik och nationella prioriteringar.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">12.7 - Promote public procurement practices that are sustainable, in accordance with national policies and priorities.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">4198.2068113188</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">27652.4618451888</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">4198.2068113188</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">27652.4851636372</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-01">29662.20398</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-28">4198.1951520946</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-28">15109.1886345883</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-28">12543.2848698248</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/capdev/12936_014133-21FrameworkAgreementforGlobalCapacityDevelopmentProgrammeonSustainablePub2910735_1_1.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Framework agreement for capacity development programme of sustainable public procurement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/capdev/12936_039571-19BeslutominsatsProgramforkapacitetsutvecklingSPP2591565_1_1.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats, kapacitetsutvecklingsprogram betr. h&#xE5;llbar upphandling</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida has procured a framework agreement in accordance with the Public Procurement Act (Lag (2016:1145) om offentlig upphandling). Sida received 7 tenders (case: 20/000392). The above-mentioned objectives of the intervention, the stipulated risk register and the appraisal and decision documents (case: 18/001314; document: 039571/19) were transformed into (1) a Terms of Reference (ToR) and (2) a procurement document (upphandlingsdokument) (case: 20/000392; document: 001389/21), including (1) requirements for services (skall-krav) and (2) evaluation criteria (utv&#xE4;rderingskriterier f&#xF6;r po&#xE4;ngs&#xE4;ttning) respectively. Sida has assessed each of the 7 tenders according to (1) the requirements for services (skall-krav) and (2) the evaluation criteria respectively (utv&#xE4;rderingskriterier f&#xF6;r po&#xE4;ngs&#xE4;ttning). All 7 tenders fullfilled the requirements for services (skall-krav) and after the standard assessment the tender of FCG Swedish Development AB is lead partner in a consortium with Crown Agents Limited&#xA0;(hereafter: FCG) scored the most (case: 20/000392; document: 001410/21). The scores (including the assessment) have been filed in the technical evaluation matrix and the decision to sign a framework agreement with FCG: (case: 20/000392; document: 001200/21).
At this stage, prior to the first call-off contract regarding inception phase 1A (Mozambique, Tanzania and Zambia), there are no results other than the outcome of the assessment of the tender in relation to the&#xA0;objectives of the intervention, the stipulated risk register and the appraisal and decision documents (case: 18/001314; document: 039571/19) to summarise and to review.
The tender of FCG is consistently robust in relation&#xA0;to the&#xA0;objectives of the intervention, the stipulated risk register and the appraisal and decision documents. More specifically the following items can be noted:
1.&#xA0;The technical and professional ability of FCG (including capacity regarding internal steering and control) fully meet&#xA0;the required requirements for services (skall-krav).
2.&#xA0;The FCG proposal establishes a clear theory of change and elaborates this in a robust and detailed matrix. The methodology for capacity development is integrated with the theory of change, resulting in a detailed overview of the entire programme.
3. The FCG proposal gives detailed information on how the inception phase will be designed and implemented (including a detailed step-by-step situation analysis).
4. The plan includes a comprehensive team of several SPP (sustainable public procurement) experts and regional specialists in order to assure a context specific and tailor-made programme.&#xA0;
5.&#xA0;There is a very clear and detailed plan on identifying, assessing and on-boarding the participating organisations.
6. The Monitoring, Evaluation &amp; Learning system (MEL) is fully integrated in the theory of change. The FCG proposal presents a draft thorough results framework that is adaptable to different contexts (different parts of the programme batches).This includes two levels of comprehensive guiding questions that will be used to develop a fully-fledged set of indicators to measure progress within and across the programme batches.&#xA0;
7. The FCG proposal&#xA0;puts forth a well elaborated and clearly structured plan on how to access and deploy expertise and additional ressources for the subsequent programmes after inception phase 1A.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12936" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1130103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Capacity development, partnership and methods that support Agenda 2030 for sustainable development 2018-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kapacitetsutveckling, partnerskap och metoder som st&#xF6;der Agenda 2030 f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar utveckling 2018-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
