<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5213003804-GGG-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conciliation Resources 2016 - March 2020</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Conciliation Resources 2016 - mars 2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conciliation Resources is an international NGO working with people in conflict to prevent violence and build peace. This contribution is    for continued core support.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Conciliation Resources &#xE4;r en internationell NGO som specialiserar sig p&#xE5; fredsbyggande. Organisationen har s&#xE4;rskilt profilerat sig genom sitt st&#xF6;d till medling och inkluderande fredsprocesser men arbetar &#xE4;ven v&#xE5;ldsf&#xF6;rebyggande och med policyarbete.  P&#xE5; senare &#xE5;r har organisationen byggt upp en s&#xE4;rskild kompetens vad g&#xE4;ller j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsintegrering inom fredsbyggande. Verksamheten sker i bort&#xE5;t ett tjugotal l&#xE4;nder och territorier p&#xE5; flera kontinenter. Insatsen g&#xE4;ller fortsatt k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d om 32,5 MSEK &#xF6;ver fyra &#xE5;r 2016 - 2019.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The contribution will support Conciliation Resources to implement its strategic plan during the period 2016 - 2019. According to this plan, Conciliation Resources will make significant and documented contributions to preventing and transforming violent conflicts and promoting peaceful and inclusive societies.
Moreover,&#xA0;Conciliation Resources has updated their theory of change which is, in the short version, formulated as follows:
&quot;Conciliation Resources aims to develop an environment conducive to and supportive of locally-led peacebuilding (&#x2018;Peace Enablers&#x2019;), in the belief that this will build a foundation for constructive formal and informal peace processes. Peacebuilding initiatives and processes that are both politically sensitive and inclusive will contribute to sustainable and transformative peace outcomes.&quot;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conciliation Resources</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conciliation Resources</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.1 - Avsev&#xE4;rt minska alla former av v&#xE5;ld och d&#xF6;dligt v&#xE5;ld &#xF6;verallt.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.1 - Significantly reduce all forms of violence and related death rates everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.2 - Eliminera &#xF6;vergrepp, utnyttjande, m&#xE4;nniskohandel och alla former av v&#xE5;ld eller tortyr mot barn.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.2 - End abuse, exploitation, trafficking and all forms of violence against and torture of children.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.4 - By 2030, substantially increase the number of youth and adults who have relevant skills, including technical and vocational skills, for employment, decent jobs and entrepreneurship.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">4.4 - Till 2030 v&#xE4;sentligen &#xF6;ka det antal ungdomar och vuxna som har relevanta f&#xE4;rdigheter, d&#xE4;ribland tekniska f&#xE4;rdigheter och yrkeskunnande, f&#xF6;r syssels&#xE4;ttning, anst&#xE4;ndigt arbete och entrepren&#xF6;rskap.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.7 - By 2030, ensure that all learners acquire the knowledge and skills needed to promote sustainable development, including, among others, through education for sustainable development and sustainable lifestyles, human rights, gender equality, promotion of a culture of peace and non-violence, global citizenship and appreciation of cultural diversity and of culture&#x2019;s contribution to sustainable development.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">4.7 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla studerande f&#xE5;r de kunskaper och f&#xE4;rdigheter som beh&#xF6;vs f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja en h&#xE5;llbar utveckling, bland annat genom utbildning f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar utveckling och h&#xE5;llbara livsstilar, m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter, j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet, fr&#xE4;mjande av en kultur av fred, icke-v&#xE5;ld och globalt medborgarskap samt v&#xE4;rdes&#xE4;ttande av kulturell m&#xE5;ngfald och kulturens bidrag till h&#xE5;llbar utveckling.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1956181.5336463223</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1586311.1919542297</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1956181.5336463226</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1586311.1919542293</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-15">3739846.900017</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-02-28">460278.0079167817</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-28">460278.0079167817</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-28">1035625.5178127589</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-28">634524.4767816919</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-28">951786.7151725378</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL 1 CAUSES AND DRIVERS OF CONFLICT ARE PEACEFULLY TRANSFORMED
Significantly, after Conciliation Resource (CR) having accompanied the peace negotiations between the Government of Ethiopia and the Ogaden National Liberation Front throughout the six years of negotiations, a peace agreement was signed in October 2018 (according to the Uppsala Conflict Data Program this was one of the five peace agreements signed globally in 2018). CR helped drafting the agreement and after the peace agreement was signed CR continued working with the parties and brought together the Somali Regional Government and the Ogaden National Liberation Front leadership (ONLF), contributing to the creation of a Joint Committee &#x2013; one of the pillars of the 2018 peace deal.
In Nigeria, CR facilitated the signing of three formal peace agreements between herding and farming communities during 2019.
In Bougainville, Papua New Guinea, CR provided core facilitation support to the &#x2018;Post-referendum Ministerial Planning Taskforce&#x2019; in partnership with the United Nations &#x2013; engaging both the national Papua New Guinea and Autonomous Bougainville Governments. This helped ensure a smooth and peaceful referendum on the political status of Bougainville in December 2019 and laid out the framework for intergovernmental dialogue post referendum.&#xA0;
In the Caucasus, CR has continued to facilitate the Limehouse Discussion Platform on the Abkhazia-Gerogia conflict (which is a semi-official alternative to the Geneva based talks that have not made a lot of progress). Following engagement with the Limehouse Discussion Platform dialogue and work by Conciliation Resources on access to higher education for students and young professionals from the disputed territories of the South Caucasus German Foreign Ministry officially endorsed German engagement in Abkhazia through education initiatives. These dialogues also helped feeding ideas into&#xA0;the formal Geneva Talks. CR continued work on the Karabakh Conflict Archive. CR also made material from the Memory Project archives on the Georgian-Abkhaz conflict public for the first time through an innovative exhibition held in Tbilisi.
GOAL 2 APPROACHES TO BUILDING PEACE SUPPORT INCLUSION
In 2017, Conciliation Resources was asked by the UN Population Fund (UNFPA) to contribute to the Progress Report on the UN Security Council Resolution&#xA0;(2250) on Youth, Peace and Security. Conciliation Resources undertook primary data collection, via a total of 43 focus group discussions with a total of 494 youth (61 % male) in Afghanistan, Kashmir, South Sudan, Georgian-Abkhaz context and Ogadeni diaspora in the UK.
The results of the research were presented in Conciliation Resources&#x2019; January 2018 report, Youth aspirations for peace and security, and were used to feed into the report by the Independent author of the Progress Report, which was submitted by the UN Secretary General to the General Assembly and Security Council in March 2018. With specific and additional financial support from Sida, CR continued to deepen the work on youth inclusion further and could, among other things, engage the same youth on the content of the Progress Report. The additional funding also helped the organisation to draw important lessons on the work on youth inclusion in the coming years.&#xA0;
Furthermore, CR published an issue of the Accord (their series of regular research and policy reports), with 21 articles exploring different aspects of inclusion, and looking at examples from Colombia, Syria an Afghanistan among others. This publication offers research and practice-based insights to help better understand what inclusion means in practice in peace processes, and what need to considered in the ways CR pursue it, as well as influence wider sector discourse.
One example of CR&apos;s work with groups that have been severely affected by conflicts is the work together with partners on the situation of &apos;half widows&apos; in Kashmir. The half widows are women whose husbands &#x2018;disappeared&#x2019; during the conflict in Kashmir (and have not been confirmed as either dead or alive). CR and partners have in various ways worked on improving the rights of this group. The Association Project estimates their total number in Kashmir at between 1,500 and 2,000. Conciliation Resources&#x2019; partner, Kargil Development Project (KDP), with sustained policy advocacy support and engagement from Conciliation Resources, has been engaging with Muslim religious leaders (the Ulema) in relation to the rights of half-widows, leading to a consensus statement on recognition of property rights for the half-widows.
CR&apos;s work in Nigeria - both in the northeastern states of Borno and Yobe&#xA0;affected by the Boko&#xA0;Haram&#xA0;insurgency and the Plateau&#xA0;State affected by herder-farmer conflicts - has increased substantially during this period of Sida&#xA0;support.&#xA0;In Nigeria, CR together&#xA0;with local partners have established 25 Youth Peace Platforms (YPP).&#xA0;The youth-led groups focus on engaging at-risk and vulnerable young people, who are traditionally perceived as being the hardest to reach in society &#x2013; often substance abusers, sex workers, orphans and victims or perpetrators of extreme violence. Through this network of 25 YPPs, young people are supported to rebuild their confidence, process the traumas of their past, analyse conflicts and voice their needs and concerns.&#xA0;
By showing their commitment for peace, these young people are beginning to challenge society&#x2019;s negative stereotypes, and lay the foundations for greater trust and understanding between youth, their communities and officials.&#xA0;
GOAL 3 POLICY IS PRIORITISING CONFLICT PREVENTION AND PEACEBUILDING
Leading a working group with the UK government, banks and NGOs, CR explored solutions to the impact of UK counter-terrorism legislation on the work of peacebuilders and humanitarian organisations.&#xA0;Through this, the group was successful in securing an exemption for humanitarian aid in the UK government counter-terrorism and border security legislation.
Primarily with support from the UK, CR has established the Women Mediators across the Commonwealth network, which raised the profile of women mediators in international circles and contributed to the establishment of a Global Alliance of Regional Women Mediator Networks.
Work on gender-sensitive conflict analysis has also been a key part of CR&apos;s&#xA0;work in the last few years.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52130038" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1120103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2017-01-01">
    <sida:title>Sustainable peace 2017-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>H&#xE5;llbar fred 2017-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
