<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5213002901-GGG-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert 2015 - 2017</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">International Alert 2015 - 2017</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating self-sustaining peacebuilding processes in International Alert&apos;s target countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert is an international NGO active in peacebuilding, violence prevention and strengthening of human security in over 25 countries and territories. The organisation also aims to influence regional and international policy development and to advise governments, organisations and the private sector to support peace. International Alert has around 200 staff in 15 offices in the world and around 300 partner organisations. Its headquarters are located in London. The contribution is for core support 2016 &#x2013; 2018.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">International Alert &#xE4;r en enskild organisation med s&#xE4;te i London. Organisationen arbetar med att f&#xF6;rebygga v&#xE4;pnad konflikt och st&#xE4;rka m&#xE4;nsklig s&#xE4;kerhet i &#xF6;ver 25 l&#xE4;nder och territorier. Vidare ser organisationen som sitt uppdrag att p&#xE5; en regional och internationell niv&#xE5; f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra policyer och policyefterlevnad som &#xE4;r viktiga f&#xF6;r att skapa f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar f&#xF6;r fred samt att st&#xE4;rka andra akt&#xF6;rer att verka f&#xF6;r fred. Organisationen har ca 200 anst&#xE4;llda p&#xE5; 15 kontor runtom i v&#xE4;rlden. Vidare har Alert n&#xE4;rmare 300 partnerorganisationer. Insatsen avser k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d 2016 &#x2013; 2018.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21038" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21038" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">711802.8780563036</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1472564.7168819027</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1170001.17000117</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">711802.8780563038</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1472564.716881903</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1170001.17000117</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-07-01">3392927.052068</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">711802.8780563036</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-28">934961.7250043827</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-28">537602.99187752</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-28">1170001.17000117</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over the partnership period, in which Alert has received a total of 22&#xA0;00&#xA0;000 SEK in core support, the organisation has continued to be a well-functioning and strategic partner to Sida. In 2017, Alert engaged and supported 177&#xA0;071 people through dialogue, training, advocacy, accompaniment, research and outreach activities. Of these, 48% were women, 51% men, and close to one percent identified as &#x2018;other&#x2019;. In October 2016, Alert received confirmation of additional funding totalling 6&#xA0;600&#xA0;000 SEK over 2016 to 2017 to enable an enhanced response capacity in country contexts that warrants a quick and flexible response, either because of a deteriorated situation or to seize opportunities for peacebuilding and conflict prevention. These were allocated to support additional work in the Philippines, DRC, Sri Lanka and Syria.
The achieved results are categorized and presented per geographical region and per, what Alert refers to as, Pathways to Peace. In 2017, 37% of the results Alert achieved were improving relations within and between communities, 27% of their work improved gender relations for peace, 17% of Alert&#x2019;s work achieved positive results to ensure economic development to support peace, 13% of the results achieved in total was categorized under improving citizen-state relationships, 4% addressed the links between climate change and insecurity and improved natural resource management.
In the grant proposal, Alert outlines seven programming pathways, however, in the reporting the pathway of &#x2018;Natural Resource Management&#x2019; has been combined with the pathway on &#x2018;Climate Change&#x2019;. As only 4% of Alerts work has achieved results connected to these two pathways combined, it can be concluded that either quite few interventions targeting these have been completed or that it is particularly challenging to reach positive results for Alert in these areas. 2% of the overall work done by Alert and its partners reduced the impact of crime on stability and violence. This pathway is the most recent addition to Alert and has so far resulted in the set-up of a subnational monitoring system that tracks incidences, causes, and human costs of violent conflict in parts of the Philippines. Other examples provided in the 2018 Internal Report are how Alert in Nigeria supported peer-to-peer support groups to women and girls who escape from Boko Haram to help them cope with trauma. The organisation also facilitated dialogue with family members to improve the understanding of the challenges these women and girls face. In Nepal, Alert helped to set up six &#x201C;Free Media Networks&#x201D; to provide a platform for journalists, civil society members and authorities to engage in discussions on issues of freedom of expression and restrictions to free media. In Myanmar, Alert undertook trainings on how to prevent sexual and gender-based violence. In Colombia, Alert worked with a national network of companies, NGOs and government officials to improve standards on human rights in the private sector. In Rwanda, Alert helped to set up 32 new community dialogue groups to improve coordination over, and involvement in, district-level planning and budgeting on agriculture. These examples give a good indication of the multifaceted work and the diverse contexts in which Alert and its partners work. These aforementioned examples also highlight the reporting style Alert is using, where the results are gathered and shared in narratives &#x2013; or what Alert refers to as Stories of Change &#x2013; alongside some more in-depth examples presented as case studies.
The results are categorized in three levels: (1) Changes in knowledge and attitudes, (2) Changes in behaviour and processes, and (3) Changes in conditions. The first level is about demonstrated changes in knowledge and/or attitudes among direct or indirect participant groups. 49% of the results achieved by Alert in 2018 were ascribed to this level. Whether Alert measures retainment of knowledge is not made clear based on the material provided. On this point, Sida has identified room for improvements for Alert to report more clearly on sustained changed triggered by its interventions. At the second level, 39% of Alert&#x2019;s engagement has resulted in changes in personal, organizational or group behaviours, approaches and/or processes among direct or indirect participants/groups. Lastly, at the third level, 12% of the results have resulted in demonstrated peace-promoting changes in policies, structures or other &#x2018;impacts of impacts&#x2019;. Alert notes in the Internal Report that there has been a 100% increase in the reporting on changed condition from 6% 2016 to 12% in 2017. This change is ascribed to Alert&#x2019;s long-term programmes and efforts in Tunisia, South Caucus, the DRC, Rwanda, the Philippines and Nepal. This increase can be seen to indicate the potency of Alert&#x2019;s work and the importance of long-term, sustainable engagement.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52130029" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
