<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5204052001-GGG-72050</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overseas Development Institute 2015 - 2017</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Overseas Development Institute 2015 - 2017</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALNAP, HPG and IRIN are unique programs in the humanitarian system that aim to strengthen learning and accountability. ODI is a world-leading research organization. ALNAP, HPG and IRIN conduct research, activities that contribute to learning and networking among humanitarian actors, compilations of research, evaluations, etc. and news reporting from humanitarian crises.

The effort contributes to meeting the goals of Sida&apos;s humanitarian strategy (mainly goal 8: increased quality, learning and innovation in humanitarian aid). The effort is relevant for the humanitarian unit&apos;s support for methods and research support in the humanitarian field. Sida should finance the effort as it contributes to the development of learning and accountability for the humanitarian system.

The assessment memorandum has been written in English due to the fact that English-speaking staff in the field are involved in the preparation and follow-up of the effort, in accordance with the Director General&apos;s decision on Sida&apos;s language selection matrix with application instructions from 1 March 2013.

The budget for the effort is as follows;
HPG: 2000000 (year 1), 2000000 (year 2), 2000000 (year 3), 6000000 (total)
IRIN: 1000000 (year 1), 1000000 (total)
ALNAP: 2500000 (year 1), 2500000 (year 2), 2500000 (year 3), 7500000 (total)
Total 5500000 (year 1), 4500000 (year 2), 4500000 (year 3), 14500000 (total)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">ALNAP, HPG och IRIN &#xE4;r unika program i det humanit&#xE4;ra systemet som syftar till att st&#xE4;rka l&#xE4;rande och ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande. ODI &#xE4;r en v&#xE4;rldsledande forskningsorganisation. ALNAP, HPG och IRIN bedriver forskning, aktiviteter som bidrar till l&#xE4;rande och n&#xE4;tverkande bland humanit&#xE4;ra akt&#xF6;rer, sammanst&#xE4;llningar av forskning, utv&#xE4;rderingar etc. samt nyhetsrapportering fr&#xE5;n humanit&#xE4;ra kriser. 

Insatsen bidrar till att uppfylla m&#xE5;len f&#xF6;r Sidas humanit&#xE4;ra strategi (fr&#xE4;mst m&#xE5;l 8: &#xF6;kad kvalitet, l&#xE4;rande och innovation i det humanit&#xE4;ra bist&#xE5;ndet). Insatsen &#xE4;r relevant f&#xF6;r den humanit&#xE4;ra enhetens st&#xF6;d till metod och forskningsst&#xF6;d inom det humanit&#xE4;ra omr&#xE5;det. Sida b&#xF6;r finansiera insatsen d&#xE5; den bidrar till utvecklande av l&#xE4;rande och ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande f&#xF6;r det humanit&#xE4;ra systemet.

Bed&#xF6;mningspromemorian har skrivits p&#xE5; engelska med anledning av att engelskspr&#xE5;kig personal i f&#xE4;lt &#xE4;r delaktig i beredning och uppf&#xF6;ljning av insatsen, i enlighet med Generaldirekt&#xF6;rens beslut om Sidas spr&#xE5;kvalsmatris med till&#xE4;mpningsanvisningar fr&#xE5;n den 1 mars 2013

Budget f&#xF6;r insatsen &#xE4;r f&#xF6;ljande;
HPG: 2000000 (&#xE5;r 1), 2000000 (&#xE5;r 2), 2000000 (&#xE5;r 3), 6000000 (totalt)
IRIN: 1000000 (&#xE5;r 1), 1000000 (totalt)
ALNAP: 2500000 (&#xE5;r 1), 2500000 (&#xE5;r 2), 2500000 (&#xE5;r 3), 7500000 (totalt)
Totalt 5500000 (&#xE5;r 1), 4500000 (&#xE5;r 2), 4500000 (&#xE5;r 3), 14500000 (totalt)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALNAPThe overall objective is that ALNAP members absorb and use learning to improve practice, policy and structures. HPGThe overall objective is that HPG inspire and inform effective and principled humanitarian action.IRINThe overall objective is to highlight neglected crises and analyzing humanitarian action.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ODI (formerly called Overseas Development Institute)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="720" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief co-ordination and support services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">237267.6260187679</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">233740.4312510957</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">237267.6260187679</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">233740.4312510957</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-05-01">474535.252037</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-05-28">237267.6260187679</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-28">233740.4312510957</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The contribution refers to Sida&#x2019;s agreement with Overseas Development Institute (ODI) with support to three separate and distinct programmes: ALNAP, HPG and IRIN. Achieved results are summarised below.
ALNAP
Strategic Area 1: Creating a high-quality evidence base for evaluation. Some key achievements in this area regards; i) ALNAP published a Method Note on &#x201C;Strengthening the quality of evidence in humanitarian evaluations&#x201D; to help evaluators, evaluation managers and users of evaluations improve the quality of evidence; ii) The scoping paper &#x201C;What is monitoring in humanitarian action? Describing practice and identifying challenges&#x201D; was published on how to improve the quality and use of monitoring information; iii) The Humanitarian Evaluation, Learning and Performance (HELP) library now holds nearly 14,500 evaluations and learning resources.
Strategic Area 2: Using the evidence base to analyse system performance. Some key achievements in this area regards; i) The main focus has been on finalising the research phase of the 2018 edition of the State of the Humanitarian System (SOHS) report and consolidation of findings across components; ii) During the reporting period, ALNAP addressed the methods by means of which Lessons Papers are produced.
Strategic Area 3: Making improvements based on informed analysis. Some key achievements in this area regards; i) Following ALNAP&#x2019;s 31st ALNAP Annual Meeting 2017, the study, &#x2018;Transforming change&#x2019; was published and captures the ideas and insights around change processes from the panels, presentations and discussions at the meeting; ii) ALNAP completed a literature review of decision-making approaches, which incorporated 40 humanitarian evaluations from the past three years. While completing the literature review, ALNAP also designed the methodology for the research study that will follow. ALNAP has also worked with RedR to develop a set of leadership training materials. The material will be finalised in early 2018-2019 for use in test and pilot phases; iii) ALNAP has worked on two case studies, in the DRC and Kenya, highlighting specific models and approaches that support adaptive humanitarian action, support operational flexibility in the face of changes in circumstances or an uncertain implementation environment.
HPG
2017-2018 marked the first phase of a two-year Integrated Programme of work on &#x2018;From the ground up: understanding local humanitarian response in crises&#x2019;. Progress below.
Stream 1: &#x2018;As local as possible, as international as necessary&#x2019;: understanding capacity and complimentary in humanitarian response.&#x2019; Country case studies in the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC) and Bangladesh have been conducted through interviews and focus group discussions with affected populations. The team also began a review of the literature and a perception survey on capacity and complementarity.
Stream 2: &#x201C;The tip of the iceberg? Understanding non-traditional sources of aid financing.&#x201D; HPG finalised a detailed research framework, and a comprehensive review to map out existing literature from academic publications, policy documents and data sources. The main focus of the current period was finalising the preparation for the first two case studies &#x2013; on South Sudanese refugees in northern Uganda and in flood affected southern Nepal.
Stream 3: &#x201C;Informality and protection: understanding the role of informal non-state actors in protecting civilians.&#x201D; The literature review has been drafted, highlighting conceptual differences and lessons from examining protection through a cross-disciplinary lens. A first case study on communal loyalty and cross border protection in Libya is nearing completion, while a second case study of cross-border protection in Myanmar/China (Kachin state and Yunnan province) has been commissioned.
Stream 4: &#x201C;Dignity in displacement: from rhetoric to reality.&#x201D;  Two in-depth case studies, of Rohingya in Bangladesh and Somalis in Kenya are being made. Together, these studies explore dignity from a variety of angles to provide a detailed picture of how dignity is perceived and has featured in different humanitarian contexts and displacement circumstances. Field visits to Cox&#x2019;s Bazar in Bangladesh and to Lebanon are being undertaken later in 2018.
Parallel to the IP, HPG has made progress in other workstreams as well during the reporting period: i) Humanitarian Practice Network (HPN), where the primary activity is the production and dissemination of specialist resources. HPN published and launched three editions of Humanitarian Exchange magazine (on humanitarian consequences of violence in Central America; the crisis in the Lake Chad Basin; and humanitarian response in urban areas); ii) Academic engagement, between April 2017 and March 2018 HPG co-edited four quarterly issues of Disasters. One issue, which focused on gender, sexuality and violence in humanitarian crises, critically addressed the gendered impacts of humanitarian interventions, providing key research on how the humanitarian community can engage with issues of gender and sexuality in crises; iii) Final update on IP 2015-17, Holding the keys: who gets access in times of conflict? The research on access was finalised with the publication of a working paper and a policy brief on local actors and humanitarian access in Ukraine, and a final report looking at the implications of the research in Syria and Ukraine. The report was launched at an event in Geneva hosted by the ICRC.
IRIN
IRIN published more than 400 articles, features, in-depths and other formats on its website which were distributed through its email newsletter and shared on its social media channels between April 2017 and March 2018. Highlights throughout the year include the scoop a sexual exploitation scandal at an aid agency which was dismissed by another NGO seven years earlier for similar misconduct; a special report diving into the EU&#x2019;s $200 million migration deal with Sudan; an exclusive investigation from South Kivu, in the Democratic Republic of Congo, uncovering a campaign of rape by the security forces; and their &#x2018;Ten humanitarian crises to look out for in 2018&#x2019;.
Thematically, IRIN&#x2019;s reporting highlights 2017-2018 include: i) Refugee/migration crisis, where IRIN continued to provide in-depth reporting on the difficulty of the Rohingya situation in Myanmar, which IRIN has been highlighting consistently 2008; ii) Forgotten conflicts, where IRIN worked with local Yemeni journalist to produce extensive coverage of any outlet on the cholera outbreak, including its spread in hospitals; iii) Forgotten conflicts, where IRIN launched a new series of six articles on the uncertain future of Kurds in the region (Iraqi Kurdistan). One of the reports, &#x201C;A country called Kurdistan?&#x201D;, examined the logistical challenges of voting in a context of war and a displacement crisis. This report became their fourth most-read of 2017 in a month.
Overall, it is Sida&#x2019;s assessment that ALNAP, HPG and IRIN have contributed towards the progress of increased humanitarian learning, policy making, advocacy and transparency, all three being widely known and respected resources within the humanitarian community. It is also Sida&#x2019;s assessment that the different outputs that have been shared provide comprehensive in-depth and overview descriptions of current humanitarian climate, including monitoring, learning and evaluation in newly emerging contexts (urban response, innovation etc), digging into the meaning of localization through various aspects, and holding the system accountable, for instance from sexual exploitation within the aid sector. More in-depth assessment will be made in the following section.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52040520" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
