<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12487A0201-GGG-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">MADRE, Kvinnor fred och s&#xE4;kerhet 2018-2023</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MADRE, Women peace &amp; security 2018-2023</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MADRE is an international civil society organization based in the United States. 
MADRE works in solidarity with local women-led organization in areas and countries affected by conflict and war to promote social justice and women&apos;s full participation in conflict resolution and peace building. Currently, MADRE is working in Iraq, Syria, Palestine, Kenya, Sudan, Nicaragua, Guatemala, Haiti, DRC and Colombia. MADRE uses a variety of strategies, such as legal advocacy work, forwarding of funds to local partners, humanitarian support, capacity building and mobilization of women&apos;s organizations and activists. MADRE is also a strong voice in the design of the international dialogue and normative framework for Women&apos;s Peace and Security in close cooperation with both international and national partners as well as by supporting the practical implementation of the central parts of the agenda at national level.

MADRE plans to expand its operations during the next strategic period and budget projection for 2018/19, 2019/20, 2020/21 is a total of approximately SEK 200,000,000, of which about 28% is planned to be forwarded to local partners. Other donors mainly consist of US private foundations and individual donors.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">MADRE &#xE4;r en internationell civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisation baserad i USA. MADRE arbetar i solidaritet med lokala kvinnoledda organisation i konflikt- och krigsomr&#xE5;den  f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja social r&#xE4;ttvisa och kvinnors fulla deltagande i konfliktl&#xF6;sning och fredsbyggande. F&#xF6;r n&#xE4;rvarande arbetar MADRE i Iraq, Syrien, Palestina, Kenya, Sudan, Nicaragua, Guatemala, Haiti, DRK och Colombia. MADRE anv&#xE4;nder en rad olika strategier, exempelvis juridiskt p&#xE5;verkansarbete, vidaref&#xF6;rmedling av medel till lokala partners, humanit&#xE4;rt st&#xF6;d, kapacitetsuppbyggnad och mobilisering av kvinnoorganisationer och aktivister. MADRE &#xE4;r dessutom en stark r&#xF6;st i utformningen av den internationella dialogen och normativ ram kring Kvinnor fred och s&#xE4;kerhet i n&#xE4;ra samarbete med b&#xE5;de internationella och nationella partner samt genom att st&#xF6;dja det praktiska genomf&#xF6;randet av de centrala delarna i dagordningen p&#xE5; nationell niv&#xE5;. 

MADRE planerar att expandera sin verksamhet under n&#xE4;sta strategiperiod och budgetprojiceringen f&#xF6;r &#xE5;ren 2018/19, 2019/20, 2020/21 &#xE4;r totalt motsvarande ca 200 000 000 kronor, varav ca 28% &#xE4;r ber&#xE4;knat till vidaref&#xF6;rmedling till lokala partners. Andra givare best&#xE5;r fr&#xE4;mst av amerikanska privata stiftelser och individuella givare.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The MADRE Strategy for 2018-22 presents 3 interlinked goals; 1) Women at the margin leads, meaning women and girls who are excluded from power and representation in their societies will gain capacities, resources and access to policy making and other centers of power; 2) Policies and attitudes change, meaning new policies at local, national and global level to uphold womens rights and change of attitudes and social norms to reflect priorities of women at the margin; 3) Progressive movements gain power, meaning movements that are critical to advancing social change for social justice and gender equality are strengthened and play leadership roles in global movements.

MADRE seeks to assist community based and women led grassroots organisations to address gendered root causes of conflict, the effect of disasters and their aftermath by advancing human rights and social justice and to meet critical needs in the communities. MADRE furthermore recognizes the disproportionate impact of conflict on women and girls, and the need to ensure their active participation in conflict resolution and peace building to ensure both inclusive society and sustainable peace. MADRE specifically seeks to prioritize marginalized groups, such as young women and girls of indigenous or Afro-descendant origin or with disablities and LGBTIQ people. MADRE also directly link conflict and fragility to climate change and environmental deterioration, and the potential gendered consequences in the communities.
MADRE argues that human rights obligations and social justice can be strengthened in conflict and fragile contexts by meeting the urgent community needs through programs that asserts womens rights and leadership, including sustaining the environment; support the participation, agency and voice of grassroots women in a rage of social movement and policy making spaces; strengthen the exchange of ideas and strategies within and across social movements and diverse communities of activists; improve policies at all levels of governance by using the human rights framework to institutionalize social movement demands; and change and challenge social norms and attitudes using legal advocacy combined with community mobilization and organizing.
MADRE builds on more than 35 years of institutional expertise and practical experience from 25 countries. MADREs current geographical focus is: Iraq, Syria, Palestine, Kenya, Sudan, Nicaragua, Guatemala, Haiti, DRC and Colombia.  MADRE is an international womens rights organisation, and distinguishes itself by standing at the intersection of the movements for global peace, economic, environmental and climate justice, womens and LGBTIQ rights, sexual rights and Indigenous and Afro-descendant rights.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FCG Swedish Development AB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.b - Promote and enforce non-discriminatory laws and policies for sustainable development.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.b - Verka f&#xF6;r och genomdriva icke-diskriminerande lagstiftning och politik f&#xF6;r en h&#xE5;llbar utveckling.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">63591.0410521284</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">63591.0410521284</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-01">63591.041052</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-28">11915.7271275169</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-28">51675.2742832492</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/fred/12487_Avtalsandring_Amendment3totheAgreementbetweenSidaandMADRE.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment 3 to the Agreement between Sida and MADRE</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/fred/12487_031497-18GrantAgreementbetweenTheSwedishInternational_DevelopmentCooperationAgency2343751_1_1.PDF.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant agreement Sia-MADRE 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/fred/12487_030433-18Beslutominsats,MADREkvinnor,fredochsakerhet2324321_1_1.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats MADRE 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/fred/12487_DecisiononAmendmentofContributionMADRE.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om &#xE4;ndring av insats MADRE</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/fred/12487_DecisiononAmendmentofContribution(12487).pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Amendement of Contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall MADRE was able to quickly respond to the Covid-19 crisis&#xA0;by rapid response grant making and advocacy for partners, many times in remote areas not reached by other support or measures. This was done thorough&#xA0;humanitarian aid efforts and health-related measures, including food security, alternative livelihoods and protection and support services for survivors of violence. MADRE reports that it&#xA0;&quot;was the sole provider of emergency support to 69% of our partners, with only 31% of partners able to access additional support from other sources.&quot; Thus, MADRE has strengthened its&#xA0;grant-making role and distributed 2,3 MUSD in grants through 120 grants to 91 organizations, including 42 VIVA Girls grantees, across 28 countries thus reaching 41 more organizations and 18 more countries than previous budget year.&#xA0;
Goal 1: Ending Sexual and Gender-based violence in conflict and disaster
Objective 1: Build the capacity of grassroots women&apos;s organisations to meet the immediate needs of sexual and gender based violence survivors and help them become leaders and long-term agents of change
In Iraq MADRE continued to support OWFI&#xA0;which engaged full-time in the protests, giving it a feminist perspective thorough&#xA0;the &#x201C;Uprising Women&apos;&apos; newspaper. At the same time OWFI continued to provide immediate physical and psychological&#xA0;safety to 151 individuals across Iraq fleeing domestic violence, trafficking, sexual slavery, rape, early/forced marriage, honor killings, and other forms of abuse. The Women&#x2019;s Center in Dohuk supported&#xA0;143 Yezidi women and girl survivors of sexual slavery and genocide of ISIS to heal from trauma andn rebuild their lives.&#xA0;MADRE also resourced OWFI&#x2019;s Feminist School, a one of its kind education on feminist history and theory, human rights, and civic participation to women, girls.&#xA0;
In Nicaragua&#xA0;steps have been taken to ensure greater&#xA0;intersectionality in the approach of its partner&#xA0;Wangki&#xA0;Tangni.&#xA0;Wangki Tangni&#x2019;s network of women radio broadcasters and promotoras (human rights defenders) have integrated disability justice messaging into its radio programming as well as in their long-standing program to combat violence against women and girls across 115 Indigenous communities.&#xA0;
In Palestine MADRE&#xB4;s partner&#xA0;Salon Plus, an women&#x2019;s health and wellness center that provides education, counseling, sexual, reproductive and maternal health services and psychosocial treatment to women under the cover of a hair salon. During the pandemic MADRE could support the organisation to move into digital and social media settings and creative systems&#xA0;to reach isolated women experiencing&#xA0;violence and even intervene in severe cases.&#xA0;
Objective 2: Increase prioritization by national, regional and international policymakers to address sexualand gender-based violence
In Colombia&#xA0;MADRE works with local partners to document cases and raise awareness of conflict-related gender-based violence committed against Afro-Colombian and Indigenous communities.&#xA0;MADRE helped its partner&#xA0;PCN organize strategy sessions with its legal team and international experts to develop methods and gain insights for enhancing black communities&#x2019; representation in the Special Jurisdiction for Peace. The partner Taller de Vida (TdV) has improved the responsiveness of Colombia&#x2019;s Truth Commission on the situation of children and adolescents impacted by conflict as it has started a formal partnership with the Truth Commission and participate&#xA0;in two key working groups:&#xA0;for children, people with disabilities and the elderly; and for women&#x2019;s organizations and those working with&#xA0;LGBTIQ people.&#xA0;By training the Commission on its psychosocial methodology and the creation and value of digital testimonials, TdV has also enhanced the capacity of the Truth Commission to prevent re-traumatization of survivors and safeguard survivors&#x2019; psychosocial health and well being.
Globally a domestic violence campaign has been launched with&#xA0;international, inter-movement coalition (Media Matters for Women, MenEngage Alliance, OutRight&#xA0;Action International, Women Enabled International and WILPF=. This campaign&#xA0;called upon &quot;governments to 1) coordinate with local women&#x2019;s organizations to design and implement plans to address domestic violence; and 2) expand the definition of domestic violence beyond intimate partner violence to include the full range of violence committed by household members against women and girls, and against disabled and LGBTIQ people.&quot; A briefing paper and toolkit for confronting and documenting domestic violence has been produced, available in English, Arabic, Spanish, French, Swahili, and Kurdish. Since its release, over 50 organizations and activists worldwide have requested training on the toolkit.
Despite curfews and lockdowns, OWFI in Iraq and Female Solidarity for Integrated Peace and Development (SOFEPADI) in the DRC have used radio broadcasts, television advertisements and newspapers to address societal stigma towards survivors of violence. Both partners also get support to document cases of domestic violence, and use this evidence to push forward&#xA0;legislation criminalizing domestic violence legislation. Using the momentum of Covid-19 to push for transition and long-lasting change of norms.&#xA0;
Objective 3: Law and Policy change and its implementation
For more than six years MADRE and OWFI have been leading a campaign, in collaboration with other Iraqi women&#x2019;s and human rights organizations, for the passage of Iraq&#x2019;s draft Family Violence Protection (FVP) Law with a proposed amendment that would allow for&#xA0;NGO-run shelters. During 2020 a major public education and advocacy campaign was launched in order to get community support for the passage of the law,&#xA0;including pressuring parliamentarians to pass the law. MADRE has used its international&#xA0;platform to advocate&#xA0;directly with UN entities in Iraq as well as raising the issue of the law and its shelter provision in international mechanisms through human rights reports, the NGO Working Group on Women, Peace and Security and in bilateral meetings.&#xA0;In August the&#xA0;draft was approve in the cabinet and was forwarded to the Council of Representatives for debate, which included the&#xA0;amendments suggested by MADRE and OWFI.&#xA0;
In DRC&#xA0;MADRE and its partner&#xA0;SOFEPADI are pursuing the passage of a legal framework to prevent, and provide justice and reparations for, all forms of domestic violence in the DRC. They have used the global momentum of debate of raised levels of domestic violence to start an informational media campaign of mixed Covid-19 and domestic violence prevention messaging&#xA0;to raise awareness and has&#xA0;laid the groundwork for the &#x201C;Campaign to End Domestic Violence and Ensure Access to Services and Justice for Survivors.&#x201D; Through the campaign they will also establish the country&#x2019;s first national observatory on domestic violence as a tool to show its extent and call for increased access to and the provision of services and justice for survivors.
Goal 2: Building a just peace
Objective 1: Capacity building
Supporting Ixil&#xA0;women survivors of genocide in Guatemala and building&#xA0;their self esteem,&#xA0;promoting&#xA0;intergenerational leadership&#xA0;and economic independence has led to more women taking place in local politics.&#xA0;In 2020 three Indigenous women leaders of MUIXIL in Chajul&#xA0;were elected to the Indigenous Mayor&apos;s office and are the district&#x2019;s only female representatives.&#xA0;
MADRE convened several joint gatherings to bring partners together&#xA0;and create learning and cross-fertilising of ideas and strategies. A&#xA0;delegation of Indigenous women and girls from Latin America, Asia, and Africa joined for eight virtual events to exchange strategies for preventing Covid-19 and addressing the social, economic, and political impacts of the virus in their communities.&#xA0;MADRE also held six virtual sessions connecting women leaders from partner organizations in the Middle East and North Africa (MENA) region. Those had never before had the opportunity for in-person joint discussion and organizing due to security threats, visa restrictions, and denial of women&#x2019;s rights to travel independently.&#xA0;The knowledge sharing and relationships&#xA0;built during the sessions create transnational solidarity and plant the seeds of a wider MENA women&#x2019;s movement. The partners&#xA0;are reported to having&#xA0;identified several ways to collaborate and continue to learn from each other in the future.&#xA0;
In times of increased digitalisation a&#xA0;webinar for rural girls with disabilities was held on &#x201C;how to join a webinar&quot; as a way to reach&#xA0;first-time information technology users and giving them opportunities to persons who would otherwise be excluded from critical online learning, organizing, and advocacy, to participate and lead.&#xA0;
Objective 2: Movement building and strategies for change between women&apos;s rights activists
In Iraq, MADRE and&#xA0;OWFI&#xA0;have&#xA0;gathered over a dozen Iraqi CSOs annually, and often biannually, for &#x201C;Strategies for Change&apos;&apos; workshops in Iraq. As a result of growing collaboration between these CSOs, MADRE secured a new grant supporting OWFI, the Handicap Union of Kurdistan (HUK), the Kurdish women&#x2019;s organization Asuda, and the LGBTIQ rights organization IraQueer to launch a formal partnership. Together, these organizations are mobilizing to protect marginalized communities, including LGBTIQ persons, women, girls, Afro-Iraqis and people with disabilities, from bias-motivated violence, increase access for these groups to essential services and legal protection, and grow their advocacy abilities to achieve policy and legislative change. Each organization also hosted empowerment sessions with at-risk communities and also launched a small grants program to support local projects led by marginalized community members themselves. Especially for the LGBTIQ&#xA0;movement - who face security issues - MADRE reports that the shift to remote organizing during the pandemic was uniquely beneficial.
At global level the FIRE Consortium - comprising of MADRE, WILPF, Kvinna till Kvinna, and medica mondiale--released a set of feminist principles for a meaningful ceasefire and hosted a virtual panel discussion titled &#x201C;Violence, Ceasefires, and Transformation: The Potential in Our Hands&#x201D;. The event was well attended&#xA0;by representatives of the UN, national governments or agencies, missions, and other representatives from INGOs, NGOs and grassroots organizations. From the discussion, FIRE will continue to build upon its feminist principles to support the UN Secretary-General&#x2019;s call for a global ceasefire as part of its collective response to Covid-19. Notably, WILPF is also an integral member of MADRE&#x2019;s global domestic violence campaign.
Objective 3: Strengthening women&apos;s participation in peace processes and securing redress for conflict-related gender-based crimes
With MADRE&#x2019;s support, Food4Humanity (F4H) in Yemen trained more than 200 local organizers and health workers to carry out their urgent work of providing food, health care, and clean water to communities impacted by conflict, displacement, famine and multiple disease and virus outbreaks.&#xA0;
Peace Track Initiative&#xA0;in Yemen continue to provide life-saving and protection and support programs for women human rights defenders and survivors of violence, which MADRE seeded in 2019, and which is now operational and has over the period helping persons&#xA0;who have&#xA0;been kidnapped, trafficked or detained and abused. One case was referred to PTI by the Group of Eminent Experts on Yemen which shows PTI&#xB4;s the&#xA0;growing reputation and leadership among international stakeholders.
In 2019, MADRE led an international effort, bringing together grassroots and global organizations across movements, to ensure that the newly proposed Crimes Against Humanity (CAH) treaty adopts a broadened definition of gender. In 2019&#xA0;the International Law Commission (ILC) formally recommended a draft in line with this and, if passed, could mean a new era of accountability for gender-based crimes. MADRE and partners worked this year to defend the draft CAH Treaty and advocate various member state, made briefing notes etc to enable a good process. The change would signify a major win for women&#x2019;s and LGBTIQ rights. The final adoption is still pending.
Planned community hearings on gender-based crimes and other atrocities committed by ISIS had to be post phoned&#xA0;as Covid-19 restrictions would not allow for it. Instead a thorough groundwork and&#xA0;planning process has taken place, including creating a broader network. MADRE and oWFI for example signed agreements with the United Nations Investigative Team for Accountability of Da&#x2019;esh&#xA0;(UNITAD) and the International, Impartial and Independent Mechanism for Syria (IIIM) to provide their extensive documentation of gender-based crimes committed by ISIS and are working closely with both bodies to ensure the community hearings are complementary. The first hearing is being planned for early 2021, with a total of four hearings scheduled from 2021 through 2022.&#xA0;This strategy is already manifesting in MADRE&#x2019;s work with local partners in Colombia, where it established the national observatory on gender-based and racialized crimes committed against Afro-Colombians, and now in the DRC, with the&#xA0;plans to establish a national observatory on domestic violence.&#xA0;
In Colombia, MADRE led trainings for PCN members on human rights advocacy and supported PCN&#x2019;s direct testimony and participation in bilateral meetings with UN bodies and other human rights mechanisms, including the Universal Periodic Review, CEDAW, the UN Security Council (UNSC) and UN Special Rapporteurs, to ensure the Ethnic Chapter of the Peace Accord is implemented.&#xA0;In January, April and July of 2020, during the UNSC quarterly reviews of Colombia, MADRE and PCN submitted briefings on ongoing violence and insecurity in black communities, particularly as Covid-19 has been an opportunity to increase military presence rather than improve access to basic services and infrastructure.&#xA0;PCN&#x2019;s presence in policy spaces such as these has effectively raised awareness and influenced the actions of national and international policymakers around Afro-Colombians, especially women&#x2019;s recommendations for peace implementation . Several UNSC members incorporated the recommendations and the information shared into their statements.&#xA0;
Goal 3: Advancing Climate justice
Objective 1: Capacity building
In Kenya MADRE&#xB4;s support to Indigenous Information Network, an Indigenous women-led organization, have improved food security for pastoralist women and families as well as enhanced their overall health and quality of life. With MADRE and IIN&#x2019;s training and resources, women have also strengthened their understanding of food storage techniques, which has helped sustain their families through long periods of drought.&#xA0;During this grant period, the women of IIN produced 70 000 seedlings for planting, helping to significantly combat desertification and promote reforestation, including in the Mau Forest.&#xA0;
During 2020 MADRE launched climate justice programming in the Middle East. In partnership with Gaza Urban &amp; Peri-Urban Agriculture Platform (GUPAP), a multi-stakeholder, participatory forum of 80 member-organizations, MADRE is supporting the development of a sustainable and resilient urban and peri-urban agricultural sector in Palestine.&#xA0;MADRE reports that the participants have become well-oriented with business planning and management as well as more efficient production methods. Also in Palestine, MADRE resourced Dalia Association, a community foundation, to support a community-led project for small-scale women farmers. Women farmers participated in trainings on organic farming with a local community farm and learned how to minimize environmental impacts through chemicalfree farming practices. The&#xA0;VIVA Girls initiative will also be used, by Dalia Association, to advance the rights of Palestinian girls to imagine and implement similarly effective and innovative project ideas that benefit their communities and respond to local needs.&#xA0;
Objective Two: Movement Building
Through VIVA Girls, MADRE is partnering with IIN in Kenya and the Pastoralist Information Development Organization (PIDO) in Tanzania to grow the knowledge and self-confidence of Indigenous young women and girls, strengthen their leadership, and build girls&#x2019; support networks within and across communities in East Africa.&#xA0; 14 workshops were orginaised, creating safe spaces and informal supporting networks for over 700 Indigenous girls. As&#xA0;a result of the workshops, MADRE and partners were able to start drawing connections for the girls between the impacts of climate breakdown and issues of violence in their lives, like early marriage, helping to cultivate girls&#x2019; engagement in the movement for climate justice. IIN plans to utilize the data collected for the workshop series to contribute to a larger data set on the current situation, needs and priorities of Indigenous girls.
Global. Building on consultations held in 2019 with MADRE&#x2019;s Indigenous partners in Guatemala, Nicaragua, Kenya and Nepal, MADRE and the International Indigenous Women&#x2019;s Forum (FIMI) continued to advance its global movement building campaign for a general recommendation to CEDAW to better protect the individual and collective rights of Indigenous women and girls.&#xA0;MADRE and FIMI participated in a Global Meeting of Indigenous Women in Mexico City.
Objective 3: Advancing law and policy change and implementation
MADRE launched its policy brief &#x201C;Towards an Indigenous Women-led Just Recovery,&#x201D; drawing from months of consultations with Indigenous women and girl partners across Africa, Asia, and Latin America. The brief maps key policy solutions to address the systemic and root causes of current crises while ensuring the identity, dignity, rights, and leadership of Indigenous women and other front line communities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12487" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1120103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2017-01-01">
    <sida:title>Sustainable peace 2017-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>H&#xE5;llbar fred 2017-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
