<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5404014601-GGG-13040</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Universal Access to Female Condoms 2013-2015</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Universal Access to Female Condoms 2013-2015</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Programmets m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att &#xF6;ka eferfr&#xE5;gan och utbudet p&#xE5; kvinnliga        kondomer. Ett annat m&#xE5;l att st&#xE4;rka det globala och nationella st&#xF6;det  f&#xF6;r kvinnliga kondomer. Tre pilotl&#xE4;nder- Nigeria, Cameroon och        Mozambique - har identifierats.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the programme is to increase the demand and supply   of female condoms. Another objective is to strengthen the global and  national support for female condoms. Three pilot countries - Nigeria, Cameroon and Mozambique - have been identified.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21501" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21501" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="130" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population Policies/Programmes &amp; Reproductive Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STD control including HIV/AIDS</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">522016.8273659645</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">874648.3184886078</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1732053.6699370055</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">701221.2937532869</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">522016.8273659645</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">874648.3184886082</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1732053.6699370055</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">701221.293753287</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-09-01">4606030.829699</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-09-28">522016.8273659645</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-05-28">874648.3184886078</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-05-28">711802.8780563036</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">1020250.7918807019</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-28">701221.2937532869</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2015Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: In March 2016, UAFC celebrated the WHO/UNFPA prequalification of two new female condoms.  UAFC contributed to this achievement through support to functionality studies and technical assistance to the manufacturers concerned in preparing their product dossiers. UAFC advocacy partners, in close collaboration with other implementing partners, increased the visibility of female condoms in Nigeria, Cameroon and Mozambique and &#x2013; even more importantly - increased the interest and commitment of their governments in female condoms.The social marketing programmes in Nigeria and Cameroon continued awareness raising and distribution of female condoms in 2015. Despite some serious logistical challenges in Cameroon during 2015, at the end of the year again, hundreds of people were trained, educated and able to buy and use female condoms. A reserve stock of condoms remaining at the end of their respective project periods (March and December 2015) will facilitate both SFH and ACMS to continue their work, even after closure of the UAFC programme. In Mozambique, where UAFC partners depend on availability through the public sector, the supply chain management system was strengthened through the various interventions from UAFC technical and local partners. 

OPO1: increased availability of a variety of affordable and quality female condoms

During this reporting period, UAFC has worked closely with FC manufacturers by providing technical assistance in meeting international and national regulatory requirements, conducting system-level assessments to understand FC supply chain flows in various countries and facilitating professional networking and partnerships with relevant stakeholders. This has proven to reduce barriers and has helped manufacturers in advancing their products in different markets whilst contributing to overall UAFC goals. One of the most important milestones reached during this reporting period was the prequalification of two new FCs in March 2016. At national level, the UAFC country programmes in Cameroon, Nigeria and Mozambique continued creating and using traditional and non-traditional outlets to increase the availability of FCs. UAFC ensured the supply of FCs to Cameroon, while UNFPA procured for Nigeria and Mozambique. For sustainability reasons, the lead partner in Cameroon, Association Camerounaise pour le Marketing Social continued its discussions with key stakeholders for FC contributions. In Nigeria, the implementation phase of the project ended in March 2015, but Society for Family Health (SFH) continued distribution of FC2s and prepared the ground for continuation of distribution after closure of UAFC, by integrating FCs in a number of programmes funded by other donors. FCs in Mozambique are made available by the Ministry of Health and the National AIDS Council in Mozambique, whilst procurement takes place via UNFPA. In 2015, the FC supply chain system was strengthened through the various interventions implemented by UAFC. In 2015, partners in the three programme countries distributed over one million FCs, adding up to nearly 8 million FCs distributed in Cameroon, Nigeria and Mozambique, 2012-2015.

Examples of  results from country programmes:

CAMEROON
The availability of FCs at project sites improved considerably 2012-2015, and UAFC multi-annual output and outcome targets were met or overachieved. A total of 336,450 units of Protectiv&#x2019; were sold during the year (up to and including Q1 2016) in UAFC outlets as follows: 82% by the community network, 18% by the commercial network and 1% by the pharmaceutical network, demonstrating the continued importance of the community network (community-based organizations and contracted hair salons) in distribution. A total of 6041 units Protectiv&#x2019; were distributed for free.

NIGERIA
UAFC partner SFH distributed 237 088 FC2s in Q1 2015, representing 47% of the target for Q1. Distribution was also low for the entire period of phase II reaching 76% of the multi-annual target. In total 3 026 303 FC2s were distributed in Nigeria in phase II, of which 2 065 896 were sold and 960 407 distributed for free. As mentioned in the annual report 2014, a major reason for this was that the re-registration of the UNFPA donated condoms took much longer than expected.
Since availability of FC2 has been low during part of phase II, due to slow release of the UNFPA donated condoms, it is assumed that many outlets have suffered stock outs at one time or the other, and that consequently so-called &#x201C;product penetration&#x201D; has suffered for a prolonged period.

MOZAMBIQUE
In 2015, a total of 202 053 units of FCs were distributed in the Pathfinder catchment areas, which exceeds the annual target (447%). The multi-annual target (2014-2015) was also overachieved (354%) with a total 256 603 FC2s distributed by December 2015. This was achieved by 26 operational outlets, 18 health facilities and 8 CBOs, in total, 113% of the multi-annual target.
Out of a total of 18 health facilities supported by the project, 16 did not have stock ruptures in 2015. None of the 8 CBOs involved in the project experienced a stock out. Although it was not possible to attain 100% of prevention of out-of-stock, significant progress was made in terms of increasing availability of FCs in project sites.

OPO2: increased demand for and correct, consistent and sustained use of female condoms

The partners in the UAFC country programmes reached out to people using interpersonal communication (IPC) conductors, peer-to-peer trainers, mass and social media. It remains important to give people adequate information on the product, including benefits and correct usage, and explain how to introduce it to one&#x2019;s partner. Specific targeted information was also directed to groups of professionals such as journalists and pharmacists. In sum, the partners in the three programme countries sensitized over half a million women and men in 2015, amounting to almost four million over the period 2012-2015. During 2015, all three countries&#x2019; partners continued building relationships with key stakeholders such as UNFPA, national AIDS organizations, ministries of health, and worked towards integrating FCs in other donor-funded programmes and initiatives.

Examples of results from country programmes:

CAMEROON
In the fourth quarter of 2015, ACMS carried out a Tracking Progress Continuously survey in order to track progress (compared with the previous made in 2012) in knowledge, attitudes and behaviour in relation to female condoms among the population in the regions where the project is implemented. The percentage of women who indicate that they used the FC the last time they had sex with a non-regular (higher risk) partner &#x2013; among those that had sex with non-regular partner in the past 12 months - increased considerably from 3.8% to 8.8%, while the same percentage for men increased slightly from 1.7% (2012) to 1.9% (2015), and for youth between 18-24 from 1.5% to 1.8%.

NIGERIA
Sensitization targets were achieved both for Q1 2015 and for phase II as a whole. In Q1 2015, 224 986 women and men (41% men) were sensitized on FCs through interpersonal communication, which is 100% of the planned target for Q1. Throughout phase II, in total 2 348 352 women and men (39% men) were sensitized, or 98% of the multi-annual target. The target for men was slightly overachieved, also reflecting the attention given to male involvement.Training targets were overachieved. It is assumed that this high investment in training and sensitization will have led to an increase in the percentage of women and men in targeted provinces knowing how to correctly use the female condom and feeling able to convince their partner to use the female condoms.

MOZAMBIQUE
The programme was not only successful in meeting the targets but also exceeded the project goals. 15 617 women and men were reached (32% men) with messages on the benefits and usage of FC in 2015, exceeding the annual target (367%). Over the whole project period (2014-2015), 24 278 women and men were reached (37% men), representing 289% of the multi-annual target. Training targets were exceeded as well, with 57 women and men trained in 2015 (143% of annual target) and 296 women and men in total (282%). 7 of the 8 partners trained on female condom programming in 2015 started integrating female condoms in their programmes, bringing the total number of new partners who integrated female condoms during the project period to 12, which is again largely exceeding the multi-annual target (240%).

OPO3: increased international and national support

Learning from UAFC programming and market intelligence have been instrumental in UAFC advocacy towards donors and international institutions. Progress has been made and UAFC has been successful in keeping the FC on the international agenda. UAFC assisted the in-country advocacy partners in Nigeria and Cameroon by providing training and technical advice on FC advocacy. Continued advocacy towards large implementing organizations has not yet led to increased funding for FC programming, therefore advocacy efforts will continue after 2015, building in particular on established relationships. An important achievement of global FC advocates is the fact that since 2012, FCs are among the three family planning methods within the list of 13 essential commodities of the United Nations Committee on Life Saving Commodities. Furthermore, support grew among stakeholders, including the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, John Templeton Foundation, Pathfinder International, and International Planned Parenthood Federation (IPPF). The second Global Female Condom Conference, organized by UAFC partners in collaboration with Maternal, Adolescent and Child Health Department, Population Services International and the Centre for Health and Gender Equity, was celebrated in Durban in December 2015. The conference gathered all major stakeholders in the FC field.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="54040146" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
