<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5400012301-GGG-43010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">OHCHR BASBUDGETST&#xD6;D 2012-2015</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OHCHR CORE SUPPORT 2012-2015</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">OHCHR BASBUDGETST&#xD6;D 2012-2015</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OHCHR CORE SUPPORT 2012-2015</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="41313" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OHCHR/Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41313" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OHCHR/Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisector aid</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">7386724.578587363</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">12282748.879199164</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">7288735.9874050645</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">6228275.182992657</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">7386724.578587363</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">12282748.879199164</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">7288735.9874050645</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">6228275.182992657</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">34348269.290431</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-09-28">7386724.578587363</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-06-28">7676718.049499477</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">4606030.829699687</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-07-28">7288735.9874050645</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-04-28">5931690.650469197</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">296584.5325234599</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2015Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: BACKGROUND
In 2012 (2012-002329) Sida decided on a total budget of 254 MSEK for the implementation of the Management Plan of the Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights (OHCHR) between 2012-2015. The agreement was first to support the OHCHR Management Plan (OMP) for 2012-2013 which would later be replaced by the Management Plan for 2014-2017. The agreement with OHCHR has been administrated by Sida&#x2019;s Department for Democracy and Human Rights (earlier the Department for Global Programs) and included both un-earmarked core support for the period 2012-2015 with contributions of 50 MSEK per year,  as well as ear-marked support to the country programs or projects on country level funded both from the allocation for the strategy for democracy and human rights (from hereon called DEMO-strategy) as well as  from the country allocations. Earmarked funding for the OHCHR country office in Myanmar was also added to the agreement and funded from the allocation for the DEMO-strategy. Funds from the original decision was divided to respective country as below:
-	Guatemala: 5 MSEK for 2012 and 5 MSEK for 2013
-	Uganda: 5 MSEK for 2012 and 5 MSEK for 2013
-	Cambodia: 3 MSEK per year 2012-2015
-	Colombia: 7 MSEK for 2012 can 7 MSEK for 2013
-	Kenya: 4 MSEK for 2012 and 4 MSEK for 2013 

During the agreement period, 7 amendments to the agreement have been made, resulting in a total contribution of 408,5 MSEK from Sida to OHCHR; 256,5 MSEK from the allocation for the strategy for democracy and human rights, and 152 MSEK from the respective country allocations The amendments were the following: 

1) 2013-003251 (20131025):  Additional funds of 12 MSEK were added and earmarked for Colombia. Funding from the country allocation.  
2) 2013-003929 (20131209): Additional funds of 30 MSEK were added, whereof 20 MSEK was provided as un-earmarked and 10 MSEK was provided as earmarked for Myanmar. Funding from the allocation for the Democracy and Human Rights strategy. 
3) 2014-003084 (20141113): Additional funds of 46 MSEK were added for 2014-2015. 14 MSEK  for Guatemala, 24 MSEK for Colombia, 8 MSEK for Kenya and 14 MSEK to Uganda. From respective country allocation.
4) 2015-001927 (2015-05-20): Additional funds of 9 MSEK for Guatemala from the country allocation.
5) 2015-002569 (20150709): Additional funds of 11,5 MSEK added. 9 MSEK to Guatemala (from country allocation), 2,5 MSEK for Myanmar (from DEMO allocation).
6) 16-000872 (20160623): 37 MSEK for the year 2016 was added, which added 14 MSEK for Guatemala, 12 MSEK for Uganda, 3 MSEK for Cambodia, and 8 MSEK for Colombia. Funding from respective country allocation. The amendment also included a non-cost extension for Myanmar, funded from the Democracy and Human Rights strategy.
7) A-30/16 (20161114): 4 MSEK was added for Colombia (from the Colombia country allocation)

Sida/DEMO has followed-up the core contribution and managed the agreement with OHCHR that covered both the core funding and the  earmarked funding to the mentioned country programmes. The responsible Sida programme managers in the respective countries have had the responsibility to monitor and follow-up the program in their country. One exception has been the contribution made to support the OHCHR office in Myanmar, which was funded through ear-marked funds within the core support which also entails that the responsibility for follow-up has been on Sida HQ. 

In 2016, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs took over the core funding from Sida. Since this information came late and therefore Embassies had not planned for their own assessments it was agreed between the MFA and Sida to extend the agreement for the country programmes for 2016. This included, a non-cost extension for the ear-marked funding to Myanmar due to significant delays in implementation.

Thus, Sida&#x2019;s assessment of the agreement period for the core funding will include the years 2012- 2015, as well as the progress during 2015- 2016 in Myanmar. While it was clear that the respective Embassy has the responsibility follow-up the country programs it was not clearly agreed if that also included formal follow-up including documenting. This goes particularly for 2012-2013 and those countries which were funded from the global allocation. From 2014, all country programmes (except for Myanmar) have been funded from their respective country allocation and the only delegation to DEMO has been the right to sign the agreement in their behalf.

During the agreement period, OHCHR adopted a new four-year Management Plan valid from 2014-2017. The new plan builds upon the previous plan for 2011-2013 but has been adjusted and updated. The results and indicators have thus been further developed and clarified in relation to what has originally been inserted into the Sida follow-up system as results and indicators. However, the general content remains. Although, due to the updated results assessment framework and revised targets it is not possible to quantify the achievements by OHCHR which is why focus in the concluding assessments will be on the achievements presented in the annual report for 2015, which is the latest within the core support from Sida. 


RESULTS
The mandate of OHCHR is to promote and protect human rights and to further implementation of human rights standards everywhere. OHCHR cooperates with governments, parliaments, judicial authorities, police and prison officers and civil society actors. OHCHR&apos;s work encompasses three broad areas (i) human rights standard setting, (ii) human rights monitoring and reporting, and (iii) supporting the implementation of human rights obligations by states. In addition, OHCHR has the main responsibility for mainstreaming human rights and is expected to provide expertise on human rights to the rest of the UN system.

During the agreement period, OHCHR has achieved significant results. The activities have been well planned and within a range of different levels and areas. In the annual report for 2015, which was the final year of Sida&#x2019;s core support, OHCHR states that considerable progress has been achieved and an estimated 19% of national expected accomplishments were fully or partially achieved and good progress was made on 35% of those expected accomplishments. At the end of 2015, OHCHR was operating or supporting 65 field presences.

Selected highlights and examples of the achieved results in 2015:

1. Strengthening international human rights mechanisms:
23 % of national expected accomplishments were partially or fully achieved and good progress were made on 62 %. In total, 51 new ratifications of or accessions to human rights treaties took place in 2015. In the African region, the Gambia acceded to the Optional Protocol to the Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities (OP-CRPD); Niger ratified the International Convention for the Protection of All Persons from Enforced Disappearance (ICPPED); Somalia ratified the Convention on the Rights of the Child (CRC); while South Sudan acceded to the Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination against Women (CEDAW) and its Optional Protocol (OP-CEDAW), the Convention against Torture and other Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment (CAT) and its Optional Protocol (OPCAT) and the CRC.

In the Pacific, the Marshall Islands ratified the Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities (CRPD); the Optional Protocol to the Convention on the Rights of the Child on the involvement of children in armed conflict (OP-CRC-AC) was ratified by Kiribati and Micronesia; and Fiji committed to ratify CAT during its Universal Periodic Review (UPR), albeit with reservations.

In the Americas, Argentina, Chile, El Salvador, Peru and Uruguay ratified the Optional Protocol to the CRC on a communications procedure (OP-CRC-IC); and Belize ratified the International Covenant on Economic, Social and Cultural Rights (ICESCR) and OP-CAT. Member states continued to engage with international human rights mechanisms and in relation to the Human Rights Council at least 150 meetings took place. 21 least developed countries were financially supported to be able to participate. Member states also continued to engage in the UPR process and 42 member states had their human rights records reviewed. Several countries established national mechanisms to report and respond to the recommendations including the development of national human rights action plans. OHCHR provided training and capacity building on the treaty body system. In 2015, the human rights treaty bodies considered a total of 173 state reports. Special procedures mandate-holders carried out 76 country visits to 53 states and territories. The response rate to communications remained unchanged at 42%.

The participation of NGOs in the Human Rights Council improved by a 25% increase in the number of NGOs that delivered statements during the sessions and a 27 % increase in the
number of side events as well as submission of 60% more written statements than in 2014. Overall, registered individual communications increased to 307 while registered requests under the urgent action procedure of the Committee on Enforced Disappearance quadrupled from 50 in 2014 to 211 in 2015. Activities were also undertaken to strengthen the cooperation between the UN and regional human rights mechanisms.

2. Enhancing equality and countering discrimination:
8 % of national expected accomplishments were fully or partially achieved and good progress
was made on 42 %. A number of legislative and institutional changes were implemented by member states to tackle multiple forms of discrimination, including those based on race, gender, disability, ethnicity and sexual orientation. In Serbia, the government issued the final draft of the new national Roma inclusion strategy which includes a strong focus on human rights. In Paraguay a national action plan on the rights of persons with disabilities was designed with the active participation of civil society and adopted by the national commission for persons with disabilities. In relation to people with albinism, the Human Rights Council adopted a resolution to establish the mandate of the Independent Expert on the enjoyment of human rights of people with albinism. OHCHR conducted various capacity building activities that focused on building the capacity of both OHCHR staff and partners to develop their work on the rights of migrants. As an example, in Tunisia, OHCHR collaborated with IOM and ILO to conduct a training session for 20 officials in ministries that deal with migration issues.

3. Combating impunity and strengthening accountability and the rule of law:
15 % of national expected accomplishment were fully or partially achieved and good progress made on 46%. OHCHR reports that there were serious issues in the administration of justice in Burundi, CAR and South Sudan while there were some positive steps in Guatemala, Kyrgyzstan and Mexico. Some progress was made on the implementation of measures to abolish or institute a moratorium on the death penalty. While Fiji, Madagascar, Mongolia, Congo and Suriname abolished the death penalty, a number of states reduced the number of crimes that are punishable by death. On the contrary, no progress was achieved in relation to Iraq as the Government rejected any recommendation to implement a moratoriumon the death penalty. OHCHR&apos;s education and training activities have contributed to the functioning of the judiciary and law enforcement agencies in various countries. In Liberia, a mechanism that is enhancing the human rights training of police has become operational. In Uganda, the Human Rights Commission facilitated training sessions to sensitise 237 participants from law enforcement agencies and local authorities about human rights. Some progress was achieved in the strengthening or creation of transitional justice mechanisms. In the Central African Republic, a task force was created to work on the establishment of the Commission of Truth. The Truth Justice and Reconciliation Commission of Mali became operational. The Truth and Dignity Commission in Tunisia opened 4 regional offices and has filed approximately 17 000 claims. In other situations, obstacles were encountered as in Burundi where the absence of a law on the protection of victims and witnesses prevented it from implementing any substantive activities.

4. Integrating human rights in development and in the economic sphere:
21 % of national expected accomplishments fully or partially achieved and good progress made on 61 %. OHCHR led efforts to mainstream human rights in the work of UN at global and country levels. Through the United Nations Development Group Human Rights working group, OHCHR coordinated the development of a new guidance note on human rights for resident coordinators and UN country teams. OHCHR was also involved in UN country planning processes through supporting the application of a HRBA and prioritising human rights issues.

5. Widening the democratic space:
20% of national expected accomplishments fully or partially achieved and good progress made on 55 %. OHCHR supported the establishments or strengthening of 71 National Human Rights Institutions in 2015. With support from OHCHR, indigenous people in Cambodia were able to claim more than 700 hectares of their land. In 2015, a number of laws were approved or reviewed which limit the ability of civil society actors to associate and express their views but there were also some positive developments in relation to civil society participation.

6. Early warning and protection of human rights in situations of conflict, violence and
insecurity:
23 % of national accomplishments were partially or fully achieved and good progress made on
67 %. A number of positive steps were taken in relation to legislation in relation to gender based violence and trafficking in for example Afghanistan, Malaysia, Nigeria, Guatemala and Jamaica. Protection mechanisms and strategies were implemented by a number of member states to better protect the rights of their populations and bring those responsible for human rights violations to justice. The National Human Rights Commission of Nigeria deployed approximately 300 monitors to the North East and North Central zones as part of a mechanism to monitor and report on the human rights situation in areas affected by insecurity. In Darfur, the ministry of justice appointed new prosecutors which contributed to an increase in the number of cases brought to the courts. In Burundi, OHCHR set up a hotline to enable right-holders to report alleged human rights violations.

THE SUPPORT TO OHCHR IN MYANMAR
In 2013 Sida provided an earmarked contribution of MSEK 10 to OHCHR. Additional funds of 2,5 MSEK were added in 2015 as well as a no-cost extension to 31 December 2016 with carry-over funds from 2015 due to implementation challenges. Thus, in total MSEK 12,5 was provided by Sida for the OHCHR country office in Myanmar. The funding came from the strategy for human rights and democracy 2014-2017, account no 610701. OHCHR&#x2019;s plans to strengthen its presence and establish a country office in Myanmar has been included in both management plans that have been active during the agreement period, with the long-term goal to establish a country office with a complete mandate including both monitoring of the human rights situation as well as an operative role in strengthening knowledge and capacity on human rights in Myanmar. The decision to support the efforts to establish a country office in Myanmar was based on dialogue between the Swedish representation to the UN in Geneva, the Embassy of Sweden Section Office in Myanmar and the Embassy of Sweden in Bangkok. OHCHRs role in Myanmar was assessed as vital in monitoring and strengthening the human rights situation in the country. In addition, an opening in the political situation in the country was identified both in 2013 and at the time of the national elections in 2015. Due to lack of funds within the country allocation for Myanmar, it was decided that funds were to be channelled within the core support, from the allocation for the strategy for human rights and democracy. 

However, the work in Myanmar has met a number of challenges. Since the formal invitation from the government to introduce a OHCHR country office in Myanmar in 2012, the number of international staff as well as their movement and duration of stay has been closely monitored by the government.The support from the UN in Myanmar has also been relatively weak, and no long-term mandate has been established for OHCHR. Hence, it has not been possible to establish an operational country office yet. In the absence of a country office, OHCHR has operated by sending staff members on mission assignments from its Bangkok Regional Office. This has naturally hindered effective implementation. 

In 2016, the OHCHR Myanmar team was comprised of one senior human rights officer (P5 level), two P3 human rights officers and two national assistants (programme and administration). The team is supported by the Myanmar desk officer based in Geneva. During 2016, OHCHR continued to make efforts to secure a Host Country Agreement for the establishment of a country office in Myanmar. Towards the end of 2016, OHCHR held discussions with the Myanmar Permanent Mission in Geneva to find a way to break the impasse on the setting up of an OHCHR office. Without prejudice to the possibility of signing a mutually agreeable host country agreement on a fully-fledged OHCHR country office in Myanmar, it was agreed that interim measures could be explored for OHCHR to better support the Government and other stakeholders in Myanmar, to strengthen the enjoyment of human rights through technical cooperation and capacity building. These efforts however stalled in early 2017 especially when it appeared that the Human Rights Council would move towards establishing the Fact-Finding Mission on Myanmar.

OHCHR&#x2019;s work in Myanmar has focused on 6 areas. Due to the challenging situation both in regard to the political situation and the funding situation, implementation according to the plan has not been possible. Despite challenging conditions, OHCHR have managed to accomplish some promising results and Sida assesses that the support has been crucial in enabling OHCHR to establish a presence in Myanmar. Below are some examples of results achieved within the focus areas: 

1.	Monitoring, legal analysis and advocacy on the human rights situation in Rakhine, and on discriminatory laws and practise. 

This has been of particular importance in the aftermath of the attacks on the Border Guard Police facilities in northern Rakhine State in October 2016. OHCHR also contributed towards the drafting and review of the High Commissioner&apos;s report to the Human Rights Council on the &apos;Situation of human rights of Rohingya Muslims and other minorities in Myanmar&apos;. The Office also provided advice and support to the Resident Coordinator and UN Country Team in Myanmar relating to the human rights aspects of violence and impact on the civilian population in the area.

2.	Strengthening accountability and the rule of law including through collaboration with the Myanmar Police Force (MPF) to mainstream human rights into their training curriculum
OHCHR has played a convening role with national and international organisations to provide analysis on bills and laws which did not meet with international standards and/or Myanmar human rights obligations to ensure that the continuing law reform process and new legislative action is compatible with international human rights laws and standards. 

Despite repeated attempts to carry on the collaboration from previous years with the MPF, OHCHR has been unable to obtain a meeting with the police. However, OHCHR remained in contact with other actors, such as UNODC and the EU, working on police reform and strategic engagement on MPF support. OHCHR further initiated contact with the General Administrative Department of the Home Ministry. However, the proposed assessment and training of the General Administrative Department in selected pilot locations did not take place due to human resource limitations, which was partly due to visa restrictions. 

3.	Widening democratic space by tracking arrests of human rights defenders and supporting them through targeted training, advice on the use of UN human rights mechanisms and trial monitoring
OHCHR delivered training on the use of the Special Procedures mechanism to civil society coalitions and translated and disseminated documents through key coalitions as well as provided assistance on drafting and submitting information to help generate Special Procedures communications. In particular, OHCHR monitored the case of U. Gambira, a prominent activist and former political prisoner, who was repeatedly arrested and tried primarily for his activism. OHCHR made interventions by raising his case with Government authorities as well as with interested/related members of the diplomatic community and also activated different mandates of the Special Procedures. U Gambira was unconditionally released from prison in July 2015, and all new charges against him were withdrawn.

4.	Continued engagement and technical cooperation with the Myanmar National Human Rights Commission [MNHRC)
OHCHR regularly reached out to MNHRC Commissioners to identify and implement technical assistance and confidence building opportunities through, e.g.. joint monitoring, workshops, translation of treaties, and attendance at civil society meetings to encourage their engagement. OHCHR co-organised a workshop on the rights of minorities in Nay Pyi Taw, in June, with the MNHRC, where Parliamentarians, State representatives, senior officials from various ministries, the Supreme Court and the Attorney-General&apos;s Office, and MNHRC Commissioners and staff participated. Its aim was to facilitate discussion on international human rights standards and mechanisms that apply to minorities, and to identify ways to better protect Myanmar&apos;s minorities.

5.	Increased responsiveness of the international community to potential, emerging or existing human rights crisis situations, with human rights protection as an integral element of this response
OHCHR conducted public advocacy aimed at ensuring that the attention of the international
community in Yangon, Geneva and New York was focused on critical human rights issues in Myanmar, including in relation to accountability issues, discrimination and the situation in Rakhine State. Advocacy efforts included the provision of inputs to briefing notes and talking points, briefings to diplomatic missions based in Geneva and support to missions undertaken by high -level UN officials. 

6.	UN entities in the region apply a human rights-based approach to policing and prosecution of sexual violence; humanitarian operations and international responses to situations of violence and conflict 
OHCHR actively participated in and provided advice to key UN groups and fora in Myanmar. Based on its monitoring, OHCHR shared information on individual cases, trends and patterns which fed into UN notes and documents.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="54000123" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
