<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10697A0201-GGG-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WILPF core support 2017-2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">WILPF k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d 2017-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Transform gendered power. 2. Stigmatize war and violence. 3. Promote a feminist political economy. 4. Movement building. 5. Amplify local and regional change. 6. Improve multilateral actions</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">The Women&apos;s International League for Peace and Freedom &#xE4;r en global kvinnor&#xE4;ttsorganisation som grundades 1915. WILPF arbetar f&#xF6;r att uppn&#xE5; feministisk fred f&#xF6;r j&#xE4;mlikhet, r&#xE4;ttvisa och en avmilitariserad s&#xE4;kerhet genom en tudelad men sammankopplad ansats: genom att adressera grundorsaker till v&#xE5;ld med en feministik ansats och genom att mobilisera f&#xF6;r ickev&#xE5;ldsam aktion. WILPF &#xE4;r en medlemsbaserad organisation med aktiva sektioner i 42 l&#xE4;nder v&#xE4;rlden runt, men fungerar &#xE4;ven som en icke-statlig organisation med programsamarbeten i till exempel MENA-regionen. Sida f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;s ge k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d till WILPF:s internationella sekretariat i Geneve baserat p&#xE5; WILPF:s internationella strategi f&#xF6;r 2017-19.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Women&#x2019;s International League for Peace and Freedom is a global women&apos;s rights organisation, which was founded in 1915. WILPF works to advance feminist peace for equality, justice, and demilitarised security by way of two interlinked paths: by addressing
the root causes of violence with a feminist lens and by mobilising for nonviolent action. WILPF is a membership organization with active sections in 42 countries around the world, but also functions as an NGO with programmatic collaborations in for example the MENA region. Sida provides core support to the WILPF International Secretariat in Geneva based on the WILPF International Strategy 2017-19.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FCG Swedish Development AB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FCG Swedish Development AB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-10" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-10" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.b - Promote and enforce non-discriminatory laws and policies for sustainable development.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.b - Verka f&#xF6;r och genomdriva icke-diskriminerande lagstiftning och politik f&#xF6;r en h&#xE5;llbar utveckling.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.3 - Avskaffa alla skadliga sedv&#xE4;njor, s&#xE5;som barn&#xE4;ktenskap, tidiga &#xE4;ktenskap och tv&#xE5;ngs&#xE4;ktenskap samt kvinnlig k&#xF6;nsstympning.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.3 - Eliminate all harmful practices, such as child, early and forced marriage and female genital mutilation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">63961.5711970525</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">63961.5711970526</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-01">63961.571197</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-28">12358.7776469354</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-28">51602.7935501172</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/fred/10697_Avtalsandring_Amendment3totheAgreementbetweenSidaandWILPF.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreeement Amendment 3 to the Agreement between Sida and WILPF</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/fred/10697_009322-20AmendmentNo2660601_1_1.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment grant agreement Sida WILPF</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/fred/10697_031497-18GrantAgreementbetweenTheSwedishInternational_DevelopmentCooperationAgency2343751_1_1.PDF.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant agreement Sida WILPF</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/fred/10697_015762-17Beslutominsats,WILPFkarnstod2017-20192045149_1_1.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om WILPF k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d 2017-2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/fred/10697_DecisiononAmendmentofContribution(10697).pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om avtalstill&#xE4;gg WILPF, jan-mar 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/fred/10697_003997-20Beslutomandringavinsats,_WILPFKarnstod2017-2021_,(10697)2617235_1_1.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om &#xE4;ndring av insats WILPF k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d 2017-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The report follow the original objectives and contains many interesting results and the below only presents some few high-lights in each area as space is limited. An additional section regarding overall and extraordinary Covid-19 response has been added at the beginning as it has been central to the work undertaken in 2020.&#xA0;
Covid-19 response
Certain activities had to be postponed during 2020 due tot he pandemic, especially internal human resources assessment and the change of the financial system. All of these will continue in 2021. It is also clear that quick adoption&#xA0;to the new realities was possible due to core support from Sida and Oak Foundation.&#xA0;
- Blog&#xA0;series with analysis to further understand the covid-19 context, reaching its own community but also beyond, including a &quot;WILPF guide to documenting and analysing responses to Covid-19 crisis&quot;.&#xA0;
- Advocacy&#xA0;for feminist principles&#xA0;for post-Covid-19 recovery - where WILPF and the FIRE consortium partners&#xA0;(MADRE and Kvinna till kvinna) developed principles which were presented to the UN demanding action in six areas: ceasefire, gender based violence, health, environment, economy and militarism/security.&#xA0;
- The set up of the &quot;Feminist peace solidarity care fund&quot; which provided 24 small-scale grants as short-term interventions by WILPF sections and groups in response to the pandemic.&#xA0;Many Sections and Groups used funds to distribute sanitizers, masks, and hand washing stations to help prevent the spread of COVID-19 in remote or under served&#xA0;communities.&#xA0;Supporting victims of gender-based violence and educating community members about the prevalence and effects of GBV was a primary focus for many funding recipients.&#xA0;Other WILPFers accessed the Solidarity Care Fund to support specific populations facing critical risk factors for COVID-19 and its impacts.&#xA0;The Section&#x2019;s support also extended to individuals with limited literacy &#x2013; the majority of whom are women and girls.&#xA0;Other WILPFers used their funds to help address the issue of food insecurity, which has emerged as a major worldwide crisis during COVID-19.
- Solidarity dialogue in the&#xA0;MENA region between and with partners organisations resulting in a report documenting the changing contexts and current challenges andin support of WILPF advocacy for safer spaces in the region.&#xA0;
Effort have also been made to safe guard the well being of staff when working remotely.&#xA0;
1. Transform gendered power&#xA0;-&#xA0;Understanding of gendered power and meaningful participation for women improves advocacy and actions for peace at global and local levels
Indicator 1.1:&#xA0;Evidence of take-up of gender analysis and women&#x2019;s meaningful participation among stakeholders, policymakers, key debates, and resolutions
Evidence:&#xA0;
WILPF contributed to the potential push back of a draft new WPS resolution which risked undermining gains and previously agreed language&#xA0;on human rights. The resolution was stopped from passing.
Participation and support to participation in high-level foras&#xA0;like&#xA0;Arria&#xA0;Formulation,&#xA0;UNSC briefs, Informal Experts Group on Covid-19 from&#xA0;WILPF&#xB4;s SG as well as local women leaders in Syria, Yemen and Afghanistan.&#xA0;
Research and publications and policy briefs: UNSCR&#xA0;1325 at 20 years: Perspectives of feminist&#xA0;peace activists and civil society, Where are the words? (lack of inclusion&#xA0;of WPS in country specific resolutions) and Bullets are cheaper than sugar (analysis of WPS in&#xA0;MENA)
Improving normative language on gender in HRC&#xA0;resolution on fire arms which was picked up by some member countries.&#xA0;
Contribution to Feminist Political&#xA0;Declaration (alternative to CSW&#xA0;political declaration) with the Womens Rights Caucus.&#xA0;
Indicator 1.2:&#xA0;Evidence of take-up of gender analysis and women&#x2019;s meaningful participation in national/local decision-making processes
The new &quot;Confronting militarised&#xA0;masculinities&quot;&#xA0;initiative was put into operations in Afghanistan, Colombia, Cameroon and DRC&#xA0;and is done in collaboration with Men Engage&#xA0;but was slowed done due to Covid, travel restrictions and escalating violence.
Supporting partners on integrating WPS and human rights advocacy to further teh agenda. In 2020 a fully online concept was used for Yemeni partners which covers UN HR mechanisms and international regulations on arms and resulted in a joint submission to CEDAW.&#xA0;
&#xA0;
2.&#xA0;Stigmatise war and violence&#xA0;-&#xA0;Militarised thinking, systems and technologies of war are challenged at global and local levels
WILPF has pushed the gendered aspects of disarmament for 20 years and the organisation continues to push for the connection between arms control, human rights and WPS. The work also contains lobbying&#xA0;for more ratifications&#xA0;of Treaty on the Prohibition of Nuclear Weapons, militarisation and securitisation&#xA0;of cyberspace and the impact of explosive weapons&#xA0;in populated areas (EWIPA). WILPF is quite alone in this niche&#xA0;of work and use Human Rights&#xA0;fora&#xA0;like UPR and&#xA0;CEDAW to pursue one of its core values.&#xA0;
Indicator 2.1:&#xA0;Evidence of increased strength of analysis, active coalition building and/or shift in thinking/discourse
Evidence:&#xA0;In 2020, 50 ratifications of the Treaty of the Prohibition of Nuclear Weapons was achieved, meaning it entered into force i January 2021. This was the results of consistent efforts of WILPF, its partners and other civil society groups. WILPF has been part&#xA0;of the international advocacy&#xA0;team since 2017. The Treaty is now international binding law on its states parties and have normative&#xA0;effects worldwide.&#xA0;
On the advocacy on accountability of States and of companies WILPF supported partners&#xA0; in Iraq with research and drafting of a report with recommendations - making arguments&#xA0;between the correlations of arms trade and violence against women.&#xA0;
Lifting the inter linkages&#xA0;between arms trade and proliferation&#xA0;of human rights had notable impact in the&#xA0;Committee on Economic, Social and Cultural rights pre-sessions on Italy, leading to the most detailed questions on arms transfers&#xA0;ever made in the Committee (which normally&#xA0;does not address this) and&#xA0;now having this added to List of Issues which countries under review needs to incorporate in their follow-up reports and next reviews.&#xA0;
Indicator 2.2:&#xA0;Evidence of outreach of analysis and advocacy on militarism, technologies and the arms trade
A series of dialogue sessions, &#x2018;Let&#x2019;s Talk Cyber,&#x2019; was held to safe guard&#xA0;NGO inputs to the ongoing consultations of the UN&#x2019;s Open-ended working group (OEWG) on developments of information and telecommunications in relation to international security.&#xA0;
Articulating feminist perspectives on autonomous weapon systems has been applied on killer robots which was put into the focus last year and showed how WILPF can help make the issue relevant to common public. Two WILPF publications applied a broader&#xA0;inter sectional&#xA0;feminist&#xA0;analysis to these weapons in the context of war and policing.
3. Promote a feminist political economy&#xA0;-&#xA0;Feminist political economy (FPE) of peace promoted as a driver of analysis, accountability, and actions at global and local levels
After initially working with this approach&#xA0;in Ukraine and Bosnia and Herzegovina, the concept to capture the gendered nature of the political&#xA0;economy in relation to peace building, WILPF has taken this work further steps ahead. WILPF shows how gender blind approaches to conflict and post-conflict reconstruction have negative impact on peace and has become the leading analytical tool of WILPF which it aims to mainstream both internally and externally.&#xA0;&#xA0;
Indicator 3.1: Evidence of buy-in/take-up of feminist political economy approach in WILPF&#x2019;s advocacy work
Mainstreaming of FPE have included: training for delegates to CSW, integration into submissions to human rights mechanisms&#xA0;(CESCR Ukraine, CEDAW Zimbabwe, UPR Lebanon and for submission to CEDAW on trafficking for recommendation on global&#xA0;migration. advocacy on arms industry and business impact for women).&#xA0;
Indicator 3.2: Outreach of FPE analysis and advocacy in different aspects of WILPF&#x2019;s work
Covid-19 blogs and articles have used FPE analysis when analysing responses and developments&#xA0;to the crisis from a feminist perspective&#xA0;which resulted in the &quot;Feminist Principles for post COVID-19 settlement&quot;.
Participation in two regional&#xA0;panels in South Eastern Europe, speaking on FPE in Covid-19&#xA0; recovery in Bosnia&#xA0;and Herzegovina.&#xA0;
&#xA0;
4. Movement building&#xA0;-&#xA0;WILPF and its contribution to the peace movement are strengthened
The movement continued to be built despite Covid-19, using a variety of methods like small grants to sections, regional meetings and new spaces to support the WILPF community.&#xA0;&#xA0;
Indicator 4.1:&#xA0;Evidence of increased effectiveness of WILPF&#x2019;s internal processes
Communication and Membership&#xA0;work have been strengthened&#xA0;during the year, to increasingly showcase stories and impact to create connection between members and the movement.&#xA0;
Governance and diversity is at the core of the organisational development process WILPF has embarked upon with the support of Peace Nexus. The Black Life Matters movement has also influences WILPF to take clear stance against racism&#xA0;but also to to priorities internal work and commit&#xA0;to safe dialogue on the matter.&#xA0;
Work to include environment&#xA0;has continued and a discussion paper&#xA0;was developed. A webinair&#xA0;series&#xA0;&quot;Down the Green Feminist Road&quot; was conducted, also connecting environment&#xA0;to militarism and&#xA0;holistic principle to environmental&#xA0;activism. This&#xA0;work includes contacts with UNEP&#xA0;to explore collaboration and in-puts on environment has gradually been incorporated in other advocacy&#xA0;work towards the HR-mechanisms (for Lebanon and Yemen in particular).&#xA0;
An Environmental Working Group is established and an internal Environment and an internal Social Responsibility&#xA0;Policy and Action plan is in place.&#xA0;
In December 2020 WILPF had a total of 42 staff and consultants.&#xA0;
Indicator 4.2:&#xA0;Enhanced community of WILPF (Sections, Groups, members, partners) over five years
WILPF has a total of 44 affiliated organisations: 32 Sections and 12 Groups globally. This shows a small downward trend from 2018 (47) but it is due to dormant sections and groups being removed by the board. If including countries where WILPF has partnerships for specific&#xA0;work it means a presence in 49 countries in total.&#xA0;
Small grants to sections to support work related to NAPs, disarmament etc and flexible funding to women&apos;s&#xA0;rights and feminist organisations continued&#xA0;to be important method&#xA0;of this goal. Special focus has been on MENA, partly due to Norwegian funding for this purpose. The solidarity care fund has been a means during Covid-19 to allow for extraordinary activities&#xA0;to address immediate community&#xA0;needs.
Indicator 4.3:&#xA0;Increased engagement of WILPF in coalition, networks, and with partners
WILPF is growing its engagements for collective results and developed over 30 new partnerships during 2020, mainly for advocacy purpose, but also to deepen areas like research, NGO collaboration, sexual rights, accountability of states and companies on arms trade. WILPF also became one of the INGO partners to work with WPHF Rapid Response Window, a new initiative&#xA0;recently also getting support from Sida. WILPF will work in Libya, Afghanistan, Yemen and Syria.&#xA0;
In 2019 the feminist FIRE consortium was formed, amongst others with two other&#xA0;Sida partners (MADRE and Kvinna till kvinna) to strengthen the feminist response and WPS and it grew stronger under 2020. FIRE developed the five feminist principles for meaningful ceasefire during the pandemic (see above).&#xA0;
&#xA0;
5. Amplify local and regional change&#xA0;-&#xA0;Strengthen how women organise, meaningfully participate, and provide gender perspectives on root causes of conflict, conflict prevention, resolution, and peace process at local and national levels
All planned activities&#xA0;and work in focus regions were impacted by the pandemic, however a lot of work could be carried out in all countries but with adjustments.&#xA0;
Indicator 5.1:&#xA0;Local initiatives and activities implemented in focus countries and regions, and documented outcomes
Afghanistan - The peace process&#xA0;has been the focus, to include women&apos;s&#xA0;meaningful participation and enhancing advocacy for girls and women with disabilities. WILPF could help disabled&#xA0;women feed&#xA0;into the peace talks in Doha&#xA0;and shared an&#xA0;advocacy briefing paper to the&#xA0;Minister of Peace which were to be presented to the taliban&#xA0;during peace negotiations.
20 years of advocacy for the official&#xA0;registration of a school for children with hearing impairments was finally successful&#xA0;- part of WILPF work with inclusion and diversity and an educations system accessible&#xA0;by all.&#xA0;
Bosnia and&#xA0;Hercegovina&#xA0;- WILPF started a review process 25 years after the Dayton agreement which will be concluded mid-21 and continued to work and push for an alternative reform&#xA0;agenda&#xA0;on the ongoing process.&#xA0;
Ukraine - WILPF and partners engaged in CESCR&#xA0;process (written statement, oral statements and participation) on womens rights, gendered impacts of cuts in social services, just workings conditions also for IDPs and&#xA0;GBV -&#xA0;many issues were pricked up into the joint&#xA0;report. Also in the CEDAW process a lot of the issues submitted will be included in the follow-up and next reporting cycle.&#xA0;
MENA&#xA0;- Support to feminist grassroots organisations continued in Yemen, Iraq, Syria, Libya, Lebanon and Egypt, strengthening woman&apos;s&#xA0;participation in peace tracks, cross-regional exchanges and arabic&#xA0;feminist knowledge production. For example, training on CEDAW in Yemen, on gender conflict analysis for MENA partners, series of webinairs&#xA0;on Covid and gender justice, submissions to HR-mechanisms. Increased focus on stalled peace processes like local peace building in Libya, Syria and Yemen.&#xA0;
Syria&#xA0;- 13 partner organisations continued to get support in order to enhance influence of women grass root activists in local and national consultations to identify women&apos;s&#xA0;priorities and challenges. WILPF provided safe space in Berlin for its partners to strategize for change. A submission to the Special&#xA0;Rapporteur on Syria on gender perspectives in transitional justice processes, based on broad community consultations.&#xA0;
Yemen - WILPF was actively&#xA0;engaging with the Office of the Special Envoy for Yemen, including Trac&#xA0;2 coordination meetings and on gender and ceasefire. It was also presenting recommendations on how to better include gender sensitive provisions in the joint declaration.&#xA0;
Libya - WILPF has been part of organisations advocating for a fact-finding mission for human rights violations, which was finally&#xA0;put in place by UN Human Rights Council, and the advocacy efforts by WILPF ensured a gender perspective was integrated in the mandate.&#xA0;&#xA0;
African region&#xA0;-&#xA0; the fastest growing WILPF region, many have been active in the Stop killer robot campaign and a lot of cross-learning have taken place between countries etc. WILPF Sweden has actively&#xA0;supported the regional growth and linked chapters in DRC and Zimbabwe with Swedish Embassies and youth networks.&#xA0;&#xA0;
Cameroon - A gender conflict analysis project continued to address the root causes of conflict by collecting data on its impact on women and girls. The project is innovative and uses anthropological&#xA0;approaches to cases of violence. The method is to be adapted in other conflict contexts. Among other things, the project helped to bring visibility internationally and regionally to gender and conflict issues through participation.&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;
Nigeria&#xA0;- In the harsh realities activities and dialogues where held to enable the Nigerian Women Mediators Network operations. A social dialogue platform&#xA0;is created to allow a safe space.&#xA0;&#xA0;
Colombia&#xA0;- LIMPAL&#xA0;had to intensify&#xA0;its works with survivors of GBV during the pandemic as lock-downs severely&#xA0;increased the number of cases. LIMPAL continued to share analysis of the implementation of the peace accord to the UN verification&#xA0;mission.&#xA0;
Korean peninsula&#xA0;- WILPF is part of the Women Cross DMZ and the Korea Peace Now campaign to stop the war. Virtual events were held to build networks and share experiences of the war and its consequences. WILPF gave lectures to various grass root organisations and created interaction.&#xA0;
Indicator 5.2:&#xA0;Frequency of dialogue and shared learning spaces for women&#x2019;s civil society, including examples of follow-up and resulting actions for participants
MENA virtual regional consultations treated Covid response as well as a series of webinairs&#xA0;on regional exchange&#xA0;- safe spaces to discuss how to work under lock-down and share best practise.&#xA0;
&#xA0;
6. Improve multilateral actions&#xA0;-&#xA0;Accountability and integrated policies of the states, multilateral forums actively promoted
WILPF has a long-term strategy to monitor and advocate multilateral foras to increase accountability and transparency and functions as a cross-cutting methodology. WILPF secretariat functions as a bridge&#xA0;between these spaces and the sections and realities on the ground. Results are captured in other areas&#xA0;
Indicator 6.1:&#xA0;Documentation of WILPF monitoring of multilateral processes
WILPF produces Security Council Monitor, National Action Plan Monitor and the UN Monitor. In 2019 WILPF made a strategic shift in the&#xA0;Security Council monitoring to focus more on mechanisms for implementation. It was the final year of the WPS Scorecard monitor of the five permanent members. The human rights program for example made detailed monitoring on the impact of Covid on civil society space at the HRC&#xA0;and its mechanisms.&#xA0;&#xA0;
Indicator 6.2: Documentation of integration of thematic areas in multilateral actions (statements, policies, resolutions, outcomes, etc.)
Despite the challenges a record number of submissions to multilateral foras by sections and partners continued in 2020. In all 52 statements were made to the UN, including 27 written submissions and 19 conference reports. For example, &quot;A submission on the gendered impact of arms transfers to the Office of the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights (OHCHR) was made to advance feminist peace and challenge militarism. This is a particularly noteworthy achievement as some of WILPF&#x2019;s suggestions on gender norms, power, and root causes of violence are reflected in the subsequent OHCHR report.&quot;
Indicator 6.3: Evidence of &#x201C;local to global to local&#x201D; participation and analysis in multilateral forums
This is notable throughout&#xA0;the report and a few additional examples are mentioned here:
-&#xA0;WILPF&#x2019;s disarmament programme contributed to the development of a political declaration against the use of explosive weapons in populated areas being led by the government of Ireland.
-&#xA0;WILPF and its Partner, Peace Track Initiative (PTI), participated at the high-level virtual round table discussion on the impact of conflict on the rights of women and children in Yemen, hosted by the Permanent Mission of the UK based in New York. PTI briefed on women&#x2019;s participation in the peace process and the impact of COVID-19 pandemic on the situation of women in Yemen. WILPF&#x2019;s participation at the event was an important achievement in terms of civil society participation in such a dialogue. It is an ongoing priority for WILPF to work towards diminishing access barriers for civil society participation in government and multilateral forums.
-&#xA0;WILPF Afghanistan Representative Jamila Afghani&#x2019;s participation in the CEDAW committee&#x2019;s session on Afghanistan and in a private round table.&#xA0;WILPF Afghanistan&#x2019;s advocacy within CEDAW is a good example of a section&#x2019;s active engagement with UN human rights mechanisms to advocate for changes at the national level.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10697" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1120103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2017-01-01">
    <sida:title>Sustainable peace 2017-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>H&#xE5;llbar fred 2017-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
