<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="32" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/5650" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HELP-CO-14-5650</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Financial Inclusion and Aging &#x2013; Facts, Challenges and Actions Needed</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge and CFI will collaborate in producing an issue paper, drawing together existing research each organization has done and consulting with experts in aging or financial inclusion. Two non-probabilistic surveys will be implemented: one online questionnaire exploring the global supply side of financial inclusion and the other using in-person interviews to examine the needs and barriers of older adults to a range of financial services and their access to income in Colombia. The paper will frame the main concerns and will offer preliminary recommendations for action and further research. 

Two in-person roundtables will be held, one in Colombia in workshop-style format that tests the initial findings of the issue paper and one in New York to disseminate the results to hand-selected stakeholders and identify action opportunities.  To ensure that the priority actors are present, each roundtable will have 35-45 invitation-only participants. Recommendations will be finalized on the basis of the first roundtable and integrated into the final publication.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Older people</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project&#x2019;s span of concern will be aging and financial services in middle and low income countries, particularly in Latin America, where older persons as a percentage of the total population is rising steeply. Lessons from high income countries may be drawn in, but are not the focus.

The investigation (and resulting issue paper) will begin with a brief recapitulation of demographic and financial inclusion data to lay out the case for attention to financial services in the context of an aging population. 

It will proceed to explore income strategies in older age through direct engagement with mature adults and older people to understand their needs and motivations and drawing on research HelpAge has already done.  HelpAge&#x2019;s prior work has revealed that there is much more variation in income strategies than stereotypical images suggest. We will investigate these patterns further through client-based research in Colombia. 

This work will not be confined strictly to looking at older age. Understanding intergenerational dynamics of household finances is critical for gaining insights on the needs for financial services in later life. Youth unemployment, for example, places a financial burden on the older generation when adult children continue to rely on their parents for housing and subsistence. Large scale migration, as well as HIV/AIDS epidemic, create large numbers of skipped-generation households where children are in care of their grandparents. The emotional and financial cost of this care arrangement is high but unrecognized.

The resulting picture of the varieties of later life income strategies will provide the foundation for moving on to specific financial services needs and issues, such as the following:

Income security
&#x2022;Income security in older age is not only relevant in old age. Preparation for older age requires advanced planning that is necessary at all stages of the life course.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Financial Inclusion (CFI)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-43-1750256" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="COL001" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-43-1750256">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge USA</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HELP-CO-14-5650" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge USA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@helpageusa.org</email>
   <website>http://www.helpageusa.org</website>
   <website>http://www.helpageusa.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-04-01">248000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-43-1750256">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge USA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.helpageusa.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
