<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="32" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/5051" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HELP-MW-10-5051</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advancing Healthy Communities - Affordable, Accessible and High Quality Eye Care</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Older people, children</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to improve the delivery of eye care services for a population of 8 million people across Mozambique, Zimbabwe and Malawi, particularly in rural areas. This is being done by: enhancing the performance of eye health practitioners, thereby increasing the quality and number of cataract operations; providing people with effective and accessible eye care screenings, surgery and support both through primary health providers and referrals to eye-care specialists; and ensuring we leave a legacy of sustainable eye health programs through the promotion of good practices and knowledge of eye-care.

Cataract causes approximately half of blindness in Africa. The incidence of cataract in Sub Saharan Africa far outweighs the annual numbers being surgically treated. This is due to lack of awareness, lack of cataract surgeons and equipment, cost of surgery and poor accessibility especially in rural areas. 

The program will put in place an appropriately trained, functional, multidisciplinary mid-level eye care workforce that will focus on the coverage, quality and sustainability of eye health services to reduce the cataract surgical backlog in the three countries, thereby contributing to poverty alleviation in these countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upgrading of infrastructure and provision of training equipment at the training institutions; Training of 38 cataract surgeons, 46 Ophthalmic Clinical Officers and 400 primary eye care workers; integration of primary eye care with the primary health systems and advocacy for eye health.

Community awareness has been listed as one of the main barriers towards the uptake of cataract surgery. To this end, the program will organize two weekly forums annually in the pilot regions around Old Persons&#x2019; Day and World Sight Day. Sightsavers International&#x2019;s Communications Specialist and HelpAge International will lead in organizing the two forums.

The forums will aim at raising awareness on the project and its activities including cataract operations with departmental heads of government ministries, communities, media representatives as well as a cross section of CBO representatives. These forums will be used to sensitize the communities on the need to seek eye care services and on the role of the community in taking care of older persons within the community.

On increasing awareness on useful eye health practices, the program will also have a series of radio programs about eight weekly sessions per year in each on the three pilot sites. Sightsavers will lead in this activity in Malawi, HelpAge Zimbabwe and Coordinating Council for the Blind will lead in Zimbabwe, while Light For the World and HelpAge International will lead in Mozambique.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-43-1750256" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sightsavers International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="AFR077" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-43-1750256">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge USA</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HELP-MW-10-5051" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge USA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@helpageusa.org</email>
   <website>http://www.helpageusa.org</website>
   <website>http://www.helpageusa.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MW" percentage="33.333333333333336"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="33.333333333333336"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="33.33333333333333"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="8" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-01-01">401327</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-43-1750256">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge USA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.helpageusa.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2010-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="625200"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
