<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="32" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/5648" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HELP-BO-14-5648</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Measuring Healthy Aging</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Defining healthy aging has significant challenges. Standard medical or health outcomes, predicated on measuring improvements in health, are not completely useful within the ageing context. It is likely that the average health status of a cohort of 80 year olds, will be somewhat poorer than an equivalent cohort of 60 year olds. WHO data and research studies from around the world, for example Sweden, confirm that health status as a whole declines with age, despite the best possible medical interventions. By the age of 77, the majority of Swedes will already have two or more chronic illnesses, and this is in spite of the fact that Sweden is the highest ranked country on the Global AgeWatch Index. In two letters to the BMJ in 2005, Ong and Forbes laid out a concept that at the end of life, medicalising this period of life within a procedures driven or targets oriented health system, could result in physical symptoms and their management becoming prioritized, with little consideration given to the balance between medical treatments, length of life and quality of life. They also articulated the idea that certain forms of socially oriented care may come to dominate the overall care package (which must of course, include health care) when at certain stages in late life or at the end of life, quality of life is given priority over mere survival.  Many of these issues are pertinent to the way in which we might successfully measure healthy aging. Health status improvements are perhaps, appropriate markers of an effective health outcome for those who have just entered older age, but gradually, within the aging process, a progressively delicate balance has to be struck between medicalising care (when appropriate) and therefore, extending life; maintaining or improving quality of life, and then finally, managing symptoms and disabilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Within the context of this project, we are also aiming to produce a rapid, easy to use, short-form instrument, that will be suitable for evaluating programs/interventions in low and middle income contexts. 

We will attempt to find a balance between brevity of instrument and a design that will still enable epidemiological data collection and case tracking capabilities. This is a significant challenge, but is much needed by the development and aging community, because rapid assessments, beneficiaries targeting and evaluations of outcomes, often have to be conducted concurrently in remote and isolated communities. 

Partners, country office and rural health center staff have suggested that the interview process should not take up more than 15-20 minutes per person if possible, because of their heavy patient/beneficiary work load.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-43-1750256" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="COL000" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-43-1750256">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge USA</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HELP-BO-14-5648" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge USA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@helpageusa.org</email>
   <website>http://www.helpageusa.org</website>
   <website>http://www.helpageusa.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BO" percentage="50"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="50"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="8" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-04-01">137000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-43-1750256">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge USA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.helpageusa.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
