<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-PB-402-3.2.1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-PB-402" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Network for Bamboo and Rattan</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Restoration of degraded land</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establish bamboo plantations in degraded lands, smallholder farm lands. Overall, it is aimed to restore 1175 hectares of degraded land. During the Year 1 (Oct 2016 - Dec 2017), a total of 302.42 hectares of degraded lands were restored with bamboo plantation with 174, 101 plants. In Ethiopia, a total of 256 hectares were planted with 154, 201 bamboo plants which includes planting of micro-scale plantations in 582 small holder farms (205M/377F) with 7030 bamboo plants. In Kenya, eight hectares of degraded land / river bank planting were undertaken with planting 4000 bamboo plants in Vihiga county. In Uganda, a total of 38.25 hectares of bamboo plantation were established with 15, 900 bamboo plants. During year 2 of the programme, a total of 514.24 hectares were restored with 363,780 bamboo plants. In Ethiopia, 308.92 hectares were restored with 275,011 plants. In Kenya, a total of 89.52 hectares were planted with 36,996 plants.In Uganda, a total of 115.83 hectares were restored with 51,773 plants. During the year 3 of the programme, a total of 761.12 hectares were restored with 455, 925 bamboo plants. In Ethiopia, a total of 402.76 hectares were restored with 310, 459 plants in 43 locations. In Kenya, a total of 216.61 hectares were planted with 89, 806 plants. In Uganda, a total of 141.75 hectares were restored with 55, 660 plants.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="3.2.1" crs-channel-code="10000" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya Forest Research Institute (KEFRI), Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="3.2.1" crs-channel-code="10000" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change, Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="3.2.1" crs-channel-code="10000" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Forest Authority, Uganda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activities towards identification and establishment of bamboo plantations in degraded lands in degraded forest and farm land.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activities were accomplished during the projects timeframe</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="25">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establishment of bamboo plantation in forest and smallholder farmland in different counties of Kenya. The project collaborated with Kenya Forestry Research Institute, Kenya Forestry Service, and with county governments. The project also collaborated with partner NGO&apos;s and CSO such as Green Belt Movement, Climate Change Mitigation Initiative, Eco Green, etc in addition to private sector players.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="50">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establishment of bamboo plantations both in forest, communal and smallholder farmland. The project collaborated at national level government agencies - Ethiopian Environment, Forest and Climate Change Commission, Ethiopian Environment and Forest Research Institute, regional bureau of agriculture and natural resources of Amhara, SNNPRS, Benishalgul Gomuz; local NGO and partner international agencies, etc.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="25">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme collaborated with National level government agencies such as National Forestry Authority, Ministry of Water and Environment; Ministry of Energy, research agencies; Universities: Muni and Mekerere University; local governments; NGO&apos;s and community associations for establishment of bamboo planting.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15" percentage="100" vocabulary="7">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Restoration of degraded lands contributing to climate change mitigation and resilience, and increase in smallholder farmer and community benefits through bamboo- both tangible and intangible benefits.</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
