<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-PB-402-Activity2.1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-PB-402" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Network for Bamboo and Rattan</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Develop INBAR technical guidelines on bamboo products/processing for East African INBAR member states</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICBR and NEN member Arjan van der Vegte of Moso International will work with INBAR&#x2019;s Technical Committee on Bamboo and Rattan Standardization, as well as national standards agencies and bamboo producers in Ethiopia, Kenya and Uganda, to develop technical guidelines for products/processes that the project has identified to have good market potential. These guidelines will act as the basis for East African countries to develop their own industry and national standards, as well as provide a long-term pathway to improve product quality and move towards compliance with EU standards and requirements for bamboo flooring. Up to 8 product/processing guidelines published by month 21. Overall, the programme developed / adopted 14 technical guidelines / manual on bamboo resource and value-chains and the same was translated to local languages (Amharic, Swahili and Madi). The programme supported working group / technical committee meetings with participants from ESA, KEBS, UNBS and key stakeholders resulting in development of 18 national standards and code of practice which are in different stages of approval (Ethiopia: 7 nos; Kenya: 6 nos and Uganda: 5 Nos).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Adal Bamboo</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Center for Bamboo and Rattan (ICBR), CHina</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MOSO Bamboo, Netherlands.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">14 technical guidelines on bamboo resource development and value-chain published. Facilitated development of 18 national standard and code of practice</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity is being planned for next year and the discussions are ongoing with the potential partners.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="34">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Working with Ethiopian Standards Agency, line department ministries and other stakeholders for development of bamboo standards and code of practice</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="33">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Working with Kenya National Bureau of Standards, line department ministries and other stakeholders for development of bamboo standards and code of practice</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="33">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Working with Uganda National Bureau of Standards, line department ministries and other stakeholders for development of bamboo standards and code of practice</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15144" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development of technical guidelines to build capacities of SME and farmers and develop standards and code of practice for SME and industry products</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
