<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-PB-402-Activity2.3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-PB-402" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Network for Bamboo and Rattan</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conduct 3 national awareness campaigns for East African Consumers</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INBAR in partnership with its national focal points will develop and implement a communications strategy for each country based on planned project activities to raise awareness about the potential of bamboo products among key consumer groups in Ethiopia, Kenya and Uganda. These consumer groups will include private households, such as urban markets for charcoal, large public procurement programmes, such as those for school furniture under ministries of education, and several private sector stakeholders, such as horticulture (props, greenhouse construction, and bamboo chips to heat greenhouses) and tea estates (bamboo chips for tea drying). By the end of the project, at least 15,000 East African consumers (a minimum of 5,000 per country) reached through national awareness campaigns that will include &#x2013; National press releases to coincide with bamboo resource assessments and market study publications; production of up to 5 policy briefs for public and private sector green procurement programmes by Month 24; 3 National workshops held by month 24 and 1 regional workshop with high media visibility held by month 36; radio, print and TV communication products released on identified bamboo value chains. Overall, the programme awareness activity reached to 12, 933 participants. Four policy briefs, two national strategy and action plan developed and proclaimed (Ethiopia and Kenya); and one bamboo policy developed and submitted to Cabinet in Kenya. The national strategies and action plan of Ethiopia and Uganda can be found at https://resource.inbar.int/download/showdownload.php?lang=cn&amp;id=168053; https://resource.inbar.int/download/showdownload.php?lang=cn&amp;id=168060. A total of 11 national workshops were organised with a participation of 536 stakeholders for development of national bamboo strategy and action plan. One regional workshop on bamboo policy / strategy organised. Three specific awareness and sensitisation video developed and broadcasted. Facilitated coverage and publication of 27 video and radio programmes / news in national TV and radio channels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya Forest Research Institute, Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Forest Authority, Uganda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National bamboo strategies and action plan developed and awareness videos and radio programmes organised</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National workshops on bamboo will be organized in all three countries involving all the relevant stakeholders.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="34">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bamboo workshops for awareness raising and bamboo sector policy development.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="33">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bamboo workshops for awareness raising and bamboo sector policy development.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="33">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bamboo workshops for awareness raising and bamboo sector policy development.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="31210" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The workshops enabled development of bamboo strategies and action plan</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="99820" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Video, radio and awareness programmes are aimed at creating general awareness and potential of bamboo and enable participation of farmers, SME and industries and also to create market for green products</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
