<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-PB-402-Activity1.3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-PB-402" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Network for Bamboo and Rattan</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conduct 3 national market assessments for Ethiopia, Kenya and Uganda, primarily aimed at identifying bamboo value chains with big potential for upscaling</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The market studies will focus mainly on domestic markets, with a long-term view to supporting East African bamboo producers export their products regionally as well as to the EU. For the studies, national experts and chinese expert teams, consisting of a bamboo agronomist, a bamboo engineer/technologist, and a bamboo value chain and livelihood specialist, will work with the following national and Dutch partners in each country. 3 market study reports will be the key outputs of this activity. A value chain analysis and market assessment of bamboo products in Ethiopia was completed. The report was published online and can be found at http://resource.inbar.int/upload/file/1528002396.pdf A value chain analysis and market assessment of bamboo products in Kenya was completed. The report was published online and can be found at http://resource.inbar.int/upload/file/1527834159.pdf A value chain analysis and market assessment of bamboo products in Uganda was completed and can be found at http://resource.inbar.int/upload/file/1527834301.pdf</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya Forest Research Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Environment, Natural Resources, and Climate Change, Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Uganda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Data collection has started in all three countries. Draft reports will be avilable by mid May, 2017.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="33">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final Draft of the market and bamboo value-chain analysis report in circulation. Shall be finalized by the end of December 2017</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="33">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final draft of the market study and value-chain development report in circulation. Shall be finalized before December 2017</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="34">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Second Draft of the bamboo market and value-chain analysis report in circulation. Shall be finalized by the end of December 2017.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="32162" percentage="100" vocabulary="7" vocabulary-uri="https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/?menu=1300">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Market studies are expected to support bamboo industrial development in the project countries.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-04-10">226612</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
