<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-PB-402-1.4.3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-PB-402" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Network for Bamboo and Rattan</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Develop 1 new composite/ resonated fibre board conversion route for African bamboo.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wageningen UR conduct a technical feasibility assessment for bamboo products manufacturing in Ethiopia, primarily aimed at upscaling of local bamboo use in fibre boards, laminates and composite products. The study will be focussed on local bamboo species for the production of composite products suitable for the local market (timber substitution ) with a long term view on qualities for export markets. The contractor / expert will work with a team of local entrepreneurs and institutions that have access to the relevant network of supply and information on the current state of bamboo processing, wood working and markets in Ethiopia. At the end, improved technical conversion pathways / processes for the manufacture of marketable composites or resonated fiberboards using local bamboo species from East Africa will be developed. In addition, technology transfer and/or capacity building activities will be undertaken.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="1.4.3" ref="NL-KVK-09098104" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wageningen University &amp; Research - Stichting Wageningen Research</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wageningen UR conduct a technical feasibility assessment for bamboo products manufacturing in Ethiopia, primarily aimed at upscaling of local bamboo use in fibre boards, laminates and composite products. The study will be focussed on local bamboo species for the production of composite products suitable for the local market (timber substitution ) with a long term view on qualities for export markets. The Wageningen UR will work with a team of local entrepreneurs and institutions that have access to the relevant network of supply and information on the current state of bamboo processing, wood working and markets in Ethiopia. At the end, improved technical conversion pathways / processes for the manufacture of marketable composites or resonated fiberboards using local bamboo species from East Africa will be developed. In addition, technology transfer and/or capacity building activities will be undertaken.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private sector and industry linked to smallholder farmers</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="32182" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development of new composite bamboo resonate board</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-11-01">45000</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
