<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-PB-402-Activity1.4</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-PB-402" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Network for Bamboo and Rattan</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity development and technology transfer for East Africa bamboo producers on market study-identified value chains.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on the findings of activities 1.1 to 1.3, INBAR will work with all partners in the project to develop a detailed capacity development plan for identified bamboo producing areas and producers across the three countries on themes such as product development and improvement, processing and technology upgrading. In Ethiopia, where there is already a bamboo industry, this activity will focus on improving primary processing and quality of raw materials, as well as improving production management and adherence to quality control and standard processes at factories. In Kenya and Uganda, where the bamboo sector is at an earlier stage of development, this will focus primarily on establishing model community enterprises, which generate local revenue and incentivize bamboo resource development. Dutch expertise under this activity will consist of Wageningen UR working with 1-2 identified bamboo factories in East Africa to develop technical conversion routes for local bamboo species to produce improved marketable composites or resonated fibre boards. Moso International will provide up to 10 days of staff time per year to support identified companies on quality control and standard requirements, with a long-term view to developing trading partnerships. Chinese support for this activity will consist primarily of technical assistance via training from ICBR and other identified Chinese expert consultants. Finally, experts from INBAR will also provide technical assistance and training support to the three countries in partnership with Government focal points and identified local enterprises, research and civil society partners. The main outputs wil be: up to 5,000 East African Bamboo Producers (Ethiopia &#x2013; 3000; Kenya &#x2013; 1000; and Uganda 1000) trained in improved processing, product development and technologies by the end of the project; 3 model enterprises established by month 24; 4 Chinese Ministry of Finance and Commerce (MoFCOM) training courses held &#x2013; 2 in China and 2 in East Africa by end of project; Wageningen UR develops at least 1 improved technical conversion route for E. African bamboo species to produce an improved marketable composite or resonated fibre board by the end of the project. During Year 1 of the programme (Oct 2016 - Dec 2017); a total of 19 training courses were conducted during the reporting period for 457 producers (255 M/ 202 F); out of which seventeen (17) training programs were conducted in Ethiopia for 417 producers (223 M /194 F); two training programs (8 PD) were conducted in Kenya benefiting 40 producers (32 M/8F). One (1) fully sponsored MoFCOM Training of Trainers (ToT) on bamboo furniture and crafts was conducted in Ethiopia from 15 June 2017 to 14 June 2017. The training was jointly organised and conducted by ICBR, INBAR and FeSMMIDA benefiting forty skilled craftsmen (39M/1F) from seven regions of Ethiopia During the Year 2, A total of 45 capacity building training program (506 PD) on bamboo value-chains including two Chinese MoFCOM funded ToT trainings were conducted for 1264 participants (985 M/279 F). A model enterprise in Ethiopia was operationalised during year 2 of the programme. Three MoFCOM training courses were conducted achieving 66 percent of the overall target indicators. DUrring Year 3, 36 skill development programme (134 PD) conducted for 875 (659M/216F) beneficiaries. A total of 11 enterprises were established and /or supported: out of which 2 common production and treatment center (1 each in Kenya and Uganda) and 8 micro enterprises (3 in Kenya and 5 in Uganda) were established with machines, tools and equipment supplied from China (ICBR). The programme in collaboration in Wageningen University and Research (WUR) conducted test and validated the development of bamboo composite from waste arising out of industrial processing.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya Forest Reearch Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Natural Resources, Forest and Climate Change</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Forest Authority, Uganda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="1.4" ref="NL-KVK-09098104" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wageningen University &amp; Research - Stichting Wageningen Research</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activities are accomplished and ended as per project end date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activities are started from November 2016</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="30">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The capacity of the bamboo stakeholders including private sector will be enhanced through capacity building activities and technology transfer. Establishment of common production and training center</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="30">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The capacity of the bamboo stakeholders including private sector will be enhanced through capacity building activities and technology transfer. Setting up of bamboo common production and training centers and micro enterprises</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The capacity of the bamboo stakeholders including private sector will be enhanced through capacity building activities and technology transfer. Technical support to industries, research in collaboration with WUR.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity will promote the value chain of bamboo sector.</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
