<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="4689624" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.inbar.int/project/sino-east-africa-bamboo-development-programme-phase-ii/" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-PB-402-01042020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-PB-402" secondary-reporter="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Network for Bamboo and Rattan(INBAR)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dutch-Sino East Africa Bamboo Development Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing Climate Change Mitigation and Adaptation benefits by developing inclusive and sustainable industrial and SME bamboo value chains resulting in enhanced livelihood opportunities, food security, and environment management in East Africa</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XI-PB-402-01042020" crs-channel-code="21000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Center for Bamboo and Rattan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XI-PB-402-01042020" crs-channel-code="10000" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya Forest Research Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XI-PB-402-01042020" crs-channel-code="12001" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XI-PB-402-01042020" crs-channel-code="10000" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Forestry and Grassland Administration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11000" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program team grounded; Bamboo Site-species matching study initiated with national level reputed environment &amp; Forests Research Institutes; Gender Study on Bamboo in final stage; Baseline survey in the final stage; Bamboo seeds procured from China and India for large scale planting materials production; Capacity building training initiated on bamboo furniture, clean energy, bamboo housing, sustainable bamboo harvesting and management, resource mapping, strengthen bamboo association for encouraging private investors; twenty-two (22-Ethiopia-6; Kenya-7 and Uganda-22) bamboo economic clusters identified diagnostic study report for the clusters in progress. Awareness and sensitization activities in progress i.e. celebrate World Bamboo Day, discussion in progress with TVET for bamboo curriculum, discussion in the pipeline with FSC Global Development GmbH for Forest Stewardship Council(FSC )for 1000 hectare in Ethiopia. An initiative in progress with the Private Bamboo Industry in Ethiopia based on the final report on bamboo-composite research, Wageningen Research, The Netherlands. Discussion and joint action plan developed with SNV in Ethiopia for collaboration in clean energy and entrepreneurship development. Due to CoVID19 pandemic and Government restrictions are challenges to speed-up the planned activities.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Network for Bamboo and Rattan</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Programme</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Selim Reza</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251115579949</telephone>
   <email>selim@inbar.int</email>
   <website>http://www.inbar.int</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">East Africa Regional Office of INBAR, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="3"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="34">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia is the largest bamboo growing country in Africa and having ample opportunity for SME and industrial value chain promotion for poverty reduction and environmental management. The country is having robust Bamboo Development Strategy and Action Plan 2019-30</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="33">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya is having bamboo resource and focusing for SME and industrial value chain promotion for poverty reduction and environmental management.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="33">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda has an estimated 54,533 ha of bamboo growing area.  The utilization of resources is mostly confined to meet the sustenance needs, traditional low value product. The country is having National Bamboo Strategy and Action Plan 2019-30</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="7"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
