<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-21/DDA-3415/SA1/P/INGO/18945</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Immediate Access to Protection through Gender Based Violence, Child Protection and Mine Action Interventions in Kachin</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Provision of Immediate Access to Protection through Gender Based Violence, Child Protection and Mine Action Interventions in Kachin project will provide lifesaving support and assistance to conflict-affected populations. We are targeting ethnic minority groups (Ka Chin, Shan Burmese) in the second biggest state in the country. The project will meet immediate humanitarian protection needs, while building communal self-reliance and resilience through series of capacity building and awareness campaigns for both communities and individual households. The project will target women and children&#x2019;s participation in the activities in order to improve access to gender transformative learning opportunities and access to services. 

The project will assist the whole communities of 15,132 persons (2,789 HHs, 4,909 Women and 4,394 Men, 2,964 Girls, 2,865 Boys) in Kachin State covering 20 villages in 3 townships of Bhamo, Momauk and Mansi. Direct beneficiaries are host communities  2,000 Men, 2,400 Women, 900 boys and 1,100 girls (6,400 people) and 8,732 indirect beneficiaries include 2,394Men, 2,509 Women, 1,965 Boys and 1,864 girls.

This will be achieved through 3 Key Project Outcomes that aims to strengthen the protective environment for crisis/conflict affected girls and boys in Bamaw District, Myanmar.

1. Addressing Gender Based Violence - Men and women understands Gender Based Violence incidents, have access to information and receive appropriate Case Management Support.

2. Promoting Child Protection Initiatives- Training for project staffs and CFS facilitators on CPIE, positive parenting, PFA, MHPSS (Structure PSS) and Safeguarding/ PSEA and establishment and capacity building to CBCPGs and CGs

Children, adolescents and caregivers benefit from MHPSS and CFS and gain enhanced capacity to prevent and protect themselves and peers from violence and exploitation

Children, caregivers and community members have access to information on child protection and receive appropriate Case Management Support.

3. Mine Action &#x2013; Women, Men and Children are knowledgeable about mine risks through education efforts for their protection and security.

The project will also sensitize communities, both men, women and children on gender equality and engage women as participants in activities such as the establishment of Community-Based Child Protection Group (CBCPGs) and Children/ Adolescents groups (CG) in targeted areas. Furthermore, it will integrate Psycho Social Support Services while providing both indoor and outdoor Child Friendly Spaces (CFS) to promote child protection actions.

This 10-month project responds directly to the immediate needs of the vulnerable people as collected through community consultations gathered by ALinn Banmaw (AB) and World Vision Myanmar (WVM) in the target area in May 2021. It also responds to the needs expressed in the MHF Allocation Strategy for 2021 targeting 26,650 crisis affected people for Protection intervention in Kachine State. In addition, these interventions will link directly to the Humanitarian Response Plan Strategic Issued January 2021 (OCHA) Objective 2 Living standards of 886,000 people affected by conflict or disasters in targeted locations are improved and their resilience is strengthened in 2021.

The partnership of World Vision Myanmar (WVM) and ALinn Banmaw (AB) is strongly positioned to deliver this project combining WV&#x2019;s strong technical expertise and AB&#x2019;s proven work experience and presence in the targeted areas of Kachin State specifically in the 20 villages. The project will also coordinate closely with other key actors, especially UNICEF WV has included regular monitoring visits in Kachin which will be timed around coordination meetings allowing for full and active participation while WVM will support AB participation at cluster meetings as required and possible, especially coordination with UNICEF. All relevant project data is shared quarterly with UNICEF as request</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alinn Banmaw Local Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alinn Bamaw</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>ahdin.gam85@gmail.com</telephone>
   <email>Gam Din</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Min Htwe Naung</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Response Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+(95) 9 7955 94210</telephone>
   <email>Min_Htwe_Naung@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Quality and Development</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>Stanlake_Kaziboni@wvi.org</telephone>
   <email>Stanlake Kaziboni</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR001">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kachin</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>26.00000000 97.50000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-28">124496.13</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-28">123677.08</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-18945">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-28">248173.21</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305139087">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-12">198538.57</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
