<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-21/DDA-3415/SA1/E-WASH-SNFI/INGO/18720</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisectoral humanitarian assistance to address the most urgent needs of conflict-affected people in Kachin State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Internally displaced people (IDPs) in Kachin state remain highly dependent on the sustained provision of humanitarian assistance. The military coup and renewal of intense armed conflict between the Tatmadaw and the Kachin Independence Army (KIA) has severely disrupted civilian life, already disrupted by COVID-19, reinforced existing vulnerabilities, and generated new and critically unmet humanitarian needs due to the surge in new displacements. 

The proposed project will respond to the most urgent Education, WASH and Shelter/NFI/CCCM needs of of 35,395 IDPs (9,391 men, 10,545 women, 7,679 boys and 7,780girls) in Bhamo, Chipwi, Hpakant, Mansi, Momauk, Myitkyina, Shwegu, Tanai and Waigmaw townships. Using an integrated multisectoral approach, this intervention will contribute to the reduction of a wide range of immediate and life-threatening risks and improve both the physical and mental wellbeing of vulnerable conflict-affected populations. The intervention will build on and complement PIN and KBC&#x2019;s previous work under MHF funded projects to address needs that remain unmet. Additionally, the partners will work to extend aid provision for the most recently displaced persons through multi-sectoral service delivery in existing IDP sites. 

Education activities will address existing gaps in home-based learning material provision in locations where conflict has escalated since the coup. Learning space renovation and contingency materials will support newly displaced children to access educational opportunities. WASH activities will address critical, unmet needs for water, sanitation facilities and hygiene materials and promotion while Shelter/NFI activities will focus on the provision of safe shelter and kitchen facilities for newly displaced people. CCCM activities will provide on-going camp management by KBC ensuring current and new IDP&#x2019;s needs are supported. This integrated approach enables the scaling up of activities in new locations to address unmet needs of IDP population. 

Through PIN/KBC partnership, the project will benefit from the sectoral expertise and geographical reach of each partner to maximize value for money, experience-sharing, and operational capacity. The inclusion of both a national NGO and international NGO will maximise access and provide contingency options given the current context in Kachin State. It will also allow mainstreaming of best practices, standards and accountability to affected persons, resulting in greater quality of project delivery. 

This project was created based on the outputs from regular community consultations and need assessments and is designed to allow participation of target communities throughout all phases of the project cycle including women, girls and people with disabilities to ensure that services and assistance will meet their specific needs. Using a conflict-sensitive approach, the project will actively contribute to removing the barriers that vulnerable groups face in order to ensure equitable access to essential humanitarian services. Ensuring that assistance reaches vulnerable groups such as women, children, elderly, and persons with disabilities (PwD) will be prioritized throughout all activities. Additionally, the project will offer a gender-responsive approach to the acute humanitarian needs and PIN&#x2019;s recruitment policies will ensure gender-balanced project teams. Duty of Care, Safeguarding and DNH are crosscutting elements throughout all activities of the proposed intervention. Beneficiaries will be engaged in implementation and monitoring of the project and a Complaints and Feedback Response Mechanism (CFRM) will be implemented. The developed MampE plan will ensure timely and quality data collection, with meaningful participation of beneficiaries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kachin Baptist Convention</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-03" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Andrius Kudaba</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director (PIN)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+34 625888209</telephone>
   <email>andrius.kudaba@peopleinneed.cz</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hpauyam Hka Li</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director (KBC)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 9421747412</telephone>
   <email>hpauyamhkali@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR001">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kachin</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>26.00000000 97.50000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="31" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="12" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="57" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-12">163453.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-03"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-12">336779.18</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-18720">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-12">500232.27</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305149264">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-19">300139.36</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
