<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-21/DDA-3415/SA1/FS-H/NGO/19053</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reducing Vulnerability and Addressing Urgent Humanitarian Needs in Southern Shan State.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will enable KMSS to address urgent the humanitarian needs of people displaced in Pekhon township, Southern Shan state due to crisis between Ethnic Armed group and Military occurred in Pekhon Township and Demoso Township (Kayah State).. The project plans to provide emergency food rations, , emergency medical supplies/ aids to the displaced people in 6 displacement sites by crisis Many people from Demoso township, Kayah state, also have taken refuge in Pekhon Township. KMSS has full capacities and resources that KMSS deployed quickly and effectively, thus reducing vulnerability and saving the lives. These pre-positioned capacities and resources will also enable KMSS to address the current humanitarian needs of displaced people. 

This plan of the project will target 13,249 (men 2592, women 3493, boys 3173 and girls 3991) conflict-affected population this include the extremely venerable people those who are pregnant women and 1695 disabled people  among the IDPs in Pekhon  Township, where KMSS-Pekhon is on-going addressing live-saving response actions in benefit of displaced and crisis affected population since crisis erupted between Ethnic Armed group and Military in third week of May. The IDPs are mainly from Mobye town, surrounding villages, Pekhon, eastern part of Pekhon lake (Mobye Dam). In addition, the people from Loikaw and Demoso townships are also taking shelter in western part (remote, rural, mountainous) of Pekhon Township.  
Under this project proposal, KMSS will support food, and health ( to the IDPs affected by armed conflicts in Pekhon Township to meet the urgent needs the displaced people that are taking refuge in Pekhon Township. The support will enable the IDPs have access to food for three months (from August &#x2013; October 2021) and medicine supplies and including COVID-19 will cover for six months (August to December, 2021).

The project activities will prioritize the needs of particularly vulnerable people and gender equality. Preferential treatment in selection processes will be given to female-headed households, women and widows, unaccompanied children (girls in particular), the elderly, people with disabilities, pregnant women and lactating mothers. Support will be provided based on the needs findings and the lesson learnt from the up-to-now experience of KMSS-Pekhon on emergency response in the township. Essential items for different (age, sex, ability, etc.) groups of people is considered and supported accordingly. : KMSS-Pekhon will appoint eighteen volunteers (3 volunteers per each site). Their main roles are to coordinate with project officers for need assessment, data collection, up-to-date information, reporting and carrying out activities throughout the project period.

The 18 volunteers (3 volunteers per location) will work in the camps/communities and mainly to assist the project officer in data collection, recording supported materials, keeping documentation related to the camp/community, reporting update to project officer, assisting in distribution, etc.


This project builds on KMSS active and strong operational presence and networks to address immediate live-saving needs for displaced person and other most vulnerable crisis-affected people in Southern Shan State</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Karuna Mission Social Solidarity</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Karuna Mission Social Solidarity</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">James Pahre</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KMSS National Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>09425022775</telephone>
   <email>Jameshre@kmss.org.mm</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR014">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shan (South)</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>21.50000000 98.00000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="96" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="4" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-07">464133.74</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-07">94658.85</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-19053">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-07">558792.59</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Karuna Mission Social Solidarity</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305157628">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-26">447034.07</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Karuna Mission Social Solidarity</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
