<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-21/DDA-3415/SA2/H/NGO/20867</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving the access to equitable primary health care and reproductive health services through the appropriate and coordinated mechanisms in conflict-affected areas in Kachin State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">gaps of the humanitarian health services by targeting all conflict-affected communities in 6 townships in Kachin State and will improve access to health care services in IDP Camps and Host community by providing primary healthcare services to 43629 beneficiaries (Men 11818, Women 13665, Boy 8550, Girl 9659, including People living with disabilities 5593 (12.8% of the population)) in which 76% are IDP camp population and 24% are host community.
Primary health care services include men, women, girls, boys, pregnant women and under 5 years old children. Primary health care services will be provided by both existing camp-based clinics in Waingmaw (NGCA), Chipwi, Mogaung, Njang Yang and Sumprabum townships while mobile clinic teams will provide mobile clinic services in Myitkyina and Waingmaw (GCA) townships. KBC will support medical supplies for primary health care, reproductive, maternal, neonatal and child health (RMNCH) activities. Seriously ill patients and under five and pregnant women including patients with serious chronic diseases will be referred to the nearest hospital to receive timely health management. Trained camp clinic staff and health workers will receive on-job training to ensure effective health services provision and to understand the project activities. Moreover, KBC health teams will provide emergency health responses for any emergency, either a natural disaster or armed conflict, within Kachin State by coordination with WHO. All targets and activities are designed and planned only based on the results from 1) Health Cluster meeting with all different health partners, 2) epidemioilogical data from previous and current health activities and assessment report in 2021.
KBC is now implementing the health project with the funding of MHF (18953) and the two projects will be complemented each other. Humanitarian assistance will be started providing immediately to the gaps of different townships while some target areas overlapping with the previous project will be continue implementing after the end of the previous project to be able to provide the humanitarian assistance with minimal gaps.
As KBC is currently working together with International Rescue Committee (IRC) in providing mobile clinic services in IDP camps, this project will enhance the comprehensive health services to the community while the needs and demands are increasing a lot during this dynamic situation.
Nutrition services are being provided in IDP camps with both financial and technical support from UNICEF. The camp health workers and mobile clinic teams will refer to the existing Nutrition teams for any children and pregnant women for Nutritional related services as needed.
KBC already has a strong and well-trained MHPSS team trained by John Hopkin University and has more than 3 years of experience and assigned focal points in most IDP camps for better coordination. For those who need psychological or mental health support from the IDP camps and for emergency cases within coverage areas, the MHPSS team is always on standby for the assessment to give mental health and psychosocial support services. Monthly MHPSS working group meeting will be participated regularly for the updated situation, needs and gaps.
As KBC is functioning the Covid-19 Treatment Center in Myitkyina with the support of IRC, camp health workers and mobile clinic teams could refer any suspected cases to the Center for further proper management.
Humanitarian and Development Department of KBC has been providing the WASH and Protection related services in IDP camps since 2011 with the support of UNICEF and UNHCR which KBC has an internal coordination channel to refer each other for the specific needs for different sectors.
KBC regularly participates in all meetings conducted by the Health Cluster to find out the needs and gaps in updated situations. With regularly (weekly and monthly) meetings, KBC will closely collaborate with WHO and other actors in complementation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kachin Baptist Convention</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kachin Baptist Convention</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Malut Naw Tawng</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager (KBC HMD)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>092401527</telephone>
   <email>malutnawtawng@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rev. Zinwa Zau Lawn</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director (KBC HMD)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>09259044125</telephone>
   <email>zinwalawn@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR001">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kachin</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>26.00000000 97.50000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-01">185798.45</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-01">17296.55</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-20867">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-01">203095</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kachin Baptist Convention</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
