<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-21/DDA-3415/SA1/H-P-N/INGO/18657</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing protection, rehabilitation and nutrition services in crises affected communities of Rakhine State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of the project is to enhance a more integrated health, nutrition and protection system to provide quality care to crisis effected communities in Rakhine state. 
Under health sector, HI will identify persons with disabilities with their needs and barriers faced. Then, Personalized Social Support Plan (PSS plan/treatment goal) will be drawn, followed by provision of rehabilitation services to beneficiaries to improve beneficiaries&#x2019; functional mobility and independence. In addition, HI will also support assistive devices, home modification/adaption services to required beneficiaries to reduce dependency to caretakers and to reduce physical barriers in their environment. If necessary, HI will refer beneficiaries to other specialized services and service providers by supporting referral fees, using Standard Operation Procedure (SOP) and service provider mapping (developed under other funding) for referral cases. COVID-19 mainstreaming activities will be done under health sector, aiming for all beneficiaries who receive HI services also in protection and nutrition sectors as well as for HI staff and camp-based staff outreach workers.
Under protection sector, the services will be mainly focused on Mental Health and Psychosocial Support (MHPSS) and Disability inclusion mainstreaming.
HI will plan to provide MHPSS training to staff, ORWs for effective usage of MHPSS skills during service provision. HI will also organize group MHPSS sessions with beneficiaries/caretakers to improve their resilience and skills on coping mechanism. In order to mainstream disability inclusion, HI will conduct awareness session on disability and inclusion in communities and disability inclusion training to humanitarian actors. 
In order to be accountability to the beneficiaries, HI will plan to strengthen existing feedback complaint mechanism, aiming for beneficiaries of HI.
Under nutrition sector, HI will provide Stimulative Physiotherapy to already identified under 5 children with Severe Acute Malnutrition (SAM) to prevent developmental delay. Besides, HI will provide training to caretakers on age-appropriate Stimulative playing therapy to reduce development delay in malnourished children. HI will also organize community awareness sessions with pregnancy and lactating women and nutrition camp-based staff on topic linked with malnutrition, developmental delay and disability. Renovation of Stimulative Physiotherapy (SPT) rooms in ACF&#x2019;s Integrated Nutrition Centers (INC) will be done for persons with disabilities to have access to HI&apos;s services.
In nutshell, project will strengthen the resilience of highly vulnerable persons with disabilities (girls, women, boys and men) who are living in HI target areas. An intersectional approach will be adopted focusing on gender, age, disability and other factors in particular displacement, ethnicity and religion to understand how these factors intersect and create vulnerability in order to target the most vulnerable people at risk including children with disabilities and isolated persons with disabilities who are at greater risk from violence. 
The proposed activities will target 10 IDP camps and 22 villages in Sittwe to reach to 2610 direct beneficiaries (657 men, 1598 women, 159 boys and 196 girls) including 395 persons with disabilities (163 men, 154 women, 36 boys and 42 girls) and it will ensure the continuation of on-going MHF programs (MM-20/DDA-3415/SA1/P-H-COVID-19/INGO/16806 and MM-20/DDA-3415/SA2/N-H/INGO/17750, ending in August and December 2021), allowing HI to keep the capacity to respond high needs without overlapping the activities between different projects. HI will directly implement activities under this proposal as HI has experiences for direct implementation under 2020 MHF allocation. Services will be delivered through field teams by linking with camp-based staff (community outreach workers) for service provision.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federation of Handicap International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federation of Handicap International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jerome Bobin</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar  Thailand Program Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 977 145 0356</telephone>
   <email>j.bobin@hi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Phoo Pwint Theint Zaw</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+959 5170121</telephone>
   <email>ppt.zaw@hi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR012">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rakhine</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.50000000 94.00000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="43" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="45" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="12" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-18">151128.97</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-18">210785.14</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-18657">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-18">361914.11</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federation of Handicap International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305164155">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-01">361914.11</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federation of Handicap International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
