<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-21/DDA-3415/SA2/H-N-WASH/INGO/20871</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening essential health, nutrition and WASH assistance in conflict-affected and vulnerable populations in northern Shan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International (RI) proposes a continuation of critical, lifesaving activities in northern Shan building on achievements made under MM-20/DDA-3415/SA2/H-P-N/INGO/17821. 

Using lessons learned from 2021 implementation, RI will strengthen and expand mobile health and nutrition services to four townships - Hsipaw, Namtu, Kutkai and Kyaukme &#x2013; to reach a total of 17,361 community members  . (M: 6250 W: 6423 B: 2257 G:2431 number of PWD M: 1001 W: 1027 B: 360 G: 389)) RI will mobilise a network of community health focal points and four local CSOs (one in each township) to increase demand for services and improve humanitarian health information, using community outreach opportunities that mainstream WASH messaging and provide additional WASH support to communities. The coordinated approach will reinforce outcomes for each of the sectors: improved hygiene practice and nutrition knowledge leading to better health outcomes. Through a more integrated approach and longer-term partnerships with CSOs, RI expects to improve resilience in more communities experiencing repeated displacement, limited movement caused by insecurity and active conflict, and severely restricted access to essential services. All activities will ensure the targeting and tailored assistance to vulnerable groups such as women-headed households and people with disabilities. 

Through the health component including sexual and reproductive health services,   RI will scale up and strengthen direct mobile health services to underserved populations, most of whom have not received any direct health support before, through mobile health clinics and support to referrals and strengthening of community engagement on public health concerns (including COVID-19). Specific outreach and tailored services for women, older persons and people with disabilities will ensure health services and health education are accessible to the most vulnerable community members. Mobile health services include SRH/MNCH services with specific support to women and girls.  Health education will include targeted sessions for men and boys.

Under nutrition, RI will strengthen support to SAM and MAM cases for children under five and pregnant and lactating women through diagnosis and referral in the mobile health services and expand nutrition awareness in communities through community outreach.  Households identified as vulnerable &#x2013; such as women headed households and those with people or children with disabilities &#x2013; will benefit from targeted outreach for screening and assistance. 

Under WASH, RI will use community outreach opportunities to mainstream hygiene promotion and COVID-19 messaging, supplemented by installation of handwashing stations and distribution of hygiene kits. Mapping of vulnerable households will ensure that hygiene kit distribution targets vulnerable households including women-headed households and people with disabilities.  Handwashing stations will be assessed for protection concerns prior to and after installation.  Hygiene promotion and COVID-19 messaging will be adapted to ensure accessibility for people with disabilities (large type verbal presentations local language).

All three components will be underpinned by the further training and support of community health focal points   (at least 50% of whom will be women) who will act as knowledge hubs for communities and advisers for mobile health teams. They will also be supported by the four partner CSOs   (one in each township two of which are women-led) who will be responsible for all community outreach and health education activities. RI will roll out operational capacity building training for all partner CSOs. Training includes GBV, PSEA, Humanitarian Principles and code of conduct training to mitigate protection concerns.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Yet Youth</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Youth Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nam Khone Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Se Loung Kham Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleksandar Kuzmanovic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 (0) 9454839705</telephone>
   <email>aleksandar.kuzmanovic@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shan (North)</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>23.50285400 98.14198900</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="10" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-04">275000.37</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-04">25600.63</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-20871">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-04">300601</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305440767">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-23">180360.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
