<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-21/DDA-3415/SA1/E/INGO/18678</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency education response in Rakhine State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will strengthen key education services for children and adolescents affected by conflict in Rakhine State, Covid-19 school closures, travel restrictions, and the ongoing political crisis in Myanmar. The interventions of this project are built upon the essential components of providing safe, quality, and inclusive education, focusing on the most urgent needs caused by this complex crisis. This project will target 15,479 children and adolescents (6,988 girls, 8,491 boys) in Pauktaw and Sittwe. Eighteen government school and volunteer teachers, and 353 community members ( Male-249, Female-104)
will also be reached to support safe and inclusive education.


The project emphasizes girls&#x2019; education, female teacher support, and expanding current initiatives to improve access for children with disabilities. The intersectionality of girls with disabilities is considered by specifically targeting girls and women with disabilities in the activities related to girls&#x2019; education. GBV and protection are mainstreamed throughout and targeting of beneficiaries follows a conflict-sensitive approach for investment in displaced and host communities, providing an opportunity to build social cohesion among groups. Specific targeting of villages is related to existing coordination among partners providing education in the camps and coordination among EiE partners supporting host community schools. Host communities selected to contribute to post-primary access for IDP children and long-term social cohesion goals, and opportunities for activities that promote social cohesion will be identified with likely activities to be through the Female Teacher Peer Network groups, teacher training, and PTA engagement. To understand the feasibility of such events, SC will conduct consultations with different stakeholders prior to the implementation of the different activities to consider the feasibility of cross-cultural engagement. This will be done further on in the project (i.e. Q3) to allow time for trust to build between communities and SC. The approaches within this project are also an extension of existing through other projects (see below on coordination for more information).

Coordination with EiE Sector partners and other sectors is essential, given the single-sector approach to this project proposal. Through our co-lead position in the EiE Sector, and our position as lead agency of the EiE Rakhine Consortium, we are in a strong position to ensure coordination and expand on learnings from other projects. Coordination with WASH and protection have been strengthened in Rakhine during the COVID crisis, and SCI will continue to support these efforts. SCI also co-leads the Child Protection in Emergencies working group, and our Quality Learning Framework places wellbeing and protection at the center of our EiE strategy. SC also supports a group of Disabled Persons&#x2019; Organizations (DPOs) in building capacity in inclusive education. They will be consulted in the development of the inclusive school kits, and efforts will be made to reach out to DPOs in Rakhine for engagement with communities or teachers where possible.

The first component of this project supports children and adolescents to access education, with an emphasis on children with disabilities and adolescent girls. The second component ensures supports government school and volunteer teachers to provide inclusive education that supports psycho-social wellbeing through key capacity building. The final component focuses on mobilizing community support of children&#x2019;s education, wellbeing, and a COVID-safe return to school.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-03" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beatrice Amimo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Awards and Partnership Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254 700 462 204</telephone>
   <email>beatrice.amimo@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caitlin Manning-Riley</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education Sector Lead</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+959770187847</telephone>
   <email>caitlin.manning-riley@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR012">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rakhine</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.50000000 94.00000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-12">170251.73</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-03"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-12">245665.25</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-18678">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-12">415916.98</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
