<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-21/DDA-3415/SA1/WASH-SNFI/INGO/18666</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Emergency WASH services and Shelters and in Rakhine State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In line with the First Standard Allocation Strategy for 2021, the Danish Refugee Council (DRC) proposes implementing lifesaving Shelter/NFI intervention in 6 camps of Sittwe Township and WASH programming in 5 displacement sites in Mrauk-U Township and in 5 villages (3 in Mrauk-U and 2 in Kyauktaw townships) of Rakhine State of Myanmar, where displaced populations&#x2019; and host communities&#x2019; needs have dramatically and continuously worsened over the past few months since the military seizure of power. The project&#x2019;s goal is to improve the overall health and wellbeing of people affected by conflict or disasters in targeted areas, including enhancement of their access to basic WASH/shelter services as well as to improve their living standards and strengthen their resilience. Based on needs identified through coordination with CCCM, Shelter/NFIs and WASH clusters, as well as through continuous presence on the ground in Mrauk-U, Kyauktaw and Sittwe locations throughout pandemic and the deterioration of the overall context since the military seizure of power, DRC is proposing this lifesaving program focused on meeting urgent needs of people displaced in IDP sites and host communities. Through this intervention, priority will be given to those with specific vulnerabilities from different ethnic background including men, women, boys, girls and those living with disabilities to ensure their active participation. Through this project, DRC will provide CCCM and NFI assistance to ensure dignified, safe, and livable conditions to highly vulnerable IDPs settling in Sittwe IDP camps. Through a targeted and flexible approach, DRC will continue its current CCCM and shelter activities through its teams to cover the gaps regarding shelter in Sittwe IDP camps where DRC is the camp management lead. This will be mainly through reconstructing longhouses in need of renovation. Camps supported under this project will include but be unlimited to: Dar Paing, Baw Du Pah 1, Baw Du Pah 2, Ohn Taw Chay, Ohn Taw Gyi North, and Say Thar Mar Gyi/Phar Ye Gone. As part of this two-fold response, DRC will aim to support crisis-affected populations&#x2019; equitable, inclusive, and safe access to safe/improved drinking water, to meet demand for domestic purposes as per minimum cluster standards. This will be achieved through the implementation of rainwater harvesting, water pond protection, provision of hand pumps, and appropriate household water storage to further facilitate water quality testing and treatment. DRC will support crisis-affected populations&#x2019; equitable, inclusive, and safe access to&#x202F;functional excreta disposal systems, through maintenance of infrastructure-water systems/latrines/bathing stations in IDP sites. DRC will work towards enabling crisis-affected populations with equitable, inclusive, and safe access to&#x202F;hygiene items and community-tailored messages, aimed at promoting health seeking&#x202F;behaviors.&#x202F;This will be achieved through Hygiene kits distribution and sharing hygiene promotion including Covid-19 messaging. Recognizing the complex, challenging and fast-paced operating environment within COVID-19 context, DRC will adopt specific guidance as a complement of standard health and safety policy in place for all construction projects under this intervention, which will remain flexible to be updated as the situation evolves. DRC&#x2019;s approach will include avoiding overcrowding at the construction sites having adaptable workplans and activity modalities that can swiftly switch to remote in case of further outbreak or ongoing conflict and security risk, increasing the overall level of hygiene in the sites taking in consideration water supply constraints and increasing COVID-19 awareness. To achieve this goal, DRC already benefits from an extended network of incentive workers in the field across proposed locations, a well-established CCCM and WASH team in respective locations with extended experience and capacity to run a high-quality Shelter/NFI and WASH program.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brenna Gabriella-McElroy Carmody</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Program</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>09 250 702 123</telephone>
   <email>brenna.carmody@drc.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Martin Vane</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>09 421 061 413</telephone>
   <email>martin.vane@drc.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR012">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rakhine</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.50000000 94.00000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-03">192405.06</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-03">307594.94</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-18666">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-03">500000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305137999">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-11">200000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305679705">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-14">150000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
