<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-17/HSD20/R/P/NGO/7309</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing and strengthening community based Child protection mechanisms and improving child protection  prevention and response services in Rashad ( Abuanga, Tasba and Falata) and Alabasiya ( Buri, Almadaris and Sugalgabal) South Kordofan, Sudan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Aid Hand is requesting funds to implement a child protection project in Rashad and Alabasiya localities of South Kordofan. This project focuses on Children and adolescents at risk (CAR), such as unaccompanied or separated children, children associated with armed forces and groups, children survivors of physical and sexual violence, children at risk of recruitment by armed groups, children care givers and children in need of psycho-social assistance. This is due to the fact that children represent on average up to 60 percent of the displaced population, but this percentage is higher among newly displaced communities particularly in Rashad and Alabasiya. 

The project would like to continue delivering a comprehensive package of child protection  but focus more on working with children most at risk to neglect and abuse including SGBV.  GAH would like to target areas in these localities that have been undeserved in the previous project and new beneficiaries in addition to completing service to some  children in need of birth registration. The project aims to work with grassroots community based networks and associations to build structures that ensure children especially CAR in these areas receive support and services in child protection and get referral to other services. We aim to offer Psycho social Support sessions in 9 communities , and within their communities using trained and experienced social workers and protection monitors,  CP education and sensitization forums and education including sensitization to SGBV and MRE and session on mine risk . Target CFS will also be points for referral and Family tracing and reunification identification and support for registration with competent social workers supporting the locality FTR network.. The project will work with the network of lawyers to offer and support legal aid for  victims including rape and continue supporting the existing case load in court. 

The project intends to use a community based mechanism to child protection in a bid to phase out from CFS and  mainstream CP into other services ensuring sustained outcomes, GAH working with partners will be building Resilience for Enhanced Protection to conflict and disaster affected children youth and their families. This will be done through strengthening community based protection networks and increasing their scope to identification, documentation and referral of CAR and SAUC. The project also plans to build capacity of community based NGOs and community volunteers  on PSS and  issues of child protection and protection of vulnerable groups . This will ensure that referral pathways created are strengthened and utilized. The networks and groups will in addition be supporting the dissemination of essential information on protection and other services, ensuring participation in decision making, and conducting advocacy with authorities and service providers hence ensuring children and other persons with specific needs (PSN) get referred for the same.  

Vulnerable Children (and caregivers) whose best interest assessments have been done will also receive direct support in FTR (SUAM) birth registration, legal aid, school fees, etc as per their need and age. Communities in the target localities will receive messages on child protection and be sensitized on eradication of harmful practices to children like early marriage and FGM. This project will benefit from a similar project to be  implemented in these areas funded by UNICEF. It is envisioned that this project will benefit from the previous GAH protection led consortium where piloting has been done on Accountability for Affected Populations (AAP) Minimum standards in Gender mainstreaming (localized for Sudan) Referral Mechanisms (RM), Profiling of Villages (Mapping of services) and Complaints and Response mechanisms (CRM) whose tools and data will be used and thus ensure that this investment does not go to waste. Project will work with MoSW to ensure sustainability</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Aid Hand</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Aid Hand</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grace Wachuka</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Development and Quality Assurance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249123344676</telephone>
   <email>grace.wachuka@globalaidhand.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hytham Malik</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Operations</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249912507740</telephone>
   <email>hytham.malik@globalaidhand.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Kordofan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.19901920 29.41793240</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-12-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">6590.86</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">143351.24</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00199258">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-19">37486</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Aid Hand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-7309">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">149942.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Aid Hand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="002020163">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-05">51080.45</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Aid Hand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00203784">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-03">29933.46</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Aid Hand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00206114">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-13">31442</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Aid Hand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
