<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-17/HSD20/S1/ESNFIs/UN/4858</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Restoring Basic Human Dignity through Emergency Shelter and Non-Food Items (ES/NFI) Assistance</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project seeks to contribute to the Emergency Shelter (ES)/Non-Food Items (NFI) sector strategic priority 1 to ensure timely shelter provision at the location of gathering or camp through the timely provision of improved emergency shelter (IES), focusing on most vulnerable newly displaced and protracted IDPs in South Darfur State. 

The requested SHF funding will contribute towards the procurement and timely distribution of improved emergency shelter kits in addition to distributing ES/NFIs from the sector pipeline to newly displaced and protracted IDPs in South Darfur State. 

A previous pilot of the Improved Emergency shelter (IES) project was undertaken in January 2016, whereby IOM trained 250 protracted IDPs to produce 250 Improved Emergency Shelters (IES), which were distributed to newly displaced persons in Shangel Tobay in North Darfur through this project IOM was able to simultaneously assist both newly displaced and protracted IDPs. Through IOM&#x2019;s pilot in El Fasher, North Darfur, the production of IES by beneficiaries takes the same amount of time as to procure the items and have a supplier undertake the assembling. 
Having successfully piloted the project in North Darfur, IOM is proposing to expand the activity to South Darfur State targeting vulnerable protracted IDPs in Kass and Gereida localities. Furthermore, IOM in partnership with one national partner will distribute ES/NFI kits from the sector core pipeline and renewal distributions to protracted IDPs. 

The project will include a strong early recovery component, as well as supporting newly displaced population with emergency ES/NFIs. Utilizing SHF funds IOM proposes to provide training to 150 protracted IDPs who will produce and assemble Improved Emergency Shelter structures composed of environmentally friendly and locally sourced grass mats, supported by bamboo, wooden poles and ropes. The IDPs will be paid for the number of IES structures they produce and they will have acquired skills that will enable them to work and generate income for themselves and their families long after the end of the project. 

The IES produced by the 150 IDPs will be distributed to the most vulnerable households and Persons with Specific Needs (PSN) in two localities in South Darfur State. The households will be trained on how to construct and maintain the IES. 

In addition, IOM and partners will undertake the distribution of 1,500 ES/NFI kits from the sector core pipeline in South Darfur. This project will benefit an estimated 13,000 beneficiaries. In this way IOM will be able to assist both protracted and new IDPs. 

Both IOM and its partner propose to follow the current three-phase distribution process starting with assessment and verification of beneficiaries, distribution of relief items followed by a Post Distribution Monitoring (PDM).

Vulnerable populations will be key partners in this project in ensuring ownership in the process and activities. IOM will work closely with women/youth committees and community leaders within the settlements to contribute to the reduction of their vulnerabilities and empowerment of the IDP and returnee communities. To further consolidate community resilience, post construction monitoring and occupancy rates for transitional shelters will be undertaken at the end of the action. 

In addition, access to shelter and household items will enhance the household&apos;s ability to resume activities such as re-establishment of income activities, enhances ability to access water and improves cooking practices and enhances hygienic preparation of food reducing health treats and enhancing the coping mechanism of household members.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alshroog Organization for Social and Culture Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Correne Omole</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Development Unit</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0962437110</telephone>
   <email>caomole@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Riad Marrow</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Preparedeness and Response Unit</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0922406671</telephone>
   <email>rmarrow@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Darfur</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.64886390 24.90422080</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-08">177454.93</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-08">22545.5</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="FTR_SUD_2017_1000031">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-06">200000.43</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-4858">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-08">200000.43</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
