<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-17/HSD20/S1/N/UN/4799</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition lifesaving service provision through improved quality of SAM Inpatient services including provision of standard package of training and  monitoring in 12 prioritized localities  in 4 states.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The planned project activities will focus on improving through capacity building and monitoring the quality of services in 10 targeted localities (12 locations in 4 states). According to the CMAM national scale up plan of January 2015, SHF 2017 priority locations are above the emergency threshold. The targeted localities are affected by recurrent conflict, disruption of health services with high burden of SAM prevalence, in addition to high food insecurity (North, South, Center Darfur and South Kordofan),. 
The intended project activities were developed in consultation with the TFUs staff topics to be discussed were suggested by the field people after in depth assessment and wide consultation. WHO is planning to conduct evaluation after the project completion to assess the patient satisfaction and the change in the quality of the services provided after the conduction of the training. and regular information about the progress of the project will be shared.
The project activities planned with consultation with cluster coordinator and sector lead agency, there is an important need for provision of quality of the SAM inpatient services by improvement the capacity of the services for management of SAM inpatient to provide quality services the malnutrition 
This project will complement and contribute to the SHF recipient partners interventions aiming to increase quality of nutrition interventions including TFC/SC centers in SHF priority areas. While, and WFP will focus on CMAM/SFP WHO project will support the delivery of inpatient SAM care through technical leadership of inpatient management of SAM will focus involving close monitoring which include 12 visits (5) visits led by WHO technical expertise from Khartoum  and state also contribute to the quality assurance. In addition to 8 supportive supervision  by 2 technical expertise on SAM inpatient management focus on ensure provision of training and capacity building for 173 (85 men and 88 women) health and nutrition staff from SAM inpatient medical staff . The capacity building and quality assurance will support the qualified treatment of about 20% of the all SAM patients with medical complications in targeted localities (over one year). The project activities was designed with the category of staff (men and women).
About 7697 severely malnourished girls and boys living in the 12 high risk areas are expected to be admitted annual. By doing so, the project will contribute to increase the SAM inpatient quality of services support in the prioritized 12 locations (Nertiti, Golo, Kabkabya, Tawilla, Allite, Elfashir, Nyala Otach, Nyala Dereig, Beleil, Kass, El Geneina and Beida) in 12 localities, in line with the national nutrition scales up strategy. 

In this project WHO will provide on the capacity building, quality assurance, monitoring and supervision, and this will be done in a transparent manner starting with state level jointly by the nutrition cluster members/lead and MOH starting at state level and based on prioritization of the most urgent needs The SHF receivers/projects will be first priority, the MOH run TFUs in the high priority locations, followed by partners present in areas of response to acute malnutrition. 

Environmental aspects will be considered during the training and the supervisory missions in form of the safe medical and biological waste management, infection prevention and control and safe burial of the hazardous wastes. During each supervisory mission the WHO guidelines in the environmental protection will be checked, staff will get orientation session during the on the job training. WHO will promote the safest and most environmentally friendly technology to manage the TFUs wastes</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Health</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-12" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-12" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amira Mohammed Almunier Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">national nutrition officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00249912689089</telephone>
   <email>alia@who.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mahgoub Hamid</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00249912160750</telephone>
   <email>hamidm@who.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU26">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Darfur</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.33330000 23.41670000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU13">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">North Darfur</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.76619690 24.90422080</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Darfur</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.64886390 24.90422080</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU23">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Darfur</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.84635610 23.00119890</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-05-13"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-22">95631.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-22">54410.79</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-4799">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-22">150041.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="FTR_SUD_2017_1000019">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-24">150041.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
