<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-45001-B898</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-45001" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Trade Centre (ITC)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fast Tracking Digital Entrepreneurship in Africa - Phase 1</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The &#x201C;Fast Tracking Digital Entrepreneurship in Africa&#x201D; project was launched in November 2019 and rolled out in seven countries: Benin, C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire, Ethiopia, Mali, Rwanda, Tanzania and Zambia. Its pilot phase will end on 31 December 2021, with a total budget of 1 M USD.

The project aims to support digital entrepreneurs and tech startups in sub-Saharan Africa with online and onsite training, advisory and coaching focused on building digital and business skills as well as domestic, regional &amp; international business generation and investment promotion. The project also engages with the business support organisations, in particular tech hubs, and government to strengthen local tech ecosystems.  

Results as of Q2 2020 are detailed below: 
Impact: Fast track the growth and internationalization of African tech and the creation of value-added jobs    
Impact level information on jobs created will be gathered in December 2020. 
The project is contributing to SDG 4 &#x201C;Quality education - TARGET 4.4: Ensure youth and adults have relevant skills for employment, decent jobs and entrepreneurship&#x201D; and 5 &#x201C;Gender equality - TARGET 5.b: Enhance use of enabling technology to promote the empowerment of women&#x201D;. The project will also report on SDG 8 - Decent Work. The team will start monitoring SDG 9 on innovation, as Covid-19 is possibly an important catalyst for digitization and sustainability. 

Outcome: The competitiveness of the tech sector is increased in partner countries   
Since mid-March 2020, we have been in regular contact with FastTrackTech beneficiaries to measure the impact of Covid 19 on their businesses. Most planned B2B activities were cancelled or postponed since traveling and public gatherings are restricted. 2020 Work Plans have been reviewed to adapt to the current situation, which will seriously impact our capacity to generate business and investment opportunities for our beneficiaries. 

Output 1: Ecosystem Development
1.1. Undertake ecosystem mapping in two pilot countries to identify key players and sector needs   
The Tech Entrepreneurship Ecosystem Mapping Report (Zambia) has been finalised in April 2020. ZICTA, The Zambia Information and Communications Technology Authority, uploaded it to their website : https://www.zicta.zm/Downloads/ecosystem.pdf. The report received very positive feedback from the stakeholders involved in its design, including from the Ministry of Commerce, Trade and Industry (MCTI). Due to the Covid19 crisis we have not been able to present the recommendations in the form of a physical meeting or event. We are talking to ZICTA and MCTI how we, together with other ecosystem players, can implement and drive the recommendations. 
Two articles on the Ecosystem Mapping were published. One on the ITC website: http://www.intracen.org/news/Coordination-is-crucial-for-Zambias-tech-start-up-ecosystem-study-find and one in the Startup Journal Africa. 
1.2. Organise private-public tech sector coordination dialogues to influence sector regulation and policies   
Discussions in Benin and C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire to contribute to the finalisation of the local startup acts are on hold due to Covid19. 

Output 2: Next-generation of trade-support institutions (tech hubs) are scaled up and networked  
2.1. Identify and engage potential partner tech hubs   
The following 18 tech hubs have been identified and engaged:
&#x25CF;	Benin: Etrilabs, S&#xE8;m&#xE8; City
&#x25CF;	C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire: Incub&apos;Ivoir, SeedSpace, BabyLab
&#x25CF;	Ethiopia: iceaddis, icoglab, AccelerateEthiopia
&#x25CF;	Mali: Donilab, Bamako Incubateur
&#x25CF;	Rwanda: 250Startups, ICT Chamber
&#x25CF;	Tanzania: Ennovate, Sahara Accelerator, Seedspace Dar es Salaam
&#x25CF;	Zambia: Bongohive, Jacaranda Hub
The project team is organising joint activities such as the Business Growth and Build Early Traction coachings with Accelerated Ethiopia, the Digital Marketing Webinar with BongoHive Zambia, the Effective Business Practices mentoring by Incub&#x2019;Ivoire in C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire and the Investment readiness coaching with 250Startups Rwanda. The project also commissioned a podcast series from Bongohive for the second half of 2020.
In Tanzania, FastTrackTech partnered with Ennovate Hub, a local incubator, to organise a hackathon &#x2013; the Covid 19 Innovation Challenge, jointly with GIZ. The hackathon took place in June. The hub will offer business development support to the local FastTrackTech startups. Foodsasa and A-Trader completed the needs assessment and had an onboarding call with Ennovate Hub at the end of June. The support includes a mentorship plan for each startup, based on the needs assessment. The general business development sessions will start in July and one-on-one sessions with each startup will take place at the end of July.
In Mali, discussions have been initiated by the Agence des Technologies de l&apos;Information et de la Communication (AGETIC) which is particularly interested in co-organising training events with #FastTrackTech and a roundtable with the different institutions supporting the Information Technology sector. A full proposal will be submitted for validation.
2.2. Build capacity through tailored online and on-site training &amp; advisory   
Discussions are ongoing  with Afric&#x2019;Innov and the Word Bank to organise a regional training involving our West African tech hubs in Bamako once travel is possible again. Alternatively, the training will take place online in Q3.
Due to COVID19, the  capacity building planned to benefit the hubs also now focuses on helping them to provide a response to the crisis. 
S&#xE8;m&#xE8; City Open Park (B&#xE9;nin), Make 3D Ltd (in the Gambia, thanks to synergies with ITC&#x2019;s YEP project), Baby Lab (C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire) and Doni Fab (Mali), four fab labs with 3D printing facilities are being connected to increase regional cooperation around initiatives to 3D print medical equipment in the context of Covid-19. Several online meetings have already taken place and the communication is ongoing. The fab labs, which encountered production-related challenges, are able to exchange on good processes &amp; supplies. Baby Lab and Doni Fab are being supported financially through the project. 
Moreover, #FastTrackTech launched a call for supported tech hubs to benefit from funding up to 2000 USD subject to validation of their needs. Incub&#x2019;Ivoire, a local incubator from C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire, will be subsidized to deliver general support to local FastTrackTech startups as a contribution to the development of the local ecosystem.
2.3. Facilitate the establishment of national umbrella tech-hub consortia for stronger advocacy impact in advanced ecosystems    
This is not foreseen at this stage due to the reduced budget in 2020.

Output 3: Startups and digital entrepreneurs are equipped with essential business and digital skills   
Due to the Covid-19 pandemic and the related restrictions, on-site training and coaching activities were shifted in late March to digital platforms. The level of engagement of our beneficiaries has been high in the beginning of the crisis. However, we lately experienced the start of a webinar fatigue due to the high number of online activities they are exposed to. 
3.1. Build #360Diagnostics tool focused on Startup Internationalisation   
ITC&#x2019;s suite of #360Diagnostics tools is being completed with a specific module on startup internationalisation. A first draft of the related handbook was completed in June. The tool will be ready for testing before the end of Q3. 
The migration of the other tools to the online platform 360diagnostics.intracen.org has been seriously delayed because of the impact of the pandemic on our IT company based in Bangladesh.  Nevertheless, we are making progress.  
3.2 Engage, assess and segment tech startups   
All the startups from the 7 beneficiary countries were assessed with the #360Diagnostic Tool. There are now 130+ startups assessed and 121 categorized under FastTrackTech.
In Q1 2020, 33 startups were assessed in Rwanda and Tanzania, including 5 women. 27 were retained for the project: 13 Growth and 14 Entrepreneurship. 3 assessment sessions took place. In Rwanda, the call for applications was promoted by 250Startups and Klab, two leading tech hubs in Kigali. A total of 23 applications were received. Applicants were assessed during the kick-off mission in Kigali in February 2020. 15 startups were selected: 5 under Growth and 10 under Entrepreneurship. In addition,the three most advanced start-ups (all youth, no women) were assessed with the newly developed #360Diagnostics Due Diligence tool that focuses on investment readiness.
In Tanzania, the last FastTrackTech country to be engaged, the mobilisation campaign was entirely remote. No kick-off mission could be organised due to the Covid19 outbreak. Out of the 15 startups that applied, 12 startups including 1 women-led were assessed online using the #360Diagnostics maturity check tool. All 12 were retained for the project (8 Growth, 4 Entrepreneurship).
3.3 Equip individual digital entrepreneurs with marketable digital skills  
In Q1, 94 digital entrepreneurs were trained and/or advised overall including 35 women and 64 youth. The training activities were conducted through webinars due to the COVID19 restrictions. The English speaking webinars were also open to Gambian tech entrepreneurs that are YEP beneficiaires (figures mentioned in the present report  exclude YEP beneficiaires).
The Freelancer component, which was entirely online in its first phase, resulted in a large pipeline of interested candidates mobilized in Tanzania, Rwanda and Ethiopia. Unfortunately, the reduced funding resulted in few interactions with too many participants. As a resulted, few were completing the online courses. 
The second phase will be focused on Tanzania only and rely more on human interactions. Initially planned to start in April, due to Covid, it was postponed to June. A partnership with Ennovate in Dar EsSalam foresees the organisation of weekly meet-ups with a local mentor. Activities are resuming in July.
3.4 Train and advise tech startup founders with business skills 
Overall, 103 startup founders and staff, including 19 women and 75 youths, were trained or coached since the beginning of the year. (In Q1, 15 startups founders and staff were trained and/or advised overall including 1 women and 11 youth. In Q2, 88 startups founders and staff were coached and/or advised overall including 18 women and 64 youth.)

Output 4: Beneficiary startups and digital entrepreneurs are exposed to and matched with business &amp; investment opportunities   
4.1. Design marketing materials to promote partner ecosystems and tech startups   
The FastTrackTech web pages under the corporate website are online and being expanded with profiles of the supported startups and contents on tools in both French and English: www.intracen.org/e-Trade-for-Impact/Fast-Tracking-Digital-Entrepreneurship-in-Africa/ 
The project is also referenced under the eTrade4All platform since the beginning of the year: https://etradeforall.org/development-solution/itc-fast-tracking-digital-entrepreneurship-in-africa/?main-policy=legal-regulatory-frameworks 
Two private #FastTrackTech Facebook Groups have been set up, one for the French-speaking countries and one for the English-speaking countries, which are being used in the framework of a 2020 Social Media Strategy with a related content calendar. 
Two editors are writing articles about our activities in French and English.  
4.2. Identify and engage potential market partners and investors   
A dedicated #FastTrackTech project page is up and running on the global CrunchBase portal. 76 companies have so far been linked to the page. The goal is to have all companies under the project included by Q3. This will bring more visibility to both FastTrack Tech and to the companies added as CrunchBase is the leading destination for company insights from early stage startups to the Fortune 1000. 
In C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire, in the context of the preparation of the UNCTAD e-commerce readiness report mission to Abidjan in early March 2020, ITC&#x2019;s e-commerce team reached out to Growth startups Ahiwaaa by Afrik&apos;apps, ETUDESK, MON ARTISAN for a case study on their operations.
4.3. Connect beneficiaries with potential clients and investors 
Due to Covid-19, several planned B2B events were cancelled: Mobile World Congress and 4YFN, Transform Africa Summit in Conakry, VivaTech, SIPEN and SLUSH.
The trade fair &#x201C;Benin Digital Tour&#x201D; that was supposed to take place late March in Cotonou and late April in Abidjan was cancelled due to Covid-19 outbreak. Likewise, the joint event on Open Innovation organised with the Chamber of Commerce postponed.
In February, #FastTrackTech startups exhibited at Bamako Digital Days in Mali. The booth was visited by the Prime Minister of Mali and the Minister of Digital Economy. Two #FastTrackTech women-led start-ups, So-Dokotoro and Denko Kunafoni, won start-up challenges and the prize for the best female digital start-up. So-dokotoro raised 5 Million FCFA (8225 USD) that they attributed to the project because of the exposure given to their venture (C3/C4).
The team is exploring innovative ways to provide the startups with access to new customers. In July, we will be partnering with La Foire Virtuelle, an innovative concept replacing physical fairs in times of social distancing through an online store where the exhibitors can sell their products. The fair is planned from 1 to 31 July 2020.
The ITC FastTrackTech country leads took part two sessions of the CIO MAG Econf #Challenge, the first one with the minister for digitalisation of Benin, Madame Aur&#xE9;lie ADAM SOULE ZOUMAROU. She presented the #FastTrackTech project activities. Sedric Degbo, CEO of Rema Medicals, a Beninese FastTrackTech startup, was showcased during the online conference, which was attended by 100+ participants. The second one hosted the Minister for the DIgital Economy of C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire, the head of Fondation Jeunesse Num&#xE9;rique, as well as Etudesk and Legafrik, two beneficiary startups. The e-conference was attended by 70+ participants. In June, the project manager promoted FastTrackTech activities and startups at a webinar organised by Smart Tunisia (60+ participants). 
The project also featured several female entrepreneurs in Africa in an article about how they are dealing with Covid19. The Fast Tracking Digital Entrepreneurship web page on the Intracen website is built and includes a French and English page, startup logos &amp; links, a documents page, a tools page and a news page.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-EC_DEVCO" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Commission, Directorate-General International Partnerships , Belgium</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ITC Trust Fund Window 1 (Belgium, Canada, China, Denmark, Finland, Germany, Iceland, India, Ireland, Norway, Sweden)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-45001" role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Trade Centre (ITC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-45001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Trade Centre (ITC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">seedstars, Switzerland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-06" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Trade Centre (ITC)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.intracen.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Trade Centre (ITC)
Palais des Nations
1211 Geneva 10
Switzerland</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="3"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="BJ" percentage="14">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benin</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="CI" percentage="14">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="14">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ML" percentage="14">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mali</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="14">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="16">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Republic of Tanzania (the)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="14">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="11430" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="22040" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="25010" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="33181" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="FA6" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Connecting to international value chains</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="S42" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">S3 - Computer and information services</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="CP7" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Value Added to Trade</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-06"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-06">164323</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-06">508676</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-06">332000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">72227</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for Q1 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-01">81317</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for Q2 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-01">48437</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for Q3 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-01">164323</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for Q4 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-01">306696</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for Q4 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">168000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming commitment</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ITC Trust Fund Window 1 (Belgium, Canada, China, Denmark, Finland, Germany, Iceland, India, Ireland, Norway, Sweden)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">300000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming commitment</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ITC Trust Fund Window 1 (Belgium, Canada, China, Denmark, Finland, Germany, Iceland, India, Ireland, Norway, Sweden)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-01">164323</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ITC Trust Fund Window 1 (Belgium, Canada, China, Denmark, Finland, Germany, Iceland, India, Ireland, Norway, Sweden)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">153544</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ITC Trust Fund Window 1 (Belgium, Canada, China, Denmark, Finland, Germany, Iceland, India, Ireland, Norway, Sweden)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-01">355132</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ITC Trust Fund Window 1 (Belgium, Canada, China, Denmark, Finland, Germany, Iceland, India, Ireland, Norway, Sweden)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
