<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/Education/NGO/19496</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education Emergency Response for equal access to education for IDPs and host community in Al - Hudaydah Governorate Bait Al Faqih district 2021 [Priority II]</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is designed with an aim to increase access to education and to improve the safety and quality of education for school-aged girls and boys in Bait Al-Faqih district in Al Hudaydah governorate, which was classified under Priority 2 under First Standard Allocation 2021&apos;s strategy being hard to reach, front lines and under-served areas with high severity of needs.  The project will be implemented closely with Education authorities to bring back the education value from the backseat to the front again through enhancing the education of the most priority 13 schools, 6,951 of most vulnerable and conflict-affected school-aged children (boys amp girls) in Bait Al-Faqih district.  the district is an under-served area in addition to the existence of a mixed community of IDPs and marginalized people in the district moreover, the suffering of the district aggravated with the spread of COVID-19. All the previous situation was the driving force of the project to contribute to filling and addressing part of the gaps in the education components in Bait Al Faqih district.
NFDHR conducted the need assessment in 18 schools, from which the project will target 13 schools that are in the most priority. The most notable findings of the need assessment where about 81 classrooms are in need of rehabilitation, the students of another 12 classrooms are studying in alternative places, while the students of 25 classrooms are studying in open, (54) classrooms are in need for construction. Among the other findings, 31 latrines of 11 schools are in need of rehabilitation and 12 schools are in need of latrines construction (27 latrines).  most of the schools are in need of whiteboards, and about 4,989 students sitting on the floor in all schools surveyed, which reflects the urgent need for school desks (5 schools are a priority). 
As a result of the previous findings, NFDHR designed the project to be implemented over a period of 9 months (August 1st, 2021 - April 31st, 2022), the alleviation of the educational burden will be visible by supporting the most in-need 13 schools with 6,000 school bags, 900 school desks, 100 whiteboards, rehabilitation and construction 20 latrines to enjoy adequate privacy (especially females) and construction of 12 learning spaces. Besides providing 40 teachers (20 males and 20 females) with capacity building trainings and hygiene promoting awareness and 50 parents (25 fathers and 25 mothers) with essential training to cover the gap in order to provide educational services. 
The schools were chosen after close coordination with the clusters, consultation with SCAMCHA and local authorities, and based on the results of the rapid need assessment conducted by NFDHR in June 2021.
NFDHR will bring YHF (AB) strategy efforts to life, through the delivery of educational assistance to students affected by conflict and natural hazards with regard to people in acute need, vulnerable communities and by providing mid-and long-term educational solutions,  and in spite of the possibility to face some risks such as delaying of sub-agreement, worsening security situation COVID-19 pandemic outbreak limited student accessibility in reaching planned services difficulties in convincing local authority/community of the project activities delay in the approval of the project by the local authority and schools/learning spaces being targeted. However, NFDHR has planned for such risks by preparing several mitigation interventions and will conduct monitoring visits for follow-up and documentation of project activities, challenges, and successes. Monitoring and reporting will be disaggregated by age, sex, and diversity and will seek to ensure beneficiaries receive the full package of interventions. Ultimately, it is anticipated that about 6,951 students who are currently receiving very limited humanitarian support will benefit from and have improved access to education.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Foundation for Development and Humanitarian Response</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Foundation for Development and Humanitarian Response</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ahlam Ahmed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967730190803</telephone>
   <email>ahlam@nfdhr.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammed Salah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967730190802</telephone>
   <email>msalah@nfdhr.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Hudaydah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.00062889 43.04031959</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-07">177811.59</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-07">140377.57</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19496">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-07">318189.16</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Foundation for Development and Humanitarian Response</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305187224">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-13">127275.66</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Foundation for Development and Humanitarian Response</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305556001">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-09">127275.66</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Foundation for Development and Humanitarian Response</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
