<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA 2/Health-WASH-Education-SHNFI/NGO/20665</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priority 1: Provision of integrated Health, WASH, Education and Shelter interventions for IDPs and most vulnerable host communities at Ataq  Nisab districts of Shabwah, Alkhalq  Alghayl districts of Aljawf and Marib  Marib Alwadi districts of Marib.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aligned with YHF SA2 strategy, YFCA plans over 12 months to implement an integrated project covering 4 sectors in 6 districts of Shabwah, Marib amp Aljawf Govs in close coordination with Health, WASH, Shelter Education clusters as well as with relevant stakeholders to meet the essential humanitarian needs and cover non-bridged gaps for the most vulnerable groups at the targeted locations. This integrated intervention is designed to complement YFCA amp other partners&apos; ongoing interventions in the targeted 6 districts. Further information on the project integration has been elaborated in the coordination complementarity section.   

The package of multi-sectorial integrated interventions designed for this proposal will provide life-saving assistance to an estimated 88,551 IDPs amp most vulnerable host communities (21253 men, 23023 women,20366, boys, 23909 girls) with a focus on IDPs under-served sites, PWD, women, to improve dignified living conditions respond to their basic humanitarian needs in priority areas at Nisab, Ataq districts, of Shabwah Gov. Marib amp Marib city districts of Marib Al-Ghail, amp Al-Ghalaq districts in Al-Jawaf. 

WASH interventions will  target 36,478 BnFs 8755 Men 9484 W8390B9849G through: 
Rehabilitation of 4 water assets: 1 in Nisab,1 in Ataq, 2 in Marib Al-Wadi  Construction of 60 Latrines:35 emergency latrines in Marib Wadi, 15 emergency latrines in Nisab of Shabwah Gov.10 for PWD in Marib, Conducting 128 hygiene promotion sessions including RCCE for COVID-19 over 8 months in Ataq. Distributing of 1600 BHKs,4800 CHKs for IDPs in sites amp/or malnutrition cases that will be provided by UNICEF. 

Health interventions will have two modalities to address the essential needs of both the IDPs and most vulnerable groups in the host communities by enhancing HF bases services to provide life-saving health services as per the MSP as well as the provision of essential health services through mobile teams. The first modality will take place in 3 HFs in Marib and Al Jawf  Gov. Al Shaheed Hail Hospital in Marib, Al Khalq HC, Al Ghayl HC in Al Jawf) to service the most vulnerable communities within the first catchment area. The second modality will focus on conducting outreach essential health services through supporting 2 EMMT in Marib to deliver essential health care to the distant beneficiaries based on an endorsed itinerary plan from the DHO  to assist IDPs amp people in need at remote locations (initially in Fantazia amp Aldairi Algharbi camps) considering the dynamic IDP movement due to armed conflicts changing picture. The supported 3 HFs and the 2 EMMTs will be provided with the suitable needed medicines, medical supplies, necessary equipment, laboratory solutions along with providing capacity-building activities.

For Education, YFCA will intervene in 2 sch.s in Ataq district of Shabwah gov. (14 October Sch. in NBHD 611 amp Arwa Sch in Nasab Sub-district by supporting maintenance interventions, rehabilitation for their damaged building structure with the aim of securing safe and suitable learning environment for their better protection and performance to the enrolled male amp female students. 
 
For Shelter, the plan is to target 4924 IDPs 1182 M1281 W1133 B1328 G  IDP through the provision of Bedding, Essential NFIs, Transitional Shelters amp shelter maintenance upgrade services based on needs.Shabwah gov, Ataq amp Nisab districts:Al Mathlel site, 90 HHs Essential amp Bidding kits Alkarmom site. 65 HHs Essential amp Bidding kits, Amkedah site. 30 HHs Essential amp Bidding kits Marib gov. Marib city amp Marib district, Aal Rashid Munif, Aal Qazah, Al Ashraf sub-districts Batha&apos;a Alkhalayit site, 80 HHs Essential amp Bidding kitsAl Khashaishat site. 60 HHs TSAl Mumallah site. 80 HHs Maintenance amp upgrade Al-Hadbaa site, 185HHs Essential amp Bidding kits in Shqman site. 50 HHs Essential amp Bidding kits,Al Salam site. 60 HHs Maintenance amp upgrade</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr.Adel Almuayed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy ED  Director of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>774093360</telephone>
   <email>a.almuayed@yfca.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nabil Alammari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">YFCA ED</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>713030100</telephone>
   <email>n.alammari@yfca.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="16">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Jawf</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.76813934 46.01014819</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="26">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marib</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.56841151 45.76081505</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shabwah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.67178974 46.95556076</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="10" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-02">1177883.83</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-02">64868.96</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-20665">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-02">1242752.79</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305424581">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-10">497101.12</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
