<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA 2/Health-Protection/NGO/20617</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting Integrated Health and Protection durable intervention for vulnerable people in Al-Mudhafar district of Taizz governorate(priority- 2)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is designed in line with the strategy - 2nd priority going beyond emergency assistance and will prioritize durable interventions. It is a need for an assessment-based intervention that will be &#x200E;implemented in Al-Mudhafar district of Taizz governorate. The health will be integrated GBV component by targeting 3 health facilities (Dermatic Diseases Hospital, Al Wafa&apos;a HC, and As Shed Al Laqiah HC ) with durable solutions and &#x200E;the establishment of women and girls safe space to provide vocational training, economic &#x200E;empowerment, multi-sectoral services, prevention activities including awareness-raising to reduce GBV mitigation risks and GBV mainstreaming into health intervention, also through conducted capacity building training for health staff to ensure strengthen referral pathways to provide complementary services for GBV survivors according to the need. The project will address the &#x200E;needs in protection (GBV) and (Health) in the targeted district. DEEM has conducted RNA for both sectors using tools in close coordination with the health cluster and GBV &#x200E;sub-cluster. The project is endorsed by both the health cluster and GBV sub-cluster (sub-national and national level). Gender equality is also considered at all stages including in assessment and implementation ensuring 50% women participation in the project. Also, this project will build on the previous activities as well as Local authorities are supportive of providing GBV service, prevention activities during 2020-2021 in Al-Mudhafar.
Four aspects of the Infrastructure capacity of one health facility ( Dermatic Diseases Hospital,) and waste management for (Dermatic Diseases Hospital, Al Wafa&apos;a HC, and As Shed Al Laqiah HC) in accordance with their specific needs in Al-Mudhafar district of Taizz governorate are improved: 1) Rehabilitation of the building of &#x200E;Dermatic Diseases Hospital including &#x200E;Pharmacy and store / Pharmaceutical preparation lab, and entrance front Yard 2) providing a solar system for Dermatic Diseases Hospital by 10 kW solar power &#x200E;system 3) Implementation and installation of an integrated water network to harvest &#x200E;rainwater, including water tanks 10000 liters, water pump, and collection pipes 4) Improving the waste management and IPC capacity of targeted 3 HFs &#x200E;through regular medical waste management. Establishment of the WASH FIT team and holding regular meetings &#x200E;for 3 HFs 3 days on the job training will be conducted for &#x200E;staff &#x200E;covering methodical guides of MoHP as well as PSEA and GBV mainstreaming through strengthening referral pathways, Health intervention will target15,511 individuals direct and 145,012 indirect benf. Importantly, these health facilities provide reproductive health (RH) services and are frequented by the female population enhancing the gender sensitivity of the facilities will complete the protection component of the project and ensure that they are safe for women, and able to respond to their specific needs in accordance with the guiding principles.

Through Health and GBV integrated interventions, women, and girls at risk for GBV will have the access to services through referring cases from targeted HFs to WampGSS and vice versa, including access to multisectoral services including access to 10 vocational training targeting 400 participants from the affected group, in AL-Mudhafar district Taizz &#x200E;governorate is facilitated for provision of services to 1705 including (Legal, PSS, health, cash, referral), 7900 from women, men, girls including community, and from &#x200E;service providers have been targeted by relevant community-based prevention and &#x200E;mitigation activities and capacity building (reached by awareness-raising on &#x200E;GBV issues, 100 service providers trained on different aspects including (GBV, psychosocial support, SOPs, PSEA, PFA) including local authorize, and 600 vulnerable &#x200E;women, girls, reached with psychological group sessions). &#x200E;6 MampE field visits for both components will be conducted and 3 PDM repor</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DEEM FOR DEVELOPMENT ORGANIZATION</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DEEM FOR DEVELOPMENT ORGANIZATION</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Mohamed Saeed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health and Nutrition Programmes Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967777387686</telephone>
   <email>dr.mohd@deemyemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ms Hanan Abdulakader</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967771134567</telephone>
   <email>hanan@deemyemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maher Al-Sabri</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partnership and Fundraising Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967772244423</telephone>
   <email>maher.alsabri@deemyemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-17">249901.05</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-20617">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-17">249901.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DEEM FOR DEVELOPMENT ORGANIZATION</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305386243/44">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-21">99960.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DEEM FOR DEVELOPMENT ORGANIZATION</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
