<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/CCM-WASH/INGO/19696</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing emergency, life-saving assistance through Camp Coordination and Camp Management services and life-sustaining services through Water, Sanitation and Hygiene programming to the most vulnerable people in Ma&#x2019;rib under priority number 3</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACTED proposes a multi-cluster, integrated response in Ma&#x2019;rib City and Marib Al- Wady districts, crosscutting the areas of Camp Coordination and Camp Management (CCCM) and Water, Sanitation and Hygiene (WASH). The proposed activities range from sites coordination and community-based projects, to WASH rehabilitations and constructions, as well as awareness and communication campaigns coupled with distribution of hygiene kits. All the activities have been developed mainstreaming a strong component of protection, gender and inclusion (PGI), creating opportunities for community participation, placing a particular focus on the needs of women and girls. Under the WASH cluster, ACTED will target 7 IDPs sites In Ma&#x2019;rib City i) Al Hameed ii) Old Ma&#x2019;rib iii) AL Maedan iv) Al Maneen Aqebli v) Kenterat Al Rawdah vi) Al Nasr Camp vii) Al Faw, by comprehensive WASH package including rehabilitation of water supply system, safe water trucking, surveilling of water quality, hygiene promotion and hygiene kit distribution. The proposed WASH intervention has been coordinated with the WASH cluster regarding the site selection and proposed activities. ACTED through its recent needs assessment and coordination has obtained a full overview of WASH situation of those IDPS and designed its activities accordingly to ensure no overlap with other partners and to complement other partners intervention. Under WASH activities, 9416 individuals (2825 women, 1883 girls, 1883 boys, and 2825 men) living in the IDPs in Marib city will benefit from the proposed activated. Under CCCM cluster, ACTED will implement full package of CCCM activities including site coordination, enhancing local governance, site maintenance and improvement, community-based projects, and enhancing communication with community. As has been coordinated with CCCM cluster, ACTED will implement the proposed CCCM activities in 20 IDPs&#x2019; sites in Ma&#x2019;rib district (Marib Al-wady) named as i) Beshah ii) Kara iii) Aljarda iv) Al-Mabad v) Bin Jaber vi) Alnaqah vii) Alkwait viii) Alkhrashi ix) Wahshan Algharbi x) Almuradi xi) Marda Al Muaeli xii) Alnooqea xiii) Alhami xiv) Batha aljalal xv) Batha alkhlayet xvi) Alhaba xvii) At Tuhail xviii) Al Mumallah xix) Alsaqet xx) Al Jathwah Ad Dakhli. The proposed CCCM activities will target 20188 individuals (4845 women,4643 girls, 5047 boys, and 5653 men) living in those IDPs sites.
For the selection of locations, ACTED has been coordinating with local authorities in Ma&#x2019;rib governorate and the CCCM and WASH cluster representatives and intends to continue liaising with other humanitarian actors (such as IOM and NRC) to complement the work of partners on the ground and avoid the risk of duplicating efforts. The proposed intervention will target 20 sites in Ma&#x2019;rib al-Wady under CCCM and 7 sites in Ma&#x2019;rib City under WASH, reaching out to a total of 29 604 beneficiaries (of which 7 670 women, 6 525 girls, 6 930 boys, and 8 470 men), while each district will be targeted under stand-alone cluster. For WASH activities, it will be only Marib city, and Marib Wady for CCCM activities. For further details on this approach, please see the Grant Justification. 

The proposed intervention will build on ACTED&#x2019;s famine response programming, which is currently being implemented in Ma&#x2019;rib city. This means ACTED will be able to quickly scale-up its operations in the governorate, considering it already has an operative team in the governorate. With a long-track record in managing IDP sites and providing key, life-saving services, ACTED has a comprehensive understanding of the key multi-sectoral needs and challenges of displaced communities. Building on this and on the learnings from the work conducted under the Yemen Displacement Response Consortium, ACTED can ensure the successful implementation of an integrated response in Ma&#x2019;rib, responding to the specific needs assessed in the target locations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Michela Magni</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967776590579</telephone>
   <email>michela.magni@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sarfraz Lal Din</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967776404721</telephone>
   <email>sarfraz.laldin@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="26">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marib</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.56841151 45.76081505</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="37" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="63" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-27">451764.71</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-27">748235.29</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19696">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-27">1200000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305214280">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-04">960000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
