<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/Education-CCM-SHNFI-Protection/INGO/19351</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proposal 3: Integrated ( Shelter, Education,Protection,CCCM) Response/Marib-Amran-Sana&apos;a/ Priority1, and Priority3</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed integrated interventions are in line with YHF First Standard Allocation Strategy 2021 and the overall objective to transition from an approach focusing mostly on emergency gap filling to a more comprehensive response where the YHF prioritizes humanitarian programmes that respond to the specific needs of all vulnerable groups in Yemen, wherever they are. Under this proposed intervention, NRC will target Marib, Amran and Amanat Al Asimah applying integration approach in hard-to-reach, frontline and under-served areas with the highest severity of needs. The multi sectoral intervention including Protection, shelter, CCCM, and Education services, will cover priorities gaps in Marib and Amanat Al Asimah. 
Under the proposed action, NRC will provide a protection services and assistance to IDPs living in and around IDP sites in the district of Marib City, Marib. In these location NRC through an integrated approach will target the most vulnerable individuals and/or groups with a focus on female headed-household, minority groups and people with specific needs (PwSN). Specifically, NRC will provide case management services to IDPs with critical and ongoing protection needs and will provide referrals to those whose needs exceed NRC technical capacity, to specialized service providers (e.g. CP, GBV, mental health, rehabilitation). 

Within Shelter, the interventions will benefit 1450 HHs around 16&#x2019;310 Individuals (3751 Men, 3914 Women, 4241 Boys, and 4404 Girls) in Marb and Amran governorates targeting Marib city, Jabal Eyal Yazid and Amran city districts. The interventions include provision of essential household items (bedding kits and bedding NFI kits) for IDPs to address their urgent needs and reduce vulnerability. Provision of cash for rental subsidies for IDPs to provide protected and healthy living space. Supporting IDPs in protracted displacement situations residing in IDP hosting sites with transitional shelter solutions that reflect local construction technologies, house designs, and cultural preferences. Under the transitional shelters, NRC plans to bring a complimentary housing, land and property component that aims to improve security of tenure of shelter infrastructures, while at the same time strengthening community based dispute resolution system to tackle HLP issues arising from transitional shelters.

Under CCCM, the interventions will benefit 3367 households in 3 IDPs hosting sites in Marib city namely Aal Haimed, Maneen Al-Hadad and Aal Mosala sites within each site the CCCM mobile team to do the following interventions1) Establishing CCCM coordination mechanisms and monitoring of service provision, 2) Capacity building of site committees and establishing mechanism of selecting IDPs community, Support/advocate for the active participation of women in IDP leaderships/site governance, 3)Community mobilization interventions, Mapping of existing community structures and including raising awareness on areas of concern identified by site representatives, encouraging community participation in various services provided in the sites, create opportunities for often excluded groups such as women and youth to take part in camp leadership and other empowerment initiatives 4) Develop site infrastructure by community-led project including community mobilization for the development of IDPs sites and carryout construction or maintenance of site infrastructures.

Under education, NRC aims to provide conflict and displacement affected and most vulnerable girls and boys such as Muhamasheen with equitable access to safe, protective child friendly learning environments in 12 targeted schools in 4 districts 4 in Bani Al Harith, 2 in As Safiyah, 4 in Ma&#x2019;rib city and 2 in Sirwah. The project will focus on targeting schools with the highest level of IDPs and vulnerabilities like Muhamasheen in the targeted districts. This project will support 15,516 school age children 7555 boys and 7961 girls.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-18" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-18" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-17" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ammar Al Fakih</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 734 688 863</telephone>
   <email>ammar.alfakih@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kitty Francesca Paulus</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interim Country Director and Head of Programmes</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 736 003 398</telephone>
   <email>kitty.paulus@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="13">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amanat Al Asimah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.36598719 44.20206450</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="29">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amran</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.35709040 43.87269369</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="26">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marib</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.56841151 45.76081505</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="3" percentage="35" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="33" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="12" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-26">782209.75</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-17"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-26">1326859.51</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19351">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-26">2109069.26</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305166998/7145">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-02">1687255.41</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
