<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/FSAC/NGO/19412</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priority 4 - Provision of FSL life-sustaining services and protection to the most vulnerable people in acute need at Khanfar district - Abyan Governorate through Cash and Vocational trainings programming.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Under priority 4 of this SA1 2021 strategy that is dedicated for the &#x201C;Provision of life sustaining services and protection to the most vulnerable people in acute needs to improve their resilience, this proposed project was designed by YFCA program team to significantly serving the achievement of its main objective and leaving no one behind at a time for those groups who are just one step away from famine in Khanfar District - Abyan Governorate by addressing the most vulnerable groups through Cash amp Vocational trainings programming based on specific amp clear findings resulted from conducting a special RNA amp market assessment in Khanfar District using FSAC adopted tools.

YFCA plans over 10 months under this project to provide Cash amp Vocational trainings interventions to the most vulnerable and acutely food insecure families at the target district. Cash for work programming will be provided to 630 HHs for 4 consecutive months while 270 HHs will be provided with Vocational trainings programming for 3 months with a total number of 900 HHs-6,300 individuals (Men 1449, Women 1701, Boy 1512, Girls 1638) at Khanfar district via FSP amp training institutes at Khanfar according to the cluster standards. Both planned vocational trainings will play an essential role in improving the wellbeing of female youths and community as It will increases productivity, empowers individual to become self reliant amp stimulates entrepreneurship. The trainings have also shown to help individuals develop social competencies and improve their Livelihoods Coping Strategy Index. It will have a positive impact on the BEN motivation, attitude, self-esteem, amp self-confidence especially among the unemployed.

In close coordination with the national and sub-national FSAC clusters in Aden amp other stakeholders, YFCA will implement the interventions of CFW amp vocational training, also all related managerial tasks including targeting, registration, 100%verification and monitoring activities to make sure that the transferred financial assistance over 4 rounds are matching with the cluster criteria so the activities will include conducting baseline, PDM, PTM, amp end-line surveys at Khanfar.
In coordination and engagement of the local communities, YFCA research unit jointly with Aden office conducted RNA to assess the needed details for preliminary needs along with a market amp labor assessment in order to obtain the maximum preliminary quantitative amp qualitative data about the targeted communities, functionality of local markets and labor market analysis.

The project possible risks are: COVID-19 escalation, security deterioration, governmental imposing, market disruption, fuel shortage and other possible risk factors are considered under this project will be addressed through proper measures based on close coordination with FSAC cluster amp sub-cluster as well as with all stakeholders specifically influential administrative amp security institution starting by MOPIC at the central amp field levels, more details are provided in corresponding chapters of this proposal.
YFCA will ensure the mainstreaming of the concepts of gender, protection against sexual exploitation amp assault also ensure accountability towards affected people in all stages of this project starting from their involvement at planning, designing stages amp ending by their participation in MampE of this project through the team amptheir representatives at LACs or their direct voices over CFM that will be established amp tailored for this project specifically
YFCA has proven experience in implementing cash programming, as through Sana&#x2019;a HO amp sub-office in Aden have the full capacity to implement this project being armed with the needed experience in this field, excellent acceptance by the local communities amp good institutional capacities in related supportive tasks needed to perform the specific tasks, this includes the great capacity in MampE, reporting, HR amp Finance capabilities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-09" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nabil Mohammed Alammari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>774090200</telephone>
   <email>n.alammari@yfca.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="12">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abyan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.69554850 46.50340692</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">283167.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">316831.16</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19412">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">599999</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305155998">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-23">239999.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305525155">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-21">239999.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
