<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA 2/Protection/INGO/20570</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multi-task mine action response: survey, clearance, EOD, and risk education in Jabal Habashi, Al-Mudhaffar, Al-Qahirah and Salah districts - Taiz governorate to protect lives and livelihoods for vulnerable conflict-affected communities under Priority 3</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With YHF funding, HALO will mitigate immediate and ongoing risk to lives and livelihoods for vulnerable communities living close to current and former frontlines in Taiz. Yemen is one of the world&#x2019;s most mine and explosive ordnance (EO) affected states, and Taiz among the worst impacted governorates. HALO will deploy three multi-task teams (MTTs) to conduct non-technical survey (NTS) and explosives clearance in conflict-affected communities with high severity of needs in Jabal Habashi, Al-Mudhaffar, Al-Qahirah and Salah districts. Teams will also deliver EO risk education (EORE), mitigating immediate risks to life. From October 2022, this project will fund two NTS teams currently supported by HALO&#x2019;s ongoing YHF SA1 project.

Responding directly to HRP cluster targets, MTTs will survey and clear 2.3km2 of mine and EO contaminated land and deliver EORE to affected communities and humanitarian staff during 10 months&apos; deployment after a two-month mobilization. In total, 11,000 men, women, boys and girls will benefit from the project. MTTs will comprise incentivized staff from the Yemen Executive Mine Action Centre (YEMAC), selected by HALO through a competitive process.

The project will directly address Priority 3, addressing needs caused by recent displacement and conflict. Three of the four target districts are specified under Priorities 1 and 2, and the fourth hosts over 12,500 internally displaced persons (IDPs). Through the identification and clearance of hazardous areas, the project will also support Priority 2, enabling fellow YHF partners to safely establish services and facilitate the return of vulnerable people. The EORE will furthermore play a key role in enhancing the safety of IDPs in line with Priority 1. This project will contribute to HRP Strategic Objectives 2 and 3 by reducing casualty risks, providing specialist protection services and mitigating the impact of mines and EO on food and income security.

A needs assessment informed project design. Desk-based assessments, field visits, and liaison with YEMAC Taiz branch indicate a high number of explosive incidents and threats in Taiz, and volunteer demining groups indicated a severe lack of services. Teams will address the specific impact of mines and EO on men, women, children, IDPs and PwDs through tailored and responsive EORE messaging. NTS and community liaison inform prioritization, including specific needs of PwDs. HALO estimates 10% of EORE beneficiaries will be PwDs.

Though conflict-affected communities will be prioritized, EORE will also target a high proportion of IDPs, who face worse outcomes from mine and EO accidents. Beneficiaries and survey informants will be informed of HALO&#x2019;s feedback and complaints mechanism, and beneficiary satisfaction will be monitored throughout.

NTS will contribute to the Yemen Baseline Survey (YBS): a systematic survey of south Yemen managed by YEMAC&#x2019;s coordination cell YMACC. The YBS will establish the extent, type and location of mine and EO hazards, and form the basis of future mine action response. As per international best practice, beneficiaries are not recorded for NTS activities, which are focused on land area targets. The project will also fund four workshops aimed at addressing women&#x2019;s inclusion and stakeholder contributions to the YBS.

HALO has implemented NTS, EORE and baseline surveys in conflict-affected areas for decades, and ensures the highest standards of training, IM and quality control. Teams will not demobilize under the project but will continue under separate funding.HALO will grow its capacity in Taiz to provide further clearance and EOD activities to fully mitigate mine and EO risks to communities.

HALO will use its own vehicles, charged on lease-back, and armour the underside to increase safety for teams, ensuring long-term value for money by reducing hire costs. HALO is mitigating operational and security risks by high international and senior national staff presence at location</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The HALO Trust</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The HALO Trust</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Matthew Walker</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>770665055</telephone>
   <email>mail@haloyemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-04">695467.03</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-04">134532.97</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-20570">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-04">830000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The HALO Trust</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305424583">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-10">332000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The HALO Trust</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
