<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/Protection/INGO/19441</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of critical child protection services for vulnerable children living in the conflict affected districts of Dhi As Sufal and Al Makhadir, Ibb Governorate. Priority (1)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will support 1861 conflict-affected children and adults from the host and IDP communities in Al-Makhadir and Dhi As Sufal districts in Ibb governorate, by strengthening community-based protection mechanisms that prevent, mitigate, and respond to protection issues and providing specialized assistance to children and adults with specific protection needs. 

The project will have three key pillars:


1. Specifically, War Child UK will facilitate and support Community Based Child Protection Committees (CBCPs) (ensuring the elderly, men, women and minority groups from the displaced and conflict-affected communities are included), to address and mitigate protection concerns, promote social cohesion and enhance community self-protection mechanisms. These community-based child protection committees will be trained on core child protection concepts to promote a protective environment for children and enable safe identification and referrals of children in need.

2. WCUK will provide individualized protection services through multi-purpose cash assistance and case management services. 

3. WCUK will facilitate and support Community Led response which will give communities the means and support they need to launch their own CP response initiatives. This component includes community consultations, capacity building and micro-grants.  

The proposed project activities will address the immediate protection needs of highly vulnerable populations, including female caregivers, children with disabilities, marginalized children (Muhamasheen), and unaccompanied/separated children. Targeting criteria will be aligned with inter-agency criteria where defined, or otherwise will follow WCUK&#x2019;s vulnerability criteria to ensure inclusive targeted, and those most at risk benefit from the services. 

War Child has a Cash for Protection SOP that will be used for this project and outlines the following vulnerability criteria:

1)	Civilian victims of indiscriminate conflict, such as airstrikes or shelling 
2)	Survivors of violence, coercion, deprivation, abuse and exploitation. This could include forced or compulsory labour, forced displacement or return, restriction of movement, prevention of return, forced recruitment, being forced to commit acts of violence against others, torture.
3)	Survivors of SGBV. This could include sexual exploitation, such as sexual slavery and forced sex work.
4)	Households at risk of protection threats having lost a primary income earner or lack of or worsened economic means. 
5)	Eviction, imminent or actual 
6)	Other emergency situations to be decided based on each case and recommended by the case manager

Eligible cases will be reviewed and verified by staff members from both the protection and the livelihoods teams. The cash assistance will not be delivered in isolation, considering the complexity of protection risks but would be complemented by the case management services, or referrals as relevant for the individual.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alla Al-Din Mohammed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Head of Programmes</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 773 737 230</telephone>
   <email>allam@warchild.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="11">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ibb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.05521633 44.26319019</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-26">157262.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-26">257545.33</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19441">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-26">414807.53</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
