<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/SHNFI/NGO/19421</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provisions of shelter solutions and non-food items for the most affected minority groups PWDs, PWSNs , vulnerable IDPs and host communities under priority (1) in Alluhayaa district and priority (3) in Bait Alfaqeh districts within Al- Hudaydah governorate.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project aims at providing lifesaving shelter solutions and non-food items to 1797 households and 12,579 individuals (3644 Men , 2389 Women, 2267 boys, 4279 girls)  of the most vulnerable IDPs, host communities and minority groups including people with disabilities and people with special needs. The project is in line with YHF 1 SA - 2021 strategic paper under priorities (1amp3) to achieve shelter/NFIs cluster objectives and activities in Yemen.

Under priority (1) the project will improve shelter/NFIs living conditions for the most vulnerable affected groups, who are more exposed to protection risks, through distribution of 280 basic kits and 336 bedding kits for IDPs (80%) and HC(20%) within Al Alluhayaa district, Al Hudaydah governorate also total of 561 displaced households in hosting sites will be supported to improve their shelters by conditional cash for shelter maintenance or upgrade . The priority in targeting will be given to the most affected groups who are hosted in open areas or in informal settlements and hosting sites such as Al Muhamshain groups, people with physical or mental disabilities, people with special needs, people with multiple vulnerabilities such as female or children headed households.

The project is under priority (3) will support the most vulnerable IDPs and host communities through provision of 100 enhanced emergency shelter kits, 300 cash for rental subsidies, 100 basic NFIs kits (80% IDPs, 20%HCs) and 120 bedding NFIs kits (80% IDPs, 20%HCs) in Bait Alfaqeh district, Al Hudaydah governorate. For EESKs solutions, attention will be given to newly IDPs without shelters or protracted IDPs who could not had accessed to shelter assistances for last period, ESKs/NFIs distributions will be delivered to newly or protracted IDPs, cash for rental subsidies will be distributed to those who are living in rented houses and unable to meet the rental charges where they are under threatened of eviction due to that. Also, beneficiary lists will be selected based on shelter cluster criteria in providing assistance such as female headed households, disabled people, big-size households, GBV survivors, children, elderly persons and PWSNs.

The Project activities will be conducted in coordination with other YHF AOBWC protection project in Bait Al Faqiah district and with other NGOs to support IDPs with integrated services in other districts. The S/NFIs materials will be provided within in-kind modality based on shelter cluster standards through direct procurement by AOBWC team then conducting coordination with all stakeholders, establishing of community committees, registration of beneficiaries and finally distribution of ESKs/NFIs kits will be conducted based on proposal work plan. The project will be in line with AAP standards take into account all COVID 19 precautions through all project phases.

AOBWC is a women lead organization mainly targeting women/girls with disabilities, It has implemented shelter/NFIs, FSL and protection activities targeted PWDs especially blind woman and girls in Bait Al Faqiah, Megalf and Zaibed and Alluhayaa districts. AOBWC is with a good experience in shelter/NFIs areas through implementing many of shelter/NFIs projects funded by YHF and other donor in Ibb, Taizz ,Sana,a, Al-Hodaydah and Hajjah during 2018, 2019 and 2020. Shelter team will closely coordinate with SCMHCA and community leaders to avoid any risks regarding to coordination to get field permits, coordination with lands owners to construct ESKs for IDPs (other risks indicted into risk management tap)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Aman Organization for Blind Women Care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Aman Organization for Blind Women Care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banan Alshrjabi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>967 712 319 153</telephone>
   <email>banan.alshrjabi@alaman.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ossan.alasbahi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>967 716 646 641</telephone>
   <email>ossan.alasbahi@alaman.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rana Aboud</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>967 716 646 644</telephone>
   <email>rana.aboud@alaman.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Hudaydah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.00062889 43.04031959</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-25">191288.61</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-25">228714.64</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19421">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-25">420003.25</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Aman Organization for Blind Women Care</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
