<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/FSAC-WASH/INGO/19520</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priority #03: Integrated emergency food security and WASH assistance to the targeted conflict-affected population in Aslem district of Hajjah Governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project main objective is to deliver integrated life-saving food security and WASH support to the vulnerable IDPs and Host Communities  in Aslam Alwast Subdistrict (Jabal Aslam, Bani Amare and Al-Thaluth Villages) Aslam Alyamen Subdistrict (Almoshwhah Village), and  Aslam Alsham Subdistrict (Bani Zaid Village and Shwgabah Camp) in Aslem district of Hajjah Governorate. Oxfam is well placed with the required capacity, infrastructure, and network in Aslem district to implement this intervention as the organization has implemented FSA and WASH projects in the past in the location.
The  project targets recent IDPs and conflict-affected host communities (HCs) in Aslem district. FSA and WASH interventions will be implemented in the same locations to fill identified FSA and WASH gaps to complement each other and maximize the impact on the targeted and assisted communities. Beneficiaries targeted under FSA activities (UCT) will be part of the intervention under WASH. Same FSA BNFs will be prioritized for and benefit from hygiene kit distribution, cleaning campaign, latrines provision, and unprotected water sources rehabilitation. In addition, WASH intervention intended to expand its reachability other than FSA beneficiaries hence, the proposal&apos;s design focuses on this integrated approach. Gender, protection, and safeguarding programming are intergraded throughout the project implementation process. Do no harm approach will be central to all activities. Proposed beneficiaries under this project comprise of 36% IDPs and 64% HCs that host IDPs or most vulnerable according to the vulnerability criteria. Minimum 35 % of the beneficiaries the project designed to target will be women. Oxfam will apply FSAC cluster and Oxfam targeting criteria to target locations prone to high level of water born deceases, high undernutrition rates, at prefamine and falling under IPC 3 amp IPC4. The targeted HHs and individuals are those suffer malnutrition retain single parent families (female headed household in particular) elderly person with disabilities and chronical illness HHs with more children and prone to any other vulnerabilities that hinder for them to have access to food and portable clean water. Oxfam also will ensure an inclusive approach in targeting criteria that includes persons with disabilities and the most vulnerable to COVID 19.

FSA component of the project aims to provide Unconditional Cash Transfer (UCT), benefiting 1200 direct households (HHs) consists of 8,400 individuals (women 2436, men 2520, girls 1764 and boys 1680). Among 70% are IDPs, and 30% are HCs. Each HH will get USD 85 (YER 50,000 and bank charges) each month for six months. The amount given per HH is adequate to cover 80% of the minimum food needs for a household with seven members.. Oxfam will provide capacity-building on gender, protection, and safeguarding approaches.
Under the WASH component of the project, Oxfam intended to reach out to 25,445 individuals as direct beneficiaries (women 5343, men 5089, girls 7634, and boys 7379). Related to providing accessible and safe community water supply systems, Oxfam will renovate five Water Supply Systems (WSS) This will benefit 25,445 beneficiaries. Oxfam will construct 200 shared household latrines equipped with simple handwashing facilities, including latrine cleaning kits. 3 families will share a latrine, in total, 600 IDP HHs. The latrine will be designed and delivered via the Sani-Tweak approach, where consultation with women and girls about safety, distance, and privacy will occur. Oxfam will facilitate cleaning campaigns at targeted IDP camps, including the supply of environmental cleaning kits, with the active participation of the community.
The project will use the existing Oxfam security management SOPs and COVID-19 SOPs to ensure BNFs, CHVs, and OXFAM staff safety. Learnings will be gathered, capitalized, and shared with cluster community, and OXFAM affiliates in other countries</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taha Alraeeini</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>739705557</telephone>
   <email>TAlraeeini@oxfam.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hajjah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.27488061 43.11225315</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-07">531867.88</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-07">1068131.36</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19520">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-07">1599999.24</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
