<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/Education/INGO/19439</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving access to quality inclusive accredited formal education for most vulnerable children in both districts of Al Mansoura and Dar Sa&#x2019;ad, Aden Governorate. Priority (1) and (4)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will directly assist a total of 2080 beneficiaries of the most vulnerable children, children with disability, muhamasheen, working and out of school children, and girls and female teachers, and school personnel in Al Mansoura District and Dar Sa&apos;ad, Aden governorate. In accordance with the allocation priority interventions 2021, it has found out that these targeting groups like children with disability, Muhamasheen and other minority groups has not been given enough attention. As educational services are seldom close to households this poses a key barrier for persons with disabilities, and female children and teachers and families cannot afford costs of transportation nor learning materials. Additionally, some schools are with limited capacity, and unsafe learning environment. Moreover, the volunteer teachers are not being paid or given any incentives  have low awareness in terms of disease outspread. Therefore, the targeted  districts such as Dar Sad and Al Mansoura districts in Aden governorate are considered severely  affected districts in all sectors, including education . 

Referring to the above mentioned reasons, such as capacity, unsafe environment, low awareness, in-accessibility for Children with disabilities, its noticeable that these contribute to the increased drop out rate.  As per the Education cluster and 1st Standard Allocation of the Yemen Humanitarian Fund 2021. , the activities proposed contribute to two objectives of the Yemen Humanitarian Response Plan Strategic Objectives (HRP SO1 and SO3). 

WCUK is contributing through these proposed activities to enhance the quality of education, that furthermore are under the Education cluster objectives of improving access to education services, in contribution to preventing infectious disease outbreak and famine reduction in schools or learning centers in addition to preventing the most vulnerable school-aged girls and boys from risks of violence by ensuring access to safe and inclusive learning environment that promotes well-being and resilience.

These activities focus on the priority 1 and priority 4 that the Education Cluster recommends. So, these activities are linked to the needs of these beneficiaries in the targeted schools. That&#x2019;s, it aims at Improving living conditions and access to assistance and protection for PWD, minority groups and persons with other specific needs besides Provision of life-sustaining services and protection to the most vulnerable people in acute needs to improve their resilience.

Regarding the implementation, WCUK has 3 year &#x2013; experience implementing the EiE activities in different locations in Yemen, and very extensive and leading EiE experience internationally. Besides, WCUK has international technical expertise to direct the team in the field for the sake of ensuring the quality work  WCUK has strong coordination with authorities and close collaboration with GEOs and DEOs ensure accessibility and facilitation in the targeted areas of intervention. .  

As per the needs identified through the rapid needs assessment, the education activities will be focusing on the rehabilitation of  schools, incl.  Gender sensitive WASH facilities, establishment of 6 Temporary Semi- Structured Classrooms (TSSCs), including school supplies such as 440 new desks and the distribution of 2000 students kits, 32 recreational kits, 80 teacher kits as well as 2,000 hygiene kits, 200 transportation incentive for the children with disabilities, 40 white boards and Markers , besides two trainings for 80 teachers in &#x201C;Teachers in Crises Context&#x201D; as well as there will be a different training for teachers on Hygiene, Covid-19 prevention practices and safe schools Protocols and conducting awareness sessions for children in Schools in Al Mansoura District and Dar Sa&apos;ad, Aden governorate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alaa Alla Al-Din Mohammed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Head of Programmes</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 773 737 230</telephone>
   <email>allam@warchild.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="24">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aden</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.84865928 45.00201169</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">100646.8</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">265474.17</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">66368.55</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19439">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">432489.52</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305155731">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-25">172995.81</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
