<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/WASH/NGO/19536</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priority 3: provision of comprehensive amp; life-saving WASH assistance for IDPs and most vulnerable groups of PWD, Minorities and people with specific needs at Damt district of Al-Dhale Gov. and Marib cityamp;Marib Alwadi districts of Marib Gov.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In line with 2021 SA1 strategy objectives for the priority 3, this project intends to provide comprehensive WASH assistance to estimated 85,786 IDPs in sites, host communities amp most vulnerable communities (20588 men, 22305 women,19731, boys, 23162 girls) from the most vulnerable groups with focus on IDPs, PWD, women, elderly people, Muhamasheen and people with specific needs to respond to their basic humanitarian needs in WASH in HTR , high priority areas in Marib city and MArib Alwadi and Damt Districts of Marib and Al-Dhale Governorates respectively.

Under the Priority 3, the WASH interventions will be providing a comprehensive , emergency , life-saving assistance , protection to the most acutely vulnerable 23,368 IDPs , other minor groups amp 62,418 host communities in the targeted 2 districts covering 1st line response for newly amp most affected IDPs amp Host communities with focus on covering critical WASH gaps within 1st and 2nd line response to improve wash conditions amp reduce risk of WASH related disease , malnutrition , improving conditions for IDPs , PWD, vulnerable host communities and ensuring the durability of basic WASH services. 

The WASH interventions will be provided through: rehabilitation/repair of 7 community water assets 1 Marib city amp 6 in Damt districts, provision of operational support for 1 water system in Damt district, providing spare parts amp maintenance for 1 water supply system in Damt, provision of emergency water trucking for IDPs in sites(Al-Jesr,Atiq,Al-Amal,1 Al-Amal 2, Al Jabjab,Al Mahror ampAl Hasor Sites) in Damt district, distributing 3600 CHKs,1200 BHKs for malnutrition cases amp IDPs that will be provided by UNICEF and distributed by YFCA project team, conducting water quality surveillance, conducting water chlorination for water points at IDPs sites, conducting solid waste management amp disposal in Damt amp Marib Alwadi districts in IDPs sites amp host communities, construction of 80 latrines in Damt ,Marib city amp Marib Alwadi districts :55 emergency latrine, 25 family latrines (10 for PWD amp 15 for most affected host communities) and couple of sanitation and hygiene software and hardware activities including COVID-19 prevention activities in both districts.

The targeted districts are located within Marib and Ibb Hubs where YFCA has strong physical presence via its programs implementation units PIU in both governorates to carry out the main implementation tasks including the coordination with WASH,CCCM cluster, RRM, GARWASP, Local authorities is already done to facilitate the planned interventions amp avoid any duplication with technical and administrative backstopping support from the main offices in Sana&#x2019;a and Aden. 

The potential risks that might face YFCA while implementing the activities include the delay in signing the SA for districts under Ibb Hub amp IDPs influx in Marib, security deterioration, airstrikes, prices fluctuation, supplies shortage in the local market, outbreaks of diseases especially Cholera , COVID-19 resulting in lockdown amp delay in handing over of the sites, these potential risks will be mitigated through close coordination with current partners, stakeholders authorities in both sides, obtaining de-confliction for sites, contracting with suppliers for the whole project to avoid prices fluctuation, amp coordinating with health cluster amp on ground actors regarding the spread of diseases: cholera,COVID-19 amp hiring local staff. A close coordination with local authorities, IOM, RRM partners, both WASH amp CCCM clusters, to joint response forces for IDPs influx especially in Marib. A close coordination with SCAMCHA to obtain the permission amp get the SA signed within the 1st 3 months of the project.

YFCA will carry out the managerial tasks including MampE, reporting and financial processes according to operation manual guidance to ensure effective implementation, accountability towards affected people, stakeholders, donors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nabeel Mohammed Alammari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>713030100</telephone>
   <email>n.alammari@yfca.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="30">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Dhale&apos;e</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.85996808 44.67423913</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="26">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marib</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.56841151 45.76081505</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">266666.3</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">533332.6</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19536">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">799998.9</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305155998">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-23">319999.56</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
