<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/RA4/Protection/UN/21150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency  response to Hodeida Governorate under Priority II&#x2013; part of the larger UNDP Emergency Mine Action Phase II, Yemen</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen has experienced protracted conflict since late 2014 and remains the worst humanitarian and development crisis in the world. Fighting since 2014 has added to the scale and complexity of UXO contamination and left large swathes of the country impacted. The contamination is a result of all types of UXO including cluster munitions, improvised explosive devices (IEDs), landmines, sea mines, abandoned explosive ordnance (AXO). Major roads, bridges and power lines across the country have been severely damaged, and oil and gas production have been totally disrupted. ERW and IED contamination continue to harm civilians and damage their homes and infrastructure. Women and girls are significantly affected by the ongoing conflict and the threat of ERW. 

The proposal is in support of UNDP&#x2019;s &#x2018;Emergency Mine Action&#x2019; Phase II Project (EMAP2), implemented in Yemen in close cooperation with the National Mine Action Committee (NMAC) and the Yemen Mine Action Centre (YEMAC). Responding to the latest developments on the Yemen West coast, following the withdrawal of the IRG forces from these areas and the plea from the DFA for more concrete support to mine action activities in these areas. More specifically, procurement of detectors and protective items, support the work of the field teams in the area (through payment of incentives) and provide much needed training on techniques relating to mines, IEDs and advanced weapons. These activities are vital for the functioning of YEMAC and with the aim of ensuring safe humanitarian access for other partners and organisations. Funding will be utilized in support of YEMAC activities in the Governorate of Hodeidah, in the dicstricts under DFA control (Al Garrahi, Al Hali, Al Hawak, Al Mina, Bayt Al Faqiah, Zabid, Ad Durayhimi, At Tuhayat, Hays, Jabal Ra&#x2019;s). Aiming at clearing 345,000 meters square of land and assisting around 989 thousand beneficiaries, from host communities as well as IDPs. In Yemen&#x2019;s modern conflict setting this will include the mitigation of complex weapon systems (such as advanced air-dropped munitions and rockets) and escalating numbers of IEDs, which per explosive event, are killing and injuring more civilians that any other explosive weapon system. 
The planned support will be delivered as: 
	Incentives to YEMAC/YMACC deminers and staff in support of their daily work
	Capacity assessment, formulation of institutional capacity building policy, EOD teams &#x2013; through experts advise and training events
	Targeted procurement of demining and protective equipment
	Supplies in support of YEMAC&#x2019;s operation &#x2013; fuel, marking tools
	Training of YEMAC staff and personnel 

YEMAC&#x2019;s operations in the Governorate of Hodeida, will ensure the areas now under DFA contrl, are rendered safe from mines and ERW through survey, marking and/or clearance. This will also provide safe access to much-needed humanitarian aid, shorten transit times to and from the Governorate for commercial traffic, facilitate better access to medical treatment, and improve food security. The activities supported by this project will also aim at providing life-saving assistance to the population of the affected areas through an effective targeted response in line with the cluster priorities and in support of YHF partners&#x2019; interventions by clearing vital infrastructure in these areas. For this allocation the targeted governorate will be Hodeidah. Should any other areas be identified as a priority then plans would need to be amended accordingly  in cooperation and with the support from the relevant Clusters and the YHF.

UNDP will support YEMAC in its currently sub-optimal response in  the Governorate of Hodiedah for a period of 6 months (February through July 2022).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peace Support</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Team Leader</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>tsunetaka.tsuchiya@undp.org</telephone>
   <email>Tsunetaka Tsuchiya</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Melanie Hauenstein</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Advisor</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+1 212 906 5456</telephone>
   <email>melanie.hauenstein@undp.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stephen Bryant</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CTA Mine Action</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 (0) 712 222 163</telephone>
   <email>stephen.bryant@undp.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Hudaydah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.00062889 43.04031959</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-17">1499728.05</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-21150">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-17">1499728.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305385587">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-24">1499728.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
