<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/Health-Nutrition-Education/INGO/19553</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Life-saving integrated response Health, Nutrition Priority 2 and Education for host community and displaced children priority 3 in Tuban Lahj</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SC proposes to provide lifesaving health and nutrition intervention to 32,141 beneficiaries and emergency education including response to 800 displaced in Tuban district, in Lahj governorate
The integrated ten-month project will be implemented to enhance access and utilization of priority first line health and nutrition services identified by both Health and Nutrition clusters in line with the cluster objective and the allocation strategy. overall aim of the project will be reduction of morbidity and mortality through enhancing access and coverage of life-saving primary health and nutrition treatment and prevention services in the targeted locations, SC will ensure and Confirm continuous presence in the targeted HFs and MT areas during the implementation of this action, SC will ensure frequent supervision and coaching the health workers at field level for continuous quality improvement (CQI) and we have Field office in Lahj. the overall objective of the project will be achieved through:
Health: Improving access to and utilization of emergency life-saving primary services represented in minimal service package for vulnerable IDPs and host communities (children U5 and their families) in conflict affected targeted districts through priority 3 YHF allocation
Nutrition: Enhancing access and coverage of life-saving nutrition treatment and preventive services for IDP and host communities (boys, girls, PLW/G) in the conflict affected targeted districts. Conducting outreach activities by operating one mobile medical team (MMT) to reach more vulnerable people within remote areas through priority 3 YHF allocation 70% of the health and nutrition workers in mobile teams will be female to ensure their access to households and reaching women and girls in the community. 
SC will provide operational and technical support for 6 identified health facilities (HFs) to sustain health and nutrition services delivery and one mobile medical team to reach 2nd and 3rd catchments of Health facilities. The key services package will include: primary health care in line with MSP package immunization support prevention of Communicable diseases and preparedness for outbreaks &#x2013; especially for cholera, preventable diseases and reproductive health care including delivery support, anti and post-natal care.
SC&#x2019;s HFs based and mobile approach successfully provides women, men, girls, and boys with access to vital health and nutrition services. Although men are targeted in this proposed project, a key focus is reproductive health in the form of antenatal and postnatal care for women. Women and children are highly vulnerable and are more restricted in their movements than men in the proposed districts.
Education: support in the continuation of education services in two Temporary Learning Spaces (TLSs) already being established by SC in Al-Rebat and Ateera camps in Tuban district, Lahj through ECHO funding. This project will contribute to the priority 3) &#x201C;Provision of emergency, lifesaving assistance and protection to the most vulnerable IDPs, refugees, migrants and host communities most at risk due to recent displacements and conflict and in acute vulnerability and need&#x201D;. With the proposed project SC will ensure education continuity for 800 displaced girls and boys and continue to promote quality education through training and other professional development activities for teachers. Access to education will be promoted through a Safe Back to School campaign, provision of teaching and learning material to teachers and children, and incentives for teachers. In order to encourage children&#x2019;s retention remedial classes will be organized for children enrolled in school but at risk of dropping out.
Health facilities:
1. Haran Daian HF
2. Alshaqaa HF 
3. Al-Waht Hospital 
4.Abder Bader HF
5.Al Fuish HF 
6.Albithara HF 
7.1 Mobile Team</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yadab Katwal</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Awards &#x2013; Strategic Portfolio and Business Development</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+976738555046</telephone>
   <email>Yadab.Katwal@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="25">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lahj</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.96593663 44.41733354</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="26" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="44" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-09">459904.43</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-09">687956.22</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19553">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-09">1147860.65</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305200715">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-21">459144.26</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
