<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/FSAC-Nutrition/INGO/19574</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Life-saving integrated Health, Nutrition and Food Security response in hard to reach and under-served areas in Bayt Alfaqih (Priority 2) and Attaizia districts in Taiz and Hodeida Governorates, Yemen</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of this response is to contribute to the reduction of morbidity and mortality due to acute malnutrition among children under five years of age and pregnant and lactating women and girls (PLW/G) in hard to reach and underserved areas with high severity of needs in Bayt Alfaqih and Attaizia districts of Hodeida and Taiz governorates in Yemen. 

Nutrition integration with minimum health services will be implemented in Bayt Alfaqih district as priority 2 This project aims to strengthen the provision of CMAM and PHC services for children under five years in Bayt Alfaqih district. This will be achieved by scaling up CMAM services in two new hard to reach and under-served locations and in other locations where SC is already implementing within the district. Community-level screening for acute malnutrition will be conducted to identify children presenting with acute malnutrition and refer them for treatment. SC will employ a pronged strategy in order to ensure a high coverage in screening for malnutrition. This strategy is MUAC screening and referral by 180 existing Community Health ampNutrition Volunteers (CHNVs) and 10 new CHNVs on a monthly basis. SC will strengthen the established referral pathways from the community to the specific service points

Food Security SCI will target 882 vulnerable and minority group households (HH) in the Bayt Al-Faqih District to improve the living condition and access to assistance and protection for people with disabilities (PWD), minor groups such as Muhamasheen, and persons with other needs (limited to female headed households, vulnerable children exposed to neglect, abuse, violence, exploitation and child marriage).  The targeted beneficiaries will be supported through cash transfer assistance and other protection services provided by the protection working partner in the same location and for the same beneficiaries.  Identified HHs will receive six consecutive rounds of cash transfers of $84 (50,000 YER) based on the new endorsed minimum food basket by the Cash and Market Working Group (CMWG) and FSAC.
In addition, SCI will provide immediate life-saving emergency food assistance to the most vulnerable acutely food insecure IDPs and at-highest risk groups due to recent displacements, allowing them to meet their critical basic food needs each month in the Attaizia district in the Taiz Governorate. This project will target 500 HHs, 3500 individuals ((839 men, 946 boys, 789 women and 926 girls) with six consecutive rounds of cash to address IDPs needs at the collective sites or at host communities. SC has begun to coordinate with the CCCM and FSAC cluster to identify the IDPs collective centers within Altaiziah district.  IDPs will receive six rounds of cash transfers of $84 in line with the minimum food basket requirements. 
As this project will provide unconditional cash assistance, the most vulnerable segments of the community will be able to receive assistance, with the prioritization of females especially if they are physically or mentally challenged or grouped with Muhamasheen. SC has a Framework Agreement (FWA) with a Financial Service Provider (FSP) who will distribute cash through mobile teams to reach women who are not able to reach our distribution sites. This will also be a measure taken to ensure easier access to people with disabilities targeted within this project
SCI has worked in Altaiziah District with the FSL, Health, WASH and Child Protection sectors and in Bayt Al-Faqih with the same sectors, in addition to the Nutrition sector. These sectors in each district have implemented several projects, funded by YHF in Altaiziah District and in Bayt Al-Faqih. SC has since established strong engagement with related stakeholders, especially local authorities (SCMCHA) and local communities, offering us access to the targeted communities in each district.

COVID-19 remains a challenge faced through programme implementation and SC will take prevention measures.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yadab Katwal</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Awards &#x2013; Strategic Portfolio and Business Development</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+976738555046</telephone>
   <email>Yadab.Katwal@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Hudaydah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.00062889 43.04031959</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="66" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="34" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-09">666090.38</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-09">851393.72</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19574">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-09">1517484.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305190455">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-20">606993.64</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
