<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA 2/Health-Nutrition-Protection/NGO/20580</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Health, Nutrition, C4D, and Protection services to internally displaced people in Dhubab district in Taiz governorate (Priority 1)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed integrated Health, Nutrition, C4D, and Protection project targets the catchment population of Dhubab district- specifically the ones of Dhubab hospital in Dhubab as well as the internally displaced persons (IDP) within the host communities. The project targets 11764 vulnerable beneficiaries (men, women, boys, and girls) in Dhubab district in Taizz governorate.
The proposed Health, Nutrition, C4D, and Protection interventions- through targeting a health facility as well as establishing a mobile clinic providing PHC will participate in the overall action toward relieving suffering and increasing access to the essential health amp nutrition services. More, the community center will cover the protections services i.e case management, PPS. In addition, the HF staff will conduct outreach visits. FMF has been active in Dhubab district in regards to IDPs as it encounters the first response to any possible movement through the RRM project plus holds two FSL projects (Food Security and FFA/FFT). FMF is UNFPA partner in regards of Rapid Response Mechanism (RRM) and the project will be extended for the year of 2022. This intervention is considered the first line response to any IDP movement through the provision of RRM kits and further coordinate with other actors to support with the other two phases.
FMF performed a rapid need assessment to the HF to tail the response accordingly, build better cooperation with the stakeholders, and better engage the local community in project designing and formulation. This will assist the project team to smoothly implement the project as well as to effectively achieve the desired outcomes. According to the Health Cluster strategic objective #1, trends should drive increase access of the vulnerable populations including IDPs to MSP in all levels of health care facilities, emphasizing RH, mental health, PSS, severe malnutrition amp non-communicable diseases. Therefore, FMF would intervene in Dhubab district hospital and a MMC to enable providing the services of the MSP, these include general consultation, basic trauma care, RH, IMCI, referral services, immunization..etc. The HWs will be trained in different training sessions that include CMAM and IMCI. The Nutrition part of the project will provide the nutrition services via the MMC besides the PHC services provided. The services are TSFP, IYCF, C4D, and nutrition referral services. Dhubab district has large need in terms of health and nutrition services. This is due to the conflict happened and it&apos;s shelter to many IDPs moving from other areas of the west coast. FMF is proposing to participate in supporting the health system through the implementation of the MSP in Dhubab district hospital and to decrease the load of IDPs influx on the HFs through a MMC.
The 11764-targeted beneficiaries are those living in the catchment zones of Dhubab DH. In Dhubab, there are no confined IDP camps rather found living in the host community. The HCWs as well as the CHVs will involve all groups of the community (men, women, boys, and girls), IDP, marginalized people, and PWD. FMF confirms the continuous presence in the HF- through its recruited/supported Healthcare workers, staff, and the project management staff who will make the necessary field visits to Dhubab- community center, and targeted community of Dhubab district during the project implementation period.
From the point of providing complementarity of intervention, FMF with other actors in the district (NRC, WC, AOBWC, SI) will complement the humanitarian interventions of each other. FMF will be the only partner providing the health and nutrition services in Dhubab (either through HF-based or MMC) therefore, the other actors will refer the cases that require the needed health interventions to the targeted locations. There may be a worsening of the health situation in Dhubab and increased IDPs due to ongoing conflict. COVID-19 is another challenge that may put more heavy on the project implementation</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Field Medical Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Field Medical Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mayada Nabih</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundraising Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>770578894</telephone>
   <email>mayada.nabih@fmfyemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mouad Al-Mansab</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>772745820</telephone>
   <email>mouad.almansab@fmfyemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Qaboos Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>773729462</telephone>
   <email>qaboos.ali@fmfyemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saber Ghaleb</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundraising Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>734883158</telephone>
   <email>saber.ghaleb@fmfyemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-21">466272.91</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-21">18650.92</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-20580">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-21">484923.83</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Field Medical Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305394241">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-28">193969.53</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Field Medical Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
