<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/WASH/INGO/19214</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priority 3: Emergency WASH Support to Conflict-Affected Population  in At Ta&apos;iziyah Districts in Taiz Governorate Yemen</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project activities aim to complement ongoing IMC humanitarian response work in Yemen. The project will enable IMC to deliver emergency lifesaving WASH services that reduce environmental health risks and provide sustainable WASH services, to support the longer-term needs of people affected by conflict and recent displacements in At Tazziah Districts in Taiz Governorate. The district was selected as it is one of the prioritise districts by WASH Cluster under Priority 3 and require urgent WASH support  To respond to the urgent WASH needs in targeted locations, IMC will implement the following activities rehabilitation of two communal water supply systems, provision of emergency water supply through water trucking to 5 IDP locations, installation/ construction of 10 communal water distribution points in IDP sites to store, treat and distribute the water supplied through the water trucking operations. In terms of selecting the water facilities that will be rehabilitated, IMC will focus on facilities will ensure that IDPs and vulnerable host community host communities receive maximum benefit.

IMC plans to conduct regular water quality monitoring to assess Free Residual Chlorine (FRC) and fecal coliform bacteria levels, both at source, communal distribution points, and household level, to ensure the water provided is safe. Operation and maintenance tools, water treatment chemicals, and water quality materials will also be provided to the water management committees to ensure the sustainability of the rehabilitated community water supply system. 

To improve sanitation infrastructure in the IDPs collection site, IMC will install 30 family emergency latrines, desludging overflowing household latrines, cesspits, septic tanks, manholes, and institutional latrines within the IDP collection sites in these two supported sub-districts. Solid waste management operation and maintenance to also be supported to mitigate risks of water and vector-borne diseases resulting from poor waste management practices. IMC will mobilize the IDP and host communities to manage solid waste through clean-up campaigns organized together with local cleaning funds that will continue to support the local authority cleaning fund with operation and maintenance support such as tools. As an integrated approach to WASH services in the IDP camps, IMC, in coordination with GHO, will identify 40 community health volunteers (CHVs) (16 males and 24 females) trained on basic hygiene practices. The trained CHVs to conduct hygiene sessions along with the water and sanitation activities in operational areas. To support the CHVs&#x2019; community hygiene promotion activities, IMC to develop, print, and distribute evidence-based and standardized IEC materials to the 40 trained CHVs to use in their regular household hygiene promotion sessions. The Wash&#x2019;Em approach will also be piloted with the IDPs to strengthen handwashing practices among the IDP populations. In coordination with the WASH cluster and UNICEF, IMC will secure 2,000 consumable hygiene kits that will be distributed to IDP camps to complement hygiene promotion activities 

With this response, an estimated 66,788 individuals (14,693 men, 15,362 women, 18,543 boys, and 18,190 girls) will benefit directly from the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sharif Uddin</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance and Administration Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 7361  880 77</telephone>
   <email>suddin@InternationalMedicalCorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tawanda Guvi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967739229555</telephone>
   <email>tguvi@internationalmedicalcorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-09">201459.85</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-09">398540.15</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19214">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-09">600000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305190466">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-20">360000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
