<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA 2/WASH-SHNFI/UN/20725</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Comprehensive Emergency WASH/Shelter Assistance for Newly Emerged IDPs sites in Maqbanah district &#x2013; Taiz governorate (Priority 1).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This 12-month project aims, through its activities, designed and implemented in light of the objectives of the two WASH and Shelter/NFIs clusters and the SA2 of YHF 2021.
The recent conflict in Maqbanah resulted in new displacement to hosting sites, which was reflected in a gap. After establishing coordination with WASH and Shelter/NFIs clusters, UN-Habitatt partner, Assistance for Response and Development (ARD) has conducted a needs assessment, which indicated urgent needs for IDPs for NFIs (bedding and basic) in some hosting sites and needs for lifesaving water activity &quot;water trucking&quot;, latrines, water tanks, and rehab of available water sources. As some organizations covered the gap related to other key sectors, the gap in WASH and NFI remained uncovered as an urgent need to be covered to effectively complement the intervention of the other partners planning to cover other sectors: TOD has intervention in shelter in the hosting sites that will be targeted with WASH intervention by this project IRC has intervention in WASH in the hosting site that will be targeted with NFI by this project. Besides, Qatar Red Crescent has intervention in health and nutrition, WFP in Food, and War Child International in protection.
UN-Habitat and ARD will be to form a partnership under the umbrella of an UN-Habitat led to undertake at improving dignified living conditions for (1262) vulnerable HHs of IDPs living in seven IDP hosting sites (Al-Rodha, Alshat Valley, Hogaig, Al-Hasbary, Al-Najd, Aldashen, and Al-Robaiq) in prioritized sub-districts (Al Yemen, AlQahifah, and Almashawlah) of Maqbanah district,Taiz Gov. through implementing a number of activities related to WASH and NFIs
At WASH sector, the project involves the rehabilitation of 4 water supply points and rehabilitation of (1) water supply system by equipped with a solar system for 350 HH in (Almashawlah) including extension of water supply network to IDPs sites, chlorinating water scheme in the targeted area, provision of water trucking for 575 HHs of IDPs in the hosting sites for 60 days, provision and installation of 16 communal water tanks/taps in IDPs sites, distribution of WASH hygiene kits and consumable hygiene kits to 575 HHs, installing 80 emergency latrines with cesspits, conducting cleaning campaigns and hygiene promotion/community mobilization in the new IDP hosting sites in Maqbanah district. At the Shelter/NFIs sector, the project involves the provision of NFI bedding kits and basic kits through in-kind NFI support to 337 vulnerable HHs in new IDPs sites (Al-Rodha, Alshat Valley, and Hogaig) in Maqbanah district

UN-Habitat has the capacity, experience, and skilled staff to carry out the humanitarian intervention involved in the current proposal. Furthermore,UN-Habitat found that it is important to have ARD as a sub-implementing partner due to its strong access to all the hosting sites and its good relationship with local authorities, Executive Unit, and water officer, which can facilitate the implementation of the project activities as it has already conducted a needs assessment in coordination with WASH and Shelter clusters. The role of ARD will involve distributing bedding and basic kits, the hygiene kits, conducting PDM surveys, rehabilitating water points, implementing field activities related to raising awareness, chlorination, water tracking, monitoring water quality.
The exit strategy of this project, it is mainly reflected in terms of the rehabilitation of the water projects in the targeted areas to ensure the access of targeted HHs of IDPs to safe water and training the community committees/CVs well to ensure their having for the knowledge/skills required to manage and follow up the functionality of rehabilitated water projects before the end of the project and in terms of the installation of latrines in the targeted hosting sites to ensure the access of the targeted HHs to suitable and appropriate sanitation when the project</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assistance for response and development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Human Settlements Programme (UN-HABITAT)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Human Settlements Programme (UN-HABITAT)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bassam Thabit (Mr.)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Construction Engineer: WASH/Shelter</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 771681918</telephone>
   <email>Bassam.thabit@un.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="70" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-04">480578.57</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-04">19223.14</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-20725">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-04">499801.71</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Human Settlements Programme (UN-HABITAT)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305430087">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-16">499801.71</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Human Settlements Programme (UN-HABITAT)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
