<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/Protection/NGO/19324</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of protection services under priority (1) to the most affected IDPs, PWDs, people with specific needs and, minority groups through establishing of community center in Bayt Al Faqih district within Al-Hudaydah governorate.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project under priority (1) aims at providing lifesaving protection services to 13,405 individuals (3884 men, 2546 women, 2415 boys, 4560 girls) of the most vulnerable people and minority groups including people with disabilities, people with special needs, female-headed households, vulnerable children and most affected IDPs and host communities through establishing of one static community center in Baiyt Al Faqih district within Al Hodaydah governorate. Also, the community center through mobile teams will access other four districts that are hosting high numbers of people with disabilities and people with special needs in Al Mansuriyah, As Sukhnah, Zabid and Al Garrahi by providing protection services that are in line with YHF 1 SA 2021 and protection cluster standards objectives/activities in Yemen.

The project will contribute to address protection concerns and needs for the most affected households and individuals through conducting the following protection activities: monitoring and protection assessment to 1915 households,13405 individuals, recreational and non-specialized PSS activities as groups and individuals to 2300 beneficiaries, multipurpose cash assistance to 700 households. The protection team will support with technical protection services to cases under protection risks such as PWDs, PWSNs by protection cash assistance to 645 cases, legal support (civil documentation and awareness) to 2200 individuals. Also the project will conduct community-based initiatives on protection targeting 2500 individuals by community development projects, awareness raising, conflict prevention/resolution. The priority in targeting will be given for people with special needs as 50% of beneficiaries 6702 individuals (1942 men, 1272 women, 1208 boys 2280 girls) from PWSNs in all protect activities. 

The community center project will identify the cases under protection risks with support of protection networks (50 members from male and female including PWSNs) that will be established and trained in the targeted areas, the monitored cases will be referred to available services in the project such as protection assistance, PSS and legal support, also external referral will be established with NGOs and service providers to provide non available assistance such as cases that are in needs for S/NFIs will be referred to other YHF shelter project applied by AOBWC for 1 SA 2021. Priority in targeting will be given to PWSNs as 50% of beneficiaries 6702 individuals (1942 men, 1272 women, 1208 boys 2280 girls) will be from PWSNs in all protect activities. 
This project is designed to cover gaps in protection services within 5 districts in Al Hudaydah governorate based on the latest needs assessment conducted by AOBWC in the target area as those needs were the highest, 70 % of interviewed people express their need for protection services including 1% a child who supports family and 14% a woman is the head of family,20% of them have chronic disease,13% are marginalized,15% of the respondents with physically handicapped, 6% of the respondents have a person with mentally handicapped (assessment report is attached ).

AOBWC is a women lead organization mainly targeting women/girls with disabilities, it is has established on 1996 with a good experience in protection areas especially with YHF by establishing two community centers and conducting protection project during 2019 and 2018. AOBWC has ongoing presence in Al Hudaydah governorate through implementing shelter/NFIs, FSL and protection activities targeted PWDs in Bait Al Faqiah, Megalf and Zaibed and Alluhayaa districts. 

AOBWC team will closely coordinate with SCMCHA and community leaders to avoid any risks regarding to coordination to get field permits or related to security situations (all risks are explained in risk management tap).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Aman Organization for Blind Women Care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Aman Organization for Blind Women Care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banan Al-Sharjabi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>967 712 319 153</telephone>
   <email>banan.alshrjabi@alaman.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amat Al-Kaream Alhadha</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>967 716 646 646</telephone>
   <email>karyma.alhadha@alaman.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ossan Al-Asbahi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>967 716 646 641</telephone>
   <email>ossan.alasbahi@alaman.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Hudaydah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.00062889 43.04031959</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-25">205765.39</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-25">544234.53</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19324">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-25">749999.92</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Aman Organization for Blind Women Care</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305167113">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-31">224999.98</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Aman Organization for Blind Women Care</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
