<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/SHNFI/NGO/19546</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priority 1 and 3: Shelter Assistance to Vulnerable Conflict-Affected Households in Ma&#x2019;rib City and Ma&#x2019;rib Districts of Ma&#x2019;rib governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is aligned with the overall objective of the First Standard Allocation 2021 and is under both priority 1 and priority 3 of this allocation strategy. 
This project was designed to provide shelter assistance to vulnerable conflict-affected households in Marib, Marib city, Al Jubah districts of Marib governorate- which were chosen in coordination with the shelter cluster. The needs were determined according to the shelter needs assessment that was conducted in June 2021 by YDN in coordination with the shelter cluster, executive unit, and the authorities in Marib governorate. The intervention includes the provision of household non-food items (essential household kits and bedding kits), as well as cash assistance for rental subsidies. The project will result in improved access to shelter and essential household non-food items for 600 vulnerable conflict-affected families comprising of 4,202 individuals of host communities, IDPs, and persons with disabilities in Marib governorates.

The assistance will be provided to the target beneficiaries based on vulnerabilities and needs criteria and will be impartial. In addition, people with disabilities, and female-headed households will be prioritized. YDN will ensure all selected HHs have equal and impartial access to assistance during project implementation.

Regarding risks, YDN considered the risks that will potentially occur during the implementation of the project and identified and analyzed them through the Risks Analysis Matrix (Uploaded under the documents tab). Risks were classified into four categories: Operational, security, financial, and personnel management. The most prominent one was the limited access to some targeted areas due to escalated conflicts, and the endorsed mitigation plan for it was through coordinating with the conflict parties to conduct the distribution activities, regarding assistance for rental subsidies, YDN will obligate the service provider to transfer the rental subsidies to the nearest exchange point for beneficiaries.

It is worth mentioning that YDN always coordinates interventions with local authorities and community leaders to ensure smooth access and implementation of its projects. YDN&apos;s accessibility has been proven through active participation in the sub-clusters&apos; meetings and the implementation of many projects in Marib governorate and similar governorates. Regarding this project, YDN has been present in Marib for more than five years providing humanitarian assistance in different sectors. YDN has a main office in Marib with operational staff, in 2020 and in Marib governorate YDN has implemented (18) interventions in several sectors (Shelter/NFI, Health, WASH, and Food Security), (7) of these interventions were in Shelter/NFI sector included (Basic NFIs and bedding kits, NFI Winterization kit, Cash for Rental Subsidies, Winterization support, Transitional shelters, etc.). In addition, YDN works with a wide range of local and international partnerships including UN Agencies. 
YDN has excellent relations and coordination with the authorities in Marib governorates that facilitate immediate pledge recognition, prompt response, and easy access to any emerging incident. So, access to the targeted districts is high. As well, a needs assessment was smoothly done in the targeted districts. Currently, YDN is in the process of implementing food security response-oriented projects in Lahj, Aden, Shabwah, Taiz, and Marib governorates meeting the needs of the most vulnerable people and implementing health and WASH response in Ibb governorate funded by YHF through the 1st Standard Allocation 2020. 
To ensure complementarity and avoid any possible overlapping, YDN has coordinated with partners functioning in the targeted district. (Coordination emails were uploaded in the Documents tab).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemeni Development Network for NGOs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemeni Development Network for NGOs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basheer Al-Bohiri</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MEAL Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>774006090</telephone>
   <email>basheer@ydnorg.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khalid Anqaa</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>770907150</telephone>
   <email>kh.anqaa@ydnorg.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="26">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marib</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.56841151 45.76081505</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-23">119098.51</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-07-19"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-23">179095.51</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19546">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-23">298194.02</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemeni Development Network for NGOs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305162259">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-27">119277.61</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemeni Development Network for NGOs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305636655/6656">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-16">89458.21</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemeni Development Network for NGOs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
