<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA 2/CCM-Health-Protection-WASH/UN/20527</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisectoral humanitarian assistance to IDP sites in Al Khukhah district, Al Hodeidah Governorate, Yemen, Priority 1</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Between 11 and 14 November 2021, a reported 895 households fled the renewal of violent hostilities to sites in Al Khukhah district, Al-Hodeidah Governorate. The new arrival of internally displaced persons (IDPs) and worsening security situation has compounded the already pressing multisectoral needs of vulnerable groups in the West Coast.  In response to the widespread needs and recent displacements in the West Coast and in line with Priority 1 of the second Strategic Allocation for 2021, IOM proposes a comprehensive and integrated multisectoral intervention to expand its delivery of life-saving humanitarian services across 12 internally displaced persons (IDP) sites in the underserved district of Al Khukhah. This 12-month project will target a total of 5,552 households (IDP and Host Community) or approximately 33,312 individuals (6,912 men, 7,285 women, 10,234 boys, 8,881 girls). A multisectoral, integrated response, that establishes/improves site management support, coordinates of service delivery, and provides integrated WASH, health, and protection assistance, is crucial to respond to the already overstrained services, the newly displaced households that fled with little to no resources, IDPs in sites, and host communities sharing the burden of limited resources.

In eight sites in Khukhah, IOM is currently implementing site management services under YHF project 19251, and providing water, sanitation and hygiene (WASH), Shelter and non-food item (NFI) services from other funding. Under this grant, IOM will expand its response in these eight IOM-managed sites to a full multi-sectoral package and extend its delivery of multisectoral services in four additional new sites that currently have no site management support. IOM plans to provide an integrated approach by providing Camp Coordination and Camp Management (CCCM), WASH, protection, and health assistance in these 12 sites (locations listed in Annex 1).

IOM aims to reduce the protection risks in nine of the 12 sites by providing safe referrals, regular protection monitoring, and providing integrated protection services. The project aims to provide timely, coordinated and complementary protection response including individual protection assistance (IPA), case management, service mapping, safe referrals, information sharing/awareness raising on fundamental rights, and protection mainstreaming training to multisector teams, partners and key community stakeholders. Additionally, gaps in humanitarian actors&#x2019; distribution of drinking water remain in many of these sites. As water-trucking is costly, subject to contractors&#x2019; pricing, and not durable, IOM aims to repair, rehabilitate, and upgrade water supply systems in IDP sites. Furthermore, IOM plans to enhance access to health services and support medical consultations in the IDP sites through a static health center and mobile health teams.

Throughout all of IOM&#x2019;s interventions, Accountability to Affected Populations (AAP) will be ensured through community consultation, information dissemination activities to communities and established complaint and feedback mechanisms. The intervention is designed and will be implemented in a gender- and conflict-sensitive way. As a result of the proposed activities, over 33,000 conflict affected individuals will be able to improve from improved living conditions and access to essential services along in Al Khukhah.

IOM and DRC will carry out complimentary interventions. DRC will deliver CCCM, WASH, Shelter, Protection, Emergency response (RRM, Cash) across 29 sites in Khukhah, Tuhayta, hays districts.  While IOM is submitting a separate project proposal and therefore YDR Consortium sites are not counted as part of the total target, it will continue to closely coordinate and integrate its activities with the YDR Consortium Partners.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kimani DeShields-Williams</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Support Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 779 181 576</telephone>
   <email>Kwilliams@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kai Wilson</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Support Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+1 860 933 9031</telephone>
   <email>Kwilson@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Paulina Odame</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Support Unit Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 730 557 722</telephone>
   <email>podame@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Hudaydah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.00062889 43.04031959</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="24" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="18" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="17" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="41" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-02">3479118.16</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-02">323881.87</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-20527">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-02">3803000.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305424568">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-10">3803000.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
