<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA 2/CCM-WASH-SHNFI-Protection-Education/INGO/20530</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Integrated Multi-Sectoral Intervention to Improve Dignified Living Conditions for Vulnerable Internally Displaced Persons in Al Hodeydah, Marib, and Taiz Governorates (Priority 1)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In line with the HRP 2021 and YHF 2nd Standard Allocation, Priority 1 objectives, the Yemen Displacement Response (YDR) Consortium partners, DRC, ACTED and NRC, aim to improve dignified living conditions of 78,448 vulnerable IDPs in 49 target IDP sites and associated host community residents in Al Hodeida (Al Khukha, Al Tuhayta and Hays districts), Taiz (Jabal Habashi district), and Marib (Marib and Marib City districts) governorates through the provision of integrated, multisectoral intervention covering CCCM, shelter/NFI, WASH, protection, and education, with linkages through coordination to other humanitarian actors implementing complementary interventions or addressing remaining sectoral gaps in the target locations. Locations targeted under this project are proposed in line with the cluster highest priority areas based on severity needs. Targeted sites may change in cases of eviction, new site development, and spikes in displacement, as identified by the field teams throughout the intervention period. 

The intervention is designed to address the specific needs of key beneficiaries, internally displaced persons (estimated 72,000 population) and host communities (estimated 6,448 population), through provision of safe, dignified, and meaningful access to lifesaving quality humanitarian services by ensuring prioritization of the most underserved and vulnerable groups with considerations for age, gender, and diversity. Particular emphasis will be placed on vulnerable sub-groups such as women, girls, boys, PwD and marginalized groups such as Muhamasheen.

YDR partners will use its presence and extensive community networks to strengthen safe access to multisectoral services at the site level through improved site supervision and coordination, strengthening national and local coordination structures and ensuring that basic services are present in prioritized sites. These services include reception services for new arrivals shelter and WASH infrastructure protection mainstreaming and multi-sectorial referrals, education as well as active coordination of interventions at targeted sites. An estimated 23,807 IDPs will benefit from targeted shelter response such as transitional shelter and shelter upgrades, as well as provision of life-saving assistance including emergency shelter kits and non-food items. An estimated 58,044 IDPs and host community residents will benefit from the provision of comprehensive WASH services, including hygiene promotion activities, distribution of basic and consumable hygiene kits, repair and maintenance of water and sanitation facilities. An estimated 8,988 IDPs and host community residents will benefit from provision of protection services such as individual protection assistance/cash for protection, legal assistance (including awareness, civil documentation), and psychosocial support (unstructured/recreational). 4,900 conflict and displacement-affected children in Al Khukha, Jabal Habashi and Marib City districts will benefit from improved quality education through the rehabilitation of schools, provision of equipment, hygiene and cleaning supplies, and recruitment and training of volunteer teachers to address overcrowded classrooms.

Under the auspices of YDR Consortium, DRC, NRC and ACTED will respond to direct needs within the identified locations, integrating each partner&#x2019;s respective multisectoral presence in these locations, while closely coordinating with IOM and other humanitarian partners&#x2019; operations to cover service gaps. For the purpose of this proposal, DRC is the lead partner, whereas NRC and ACTED are the sub-implementing partners, however, in practice DRC, NRC, and ACTED will operate as consortium partners, under the YDR Consortium umbrella. IOM, which is a non-funded member of the YDR Consortium, will closely coordinate and integrate its activities with YDR partners, and additionally facilitate access to health facilities in DRC&#x2019;s areas of intervention.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACTED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NRC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-24" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taline El Khansa</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 734700118</telephone>
   <email>taline.elkhansa@drc.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Hudaydah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.00062889 43.04031959</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="26">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marib</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.56841151 45.76081505</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="15.6" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="3" percentage="10.6" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="32.1" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="12.6" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="29.1" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-02">6801202.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-02">480084.87</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-20530">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-02">7281287.27</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305424580">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-10">4368772.36</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
