<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/Health-Nutrition/NGO/19679</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Health, Nutrition and C4D Project in Zingibar district (priority district 3) in Abyan governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed integrated Health, Nutrition and C4D project is directed toward the catchment populations of the one health Unit in Zingibar as well as the Internally displaced people (IDP). The project targets 4642 vulnerable beneficiaries (men, women, boys and girls) in Zingibar district in Abyan governorate. The proposed Health, Nutrition ampC4D interventions- through targeting a health facility as well as establishing a mobile clinic providing PHC will participate in the overall action toward relieving suffering and increasing access to the essential health amp nutrition services.   In addition, tthe HF will conduct outreach visit one time per week
FFMF has been working in the catchment zones of the health facility and participate in decreasing the burden on the health facility through the Supplementary Feeding Program (TSFP amp BSFP) it has in Zingibar. This and the referral of SAM cases to the health facility to link the community with the HF. FMF performed a rapid need assessment to familiarize with the needs of the health facility as well as to have a pre-forming idea before project formation/submission. The FMF got strong coordination and support with the stakeholders in Abyan as well as the health and administrative authorities that allow us to propose a project in Zingibar and in the HF specifically. This will assist the project team to smoothly implement the project as well as to effectively achieve the desired outcomes
According to the Health Cluster strategic objective #1, trends should drive increase access of the vulnerable populations including IDPs to Minimum Health Service Package (MSP) in all levels of health care facilities, emphasizing on reproductive health, mental health and psychosocial support, severe malnutrition amp non-communicable diseases. Therefore, FMF would intervene in a Health Unit (HU) to enable providing the services of the MSP, these include general consultation, basic trauma care, RH, IMCI, referral services, immunization..etc. The healthcare workers (HCWs) will be trained on different training sessions that include CMAM, COVID-19 case management, and referral. 
The Nutrition part of the project will be through the provision of the nutrition services via the mobile clinic besides the PHC services provided. The services are TSFP, IYCF, C4D, and nutrition referral services.  
For the C4D activities, FMF will recruit 21CHVs to cover the three zones of the targeted health facility with awareness sessions as well as accompany the mobile clinic in their work in the different IDP camps
The 4,642-targeted beneficiaries are those living in the catchment zones of the health facility- Al-Shiekh Abdullah Health Unit, the IDP camps that are not covered by Abyan GHO intervention, and the IDP within the host communities. The HCWs as well as the CHVs will involve all groups of the community (men, women, boys, and girls), IDP, marginalized people, and people with disabilities (PWD). The IDP camps served are:  Hosn Shadad Camp, Sawahil Camp, Amodiah Camp, Bashaharah Camp, Dahl Ahmed Camp, AlTomaisi Camp, Bagedar Camp, Alnasr Camp. Those camps are the well-defined camps in Zingibar and besides the IDP who will be served and those are dissolved within the host community
Since the HF and the MC will provide nutrition services and those may need nutrition commodities from WFP and UNICEF, there were previous communications in this regard and they will provide us with them. For UNICEF, the commodities will be taken from the GHO stores. The need of nutrition commodities for RUSF &#x201C;2.61 MT for the whole project period&#x201D; and for WSB &#x201C;0.4199 MT for the project period.
FMF confirms the continuous presence in the HF during the project implementation period, through its field and office staff: continuous visits of the Field HampN Officer, MampE assistant amp the deputy HampN coordinator. FMF has been active in Abyan since 2012 and it has been providing H, N, and C4D services in Zingibar district during the previous period.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Field Medical Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Field Medical Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mayada Nabih</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundraising Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>770578894</telephone>
   <email>mayada.nabih@fmfyemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mouad Al-Mansab</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>772745820</telephone>
   <email>mouad.almansab@fmfyemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saber Ghale</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundraising Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>734883158</telephone>
   <email>saber.ghaleb@fmfyemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="12">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abyan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.69554850 46.50340692</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="57.1" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="42.9" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-26">79015.83</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-26">218109.82</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19679">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-26">297125.65</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Field Medical Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305167115">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-31">118850.26</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Field Medical Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305476721">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-21">89137.7</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Field Medical Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
