<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/WASH/INGO/19519</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priority #3: Emergency WASH assistance to most vulnerable IDPs and host community in Maqbanah District of Taizz Governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 12-month project proposes to provide emergency life-saving WASH assistance to the recently conflict-affected IDPs in Al Hagab and Al Rahabah IDPs sites and other vulnerable host communities living in Al Fakikah, Al Affairah, Bani Himyar, and Al Yemen  sub-districts (under IRG control) in Maqbanah district, Taizz Governorate. For more than seven years, OXFAM is operational and has an office in ALTurbah thus, it is well-positioned and capacitated to respond to the identified needs in the Maqbanah district. The project aims to provide humanitarian emergency WASH assistance for 17,353 IDPs and vulnerable host communities (4,385 women, 4,435 men, 4,073 girls, 4,458 boys) to access safe and basic WASH services. The project will adopt a robust community engagement approach. The targeted IDPs and host communities will be motivated, mobilized, and engaged to deliver the various WASH interventions proposed.
Oxfam will rehabilitate and restore one public water supply scheme and seven other open water sources, all to be solarized with water pumping sets to ensure the provision of safe, sufficient, and affordable drinking water supply to 8,512 persons (1988 IDPs and 6,524 host  communities) who are currently fetching the water from open water sources and at high public health-related risks.
To avoid water contamination during water collection and storage, OXFAM will distribute 1000 locally -made, easy-to-OampM, and environment-friendly water ceramic filters to allow IDPs and other vulnerable HHs to treat the drinking water at the HH level to reduce the risks of water-related diseases. Through its Sani-Teak progressive approach, OXFAM will ensure IDPs access gender-protection sensitive and socially accepted sanitation by constructing new 50 emergency shared latrines for IDPs. IDPs, including women, girls, and children, will be intensively engaged and consulted about the main gender-related risks, protection concerns, needs, and preferences they retain and would like to have in the provided and constructed latrines. Besides, all latrines will be linked with simple handwashing facilities and supplied with latrine sanitation kits to enable BNFs to maintain handwashing with soap and maintain the latrines&apos; functional and hygienic conditions. In parallel, OXFAM PHP teams and skilled CHVs will be equipped with skills and tools to effectively deliver hygiene promotion activities in the targeted IDP sites and other communities in Maqbanah district. IDPs and other BNFs will be provided with basic standard hygiene kits. Women and girls will receive additional support of menstruation hygiene material and extensive and influential hygiene promotion sessions. Gender assessment and analysis ensured women&apos;s inclusion and safe programming during the lifecycle of the project. Coordination with line authorities community engagement, and capacity building for the Water community committees and CHVs will ensure sustainability in project initiatives. Before starting the project, the project will conduct gender and protection-related risks assessment to provide staff, partners, and BNFs with clear mitigation measures. The project will use the existing Oxfam security management SOPs and COVID-19 SOPs to ensure BNFs, CHVs, and OXFAM staff safety. Learnings will be gathered, capitalized, and shared with the WASH cluster community members, and OXFAM affiliates in other countries. Oxfam&apos;s WASH team will implement the project activities in ALTurbah office, with the support of a local partner and WASH advisor from the country office to ensure quality and standard deliverables. Finally, strengthening the resilience of the targeted communities through durable water schemes, community engagement, and capacity building are deemed to cope with future need.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taha</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>739705557</telephone>
   <email>talraeeini@oxfam.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-07">182829.67</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-07">367170.33</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19519">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-07">550000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305186481">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-15">220000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
