<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/Nutrition/INGO/19168</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency life-saving nutrition response for vulnerable populations in Mustaba district, Hajjah Governorate (Priority 3)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the intervention, Relief International (RI) will deliver life-saving nutrition services through support to 4 static health facilities (HFs) in Mustaba district, Hajjah - Al-Sha&apos;fal Health Unit (HU), Al-Sawafah HU, Al-Mawzat HU, and Shat&#x2019;e Al Bard HU - through implementation of CMAM and support to optimal IYCF practices. RI will implement nutrition activities in the static HFs and also support outreach activities to increase access to nutrition services for IDPs and host communities living in second and third tier zones.
Key services will include:
- Management of SAM through OTP where children 6-59 months will be screened for malnutrition, classified based on MUAC measurements and z-Score and treated using RUTF. RI will coordinate with the GHO in Hajjah and UNICEF to ensure uninterrupted supply of RUTF. Children with SAM will also be supported with hygiene kits to promote good hygiene practices in their households and prevent hygiene related diseases that have a direct impact on the nutrition status of all family members.
- Treatment of children 6-59 months and PLWs with moderate acute malnutrition through a targeted supplementary feeding program (TSFP) using RUSF for CU5 and FBF for the PLWs. RI will coordinate with GHO and WFP to ensure supply of supplementary foods throughout the project.
- Support to practice of optimal IYCF for children and caregivers of children 0-23 months through IYCF corners in the supported HFs. IYCF difficulties will be assessed and support provided including treatment of infections, IYCF counselling and referral of children with severe wasting and requiring surgical interventions to secondary/tertiary hospital and stabilization centers.
RI will support HFs with 1) payment of hazard allowances for the nutrition workers to ensure that health service delivery is undertaken by qualified staff 2) provision of medical supplies, pharmaceuticals, medical equipment and furniture to ensure that HFs have the capacity to provide nutrition services, and 3) HF rehabilitation to ensure adequate and safe water supply, sanitation and waste management facilities to uphold standards of safety and comfort within the HFs. 
Healthcare staff will be trained in CMAM and receive regular supportive supervision visits to ensure they are able to provide quality identification, management, follow-up and referral of cases. They will also receive orientation on protection, gender and inclusion mainstreaming to strengthen their support to particularly vulnerable persons while ensuring they are adhering to the highest standards of mainstreaming principles. RI will further support preparedness and response for outbreaks including COVID-19 through prepositioning of response materials such as PPE, establishment of a triage system and training of HF staff on IPC. 
RI will ensure continued presence in HFs through the project officer and assistant who will visit the HFs twice per week and supervise outreach activities on alternate outreach days. RI has an office in Hajjah and has budgeted for a program car to facilitate the movement of staff to program areas.
To ensure consistent supply of nutrition supplies, RI has coordinated with WFP and has to provide information on the proposed action. WFP has confirmed that TSFP supplies for the supported health facilities are provided through the GHO and RI will continue to coordinate with the GHO and provide technical support to ensure consistent supply and accountability. RI has not yet directly coordinated with UNICEF for SAM management supplies but similar conversations will be initiated before the start of activities.
The areas of intervention and identified HFs have been selected in collaboration with the GHO in Hajjah and MoPHP in Sana&#x2019;a, both of which were actively engaged in the nomination process. RI is undertaking further coordination with government ministries including SCMCHA to facilitate timely approval at project outset.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdirahman Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 711 788 880</telephone>
   <email>abdirahman.ali@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Morgane Aveline</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East Interim Regional Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+962 7 75 46 80 73</telephone>
   <email>morgane.aveline@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hajjah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.27488061 43.11225315</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-07">168870.81</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-07">276556.55</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19168">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-07">445427.36</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
