<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/FSAC/NGO/19548</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priority 4: Life-sustaining food security support to the most vulnerable people in need in Maqbanah district of Taiz governorate to improve their resilience &#x2013;YHF 1st Standard Allocation 2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposed project is implemented under Priority 4: Provision of life-sustaining services and protection to the most vulnerable people in acute needs to improve their resilience of the YHFSA1 2021, with the objective to leave no one behind at a time when 5 million vulnerable people are just one step away from famine and the humanitarian response remains underfunded&#x201D;. The 12-months intervention will provide life-sustaining amp lifesaving food security and livelihood support to the 600 HHs ((4,200 individuals 999 men, 1,147, 993 boys and 1,062 girls) most vulnerable in need in Maqbanah district,Taiz governorate to improve their FS amp resilience allowing them to meet their basic food and livelihood needs through cash for work assistance to 400 HHs for 3 months, Micro-business startup assistance to 175 HHs for one time and vocational training to 200 HHs. This project will contribute to FSAC objective of &#x2018;Improve access to livelihoods opportunities, increase household incomes and rehabilitate food security assets and infrastructure in areas with high levels of food insecurity. TYF will adhere to the amount of cash assistance as per FSAC Conditional Programmes Guidelines and FSAC YHF SA1 2021 Guidance notes. TYF will adopt FSAC&#x2019;s vulnerability and targeting criteria to select the HHs including most vulnerable households elderly, PWDs, minority groups, including but not limited to women headed HHs, HHs with PLW, and MAM cases as well as children with SAM cases, Vulnerable IDP HHs, Vulnerable HHs with no productive assets, or functional means of income/ reliable source of income, no formal employment, no land and productive assets. This project has designed based on the NA conducted in Maqbanah district in June 2021 to identify food and livelihood needs of the targeted beneficiaries. The project activities including market and labor assessment to determine appropriate modality of cash and the appropriateness of CFW, microbusiness and vocational training. Further, TYF will conduct baseline and endline assessments to measure the food security indicators before and after the project,Selection of CFMCs, beneficiaries verification and registration, Provision of micro-business startup grant assistance, vocational training, provision of cash for work to 400 HHs for 3 months, rehabilitation of 3 community assets, PTM and PTM. TYF has the technical capacity and access to implement this project. In terms of capacity, TYF has already implemented a YHF-funded food security and livelihood projects in Maqbanah district 20/21 which was evaluated by the third Party Monitoring (TPM) as &quot;good performance&quot;. In addition, TYF is currently implementing other FAO-funded food security and livelihood interventions in Maqbanah and many Governorates (Taiz, Abyan, Lahj, Aden, Ibb). In terms of access, TYF has its main office in Sana&#x2019;a governorate and branchs in Taiz and Ibb and in  Maqbanah and can easily access thorough its office and staff exist in the district. TYF have built excellent good relation with authority and other stakeholders through the previous YHF SA1 2020 Health and education project in Maqbanah district. TYF has assumed some risks that might be faced during the implementation of this project and planned to mitigate them:1.access constraint in the target areas which can be mitigated by enhancing the coordination with local authorities and issuing the required documents to facilitate the distribution of assistance.2 exclusion of some beneficiaries which can be mitigated by raising the awareness on beneficiary selection criteria, introducing different channels of complaints and feedback mechanism, 3 conflict escalation in district which can be mitigated by coordinating with local authority at the level of district as well as governorate to ensure safe access to project location and deconflicting the activity sites and routes on the days of assistance distributions. TYF coordinates its activities with FSAC amp other stakeholders to avoid duplication</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tamdeen Youth Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tamdeen Youth Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdulrazzak Alfarran</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>730100497</telephone>
   <email>afarran@tamdeen-ye.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eisa Qahtan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>730002674</telephone>
   <email>e.qahtan@tamdeen-ye.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tammam Alhitari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>730002441</telephone>
   <email>t.alhitari@tamdeen-ye.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">132077.11</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">264154.22</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19548">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">396231.33</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tamdeen Youth Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305156002">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-23">158492.53</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tamdeen Youth Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
