<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA 2/CCM/NGO/20717</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Site Management and Coordination to Enhance dignified living condition  for IDPs in Hosting Sites in Al Mukha District, Governorate of Taiz &#x2013;  priority 1</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is 11-months project aims to ensure integrated assistance to 1020 IDPs HHs (4918 individuals 
( W 1097,G 1292, M 1016, B 1513 ) living in hosting sites in Al Mukha District, Taiz Governorate, through CCCM package of activities including the establishment of functional community self-governing committees with inclusive participation and conducting a functional monthly meeting of self-governing committees in 12 IDP Hosting Sites training for NOG partners working in Al Mukha amp local authorities on SMC and organizing monthly coordination meeting, establishing functional Complaints and Feedback Mechanisms for 12 hosting sites, and cash of $75 for maintenance amp shelter upgrades to 640 HHs. This proposed project is covering 12 sites by multi-sector monitoring (including inhabitant list verifications) assessments, monitoring amp updating of population movements. Besides, contingency activities such as sites planning, which will be implemented if some sites s are threatened with eviction, where the executive unit will work to find appropriate land to receive displaced persons and GWQ will work on land planning to move IDPs to the new sites in addition to providing water services in case there are no partners covering the sites with water services. GWQ will work to provide water and cover the gap until another partner is found. Women will be ensured to participate in training and regular meeting of local authorities and partners. Also, they will be encouraged to represent IDPs in community committees. Females will participate in mass communication campaigns, and population movement updating. People with special needs will also be encouraged to represent IDPs in the sites structure of the established community committees. 200 host community HHs (1400 individuals) in surrounding of the hosting sites will be targeted with awareness and IEC materials. 12 IDPs sites are proposed to be targeted in this intervention named (named (1- Al Hasseb, 2- Al Shaheed Hamood, 3- Al Sowais , 4- Al Qahira, 5- Al Shatheli, 6- Al Hali, 7- Al Niaba old building, 8- Old Government building, 9- Al Zahaira, 10- Al Raowais, 11- Al Qatabia and 12- Al Holaibi).
Referral Mechanism will be implemented through the meetings with the sites committees, and monthly assessment of sites. Also, the population of the site will be aware of feedback amp referral mechanisms by targeted in awareness campaigns. Monthly report amp referral maps will be developed amp shared with the cluster, sub-clusters ampNGOs to address the needs in an integrated response.
To be aligned with 2nd allocation Strategy,2021,&apos; objective of Improving dignified living conditions for the most vulnerable IDPs in under-served IDP sites and supporting partners&#x2019; interventions in new sites lacking services in prioritized sub-districts through integrated interventions, GWQ has coordinated with different partners to cover the gaps of services in hosting sites in AlMukha districts where SI will cover WASH, FS L and shelter gaps, IMC (Health amp Nutrition ), NRC(Protection, WASH) and AOBWC (S/NFIs).
This project is a reflection of the 2021 HRP strategic objectives 3 &quot; protecting and assisting civilians &quot;, which aims to prevent, mitigate protection risks and facilitate redress for women, men, girls, and boys, especially the displaced and most vulnerable civilians through building their resilience, humanitarian assistance, specialized protection services, and advocacy. Also, it fits with the 2021 Humanitarian Response Plan1, CCCCM Cluster Objective 1: &#x201C;Strengthen safe access to multi-sectorial services at site level through improved site supervision and coordination&#x201D;. 
Being a partner of CCCM and Shelter/NFIs clusters and carrying out several projects in Al-Mukha, GWQ has strong access to Al-Mukha as it has established good relationships with all stakeholders, which can help to get smooth access to the targeted areas and to implement the project activities successfully.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generations Without Qat</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generations Without Qat</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mesk Alabsi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>770115919</telephone>
   <email>misk.absi@gwq-ye.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-03"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-02"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-13">242531.55</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-20717">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-13">242531.55</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generations Without Qat</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305377961/62">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-19">97012.62</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generations Without Qat</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305636667/6668">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-16">97012.62</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generations Without Qat</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
