<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA1/WASH/NGO/19277</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priority 2.-Provision of life-saving integrated WASH response for the affected people with high severity of needs in Hays district in Al Hodeidah governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project links to 1st standard allocation-2021, the WASH priority two: Provide comprehensive WASH response in close coordination with nutrition and health responses to address acute needs of the affected people in hard to reach, frontlines or under-served areas with high severity of needs.
 The For Human Development Foundation (FHD) aimed with this project to contribute to improving well-being and reduce risk of WASH related disease, malnutrition and improving conditions for IDPs and vulnerable host communities in Al-Saba&#x2019;a Al-Olya, Al-Saba&#x2019;a Al-Sufla, and Al-Eqsh areas in Hays district in Al Hodeidah governorate, by ensuring adequate and dignified access to improved water and sanitation facilities, hygiene materials, and essential knowledge to optimize the health related WASH practices.
The need assessment conducted by FHD in May 2021 showed clearly the high severity of needs to safe water, hygiene materials and sanitation facilities among people in targeted areas. As mentioned in attached detailed need assessment report and related Factsheet, only 1% of surveyed HHs reported with access to enough water for drinking, cooking, bathing and washing. With no access to related knowledge and supplies only 8% of surveyed HHs who ever treat their drinking water. 91% HHs had issues accessing soap in last 30 days prior to data collection and 97% of these HHs reported that the soap is too expensive. 77% of the household reported experiencing differs issues related to access to latrines including too crowded latrines, private-less latrines, and not functioning or full (overflowing septic tanks). 
As mentioned in attached DHO letter, SAM prevalence is high in the targeted areas. In close coordination with nutrition and health partners, FHD is going to address acute WASH needs highlighted above through delivering integrated WASH response including the following key activities:
 Three-month&#x2019;s water trucking for 250 needed households in Al-Eqsh village, reported with need to travelling more than 31 minutes to bring water.
 Provision in-kind water treatment chemicals for 1150 affected households&#x2019; in targeted areas.
 Rehabilitate/upgrade the Al-Saba&#x2019;a water scheme.
 Rehabilitate/ upgrade of 60 family latrines for the most vulnerable IDPs and SAM HHs in targeted areas.
 Providing operational support for the Cleaning Fund in Hay district to ensure desludging regularly overflowing septic tanks within the targeted IDPs sites and host communities.
 Mobilize the targeted IDPs and host communities to conduct monthly cleaning campaigns, 
 Provision of 1,000 in-kind consumable hygiene kits for most vulnerable SAM households (125 SAM HHs/month  for 8 months).
 Training of 30 CHVs (50% female) on hygiene messages, community engagement, household water treatment and safe storage (HHSWT), and RCCE for COVID-19
 Conduct raising awareness sessions, home visits, and distribution IEC materials.
To insure good community participation in all project implementation phases and to create ownership for the outputs, FHD will work closely with the targeted communities&#x2019; leaders and active groups to organize people in targeted communities according to inter-linkages and needs in gender based groups. Equally male and female of all ages including those with disabilities will be encouraged to represent these groups in counselling sessions that will be hold during the project preparation phase to determine all issues relate to implementation of proposed interventions, which commonly include time of water trucking, time and site for supplies distribution and distribution mechanism, so they can voice their concerns and express their preferences while implementing project activities.
The households headed by women, child, disabled persons and elderly will have prioritized during selection the beneficiaries from the each activity. The project field team will be selected from the targeted communities to insure better access in different scenarios.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">For Human Development Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">For Human Development Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mona Alhajri</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Unit Head</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>775900889</telephone>
   <email>mona@fhdye.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somaia Al-asad</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wash Unit Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>770456765</telephone>
   <email>somaia@fhdye.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Hudaydah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.00062889 43.04031959</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">129237.71</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">154523.35</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-19277">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-17">283761.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For Human Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305156005">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-23">113504.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For Human Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305477966/967">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-17">85128.32</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For Human Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
