<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA 2/SHNFI-Protection/NGO/20642</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rehabilitation of the damaged Houses of the Vulnerable People (Priority 2) &#x2013;linking with livelihood support to empower the target HH in Al-Mudhaffar district- Taizz Governorate.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This 8-month Shelter project aims - through a set of activities planned and would be implemented in line with the objectives of the two clusters and their strategy for the SA2 of YHF 2021, giving priority to the most vulnerable and affected people in the light of the cluster&apos;s vulnerability criteria &#x2013; at providing (44) vulnerable HHs in Al-Mudhaffar district of Taiz city with cash for rehabilitation of their damaged houses, which will help in re-establishing them in areas of return and more durable and sustainable shelter solutions, making them live in safe and habitable residences. Regarding the amount of assistance, each targeted HH will receive ($ 2300) through cash-based modality in three payments. Besides, one individual from each of the targeted HHs will receive vocational training (44 youths from males and females) according to their skills and cash assistance for empowerment kits to start up their own works to enhance their self-reliance to be able to address their basic needs and be more stable.
This makes the proposed project in line with the priority 2 of SA2 2021 in particular and with SA2 2021 in general, which prioritizes supporting durable solutions and responding to the need of vulnerable groups in a holistic and integrated manner, including protection activities through linking the intervention with empowerment activities. This also makes the project aligned with the objectives of the Shelter/NFIs cluster which highlights the importance of developing the resilience of the affected population through mid and long-term shelter solutions to improve sub-standard conditions considering the durability of structures. Besides, responding to the SA2 2021, the project activities were planned and will be implemented to give priority in particular for vulnerable people that have returned or are trying to return and re-establish themselves in their areas of origin, giving priority PWDs as well as other vulnerable groups, such as  female-headed households, elderly and sufferers of chronic illnesses, etc.
In terms of complementarity and integration, BCFHD will establish coordination with organizations concerned with IDPs and returnees, such as INTERSOs, Solidarities International, Human Access to ensure the provision of integrated support for the vulnerable HHs who will also receive cash for empowerment to improve their income and be more stable. 
Based on the project&apos;s context and BCFHD&apos;s experience, some risks in relation to increase in the number of returnees who are in needs for cash assistance for rehabilitation and in relation to receiving the first payment of the cash assistance without achieving the required portion of rehabilitation have been expected and procedures to mitigate determined as indicated in the Assumptions and Risks tab.
Being an active partner of Shelter/NFIs and other clusters, carrying out several projects in the targeted districts in various sectors, and having experienced staff, including civil engineers BCFHD can implement the project activities successfully.
What is special about this project is its exit strategy which is reflected in the provision of cash assistance to vulnerable people that have returned or are trying to return and re-establish themselves in their areas of origin to make rehabilitation for their damaged houses, which will provide them with durable and sustainable shelter solutions and make them live in safe and habitable residences. Besides, one individual from each of the targeted HHs will receive vocational training according to their capacity, skills, and interests and cash assistance for empowerment kits to start up their own works to enhance their self-reliance to be able to address their basic needs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bena Charity For Human Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bena Charity For Human Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Motahr Faed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PM</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>770132061</telephone>
   <email>BY.SOCIAL@GMAIL.COM</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdulkarem Abdullah Ahmed Shamsan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of the Org</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>771151581</telephone>
   <email>bena@bcfhd.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="85" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="15" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-13">200007.61</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-20642">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-13">200007.61</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bena Charity For Human Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305377956/57">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-19">80003.04</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bena Charity For Human Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305636665/6666">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-16">80003.04</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bena Charity For Human Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
