<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA 2/Education-Protection/NGO/20637</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provide Education  Child Protection in Schools Interventions Serving Vulnerable community in Al Qahira district in Taizz Governorate under Priority (2)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is an Education/Child Protection  project targeting highly vulnerable community of Al Qahira district in Taizz Gov. The proposal is planned based on beneficiaries&#x2019; needs as well as communication with the Education sub-cluster and the relevant authorities at different levels. 11 schools were studied for their urgent needs in a Specific In-Depth Assessment in coordination with West Cost Sub-Cluster amp Education Offices (please see RNA report). 4 schools were prioritized to be targeted in this intervention for their urgent needs amp high number of students. 

5,601 school-aged children primary amp secondary schools will be provided by education/child protection services 2,906 girls amp 2,695 boys as well as 300 males amp 192 females ( i.e. parents/caregivers, teachers, education staff, social workers, businessmen, community figures, Education local partners) will benefit from the project. Equipped by YHF assistance, SOUL will be able to reach out to give a hand to the neediest including IDPs, returnees, minorities amp with disabilities. 
SOUL is proposing with 2 projects targeting the same location for complementarity. Through this project, SOUL will be able to contribute to achieving the YHF objectives for priority (2) working in harmony with other partners as SI amp INTERSOS to provide the assistance in Al Qahira dis. In addition, with YHF support amp as a SAG member of the Global amp National Education Clusters, SOUL will join YEC efforts for building the capacity of Education partners to work effectively.

The planned Education project is to cover gap in the following schools:
1. Bakatheer School.
2. Nasser School.
3. Khadija School.
4. Al wihda for girls School.

The proposed activities include the following:
1. Establishing, expanding new Temporary Classrooms TLCs.
2. Supporting volunteer teachers by providing incentives.
3. Provision of repaired school desks.
4. Provision of essential school supplies.
5. Provision of white/black boards.
6. Provision of Teachers kits.
7. Provision of Recreational Kits.
8. Provision of basic learning materials (School Bags) to vulnerable amp needy students.
9. Establishing amp supporting of Parents Teachers Association (PTA) amp enhancing women efficient participation.
10. Building the capacities of Parents Teachers Association (PTA) and representatives of Mothers&#x2019; amp Fathers&#x2019; Councils on Social Responsibility, AAP and Community Participation Approach.
11. Building the capacities of schoolteachers on the basics of active learning amp student center classes Early Learning Approach and non-formal education training.
12. Delivering awareness raising messages on: Importance of EDUCATION as well as providing psychosocial support amp consultancies to parents, teachers and social workers through SOUL call center and providing the same group with hygiene promotion through SOUL other proposed project.
13. Supporting education local partners to overcome language barriers enabling them to provide effective interventions. 

for the protection, SOUL is proposing the below activities which will be in line and coordinated with INTERSOS amp other partners as appropriate:
1. Activity 1.1.1  Support children with disabilities through case management to be refereed to the above partner
2. Activity 1.2.1 Conduct community initiatives to support social cohesion amp re-establishment of the returnees.


In this project SOUL will be utilizing local competencies for more durable outcomes.

As of 2011, SOUL maintains its presence in Taizz mainly through Nutrition, Health, WASH, FSAC amp Education interventions in around 15 districts Thus, this project will utilize SOUL&#x2019;s multi sectorial experience, its very good connections, and coordination capabilities. Accessibility risks are inevitable. However, since the projects&#x2019; staff will be recruited from the targeted areas amp SOUL maintains its intense pre-coordination, the project</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOUL for Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOUL for Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-04" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hend Attiah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Development Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967-774 099 164</telephone>
   <email>h_attiah@soul-yemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammed Al Nhari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967-712 000 052</telephone>
   <email>m_al-nhari@soul-yemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="99.1" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="0.9" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-05"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-17">430297.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-17">4781.08</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-20637">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-17">435078.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOUL for Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
