<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-21/3420/SA 2/WASH-FSAC-Protection/INGO/20677</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priority 1: Provision of safe and comprehensive WASH, FSL, and Protection response to cover the basic needs and increase dignified living conditions in the under-served IDP sites and crises-affected communities in Marib district.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of this project is to provide access to food, water, sanitation, and hygiene, as well as adequate protection services. Underserved 11 IDP locations in Aal Rashid Munif, Aal Jalal, and Aal Shabwan subdistricts of Marib district, Marib, who face the threat of famine, disease, and direct protection. Oxfam takes a multi-sectoral, cash-based, and participatory approach to meet the multiple humanitarian needs of selected beneficiaries. Interventions proposed are aligned with Priority One of the YHF 2nd Standard Allocation 2021 and the Oxfam Country Strategy 2022-25.
A total of 14,074 IDPs and crisis-affected host communities will be assisted (3,659 men, 3,096 women, 3,800 boys, 3,519 girls), of which 11,347 live in 11 underserved IDPs settlements. The water supply interventions will cover and benefit 11347 IDPs (2,950 men, 2,496 women, 3,064 boys, 2,837 girls) enabling them to have access to safe, sufficient, and reliable drinking and domestic water supply services through the water supply networks extension. 14,047 IDPs and crisis-affected host communities will be assisted by OXFAM to have improved access to adequate gender-protection-sensitive sanitation facilities and be enabled to exercise dignified personal and environmental hygiene promotion practices. OXFAM will construct 344socially accepted and gender-protection sensitive new latrines through its Sani Tweak approach through which targeted communities including women and girls are widely consulted on the latrines design, locations, sharing modality&#x2026;etc, and further 120 latrines will be rehabilitated and functionalized as well. All latrines will be provided with cleaning kits, and hygiene kits will be distributed to 14,047 IDPs and surrounding communities.   The latrines and hygiene kits assistance will be priorities to the vulnerable IDPs and priority will be given to the IDP HHs selected by the food security intervention,  A total of 1,200 HHs (8,400 individuals) selected through a community-based targeting method will receive cash/voucher support to meet their minimum food needs over 6 months along with WASH and protection services. The support will prevent the beneficiaries from the risk of famine and use negative coping mechanisms such as begging and child labor.
Oxfam will pursue a joint planning and coordination approach among the sectors to ensure better integration of the interventions to meet the multiple needs of  beneficiaries and increase synergy and  impacts  
Protection activities will centralize EFSVL and WASH activities where protection activities will support the third level of activities for the same targeted beneficiaries as specialized services, EFSVL and WASH community committees will have a session on protection risks/threats and how they can act with persons with protections risks and what are the available referral channels within Oxfam. Moreover, the protection team will attend EFSVL community committees and WASH listening groups to address protection issues raised by the committee&#x2019;s members and provide the needed protection assistance. In addition, Community-based protection networks and protection team reports including protection issues related to water, sanitation, Hygiene, and UCT activities will be mitigated daily in coordination with other sectors. Furthermore, Cash for protection will target cases referred by other sectors who have protection risks and cash will contribute to protection outcome and internal referral within Oxfam sectors will be supported and a follow-up process will be led by the protection team. Finally, WASH and EFSVL technical team will support the implementation of protection community initiatives when needed</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taha Al Raeeini</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 739 705 557</telephone>
   <email>talraeeini@oxfam.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="26">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marib</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.56841151 45.76081505</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="10" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-27">1922552.21</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-27">76902.09</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-20677">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-27">1999454.3</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
