<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-9528</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sociedad Agricola Drokasa S.A.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name:    PERU-AGROKASA      Region:Latin America and Caribbean   Sector:   Project No:009528   Projected Board Date:June 1, 1999   Company Name:Sociedad Agricola Drokasa S.A.   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	Headquartered in Ica (300KM south of Lima), Agrokasa is a wholly owned subsidiary of  Corporacion Drokasa, one of Perus leading producer/distributor of pharmaceutical, health, beauty products, liquor and  miscellaneous foods. Drokasa was founded in 1996 with the acquisition of fundo Santa Rita in Ica (200 ha)initiating a successful 150 ha pilot project growing grapes and asparagus. Agrokasa uses state-of-the-art drip irrigation technology; packing is presently contracted out to third parties and water resources have been secured through purchase, conditioning and rehabilitation of its own wells.      Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	The project cost is US$22 million.  IFC is considering a US$6 million investment in the form of a loan.    Location of project and Description of site    	Agrokasa&apos;&apos; expansion site and future packing facility  are in the Department of Ica 300KM south of Lima.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	The Project consists of developing a high value horticulture operation in Ica based on exports of asparagus and grapes to Europe and the United States. After a very successful pilot project, the company plans to expand the hectares under asparagus and grapes cultivation from 73 has. to 730 has. and from 65 has. to 360 has. respectively.  The project also includes: i) the construction of an export packhouse; ii) completion of infrastructure work; iii) working capital for growing crops; iv) an integrated feeding center for cattle that will be fed from asparagus brushwood using their manure to fertilize the land; and v) debt restructuring.      Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a category B project according to IFCs environmental review procedure because specific impacts may result which can be avoided or mitigated by adhering to generally recognized performance standards, guidelines or design criteria.  Key environmental, social and occupational health and safety issues that were of potential concern in the project include:  land acquisition and prior land uses; sustainability of irrigation water supply; impacts on environmentally-sensitive areas; use of Integrated Pest Management and pesticide use;   impacts of air and wastewater emissions and solid wastes; general worker health and safety.    The company has acquired two farm sites near Ica.  One of which (Santa Rita) was formerly owned by a cooperativa.  Although it was not required as part of the purchase, the sponsor provided a compensation package to the former cooperative owners who unanimously transferred land possession. The process of consultation and compensation has been documented and details of the process are presented as a resettlement plan attached to the ERS.      Ground water rights are allocated by the Ministry of Agricultures department for natural resources (INRENA) who are also responsible for monitoring groundwater levels.  The sponsor has a well-documented record of the methods by which water rights were obtained and this material forms part of a resettlement plan attached to the ERS.    Impacts on environmentally-sensitive areas: The Santa Rita farm is a long established farm and contains no sites of ecological importance.  The La Catalina site comprises an area reclaimed from desert and did not contain areas of ecological significance.  Neither site is near to any protected areas of ecological significance.    Use of Integrated Pest Management and pesticide use: The sponsor is developing an integrated pest management system that includes management, biological and chemical control systems.    Impacts of air and wastewater emissions and solid waste: The company does not generate power and there are no significant emissions to the atmosphere except for methyl bromide which will be used in compliance with US requirements and phased out in accordance with international requirements of the Montreal Protocol and replaced with an acceptable alternative fumigant.    Wastewater will come from washing facilities (potential significant contaminants will include chlorine) and septic waters. The sponsor is discussing options for the treatment of process wash waters and has confirmed that treatment will achieve WBG requirements.  Septic waters will be discharged to on site septic tanks.    General worker health and safety:   At the Santa Rita site, the company will employ approximately 180 full time staff rising to up to 600 during harvest.  Additionally, Fundo La Catalina will employ from 390 permanent employees rising to 1,400 during the harvest season. The company has an occupational health and safety plan and provides appropriate training for all employees.    The  is  April 30, 1999 from the InfoShop.       Date SPI sent to InfoShop:     April 30, 1999      This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sociedad Agricola Drokasa S.A.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-9528" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1999-12-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-01-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peru</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="PE-Peru">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-10.0000000000 -75.2500000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AF - Fruits and Vegetables</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $6.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1999-12-02"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2000-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-12-02">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1999-12-02"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2000-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-12-02">6000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1999-12-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-12-02">6000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sociedad Agricola Drokasa S.A.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1999-12-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-12-02">0</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sociedad Agricola Drokasa S.A.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/9528/sociedad-agricola-drokasa-s-a">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
