<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-11007</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gloria, S.A.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gloria, S.A. is a Peruvian company with three main business divisions: food, paper products and pharmaceuticals.  It also has investments in the cement industry through its subsidiary, Cemento Yura, S.A.  In 2000, Gloria reported sales of US$226.6 million.  The food division (90% of sales) is primarily involved in the production, sale, and distribution of dairy products including evaporated, condensed, and UHT milk, yogurt, and cheese. The company also distributes canned fish and fruit juices with its Gloria brand name. The pharmaceutical division (5% of sales) produces and distributes a range of drugs and cosmetic products. The paper division (5% of sales) manufactures corrugated board, boxes and liner.         Gloria has had a leadership position in the Peruvian dairy industry for 50 years. It was founded in 1941 in Arequipa, Peru, as Leche Gloria, S.A. with majority ownership by General Mills company of the U.S. and subsequently by Nestle.  The present shareholders acquired the company in 1986 from both local shareholders and from Nestle, and have since progressively grown the business into its present more diversified profile. In 1998, the company started a strategic investment program (the project) whose main objectives were to (i) consolidate and rationalize its dairy sector operations into a new production facility in Huachipa, near Lima; (ii) build a new UHT plant; (iii) expand domestic milk collection; and (iv) upgrade its paper division with a new plant in Huachipa.  The project will allow Gloria to expand northward from its traditional base in Arequipa, southern Peru, bringing it closer to its main consumer markets.       Development Impact:    IFCs support of Gloria will have a positive development impact in Peru in three areas:     First   , the project will  support rural farmers serving the Peruvian dairy industry with technical assistance (  Gloria assists its suppliers by providing technical assistance including breeding stock improvements, cattle nutrition to improve quality and yields; veterinary services) and reliable market access with guaranteed daily milk collection and regular payments;     Second   , IFC will support an important Peruvian employer: the company has 1,720 employees and its   operations are highly integrated, extending into many remote and rural communities.  The company works with 15,000 farmers, most with less than 10 head of cattle; only 5% of Gloria&apos;&apos;s suppliers have more than 100 head of cattle; and     Third   : Gloria&apos;&apos;s activities will increase the consumption of safe, quality, pasteurized milk in rural areas in Peru by making available both canned and UHT products (which require no refrigeration and have a long shelf-life) through its extensive distribution network.  Perus milk consumption has shown an increased trend, but it is currently only 58 liters per capita p.a., compared with the FAO recommended level of 121 liters per capita, p.a. (   source: USDA Peru: Dairy situation 2000   ).  Finally, Peru is a milk deficit country.  The project will help further develop the Peruvian dairy industry, and the government of Peru is encouraging greater domestic milk collection and dairy production as a way of reducing milk imports.      IFC Role   : Among its other contributions, IFC will provide Gloria with long-term financing currently not available locally.  Gloria embarked on its strategic investment program prior to Peru&apos;&apos;s financial distress of 1999 and political crisis of 1999-2001.   Due to recession and political uncertainty in Peru, the company approached IFC for long-term financing on terms not available locally.  The company requires adequate tenor given that it has entered a consolidation phase in which it will integrate new assets and complete the rationalization of its operations between its traditional southern base in Arequipa and its new plant in Huachipa, Lima.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gloria S.A.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-11007" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2003-07-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2005-08-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Francis Pilkington, CFO, Grupo Gloria         Address: Av. Republica de Panama, 2461 Sta. Catalina, Lima PERU         Phone: (511-470-7170)         Fax: (511-470-9837)</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peru</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="PE-Peru">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project site is primarily Gloria&apos;&apos;s newly constructed production facility in Huachipa, near Lima, Peru.  The new plant is located on a 10 hectare site as part of a larger, 31 hectare property in the district of Ate Vitarte, a suburb of Lima with good infrastructure and transportation routes.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-10.0000000000 -75.2500000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AI - Other Food</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $25.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2003-07-02"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2004-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2003-07-02">25000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2003-07-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2003-07-02">25000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gloria S.A.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/11007/gloria-s-a">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
