<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-10651</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inka Terra, Peru S.A.C.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project proactively supports positive environmental development by encouraging environmentally friendly, sustainable tourism activities and may generate more widespread uptake of eco-tourism through replication by others.  The Sponsor has a proven track record in development of eco-toursim facilities and dedication to ecological study, development and conservation.    The Company has been offering eco- tourism experiences since the mid-1970s, initially with Cuzco Amazonico and more recently with the Machu Picchu Pueblo Hotel.    The existing hotels are recognized internationally as locations for scientific research.  Furthermore, Inka Terra is in the process of offering ecological study programs that provide academic credit for accredited institutions in the United States.    Over the years, the Company has achieved the delicate balance necessary to operate a profitable business while fostering an environment that protects local nature and culture, as well as augmenting scientific studies and ecological awareness of the area.  Sr. Koechlin has also contributed significantly to the government&apos;&apos;s efforts and awareness of environmental protection.    The Project builds on IFC&apos;&apos;s cultural heritage and tourism strategies.  At several sites, the Project will embody direct, proactive development of cultural heritage through several measures.  The project will contribute to the preservation, renovation and interpretation of Inka and Spanish Colonial cultural heritage into the tourist experience. Furthermore, the Project will facilitate the growth of cultural-heritage or nature related travel in a sustainable manner to several regions, including Machu Picchu, Amazonia, and the Andes (Lake Titcaca).  The development of higher quality lodging in such areas is expected to encourage increased visitation and, thus, economic benefit to the local areas.  The expansion of this Peruvian, private sector, small business will bring related positive impacts on local employment, local training, foreign exchange and tax revenue.       IFC Role:       Inka Terra does not have access to financing from traditional sources due to its limited size, specialized focus and related ecological undertakings.  Despite these limitations, the Company has built up an impressive record of sustainability and growth.  By supporting the Company, IFC will allow it to expedite the implementation of its strategy to build a network of eco-tourism lodges.  Such a network will enable the Company to offer a broader range of eco-tourism vacation packages and significantly increase its visibility vis-&#xE0;-vis tour operators and the public in general.  This, in turn, will improve the Company&apos;&apos;s financial performance and help it build a stronger financial structure for future growth.  IFC&apos;&apos;s support for this project will also help to publicize the success of the concept, set physical standards for future investments and increase foreign exchange earnings for Peru.     Development Impact   :  Mr. Jose Koechlin and Inka Terra have shown that eco-tourism is an effective mechanism for balancing conservation and social development opportunities with commercial reality and demands.  The proposed Project will help them to build on their successful experiences in the Amazon and elsewhere in Peru.  By promoting sustainable tourism in a culturally and ecologically sensitive environment the Project could potentially have wider beneficial impacts through replication by others.  The Project is also expected to contribute to Peru&apos;&apos;s tourism infrastructure by providing international standard accommodations in a variety of important tourist destinations throughout the country, thereby attracting more visitors, more foreign currency spending and more jobs.  Meanwhile, traditional culture and other natural elements will be preserved.  Additionally, the Company will upgrade its human capital by imparting professional training to its employees, and providing life style changing career paths in the hospitality industry.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INKA TERRA PERU S.A.C.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-10651" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2001-01-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2001-01-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sr. Jose Koechlin, Presidente   422-6574   Inka Terra   Andalucia 174   Miraflores-Lima-Peru</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peru</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="PE-Peru">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will include expansions at several sites, including:  the Machu Picchu Pueblo Hotel in Aguas Calientes, Peru (existing); Cuzco Amazonico Pueblo Hotel near Puerto Maldonado, Peru (existing); Cusco Pueblo Hotel (existing structure) in Cuzco, Peru; Machu Picchu Pueblo Lodge on the same site in Aguas Calientes, Peru (new); Concepcion Pueblo Hotel, near Puerto Maldonado, Peru (existing structure) and the Puno Pueblo Hotel (new) in Puno, Peru.  Two of the projects will be the renovation of existing structures, two will be additions to existing lodges, and two will be entirely new structures.  The projects are located in a wide array of sites, ranging from the Madre De Dios rain forest to the center of Cuzco.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-10.0000000000 -75.2500000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AD - Tour Operators (i.e., Arranging and Assembling Tours)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $8.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2001-01-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2001-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2001-01-25">8000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2001-01-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2001-01-25">8000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INKA TERRA PERU S.A.C.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/10651/inka-terra-peru-s-a-c">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
