<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-506050</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GEF Inka Terra</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Although ITA is a relatively new organization, it contains highly capable and dedicated staff who have been working on biodiversity conservation in Peru for many years.  The staff members have undertaken various conservation projects in conjunction with the Missouri Botanical Garden.  These have included, for example, an orchid conservation initiative and a reforestation project for cock of the rock habitat. ITA staff members have also implemented a conservation project for the spectacled bear and collaborated on a biological research endeavor with the University of Kansas.      This project aims to achieve long-term conservation of the 10,000 hectare Inka Terra Ecological Reserve and its many species of flora &amp; fauna.  The specific objectives include the following:     -1  To develop a Forest Conservation and Management Plan that properly zones the reserve based upon a solid understanding of its ecology;    -2  To develop partnerships with the four local communities so they can improve their quality of life while helping to preserve the forests;    -3  To promote increased support for forest conservation and sustainable development through training programs; and    -4  To generate long-term funding for conservation through development of new ecotourism attractions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNKNOWN</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-506050" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2004-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jose Purisaca   Jir&#xF3;n Andaluc&#xED;a N 174    Miraflores, Lima 18, Peru   Fax: (511) 422-4701</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peru</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="PE-Peru">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will be implemented in conjunction with Inka Terras Reserva Amaz&#xF3;nica lodge in southeastern Peru.   Reserva Amaz&#xF3;nica has been in operation for over 25 years and was one of the first eco-tourist facilities developed in Peru.  The Reserva Amaz&#xF3;nica lodge was formerly known as Cusco Amaz&#xF3;nico.    During much of this time, Inka Terra has leased a 10,000 hectare area of tropical rainforest located adjacent to the lodge.  Known as the Inka Terra Ecological Reserve (IER), the company has supported considerable ecological research within this reserve.  The studies carried out to date in the reserve have identified considerable biological diversity, including 136 species of mammals, 366 species of birds, 83 species of reptiles, and 362 species of ants.  Many of the species of flora and fauna in the reserve were discovered there and some have not been found elsewhere in Peru.    Despite Inka Terra S.A.s desire to promote forest conservation, the IER has remained largely unmanaged because the company has been largely occupied with running its tourism operations. Although Inka Terra S.A. possesses staff members with considerable conservation experience and expertise, until recently these individuals faced conflicting demands on their time (between commercial and conservation priorities).  In fact, until this project was developed, there had been relatively little diagnosis of the threats to the areas biodiversity.    Yet various threats have emerged to the forest.  A transcontinental road has been built on the back (north) of the reserve, going to Brazil.  Since it is still a dirt road it does not have heavy traffic yet, but it has nonetheless facilitated encroachment upon the reserve.  The threat of logging has also been exacerbated by the road. Furthermore, several communities have arisen on the border of the IER.  Finally, mercury pollution from gold mining in the Madre de Dios River is threatening aquatic biodiversity (as well as human health).</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-10.0000000000 -75.2500000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other (For Non-Investment Projects)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/506050/gef-inka-terra">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
