<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5113008402-MLI-14010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Water Resources Management</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Integrerad vattenresursf&#xF6;rvaltning</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) support and development of existing Local Water Resources User Committees (CLEs) for common well-informed decisions on water         allocation and contribute to increased food security and higher incomes in rural area,  2) strengthening of national water information system to measure, store and analyze water data for informed decision making, 3) update the national IWRM plan (PAGIRE)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Prgm best&#xE5;r av: 1) st&#xF6;d och utveckling av befintliga lokala vattenresurskommitt&#xE9;er (CLEs) f&#xF6;r att underl&#xE4;tta gemensamma           v&#xE4;linformerade beslut om tilldelning vatten och d&#xE4;rigenom bidra till  &#xF6;kad livsmedelstrygghet och h&#xF6;gre inkomster p&#xE5; landsbygden, 2)        St&#xE4;rkande av det nationella vatteninformationssystemet och 3)uppdatera den nationella vattenresursf&#xF6;rvaltningsplanen (PAGIRE)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The joint programme on IWRM (PCA-GIRE) has been financed by the Netherlands and Sweden and implemented by the National Water Directorate (Direction Nationale de l&#x2019;Hydraulique, DNH) under the Ministry of Water and Energy as well as Wetlands International Mali. Sweden contributed with about 20 M SEK (11 % of the total budget) for the period 2014&#x2013;2019.
&#xA0;
The Swedish support included a technical assistance component implemented by COWI amounting to 6,5 M SEK. The remaining budget allocated to the DNH has among other things contributed to improving access to reliable data. The Netherlands finances activities implemented by the DNH and Wetlands while also having a specific focus on activities within the transboundary water management component, including activities that are implemented in Guinea and on in the border areas with Burkina Faso (the Sourou). The Dutch support continues until 2020 and has been extended to 2021.
&#xA0;
The total budget is about 130 M SEK to which Mali contributes 15 %. The PCA-GIRE is built around five main pillars; improving policy, legal and financial frameworks, increasing transboundary water management and cooperation, increasing access and use of hydrological data, support to the decentralization of the water sector according to sub-basins and promoting cross-cutting aspects such as climate change and gender. Since the PCA-GIRE was initiated, the new national programme for IWRM (PN-GIRE) has been developed and approved by a technical committee (not politically).
The PN-GIRE sets out a new direction with new priority results areas</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COWI A/S</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DNH Mali/Direction Nationale de l&apos;Hydralique du Mali</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ML" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mali</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">124263.5806057443</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">124263.5806057443</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-01">152692.459073</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">124263.5675560248</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since the start of the programme in 2014, the following main results per results component of the PCA-GIRE can be noted.
Component 1 - development and function of the IWRM framework: - The policy framework of the water sector has since the crisis in 2012 been under revision. Contributing to this process has been a key focus on the PCA-GIRE, in collaboration with other actors such as the World Bank. During the final years of the programme, the national water policy was finalised and approved by the technical committee. The legal framework seems to have been finished and approved by the technical committee, although the process has been less transparent.
- The development of the policy framework was somewhat blocked for several years due to diverging visions between the DNH, the DNACPN and various donors. During 2018 and 2019, the blockage was mainly between the DNH and the GIZ due to the unclear status of the PROSEA II. The Embassy has continuously engaged with the DNH and the other donors while attempting to find a balance between promoting ownership and ensuring harmonisation with other donors while also promoting important institutional change. By the end of 2019, it appears that the development of all the programs will receive funding (funding for implementation is not clear). During 2020, the recruitment of consultants was initiated by the DNH. National ownership now appears stronger, mainly since it is the DNH model that has been maintained; a policy and five accompanying programmes. The role of the DNACPN is also important to keep in mind, as well as other state structures such as the ABFN.
- The PROSEA II has hence been given less importance but could serve as a way for donors to harmonise in the future. The remaining risk is that the programs are developed in an unharmonized way and that important aspects, such as transboundary water management and institutional change, are left out or not carried out.
&#x2013;During 2018, the Minister of Energy and Water called for two meetings in the National council of water on (1) the water stress experienced by the end of 2017 and beginning of 2018 and (2) the achievements within IWRM over the years and perspectives for the new IWRM program. These meetings were the first meetings of the council since several years. However, no council meetings were held in 2019 which shows a certain decrease in momentum again.
&#xA0;
- In addition to the policy documents (policy and legal framework), a new IWRM program was finalised and adopted by a technical committee in 2019. This is a positive sign of progress, although civil society was barely active during consultations (with the exception of Wetlands international) and there are technical weaknesses of the programme (mainly linked to transboundary water management and governance).
- An important forum for water management is the Commission that manages water levels in S&#xE9;lingu&#xE9; and Markala. The commission made extensive efforts to communicate around the impacts of the low water levels due to the poor rainy season in 2017. The commission continued to be active in 2019 but had a less prominent role since water levels were not as extreme. Flooding was however experienced, and the commission played a role in water level management as per their mandate.
Component 2 (transboundary water management):
- The key issue in terms of transboundary water management is the planned/ongoing dam construction in Guinea. The development has been politically sensitive since several years, also within the Niger Basin Authority. The main aspects to keep in mind is the Guinean need for electricity (likely for industrial development and for Conakry mainly) and the Malian interest in storing water for rice production. - The environmental interests are mainly promoted by Wetlands international which plays a key role in producing extremely important data from the Niger Delta.
&#xA0;- It is not clear which is presenting and lobbying for the diverse social interests, locally and downstream (including for example the pastoralists groups in the delta). The development is very sensitive, and several actors are involved in the process at regional level, including Sweden through the support to the World Bank programme CIWA.
&#xA0;- Transboundary cooperation in the Sourou continues to be a priority and the development of a basin plan (SAGE) is ongoing. The SAGE is linked to other Dutch-funded projects in the Sourou (overall cross-sectoral planning). The security situation has continued to deteriorate significantly in this area.
Component 3 (national water information system):
&#xA0;- In 2018, the DNH carried out the first water analysis of the water in Mali. This was a key success of the programme and mainly financed through Sweden. In 2019, the DNH continued with one measurement of water quality in collaboration with the national laboratory.
- A few main polluters have been identified, including the leather dyeing industries, the brick makers, the artisanal miners, etc. Initial collaborations have been initiated with the dyeing industries to improve effluent.
&#xA0;- Overall, water chemical and physical water quality seems satisfactory, except for the site Sidikila where levels of turbidity, nitrate and heavy metals are above norms (2019 report).
Component 4 (local water management):
&#xA0;- The work on local water management is longstanding and several approaches have been tested. In 2017, a collaboration with a national NGO, GFORCE, was initiated which strengthened DNH&#x2019;s capacity to work locally. The work has also received significant support through COWI, focusing on gender, conflict management and rights.
- The quality of the work and the results are still questionable due to several factors: the lack of basin agencies, the lack of real interest or role, the lack of capacity of the DNH to support, etc. The need for strengthened local structures for improved water management is however clear, especially addressing the need to prevent conflict around water resources and using water sustainably for economic development. - Worth noting is that Sweden supports IUCN in promoting CLEs in Mali and in Burkina Faso. IUCN in Mali might be well placed to work on these issues and the collaboration between the DNH and IUCN seems to be at least functioning.
Component 5 (transversal areas including gender, governance, climate change, education): - The climate change study was finalised in 2019 and resulted in very good dialogue across several ministries as well as input to the water policy, legal framework and new programs. The approach was successful and there are opportunities to build on these results. - COWI has since 2014 provided important support to the DNH, for example through the development of guides and other tools for local water management that integrates gender and human rights-based approaches.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51130084" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
