<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5113008201-MLI-15151</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local elections support Mali 2014-2015</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Valst&#xF6;d lokala och regionala val Mali 2014-2015</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention&apos;s outcome objectives are clearly described, as follows:
1- The organisation f communal, municipal and local elections- with an integrated gender perspective- that are credible, legitimate and conformant to national legislation, international norms and regional instruments governing electoral processes.
2- National institutions, systems and processes of democratic governance are strengthened for better management of electoral processes.
Expected results- i.e. outputs are relevant and follow a logical chain in relation to the intended outcomes as well as contribute to the overall impact of the intervention. They are as folows:
1. The national capacity to manage the electoral process is strengthened permitting national ownership of the coordination mechanisms and sustainability of results2. Equal access and participation of women and vulnerable groups is ensured through an inclusive programme of civic education, communication/information and awareness raising taking into account their specific needs3. The local elections are organised in accordance with legal provisions and in a free, fair and transparent manner4. The election results are maintained based on the joint evaluation of the Ministry of Interior and Security(MIS) and development partners with the view to continue developing capacity of the institutional actors and civil society active in the electoral domaine5. RAVEC is restructured and finalised for the recast of the electoral register for the electionsMeasurable indicators are part of the results framework and Sida assesses them to be of sufficient quality. Baseline values exist for most but not all indicators, building on results to date in the ongoing electoral process project. This is deemed satisfactory at present but dialogue with UNDP will be undertaken to include more baselines if possible, based on project results to date and previous data pertaining to the electoral process in Mali.Critical assumptions are presented in the project document with major factors such as political will, potential low interest in the voting population and the dominant issue of insecurity and low state presence in the northern regions. Some mitigation measures have been defined but most will be beyond the scope of this project. The recent outbreak of Ebola is an additional risk which needs to be taken into account with potential need for additional mitigation strategy - to be explored further in dialogue with UNDP. It is the intention of the Sweden&#x2019;s Embassy to liaise closely with the steering committee, national and international partners, to monitor and, if possible, influence the electoral process in face of these external conditions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNDP har s&#xF6;kt finansiering fr&#xE5;n Sida f&#xF6;r den korgfond som etablerats till st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r valprocessen i Mali,  f&#xF6;r den andra fasen som fokuserar p&#xE5; lokala val under 2014-2015.

Insatsen &#xE4;r del av en l&#xE4;ngre demokratiseringsprocess som startat till f&#xF6;ljd av den politiska och institutionella krisen 2012. Insatsens huvudsyfte &#xE4;r att st&#xE4;rka den pluralistiska demokratin, bygga grundvalar f&#xF6;r r&#xE4;ttsstaten samt konsolidera den politiska stabiliteten i Mali. St&#xF6;det till valprocessen kanaliseras genom en korgfond som administreras av UNDP och som genomf&#xF6;rs i n&#xE4;ra samarbete med andra nationella och internationella partners. Denna fas av valprocessen inkluderar lokala och regionala val som planeras h&#xE5;llas den 27 april 2015.

Insatsen best&#xE5;r av fyra nyckelkomponenter:
1. St&#xE4;rkande av kapacitet f&#xF6;r Inrikesministeriet f&#xF6;r att samordna och ansvara f&#xF6;r valprocessen 2014-2015
2. St&#xF6;d till medborgarutbildning med fokus p&#xE5; spridning av valrelaterad information.
3. Uppr&#xE4;tth&#xE5;lla resultaten som uppn&#xE5;tts genom arbetet med den administrativa folkr&#xE4;kningen (RAVEC)
4. St&#xE4;rkande av kapacitet p&#xE5; sikt f&#xF6;r valinstitutionerna

Den totala budgeten f&#xF6;r dena insats &#xE4;r ca 80 MUSD d&#xE4;rav Malis regering bidrar med ca 42 MUSD - vilket l&#xE4;mnar 38 MUSD f&#xF6;r extern finansiering. 20 MUSD finns redan i korgfonden vilket ger ett finansiellt behov av ca 18 MUSD - ca 133 MSEK. Det svenska bidraget uppg&#xE5;r till 45 MSEK. Detta &#xE4;r en forts&#xE4;ttning av utvecklingsinsatsen 2013 d&#xE5; Sverige bidrog med 45 MSEK till samma korgfond.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP has applied to Sida for contribution to the basket fund established to support the electoral process in Mali, its second phase now focussing on local elections during 2014-2015.

The intervention is part of a longerterm process of democratisation following the political and institutional crisis that erupted in 2012. The main purpose of the programme is to strengthen the pluralist democracy, entrench rule of law and consolidate the political stability of Mali. The support to the electoral process is channeled through an election basket fund managed by UNDP in close cooperation with other national and international partners. This phase of the electoral process includes local and regional elections which are foreseen for 27 April 2015.

The intervention consists of four key components:
1. Strengthening the capacity of the Ministry of Interior and Security (MIS) to manage and coordinate the electoral process 2014-2015
2. Support to civic and voter education with focus on dissemination of electoral information.
3. Sustaining the results achieved through the work on the adminstrative census with civil registration (RAVEC Recensement Administratif &#xE0; Vocation d&apos;Etat Civil)
4. Strengthening the long term capacity of the electoral institutions

The total budget of this intervention is approximately 80 MUSD of which the Government of Mali will contribute approximately 42 MUSD - leaving 38 MUSD for external financing. 20 MUSD is already in the basket fund, making the gap to be mobilised approximately 18 MUSD - or 133 MSEK. The Swedish contribution amounts to 45 MSEK, to be disbursed upon signature of agreement. This is a continuance of the 2013 development intervention where Sweden contributed 45 MSEK to the same basket fund.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ML" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mali</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15151" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elections</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B04" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">6559862.3886645585</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">6559862.3886645585</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-01">6559862.388664</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-28">6559862.3886645585</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Embassy signed two agreements with UNDP: the first in 2013 regarding Presidential and legislative elections (45 MSEK) and the second in 2014 for local elections (45 MSEK). The local elections after several postponements took place in November-Decemeber 2016. The contribution Id for the two interventions are respectively 51130075 (electoral Process in Mali) and 51130082 (Local elections support Mali 2014-2015). From UNDP side, this was understood as a continuity between the two agreements. Thus, the final report submitted covers all the three elections mentioned above. On the 90 MSEK disbursed, UNDP, after the operational completion date, has been requested to make a repayment of unexpended funds as it was above 5,000 USD. On 2018-02-23, Sida received from UNDP 1 554 186:39 USD from UNDP. (See Email from&#xA0;Jenny Romin, Ekonomiadministrat&#xF6;r LED/REDO dated 2018-03-13).&#xA0;The whole contribution to the electoral support from 2013 to 2016 has been booked under&#xA0;51130075 01.&#xA0;However, the completion report is written under the contribution 51130082 (local elections support Mali 2014-2015) because the appraisal of the contribution 51130075 has been done on templates when the Embassy had not access to the new computer-based contribution management. &#xA0;
Significant results have been achieved through the support to electoral process in Mali from 2013 to 2016:
1) The successful organization of five elections: the two rounds of the presidential elections, the two rounds of the legislative elections and local election throughout the national territory and in Diplomatic and Consular missions despite the insecurity climate; &#xA0;
2) The credibility of the electoral process, the conduct of peaceful elections, the acceptance of the votes results by both winner and losing parties thanks to the sensitization campaigns and the adoption of consensual code of good practices for political parties and candidates 
3) The establishment of the biometric electoral register, updated periodically, reliable and consensual
4) The high turnout at the election, including the record turnout of 51, 54% at the first round of the 2013 presidential elections 
5) The establishment of a pool of 125&#xA0;000 electoral experts, recruited, trained by PAPEM on which the country will be able to rely on during the future elections.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51130082" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
