<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5113004803-MLI-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mali Local Democratic Governance phase 3</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Mali Local Democratic Governance phase 3</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) Improved performance of local land management arrangements; 
2) Improved ownership of local government authorities in land and natural resources management; 
3) Improved the performance of citizen control for accountability among stakeholders involved in land and natural resources management; 
4) Improved sustainable use of agricultural land and other natural resources (forests, grazing, water).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Four INGOs led by Diakonia have submitted an application for the development intervention &#x201C;Local Democratic Governance&#x201D; (LDG), phase 3 in Mali during the period 2014-2017. The overall development intervention cost is approximately 76 MSEK. 

The intervention aims to improve inclusiveness and accountability of land governance and prevent conflict linked to land management in Mali. This will be achieved through the implementation of four components with the following results: 

1) Improved performance of local land management arrangements; 
2) Improved ownership of local government authorities in land and natural resources management; 
3) Improved the performance of citizen control for accountability between stakeholders involved in land and natural resources management; 
4) Improved sustainable use of agricultural land and other natural resources (forests, grazing, water). The four INGOs i.e Diakonia, Norwegian Church Aid, SNV and Helvetas Swiss Intercooperation will implement the intervention together with local Civil Society Organisations.

The intervention is supported solely by Sweden and it is planned that the four INGOs will forward funds to their local partners.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Fyra intenationella enskilda organisationer (INGOs) med svenska organisationen Diakonia som fokalpunkt har inkommit med en ans&#xF6;kan om finansiellt st&#xF6;d till programmet &#x201C;Local Democratic Governance&#x201D; (LDG), fas 3 i Mali f&#xF6;r perioden 2014-2017. Den totala kostnaden f&#xF6;r programmet &#xE4;r SEK 76 miljoner.  

Insatsen syftar till att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra delaktighet och ansvarstagande inom markfr&#xE5;gor f&#xF6;r sm&#xE5;skaliga jordbrukare och motverka konflikter i relation till markanv&#xE4;ndning i Mali. Fyra resultatomr&#xE5;den &#xE4;r identifierade: 

1) F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad funktionalitet av lokala &#xF6;verenskommelser f&#xF6;r markanv&#xE4;ndning; 
2) St&#xE4;rkt &#xE4;garskap hos lokala myndigheter vad g&#xE4;ller mark- och naturresursfr&#xE5;gor; 
3) St&#xE4;rkt medborgarkontroll och &#xF6;kat ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande i relation till mark- och naturresursfr&#xE5;gor; 
4) Mer h&#xE5;llbar anv&#xE4;ndning av jordbruksmark och andra naturresurser (skog, betesmarker, vatten). 

De fyra organisationerna som ans&#xF6;ker om st&#xF6;d &#xE4;r svenska Diakonia, norska Kyrkans N&#xF6;dhj&#xE4;lp, holl&#xE4;ndska SNV och schweiziska Helvetas Swiss Intercooperation. Dessa kommer att genomf&#xF6;ra programmet i n&#xE4;ra samarbete med lokala organisationer. 

Insatsen finansieras endast via svenska medel. Medel kommer att vidarebefordras till lokala organisationer.

Av Sidas spr&#xE5;kregel f&#xF6;ljer att aktuellt avtal enligt huvudregeln ska utformas p&#xE5; svenska. I detta fall utg&#xF6;r avtalet en tillkommande del i ett befintligt samarbete med mellan parterna, d&#xE4;r tidigare avtal har uppr&#xE4;ttats p&#xE5; engelska. D&#xE4;rtill &#xE4;r den faktiska m&#xE5;lgruppen f&#xF6;r avtalet Diakonias regionala kontor och dess samarbetspartners, f&#xF6;r vilka engelska &#xE4;r ett krav. Med h&#xE4;nsyn h&#xE4;rtill bed&#xF6;ms det motiverat att i detta fall genom avsteg fr&#xE5;n spr&#xE5;kregelns huvudregel utforma avtalet p&#xE5; engelska.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ML" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mali</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">49481.914334132</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">49481.914334132</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-07-01">61719.850143</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-28">49481.914334132</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conducting joint advocacy on issues regarding the management of natural resources at local level 
A strength of the Consortium was its ability &#x2013; through its local network of partners- to gather evidence on issues related to natural resources management at local level. The consortium has used those inputs for conducting joint advocacy and raising priorities and messages. This process serves as a practical mean to connect different levels including the local, regional and national. The Consortium uses its size and diversity of experiences and profiles to amplify advocacy action. The result is a significant depth and breadth of reach and influence. In addition, the consortium utilises its growing evidence-based and collective voice to provide input into a wide range of important forums and processes related to the governance of natural resources management. The work was often conducted in collaboration with other alliances and movements &#x2013; serving to further expand the Consortium&#x2019;s reach and impact. 
An illustration of this area of achievement is provided by the recent adoption of the agricultural land law (Programme GLD, Rapport Final 2014-2017, Pages 7 to 8) which was the result of a long process of mobilization of various actors as well as in the preparation of arguments and advocacy campaigns by CSOs. 
Increasing accountability and responsiveness from duty bearers on natural resources management 
Throughout the implementation, it was noted that more communities across the program are demanding increasingly more accountability and responsiveness from the duty bearers following the different actions carried out. In most of the municipalities covered, held public hearings, space where citizens had the opportunity to question local elected government officials on natural resources issues were held. This was used as a conduit to demand accountability and influence the quality of services.
 In line with this action mentioned above, the program has supported the monitoring, information and control systems as well as the participation of natural resources users through dialogue and debates on the issues of the exploitation of natural resources.
Local government authorities have been the main beneficiaries of the activities implemented under this component. Key activities have included training sessions for representative of municipalities as well as the organization of the Malian Environment Weeks (Quinzaine de l&apos;environnement) by certain municipalities. Some exchange visits with the purpose of learning and sharing experiences have been also organized.
As part of the media coverage of natural resources management activities, the program has supported the pool of journalists/facilitators to hold exchange meetings and to participate in activities initiated by other actors working on the same theme. Thus, the representatives of the local radio stations have participated in the training sessions and information/awareness meetings of the networks and platforms in which local CSOs supported by the program are member.
The citizen jury made up of elected local authorities and citizens coming from municipalities have listened to and examined information on natural resources and land issues. Elected local authorities have responded to questions of citizens. Certain deliberations and recommendations of the different citizen jury have been taken into account in the local development plans and by local decision makers. These experiences have provided a transparent and democratic tool to support a decision making process at local level. examples of concrete recommendations translated into decisions include bans on cutting green wood, the fight against bush fires and the participation&#xA0; of citizens watch committees in municipality council meetings. (page 25).
&quot;It would appear that LDG III has succeeded in imparting on beneficiaries a sense of the meaning of accountability that previously did not exist, a very important result if it can be sustained over time&quot;. (Rapport final, Revue Ind&#xE9;pendante &#xE0; mi-parcours du Programme de Gouvernance Locale D&#xE9;mocratique (GLD) Phase III, Octobre 2016, Page 11)&#xA0;
Improving the participation of women in decision-making bodies
Women&apos;s access to decision-making bodies has improved. This result is based on the presence of women in the municipal councils, monitoring committees and local infrastructures management bodies. This situation is the result of the support of the various phases of the LDG program and the support to the electoral process by other programs. Efforts have been made to maintain and improve the presence of women in community management bodies through the consolidation of land commissions or advocacy/lobbying for women&#x2019;s representation. &#xA0;The set-up of socio-professional organizations management structures as well as for those regarding local infrastructures management were also an opportunity to improve women&#x2019;s access to decision-making bodies. (Page 9 Rapport final 2017).
64 citizens watch committees have been set-up and are composed on average of 30% of woman.
Improving performance of local land management arrangements&#xA0;
The important result achieved against this component is the operationalization of 23 land commissions in 32 municipalities. These land commissions have been equipped with tools allowing them to perform tasks as for example the inventory of habits and customs in the area of land tenure management, the adoption of their rules and procedures and the development and the adoption of the record model of conciliation or non conciliation regarding the management of conflicts linked to the use of natural resources.&#xA0;Reinforced by these tools, the land commissions have intervened in the management of 90 cases of conflicts relating to the settlement of land disputes to the satisfaction of conflicting parties. The record of the settlement of land disputes were sent to the court for its technical approval (French word Homologation), which allowed the conflicting parties to gain in time and economy especially during periods of major agricultural work.&#xA0;Indeed, if the conflict cases were brought directly to justice, the procedures would take more time and require a lot of resources from the parties in conflict.
The land commissions members are now able to lead a mediation process and master their roles and responsibilities through the different trainings received throughout the implementation period (Page 19 of the final report).&#xA0;
The land commissions supported by the program have been active during the three years of implementation. They have intervened in the management of ninety (90) cases of conflicts related to the settlement of land disputes (pastoral and agricultural land) to the satisfaction of the parties and the concerned municipalities. The minutes drawn from the conciliations are sent to the court for homologation; this allowed the actors, during periods of intensive agricultural work, to save time and resources (money and work). Indeed, if the problem were directly brought to justice, these resolved conflicts would drag on long enough time and require a lot of resources to the parties in conflict.
The program has also accompanied communities in the realization of collective infrastructures enabling the sustainable exploitation of natural resources.  At the end of 2015, &#xA0;11 collective installations including 4 small market gardens, 2 small dams and 5 operational deep-sea pools have management committees.
These infrastructures have improved the access to water for humans and animals. For example, 4 ponds have been dug out in the municipalities of Anchawadji, Intillit in the Gao region. &#xA0;
Another key result reported under this component is the involvement of local radios in sensitizations activities through non-violent transformation activities, the dissemination of local conventions regarding sustainable use of natural resources.&#xA0;Moreover, the agricultural orientation law, the pastoral charter, the land tenure code have been translated in local language and disseminated in 18 municipalities covered by the program. (Page 14). The partnership with 22 local radio stations has permitted an awareness raising of citizens on land and natural resources issues. (Page 21).&#xA0;
Improving sustainable use of agricultural land and other natural resources (forests, grazing, water)
Communities have been strengthened in the protection, conservation and restoration of soils to ensure sustainable use of land and water resources through erosion control, reforestation and sites reserved for natural regeneration.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51130048" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060603" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1180000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Mali 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Mali 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
