<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11790A0101-MLI-41081</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to National Environmental Weeks 2018</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Support to National Environmental Weeks 2018</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida&apos; s support to Mali yearly Environmental Education Weeks and Outreach linking the World Environment Day ( June 5) and the World Anti- Desertification Day (June 17) for 2018.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Sidas st&#xF6;d till Malis &#xE5;rliga milj&#xF6;utbildningsveckor och Outreach som knyter samman v&#xE4;rldsmilj&#xF6;dagen (5 juni) och v&#xE4;rldsdagen f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa &#xF6;kenspridning och torka (17 juni) f&#xF6;r 2018.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="12001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AEDD/Agence de l&apos;Environnement et du Developpement Durable</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="12001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Government in recipient country</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ML" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mali</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="41081" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental education/training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="410" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Environment Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">57534.7509895977</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">57534.7509895977</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-05">57534.750989</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-28">57534.7509895977</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Mali National Environmental Weeks aims at increasing the citizen&apos;s, the decision makers, the private sector, the Civil Society members and the donor community&apos;s awareness of the emergency to preserve and restore environmental resources for current and future generations&apos; sustainable uses.The Mali annual environmental weeks regularly organized and held since 2000, refer to two dates: June 5, the World Environment Day (WED) and the World Anti Desertification Day held on June 17. The Mali National Environment Day is the biggest, most celebrated day for positive environmental action and collective behavior change as well as in Mali and globally. It is a vehicle for encouraging nationwide awareness and action for the environment. Over the years, it has grown and has become a broad, global platform for public outreach that is widely celebrated by the government in collaboration with local communes, private sector, civil society and donors&#x2019; community. In 2018, the World Environment Day has been organized around the theme &#x201C;Beat Plastic Pollution&#x201D; while the World Day to combat desertification and drought is organized around the theme &#x201C;Land has true value. Invest in it&quot;. The theme reminds the world that land is a tangible asset with measurable value beyond just cash.Concerning the 2018 event, most of the activities took place in Koulikoro, about 60 km away from Bamako where Sida supports a major Programme Decentralized Forests Management. The aim of the event was to sensitize the regional public as well as the national policy decision makers on the environmental and climate change problematic issues, their consequences and potential solutions in development programming. For the 2018 event, Daniel Tiveau, Programme Officer at the Embassy, Bamako represented the Embassy of Sweden at the opening ceremony. Numerous activities were held:Ahead of the official launch of the event, five major activities were held: 1. Preparatory meetings were held in Bamako as well as in the administrative regions of Mali2. A National Organizational Committee was officially created by the Ministry of Environment, Sanitation and Sustainable development3. A Workshop has been organized on the achievements and constraints of the 2017 event4. Information was exchanged between the authorities of Koulikoro and the National Organizational Committee to mobilize them and to ensure the success of the event5. Various media campaigns were organized in Bamako and in various other locations. During the opening ceremony, speeches from the Mayor of Koulikoro, the UNDP Mali Director on behalf of the donors&#x2019; community in Environment and Climate Change, the Minister of Environment, Sanitation and Sustainable development and finally by the Prime &#x2013; Minister.After the official inception ceremony and for fifteen days, various educational, sanitation and afforestation activities have been conducted among which:&#x2022;Workshops and fora were organized on various themes related to environmental protection/restoration, sustainable land and forests management, as well as to sanitation, pastoralism, sustainable management of fisheries, the UN Sustainable Development Goals, the Integrated Water Resources Management, The irrigated agriculture, the role and place of youth and women in climate change mitigation and adaptation, waste management, mining versus environment, etc.&#x2022;Journalists have been also trained on environmental communication&#x2022;Symbolic plantation activities and sanitation have been made also in various locations of Mali &#x2022;Sketches have been performed by local artists on the negative impact of plastic pollutants, sustainable land resources management and environmental good governance.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11790" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060603" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1180000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Mali 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Mali 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
